<xml><p>

The War and Peace Digest is a bimonthly international newsletter on issues
of disarmament, government secrecy, media accountability, the nuclear
threat (from both civilian power plants and the military weapons complex),
ecological destruction, and peaceful conflict resolution through the
structures of the <ent type='ORG'>United Nations</ent>.  If you would like to be placed on our
mailing list or receive a copy of our new information packet on nuclear
power, contact Matthew Freedman at 32 Union Square East, New York, NY
10003-3295 (Tel: 212-777-6626).

Contributions are always welcome.  All materials may be reproduced without
permission.

    --------------------

   <ent type='ORG'>BNL</ent> - IRAQGATE SCANDAL

    The <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> Connection - Bush &amp; Saddam Inc.
    Key documents - sought by Gonzalez - withheld

With George Bush ready to take <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> into another war with <ent type='GPE'>Iraq</ent> to
destroy the nuclear, chemical, biological and missiles weapons that Bush
himself helped Saddam Hussein to build, <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>men Henry Gonzalez, the
courageous <ent type='GPE'>Texas</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Democrat</ent> who heads <ent type='ORG'>the House <ent type='ORG'>Banking Committee</ent></ent>, continues,
single-handedly, to peel back layer after layer of cover-up to reveal the
monumental proportions of the <ent type='GPE'>Iraq</ent>gate-<ent type='ORG'>BNL</ent> (<ent type='ORG'>Banca Nazionale Del Lavoro</ent>)
scandal that now threatens to bring down the Bush regime. But the most
explosive documents have been withheld.

   Over the past several months Gonzalez  has shown  the  <ent type='GPE'>Iraq</ent>gate-
<ent type='ORG'>BNL</ent> scandal to be bigger than anyone had imagined.  He has uncovered and
reported incontestable evidence that Bush and his associates secretly sold
nuclear, biological, chemical and missile-related weapons materials to
Saddam Hussein; blocked investigations into the use of such materials by
Hussein; suppressed memos warning of the dangers of such sales;
deliberately  falsified documents on such sales submitted to <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent> and
interfered illegally to halt investigations into the criminal activities of
the <ent type='ORG'>BNL</ent> bank in secretly diverting <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n agricultural loans to buy the
weapons for Hussein.

<ent type='ORG'>BNL</ent>-<ent type='ORG'>BCCI</ent>  <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> Branches

 Gonzalez has revealed a Bush policy disaster that lead to the first
<ent type='LOC'>Gulf</ent> War and a blunder that is now costing the <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>ns  $2 billion to pay
off the loans Bush guaranteed with U.S. taxpayersU money . Bush repeatedly
ignored warnings that <ent type='GPE'>Iraq</ent> would default on the loans.  Now,  certain key
documents - perhaps the most revealing yet -  are  being withheld from the
Gonzalez investigation.  They are said to be the records of the <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>
branches of <ent type='ORG'>BNL</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>BCCI</ent> (Bank of Credit and Commerce International),
through which, some investigators say , George Bush and Saddam Hussein may
have been  involved in a joint, private enterprise to skim oil profits
arising from Reagan-Bush policies toward <ent type='GPE'>Iraq</ent>. The  documents have been
impounded by a <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> court and <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>man  Gonzalez <ent type='ORG'>Banking Committee</ent>
has been denied access.

Bush's <ent type='ORG'>Pennzoil</ent> Profits

 Between 1980 and 1990 the <ent type='LOC'>Gulf</ent> region exported a trillion dollars
worth of oil to the West. Hundreds of billions of dollars in kickbacks were
involved. Some of the kickbacks were said to be  handled by the <ent type='ORG'>BNL</ent>/<ent type='ORG'>BCCI</ent>
banks for <ent type='ORG'>Pennzoil</ent>, an oil company founded by George Bush  The <ent type='ORG'>Pennzoil</ent>
case  was (is?) the target of Ross PerotUs much-denied investigation of the
Bush family and friends. Investigators believe the <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> bank records
could help explain <ent type='ORG'>BushUs</ent> massive, covert military support for <ent type='GPE'>Iraq</ent> in the
years between 1981-1990.

   The <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> <ent type='ORG'>BNL</ent> /<ent type='ORG'>BCCI</ent> records could also provide clues to why the
Bush Administration secretly - and possibly illegally - exempted eleven
members of the Bush cabinet from conflict of interest restrictions in their
handling of the <ent type='LOC'>Gulf</ent> war policy. Bush simply declared that the law
regarding conflict of interest would cease to apply to his advisors on the
<ent type='LOC'>Gulf</ent> war policy. He then ordered that his declaration would be not be made
public. <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>man Gonzalez is now asking Bush to  explain the deal. Bush
has not responded.

  According to some investigators,  the <ent type='ORG'>BNL</ent>-<ent type='ORG'>BCCI</ent> bank documents
now impounded by a <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>  judge could  shed light not only on the
<ent type='GPE'>Iraq</ent>gate case, but on other illegal transactions including <ent type='GPE'>Iran</ent>-Contra,
October Surprise and the Inslaw case. In all instances monies passed
through the <ent type='ORG'>BNL</ent>/<ent type='ORG'>BCCI</ent>  banking network.

  <ent type='ORG'>BNL</ent> is an <ent type='NORP'>Italian</ent> bank now under  investigation by <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent> for
fraud in using loans from the U.S. Department of Agriculture to finance
<ent type='GPE'>Iraq</ent>Us pre-war military buildup. Over the past thirty years, <ent type='ORG'>BNL</ent> is
suspected of involvement in a wide range of international criminal
activities. (<ent type='ORG'>French Intelligence</ent> investigators have even linked the bank to
large payments to certain individuals in <ent type='LOC'>Europe</ent> in late 1963, thought to be
associated with the John Kennedy assassination.)

   On December 28th 1990, when Gonzalez  sought the records of the
<ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> branch of <ent type='ORG'>BNL</ent> (Case number 90 C 6863 of the U.S. District Court in
<ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>: People of the <ent type='ORG'>State</ent> of Illinois ex re; William C. Harris v. the
Board of Governors of the <ent type='ORG'>Federal Reserve</ent> System), Gonzalez was told by
Federal Judge, Brian Duff that he could not have them. Duff, a friend of
both Bush and Reagan, works closely with <ent type='ORG'>the <ent type='ORG'>Federal Reserve</ent> Bank</ent>. Duff
impounded the documents and abused GonzalezU attorney for Rbehaving like an
800 -pound gorilla.S That is when Duff impounded the records.

  Questions abound. Suspicions arise from the fact that among
officials involved in the <ent type='ORG'>BNL</ent> bank is Brent Scowcroft, <ent type='ORG'>BushUs</ent> National
Security advisor who, Gonzalez has now revealed, maintained a million-
dollar financial interest in 40 of the biggest U.S. weapons companies that
profited from U.S. policies toward <ent type='GPE'>Iraq</ent>, including General Electric,
<ent type='ORG'>General Motors</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>ITT</ent>, and <ent type='ORG'>Lockheed</ent>. Gonzalez has also revealed that
Assistant Secretary of <ent type='ORG'>State</ent> Laurence Eagleberger worked closely with <ent type='ORG'>BNL</ent>
when he and Scowcroft were part of Henry KissingerUs consulting firm.
Kissinger was a member of the board of <ent type='ORG'>BNL</ent> and his firm represents <ent type='ORG'>BNL</ent> in
the <ent type='GPE'>USA</ent>.

<ent type='ORG'>BNL</ent>, P2 and <ent type='ORG'>the <ent type='ORG'>Vatican Bank</ent></ent>

  The <ent type='ORG'>BNL</ent> bank was also used for secret arms trade by the outlawed P2
<ent type='ORG'>Masonic Lodge</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>Rome</ent>, whose Grandmaster, Licio Gelli is thought to have
been the mastermind behind <ent type='ORG'>BNL</ent>Us illegal, world-wide banking strategies,
until his arrest in 1981, for embezzling $1.5 billion from the Vatican
Bank. The <ent type='ORG'>Vatican Bank</ent> had close ties with <ent type='ORG'>BNL</ent>. Gelli was recently
sentenced to 18 years in jail for his role in the case.

  Gelli was involved with the PopeUs banker and bodyguard, Bishop
Marcinkus (formerly of <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>) in <ent type='ORG'>the <ent type='ORG'>Vatican Bank</ent></ent> embezzlement. When  the
<ent type='NORP'>Italian</ent> government issued a warrant for the BishopUs arrest they were
blocked by the Vatican, which claims  separate city-state authority. (The
Pope is still closely involved with Marcinkus and <ent type='ORG'>the <ent type='ORG'>Vatican Bank</ent></ent> is still
closely associated with <ent type='ORG'>BNL</ent>.)

  Bush and Gelli are friends.  Gelli was guest of honor at the 1981
Reagan-Bush inaugural ball. (N.Y. <ent type='ORG'>Times</ent>, June 4, 1981, page 7.)  Kissinger
also knew Gelli. When Gelli was arrested in March, 1981, Kissinger
immediately sent an agent to <ent type='GPE'>Rome</ent> with $18000 to try to buy some of the
documents in the P2 case to keep them from becoming public ( In These
<ent type='ORG'>Times</ent>, Sept. 1982).  It may be of interest that P2 had a lodge in <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>.

  <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>, it is now emerging, has been the central point for vast,
international, illegal transactions involving the <ent type='ORG'>BNL</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>BCCI</ent> banks and
secret deals with <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n oil companies, military manufacturers, the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>,
and possibly U.S. politicians. (According to a <ent type='GPE'>London</ent> source, unreleased
<ent type='ORG'>BCCI</ent> documents in the possession of the Bank of <ent type='GPE'>London</ent>  list the names of
at least 105 members of U.S. <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent> - of both <ent type='ORG'>Houses</ent> and both parties -
who have received money through the <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> branch of <ent type='ORG'>BCCI</ent>. The U.S.
<ent type='ORG'>Federal Reserve</ent> is said to have a copy of the same secret <ent type='ORG'>BCCI</ent> list).

The Octopus

 Just as the P2 scandal in <ent type='GPE'>Italy</ent> brought down the government and
destroyed hundred of careers in politics, industry and banking,  so too the
<ent type='ORG'>BNL</ent>/<ent type='ORG'>BCCI</ent> - Penzzoil case could bring down the Bush administration and send
dozens of top administration officials to jail. Indeed the P2 and <ent type='ORG'>BNL</ent> cases
overlap in the October Surprise case,  and U.S. investigators would do well
to examine the <ent type='NORP'>Italian</ent> government documents in the P2 case as part of their
inquiry into the October Surprise/<ent type='ORG'>BNL</ent>/<ent type='ORG'>BCCI</ent>/Penzzoil/Bush/Hussein links. It
is beginning to look as though the late journalist, Danny Casselaro was on
the right track at the time of his highly suspicious <ent type='GPE'>RsuicideS</ent> last year,
when he was investigating what he called <ent type='ORG'>RThe OctopusS</ent>, a vast,
interlocking, international criminal conspiracy.

Bush's Watergate

 <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent> is now calling for the appointment of a Special Prosecutor
to investigate the ballooning <ent type='ORG'>BNL</ent>-<ent type='GPE'>Iraq</ent>gate case.  In his insightful and
relentless reporting on the case in The New York <ent type='ORG'>Times</ent>, William Safire says
flatly that <ent type='ORG'>BNL</ent> will be <ent type='ORG'>BushUs</ent> Watergate.  Saffire is now investigating the
<ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> link to the case. (Updates on the case now appear regularly on the
recorded telephone hotlines of controversial <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> investigator, Sherman
Scholnick of <ent type='ORG'>the RCommittee to Clean Up</ent> the CourtsS,  who has spearheaded
his own investigation. Call: 312 - 731 1100 &amp;  312- 731 1505 for five-
minute recorded updates.)

   When appointed, the Special Prosecutor in the <ent type='ORG'>BNL</ent>/<ent type='GPE'>Iraq</ent>gate case
should have immediate access to all the records, including the crucial
documents now confiscated and impounded by the <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> court.

  When the truth of the <ent type='ORG'>BNL</ent> case is finally revealed, the War &amp;
Peace foundation believes we will see the extent to which politics around
the world
have been corrupted by the arms trade. <ent type='GPE'>Iraq</ent>gate will serve as further
evidence of the need for international monitoring by the <ent type='ORG'>United Nations</ent> of
all weapons traffic as a first, essential step toward complete world
disarmament.

  Ironically, as we go to press,  joint efforts by both houses of
<ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent> in the wake of the <ent type='GPE'>Iraq</ent>gate revelations to tighten restrictions on
the sale of nuclear weapons-related materials to nations like <ent type='GPE'>Iraq</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Iran</ent>
and <ent type='GPE'>Syria</ent>, have provoked a threat of veto by George Bush, who argues that
such non- proliferation legislation would mean a loss of business for
<ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n nuclear exporters!

  ** End of text from <ent type='ORG'>cdp</ent>:gen.newsletter **


</p></xml>