<xml><p>Article 15189 of alt.activism:
From: covici@ccs.covici.com (John Covici)
<ent type='GPE'>Newsgroups</ent>: alt.activism
Subject: Part 1: Unauthorized Biography Of George Bush
<info type="Message-ID"> 1RokeB1w164w@ccs.covici.com</info>
Date: 15 Jan 92 03:55:59 GMT
Organization: Covici Computer Systems
Lines: 1361</p>

<p>George Bush: The Unauthorized Biography</p>

<p>by Webster Griffin Tarpley and Anton Chaitkin</p>

<p>With  this  issue of the <ent type='ORG'>New <ent type='ORG'>Fed</ent>eralist</ent>, Vol. V, No. 39, we begin
to serialize the book, {George Bush: The Unauthorized Biography,}
by Webster Griffin Tarpley and Anton  Chaitkin.  This  book  will
soon be published by {<ent type='ORG'>Executive Intelligence Review</ent>}.</p>

<p> At  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>heart  of  any  effort at biography is the attempt to
discover the essence of the subject as a human personality. The
essential  character  of  the subject is what the biographer must
strive to capture, since this  is  theindispensable  ingredient
that  will provide coherence to the entire story whose unity must
be provided by the course of a single human life.</p>

<p> During the preparation of <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>present  work,  there  was  one
historical  moment  which  more  than  any  other  delineated the
character of George Bush. The scene was  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>Nixon  White  <ent type='ORG'>House</ent>
during <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>final  days  of  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>Watergate debacle.  <ent type='ORG'>White <ent type='ORG'>House</ent></ent>
officials, including George Bush, had spent the morning  of  that
Monday,  August 5, 1974 absorbing the impact of Nixon's notorious
<ent type='ORG'>``</ent>smoking gun'' tape, the recorded conversation between Nixon and
his chief of staff, H.R. Haldemann, shortly  after  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>original
Watergate  break-in,  which  could now no longer be withheld from
the public.  In that exchange of June  23,  1972,  Nixon  ordered
that  the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> stop the <ent type='ORG'>FBI</ent> from further investigating how various
sums of money found their way from <ent type='GPE'>Texas</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Minnesota</ent> via <ent type='GPE'>Mexico</ent>
City to the coffers of the <ent type='ORG'>Committee</ent> to  Re-Elect  thePresident
(CREEP)  and thence into the pockets of the <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>Plumbers'' arrested
in the <ent type='ORG'><ent type='NORP'>Democrat</ent>ic Party</ent> headquarters in <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>Watergatebuilding.
These  revelations  were  widely  interpreted  as  establishing a
{prima facie} case of obstruction of justice against Nixon.  That
was  fine  with  George,  who  sincerely  wanted  his  patron and
benefactor Nixon to resign.  George's great concern was that  the
smoking gun tape called attention to a money-laundering mechanism
which  he,  together  with  Bill  Liedtke of <ent type='ORG'>Pennzoil</ent>, and Robert
Mosbacher, had helped to set up at Nixon's request.  When  Nixon,
in  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='ORG'>``</ent>smoking  gun''  tape,  talked about <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>the <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Texan</ent>s</ent>'' and
<ent type='ORG'>``</ent>some <ent type='GPE'>Texas</ent> people,'' Bush, Liedtke, and  Mosbacher  were  among
the most  prominent of those referred to.  The threat to George's
political ambitions was great.</p>

<p> The <ent type='ORG'>White <ent type='ORG'>House</ent></ent> that morning was  gripped  by  panic.  Nixon
would be  gonebeforethe end of the week.  In the midst of the
furor, <ent type='ORG'>White <ent type='ORG'>House</ent></ent> <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>ional liaison William  Timmons  wanted
to  know  if  everyone who needed to be informed had been briefed
about the smoking gun transcript.  In  a  roomful  of  officials,
some  of whom were already sipping <ent type='NORP'>Scotch</ent> to steady their nerves,
Timmons asked Dean <ent type='ORG'>Burch</ent>,</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>``</ent>Dean, does Bush know about the transcript yet?''
 <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>Yes,'' responded <ent type='ORG'>Burch</ent>.
 <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>Well, what did he do?'' inquired Timmons.
 <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>He broke out into assholes  and  shit  himself  to  death,''
replied <ent type='ORG'>Burch</ent>.
 Inthis exchange, which  is  recordedin  Woodward  and
Bernstein's {The Final Days,} we grasp the essential George Bush,
in a crisis, and for all seasons.</p>

<p>Introduction</p>

<p> The thesis of this book is simple: if George Bush were  to  be
re-elected in November 1992 for a second term as the President of
<ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>United  <ent type='ORG'>State</ent>s, this country and the rest of the world would
face a catastrophe of gigantic proportions.</p>

<p> The necessity of writing this book became overwhelming in  the
minds  of the authors in the wake of the ghastly slaughter of the
<ent type='GPE'>Iraq</ent> war of January-February 1991. That war was an act of  savage
and  premeditated  genocide  on  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>part of Bush, undertaken in
connivance with a clique in <ent type='GPE'>London</ent> which has, in  its  historical
continuity,  represented  both<ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>worst enemy of the long-term
interests  of  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent>  people,  and  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>most  implacable
adversary of the progress of the human species.</p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>Theauthors</ent>  observed  George Bush as the <ent type='LOC'>Gulf</ent> crisis and the
war unfolded, and had no doubt that his enraged publicoutbursts
constituted  real  psychotic  episodes,  indicative of a deranged
mental state that was full of ominous portent for humanity. The
authors  were  also horrified by the degree to which their fellow
citizens willfully ignored the shocking reality of  these  public
fits.  A majority of the <ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent> people proved more than willing
to lend its support to a despicable enterprise of killing.</p>

<p> By  their  role-call votes of January 12, 1991, the <ent type='ORG'>Senate</ent> and
<ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='ORG'>House</ent>  ofRepresentatives  authorized  Bush's  planned  war
measures  to  restore  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>Emir  of  <ent type='GPE'>Kuwait</ent>,  who owns and holds
chattel slaves.  That vote was a crime against God's justice.</p>

<p> This book is part of an attempt to help the <ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent> people to
survive this terrible crime, both for the sake of <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>world  and
for their  ownsake. It  is  intended  as a contribution to a
process of education that might help to save the <ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent>  people
from <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>awesome destruction of a second Bush presidency.  It is
further intended as a warning to all citizens that if  they  fail
to deny Bush a second term, they will deserve what they get after
1993.</p>

<p> As  this book goes to press, public awareness of the long-term
depression of the <ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent> economy is rapidly growing. If  Bush
were re-elected, he would view himself as beyond the reach of the
<ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent>  electorate;  with  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>federal  defi<ent type='ORG'>cit  </ent>rising over a
billion dollars a day, a second Bush administration would dictate
such crushing austerity as to bring the country to thebrink  of
civil war.  Some examples of this point are described in the last
chapter of this book.</p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>Ourgoal</ent> has been to assemble as much of the truth about Bush
as possible within thetime  constraints  imposed  by<ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>1992
election. <ent type='ORG'>Time</ent>  and  resources have not permitted us meticulous
attention to certain matters of detail; we can say, nevertheless,
that both our commitment to the truth and our final  product  are
betterthan  anythinganyoneelse  has  been  able  to muster,
including  news  organizationsand  intelligence  agencies  with
capabilities that far surpass our own.</p>

<p> Why do  we  fight  the Bush power cartel with a mere book?  We
have no illusions of easy success, but we were encouraged in  our
work  by  the hope that a biography might stimulate opposition to
Bush and his policies.It will  certainly  pose  a  new  set  of
problems for  those seeking to get Bush re-elected.  For although
Bush is now what journalists call a  world  leader,  no  accurate
account of his actual career exists in the public domain.</p>

<p> Thevolumewhich  we  submit  to  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>court of world public
opinion is, to the best of our knowledge, the first  book-length,
unauthorized biography ofGeorgeBush.  It  is  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>first
approximation of the truth about his life. This  is  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>first
biography worthy of the name, a fact that says a great deal about
the sinister  and  obsessive  secrecy of this personage.  None of
the other biographies (including Bush's  campaign  autobiography)
can  be  takenseriously;  each  of these books is a pastiche of
lies, distortions and banalities that run the gamut from campaign
panegyric, to the Goebbels Big Lie, to fake but edifying  stories
for credulous  children.  Almost without exception, the available
Bush literature is worthless as a portrait of the subject.</p>

<p> Bush's family pedigree establishes him as a networkasset  of
Brown  Brothers  <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>,  one  of  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>most powerful political
forces in <ent type='GPE'>the United <ent type='ORG'>State</ent>s</ent> during much of the twentieth century,
and for many years the largest private bank in<ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>world.  It
suffices in this context to think of <ent type='ORG'>Averell <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent></ent> negotiating
duringWorld  War  IIin  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>name  of  <ent type='GPE'>the United <ent type='ORG'>State</ent>s</ent> with
<ent type='ORG'>Churchill</ent> and Stalin, or of the role of Brown  Brothers  <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>
partner Robert Lovett in guiding John F.  Kennedy's choice of his
cabinet,  to  begin  to  see the implications of Senator Prescott
Bush's post as managing partner of this  bank.  Brown  Brothers
<ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent> networks  pervade  government and the mass media.  Again
and again in the course  of  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>following  pages  wewill  see
stories embarrassing to George  Bush  refused  publication,
documents  embarrassing  to  Bush  suspiciously  disappear, and
witnesses  inculpatoryto  Bush  be  overtaken by mysterious and
conveniently timed deaths.  The few  relevant  facts  which  have
found  their  way  into  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>public domain have necessarily been
filtered by this gigantic  apparatus. This  <ent type='GPE'>problemhas</ent>  been
compounded by thecorruption and  servility  of  authors,
journalists, news executives and publishers who  have  functioned
more  and  more  as  kept  advocates for a governmental regime of
which Bush has been a prominent part for a quarter-century.</p>

<p>The <ent type='ORG'>Red <ent type='ORG'>Studebaker</ent></ent> Myth</p>

<p> George Bush wants key aspects of his life  to  remain  covert.
At  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>same  time,  he  senses  thathis need for coverup is a
vulnerability.The need to protect this weak flank accounts  for
<ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>steady  stream  of  fake  biographical  material  concerning
George, as well as the spin given to many studies that may  never
mention Georgedirectly. Over the past several months, we have
seen a new book about Watergate that pretends to tell <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>public
something  newby fingering Al Haig as Deep Throat, but ignoring
the central role of George Bush and his business partners in  the
Watergate affair.  We  have a new book by Lt. Col. Oliver <ent type='LOC'>North</ent>
which alleges that Reagan knew everything about  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='GPE'>Iran</ent>-Contra
affair,  but  that  George  Bush was not part of <ent type='LOC'>North</ent>'s chain of
command.  The latter point merely  paraphrasesBush'sown  lame
excusethat  he was <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>out of the loop'' during all those illegal
transactions.  During the hearings on <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>nomination  of  Robert
Gates  to  become  director  of  <ent type='ORG'>Central Intelligence</ent>, nobody had
anything new to add about the role of George Bush,  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>boss  of
<ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>National  Security  Council's Special Situation Group crisis
staff that was a command center for  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>whole  affair.  These
charades  are  <ent type='ORG'>peddledto</ent>  a very credulous public by operatives
whose task goes beyond mere damage control to  mind  control--the
<ent type='ORG'>``</ent>MK'' in the government's MK-Ultra operation.</p>

<p> Part  of  the free ride enjoyed by George Bush during the 1988
elections is reflected in <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>fact  that  at  no  point  in  the
campaign  was  there  any  serious  effort  byany  of  the news
organizations to provide the public with an accurate and complete
account of his political career.  At  least  two  biographies  of
Dukakis  appeared  which,  although  hardly  critical,were  not
uniformly laudatory either.  But in the case  of  Bush,  all  the
public could turn to was Bush's old 1980 campaign biography and a
newer campaign autobiography, both of them a tissue of lies.</p>

<p> Early  in the course of our research for the present volume it
became apparent that all books and most longerarticles  dealing
with  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>life  of  George Bush had been generated from a single
print-out of thoroughly approved <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>facts''  about  Bush  and  his
family. We  learned that during 1979-80, Bush aide Pete Roussel
attempted to recruit biographers to prepare a life of Bush  based
on  a  collection  of press releases, news summaries, and similar
pre-digested material. Most  biographical  writing  about  Bush
consists  merely  of  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>points  from this printout, strung out
chronologically  and  made into anarrative through the
interpretation of comments, anecdotes, embellishments, or special
stylistic devices.</p>

<p> Thecanonical  Bush-approved  printout is readily identified.
One dead giveaway is the inevitability with which <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>hacks  out
to  cover  up  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>substance  of Bush's life refer to a 1947 red
<ent type='ORG'>Studebaker</ent> which George Bush allegedly drove into  <ent type='GPE'>Odessa</ent>,  <ent type='GPE'>Texas</ent>
in  1948.  This  is  the sort of detail which has been introduced
into Bush's real life in a deliberate and  deceptive  attempt  to
humanize his  image.It  has been our experience that any text
that features a reference to Bush's red <ent type='ORG'>Studebaker</ent>  has  probably
been derived from Bush's list of approved facts, and is therefore
practically worthless  for serious research into Bush's life.  We
therefore assign such texts to the <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>red <ent type='ORG'>Studebaker</ent>  school''  of
coverup and falsification.</p>

<p> Some examples?  This  is from Bush's campaign autobiography,
{Looking Forward,} ghost-written by his aide Vic Gold:<ent type='ORG'>``</ent>Heading
into  <ent type='GPE'>Texas</ent>  in  my  <ent type='ORG'>Studebaker</ent>,  all  I  knewabout the state's
landscape was what I'd seen from the cockpit of a <ent type='ORG'>Vultee Vibrator</ent>
during my training days in the <ent type='ORG'>Navy</ent>.''s1
 Here is the same moment as recaptured by Bush's crony Fitzhugh
Green, a friend of the <ent type='NORP'>Malthusian</ent> financier Russell Train, in his
{George Bush: An Intimate Portrait,} published after Bush had won
the presidency:  <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>He  (Bush)  gassed  up  his1948  <ent type='ORG'>Studebaker</ent>,
arranged  for  his wife and son to follow, and headed for <ent type='GPE'>Odessa</ent>,
<ent type='GPE'>Texas</ent>.''s2</p>

<p> Harry Hurt III wrote <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>followinglines  in  a  1983  <ent type='GPE'>Texas</ent>
magazine  article  that was even decorated with a drawing of what
apparently is supposed to be a <ent type='ORG'>Studebaker</ent>,  but  whichdoes  not
look  like  a  <ent type='ORG'>Studebaker</ent>  of  that vintage at all: <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>When George
Herbert <ent type='ORG'>Walker Bush</ent> drove his battered red <ent type='ORG'>Studebaker</ent> into <ent type='GPE'>Odessa</ent>
in the summer of 1948, the town's population,  though  constantly
increasing  with  newly-arrived  oil field hands, was still under
30000.''s3</p>

<p> We see that Harry Hurt has more  imagination  than  many  Bush
biographers,  and  hisarticle  does provide a few useful facts.
More degraded is the version offered by Richard Ben Kramer, whose
biography of Bush is expected to be published during 1992. Cramer
was given the unenviable task of breathing life  once  more  into
the same  tired  old  printout. But the very fact that the Bush
team feels that it requires another biography indicates  that  it
still feels  that  it has a potential vulnerability here.  Cramer
has attempted to solve his problem  byrecasting  thesame  old
garbage  into  a  frenetic  and hyperkinetic, we would almost say
{hyperthyroid} style.  The following is from an excerpt  of  this
forthcoming  book  that  was published in {Esquire} in June 1991:
<ent type='ORG'>``</ent>In June, after <ent type='ORG'>the College World Series</ent> and graduation  day  in
New  Haven,  Poppy packed up his new red <ent type='ORG'>Studebaker</ent> (a graduation
gift from Pres), and started driving south.''s4</p>

<p> Was that <ent type='ORG'>Studebaker</ent>shiny  and  new,  or  old  andbattered?
Perhaps  the printout is not specific on this point; in any case,
as we see, our authorities diverge.</p>

<p> Joe Hyams's 1991 romance of Bush at war, <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>{Flight  of  the
Avenger,}s5  does  notinclude the obligatory <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>red <ent type='ORG'>Studebaker</ent>''
reference, but this is more than  compensated  for  by<ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>most
elaborate  fawning  over other details of our hero's war service.
The publication of {Flight of the Avenger,} which concentrates on
an heroic  retelling  of  Bush's  war  record,and  ignores  all
evidence  <ent type='NORP'>thatmight</ent>  tend  to  puncture this myth, was timed to
coincide with Bush's war with <ent type='GPE'>Iraq</ent>. This is a vile tract  written
with  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>open  assistance  of Bush, Barbara Bush, and the White
<ent type='ORG'>House</ent> staff.  {Flight of the Avenger}  recalls<ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>practice  of
totalitarian  states according to which a war waged by the regime
should be accompanied by propaganda which  depicts  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>regime's
strong man  ina  martial posture.  In any case, this book deals
with Bush's life up to the end of World War II;  we  never  reach
<ent type='GPE'>Odessa</ent>.</p>

<p> Only  one  of  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>full-length  accounts produced by the Bush
propaganda machine neglects the red <ent type='ORG'>Studebaker</ent> story. This  is
Nicholas King's {George Bush: A Biography,} the first book-length
version  of  Bush's  life, produced as a result of Pete Roussel's
efforts for the 1980 campaign.  Nicholas  King  had  served  as
Bush'sspokesman  when  he  was  U.S.Ambassador  to the United
Nations.  King admits in his preface that he can be impugned  for
writing a  work  of  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>most  transparent  apologetics:  <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>In
retrospect,'' he says , <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>this book may seem open to  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>charge
of  puffery,  for  theview  of  its  <ent type='NORP'>subjectis</ent>  favorable all
around.''s6 Indeed.</p>

<p> Books about Barbara Bush slavishly rehearse <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>same  details
from <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>sameprintout. Here is the relevant excerpt from the
warmly admiring {Simply Barbara Bush:  A  Portrait  of<ent type='GPE'>America</ent>'s
<ent type='ORG'>CandidFirst</ent>  Lady,}  writtenby Donnie Radcliffe and published
after Bush's 1988 election victory: <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>With $3000 left over after
he graduated in June, 1948, he headed for <ent type='GPE'>Texas</ent> in the1947  red
<ent type='ORG'>Studebaker</ent> his father had given him for graduation after George's
car died on the highway.''s7</p>

<p> Even  foreign  journalists  attempting to inform their publics
about conditions in <ent type='GPE'>the United <ent type='ORG'>State</ent>s</ent> have fallen victim  to  the
same old  <ent type='ORG'>Bushprintout</ent>. The <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> author and reporter Rainer
<ent type='ORG'>Bonhorst</ent>, the former <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>correspondentof  the
{<ent type='ORG'>Westdeutsche Allgemeine Zeitung</ent>,} in his 1988 book {George Bush:
<ent type='ORG'>The  </ent>New  Man  in  the <ent type='ORG'>White <ent type='ORG'>House</ent></ent>,} named a chapter of this Bush
political biography <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>To <ent type='GPE'>Texas</ent> in the <ent type='ORG'>Red <ent type='ORG'>Studebaker</ent></ent>.''  <ent type='ORG'>Bonhorst</ent>
writesas  follows: <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>Then there was still the matter of the red
<ent type='ORG'>Studebaker</ent>. It  plays--rightafter  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>world  wareffort--a
central  role  in  thelife  history  of  George Bush. It is the
history of his rebellion.  The step which made a  careless  <ent type='NORP'>Texan</ent>
out  of  a  stiff  <ent type='ORG'>New<ent type='GPE'>England</ent>er</ent>,  a  self-made  man  out  <ent type='ORG'>ofa</ent>
patrician's son, born into wealth....  Thus, George  and  Barbara
Bush,  24  and23  years  old,  he having just finished with his
studies, she having prematurely withdrawn from her university and
become a mother a few months earlier, packed their baby and their
suitcases and loaded  them  into  their  glaring  red  <ent type='ORG'>Studebaker</ent>
coupe.</p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>Asupermodern, smart car, certainly somewhat loud for the
<ent type='LOC'>New <ent type='GPE'>England</ent></ent> taste,' the Bushes later recalled. But  finally  it
departed towards <ent type='GPE'>Texas</ent>.''s8
 We  see  that  <ent type='ORG'>Bonhorst</ent>  isacutely  awareof  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>symbolic
importance assumed by the red <ent type='ORG'>Studebaker</ent>  in  these  hagiographic
accounts of Bush's life.</p>

<p> What is finally the truth of the matter?  There is good reason
to  believe that George Bush did not first come to <ent type='GPE'>Odessa</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Texas</ent>,
in a red <ent type='ORG'>Studebaker</ent>. One knowledgeable source is  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>well-known
<ent type='GPE'>Texas</ent>  oil  man  and  Bush  campaign  contributor  Oscar Wyatt of
<ent type='GPE'>Houston</ent>. In  arecentletterto  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>{<ent type='GPE'>Texas</ent>  Monthly,}  Wyatt
specifies that <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>when  people  speak  of  Mr.  Bush's  humble
beginnings in the oil industry, it should be noted that  he  rode
down to  <ent type='GPE'>Texas</ent> on Dresser's private aircraft.  He was accompanied
by his father, who at that time  was  one  of  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>directors  of
Dresser  Industries....  I  hate  it  when people make statements
about Mr. Bush's humble beginnings in the oil industry.  It  just
didn'thappenthat  way,''  writes  Mr.  Wyatt.s9 Dresser was a
<ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent> company, and Bush got his start working for one  of  its
subsidiaries.One  history  of  Dresser  Industries  contains a
photograph of George Bush with his parents, wife, and infant  son
<ent type='ORG'>``</ent>in front of a Dresser company airplane in West <ent type='GPE'>Texas</ent>.''s1s0 Can
this  be a photo of Bush's arrival in <ent type='GPE'>Odessa</ent> during the summer of
1948?  In  <ent type='ORG'>anycase</ent>,  this  most  cherished  myth  of<ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>Bush
biographers is very much open to doubt.</p>

<p>The <ent type='NORP'>Roman</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Propaganda</ent> Machine</p>

<p> Fawning biographies of bloodthirsty tyrants are nothing new in
world literature.  <ent type='ORG'>The  </ent>red  <ent type='ORG'>Studebaker</ent> school goes back a long
way; these writers of today  can  be  usefullycompared  witha
certain  Gaius Velleius Paterculus, who lived in <ent type='GPE'>the <ent type='NORP'>Roman</ent> Empire</ent>
under the emperors Augustus and Tiberius, and  who  was  thus  an
approximate contemporary of Jesus Christ. Velleius Paterculus was
an  historian  and  biographer who is known today, if at all, for
his  biographical  notes  on  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>Emperor  Tiberius,  which  are
contained within Paterculus's history of <ent type='GPE'>Rome</ent>.</p>

<p> Paterculus,writing  <ent type='ORG'>underTiberius</ent>,  gave  a very favorable
treatment of Julius Caesar, and became fulsome when  he  came  to
write  of  Augustus.  But  the worst excesses of flattery came in
Velleius Paterculus's treatment of Tiberius  himself. Here  is
part of what he writes about that tyrannical ruler:</p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>Of  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>transactions  of the last sixteen years, which have
passed in the view, and are fresh in the memory of all, who shall
presume to give a full account?  ... credit has been restored  to
mercantile  affairs,  seditionhas been banished from the forum,
corruption  from  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>Campus  Martius,  and  discord  from the
<ent type='ORG'>senate</ent>-house;  justice,  equity and industry, which had long lain
buried in neglect, have been revived in the state; authority  has
been  given  to  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>magistrates,  majesty  to  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='ORG'>senate</ent>, and
solemnity to the courts of  justice;  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>bloody  riots  in  the
theatre  have  been  suppressed,  and  all  men have had either a
desire excited in them, or a necessity imposed on them, of acting
with integrity.  Virtuous actsare  honored,  wicked  deeds  are
punished. <ent type='ORG'>The  </ent>humble  respects  the powerful, without dreading
him;  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>powerful  takes  precedenceof  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>humble without
condemning him.  When  were  provisions more moderate in price?
When were the blessings of peace more abundant?  <ent type='GPE'>Augustan</ent>  peace,
diffused  overall the regions of the east and the west, and all
that lies between the south and the north, preserves every corner
of the world  free  from  all  dread  of  predatory  molestation.
Fortuitous  losses,  not  only of individuals, but of cities, the
munificence of the prince is ready to relieve.  <ent type='ORG'>The  </ent>cities  of
<ent type='LOC'>Asia</ent> have been repaired; the provinces have been secured from the
oppression of  their  governors.  Honor  promptly  rewards  the
deserving,  and  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>punishment  of  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>guilty,  ifslow,  is
certain. Interest  gives  place  to  justice,  solicitation  to
merit.For the best of princes teaches  his  countrymen  to  act
rightly  by  his  own  practice;  and while he is the greatest in
power, he is still greater in example.</p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>Having exhibited a general view  of  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>administration  of
Tiberius Caesar, let  us  now  enumerate  a  few  particulars
respecting it....  How formidable a war, excited  by  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='NORP'>Gallic</ent>
chief <ent type='NORP'>Sacrovir</ent> and Julius Florius, did he suppress, and with such
amazing expedition and energy, that the <ent type='NORP'>Roman</ent> people learned that
they were conquerors, before they knew that they were at war, and
the news  of the victory outstripped the news of the danger!  The
<ent type='NORP'><ent type='LOC'>Africa</ent>n</ent> war too, perilous as it  was,  and  daily  increasing  in
strength, was quickly terminatedunder  his  auspices  and
direction....''s1s1</p>

<p> All of this was written in praise of the regime that crucified
Jesus Christ, and one of the worst  genocidal  tyrannies  in  the
history of  the world.Paterculus, we must sadly conclude, was a
sycophant of the Tiberius administration.  Some of his themes are
close parallels to the propaganda of today's Bush machine.</p>

<p> In addition to  feeding  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>personality  cult  ofTiberius,
Paterculus  also  lavished  praise  on Lucius Aelius <ent type='NORP'>Sejanus</ent>, the
Prefect of <ent type='ORG'>the Praetorian Guard</ent> and  for  manyyears  Tiberius's
number one favorite, second in command, and likely successor.  In
many  respects<ent type='NORP'>Sejanus</ent>  was not unlike James Baker III under the
Bush regime.  While Tiberius spent all of his time  inseclusion
on  his  island  of <ent type='GPE'>Capri</ent> near <ent type='GPE'>Naples</ent>, <ent type='NORP'>Sejanus</ent> assumed day to day
control  of  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>vastempireand  its  100  millionsubjects.
Paterculus  wrote  of  <ent type='ORG'><ent type='NORP'>Sejanus</ent>that</ent>  he  was  <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>a most excellent
coadjutor in all the toils of government ... aman  of  pleasing
gravity, and  of unaffected cheerfulness ...  assuming nothing to
himself.'' That was the voice of <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>red  <ent type='ORG'>Studebaker</ent>  school  in
about  30  A.D.  Paterculus  should  have  limited his fawning to
Tiberius himself; somewhat later, the emperor, suspecting a  coup
plot,  condemned  <ent type='NORP'>Sejanus</ent>  andhad  him  <ent type='ORG'>tornlimb</ent> from limb in
gruesome retribution.</p>

<p> But why bring up <ent type='GPE'>Rome</ent>?  Some readers may be scandalized by the
things that truth obliges us to record about a sittingpresident
of  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>United  <ent type='ORG'>State</ent>s.  Are  we  not disrespectful to this high
office?  No. One of the reasons for  glancing  back  at  Imperial
<ent type='GPE'>Rome</ent>  is  to remind ourselves that in times of moral and cultural
degradation like our own, rulers of  great  evil  haveinflicted
incalculable sufferingon  humanity.In our modern time of war
and depression, this is once again the case.If  Caligula  was
possible  then, who could claim that the <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> of the New World
Order should be exempt?  Let us therefore tarry for a moment with
these old <ent type='NORP'>Roman</ent>s, because they can show us much about ourselves.</p>

<p> In order to find <ent type='NORP'>Roman</ent> writers who tell us  anything  reliable
about  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>first dozen emperors, we must wait until the infamous
Julio-Claudian dynastyof  Julius  Caesar,  Augustus,Tiberius,
Caligula,  Claudius,  Nero, and the rest had entirely passed from
the scene, to be supplanted  by  new  ruling  houses. Tiberius
reigned  from  14 to 37 A.D.; Caligula, his designated successor,
from 37 to 41 A.D.; and Nero from 54 to 68  A.D.  But  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>first
accurate  account  of  the crimes of some of these emperors comes
from <ent type='ORG'>Publius Cornelius <ent type='ORG'>Tacitus</ent></ent> in about 115-17 A.D., late in  the
reign of the emperor Trajan. It was feasible for <ent type='ORG'>Tacitus</ent> to write
and  publish  a  more  realistic  account  of  the Julio-Claudian
emperors  because  oneof  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>constant  themes of Trajan's
propaganda  was  to  glorify  himself  as  an enlightened emperor
through comparison with the earlier series of bloody tyrants.</p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>Tacitus</ent> manages to convey how  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>destructivenessof  these
emperors  in  their  personal  lives  correlated  with their mass
executions and their genocidal economic policies.  <ent type='ORG'>Tacitus</ent>  was
familiar  with<ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>machinery of <ent type='NORP'>Roman</ent> Imperial power: he was of
senatorial rank, served as consul in <ent type='GPE'>Italy</ent> in 97  A.D.,  and  was
<ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>governor  of  theimportant  province  of  western <ent type='GPE'>Anatolia</ent>
(today's <ent type='GPE'>Turkey</ent>) which the <ent type='NORP'>Roman</ent>s referred  <ent type='ORG'>tosimplyas</ent>  <ent type='LOC'>Asia</ent>.
<ent type='ORG'>Tacitus</ent>  writes of Tiberius: <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>... his criminal lusts shamed him.
Their uncontrollable activity was worthy of anoriental  tyrant.
Free-born children  were  his  victims.  He  was  fascinated by
beauty, youthful innocence, and aristocratic birth.  New  names
for types  of  perversions were invented.  Slaves were charged to
locate and procure his requirements....  It was like the sack  of
a captured city.''</p>

<p> Tiberius  was  ableto dominate the legislative branch of his
government, the <ent type='ORG'>senate</ent>,  by  subversion  and  terror:  <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>It  was,
indeed,  a  horrible feature of this period that leading senators
became informers  evenon  trivial  matters--some  openly,  many
secretly. Friends  and  relatives were as suspect as strangers,
old stories as damaging as  new.  In<ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>Main  Square,  ata
dinner-party,  a  remark  on  any subject might mean prosecution.
Everyone competed  forpriority  in  marking  down  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>victim.
Sometimes  this  was  self-defense,  but  mostly it was a sort of
contagion, like an epidemic....  I realize that many writers omit
numerous trials and condemnations, bored by repetition or  afraid
that  catalogues  they themselves have found over-long and dismal
may equally depress  their  readers.But  numerous  unrecorded
incidents, which have come to my attention, ought to be known.</p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>... Even  women  were  in danger.They could not be charged
with aiming at <ent type='ORG'>supreme power</ent>.  So they were charged with weeping:
one old lady was executed for lamenting her  son's  death.  The
<ent type='ORG'>senate</ent> decidedthis case....  In the same year the high price of
corn nearly caused riots....</p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>Frenzied  with  bloodshed,  (Tiberius) now ordered the
execution  of  all those arrested for complicity with <ent type='NORP'>Sejanus</ent>. It
was a massacre.  Without discrimination of sex or  age,  eminence
or obscurity,  therethey  lay,  strewn  about--or  in  heaps.
Relatives and friends were forbidden to stand by or lament  them,
or even  gaze  for long.  Guards surrounded them, spying on their
sorrow, and escorted the rotting bodies  until,  dragged  to  the
Tiber,they  floated  away  or grounded--with none to cremate or
touch them.  Terror had paralyzed human  sympathy.  <ent type='ORG'>The  </ent>rising
surge of brutality drove compassion away.''s1s2</p>

<p> This  is  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='ORG'>sameTiberius</ent>  administration so extravagantly
praised by Velleius Paterculus.
 Because of lacunae in the manuscripts of <ent type='ORG'>Tacitus</ent>'s  work  that
have  come  down  to  us,  much  of  what  we know of the rule of
Caligula (Gaius Caesar, in power from 37 to 41 A.D.) derives from
{The Lives of the Twelve Caesars,}  a  book  by  GaiusSuetonius
Tranquillus. The character and administration of Caligula present
some striking parallels with the subject of the present book.</p>

<p> Asa  stoic,  Caligula  was  a  great  admirer  of  his  own
<ent type='ORG'>``</ent>immovable rigor.'' His motto was <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>Remember  that  Ihave  the
right  to  do  anything  to  anybody.''  He made no secret of his
bloodthirsty vindictiveness.  Caligula was a  fan  of  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>green
team  in  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='NORP'>Roman</ent>  arena,  and  when  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>crowd  <ent type='ORG'>applaudeda</ent>
charioteer who wore a different color, Caligula  criedout,  <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>I
wish  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='NORP'>Roman</ent>  people  had  but a single neck.'' At one of his
state  dinnersCaligula  burst  into  a  fit  of  uncontrollable
laughter,  andwhen  a  consul  askedhim what was so funny, he
replied that it was the thought that as emperor Caligula had  the
power to have the throats of the top officials cut at any time he
chose. Caligula  carried  this  same attitude into his personal
life: whenever he kissed or caressed the neck of his wife or  one
of his mistresses, he liked to remark: <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>Off comes this beautiful
head whenever I give the word.''</p>

<p> Above all,  Caligula  was  vindictive.  After his death, two
notebooks were found among  his  personal  papers,  one  labelled
<ent type='ORG'>``</ent><ent type='ORG'>The  </ent>Sword''and the other labelled <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>The Dagger.'' These were
lists of the persons he had proscribed and liquidated,and  were
<ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>forerunners  of the enemies lists and discrediting committee
of today.  Suetonius frankly calls Caligula  <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>a  monster,''  and
speculates on thepyschologicalrootsof  his  criminal
disposition: <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>I think I may attributeto  mental  weakness  the
existence  of  two  exactly  opposite  faults in the same person,
extreme assurance and, on theotherhand,excessive
timorousness.''  Caligula  was<ent type='ORG'>``</ent>full of threats'' against <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>the
barbarians,'' but at the same time prone to precipitous  retreats
and flights  of  panic.  Caligula worked on his <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>body language''
by <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>practicing all kinds of terrible  and  fearsome  expressions
before a mirror.''</p>

<p> Caligula  built an extension of his palace to connect with the
Temple of Castor and Pollux, and  often  went  there  to  exhibit
himself  as  an  object  of  public  worship, delighting in being
hailed as <ent type='ORG'>``</ent><ent type='LOC'>Jupiter</ent> Latiaris'' by the populace. Later  Caligula
would officially  opentemples  in  his  own name.  Caligula was
brutal in his  intimidation  of  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='ORG'>senate</ent>,  whose  members  he
subjected  to open humiliations and covert attacks; many senators
were <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>secretly put to death.'' <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>He often inveighed against  all
the Senators  alike....  He  treated the other orders with like
insolence and cruelty.'' Suetonius recites  whole  catalogues  of
<ent type='ORG'>``</ent>special  instances  of his innate brutality'' toward persons of
all walks of life.  He enjoyed inflicting torture,  and  revelled
in  liquidating  political opponents or those who had insulted or
snubbed him in some way.  He had a taste for  capital  executions
as theperfect backdrop for parties and banquets.  Caligula also
did everything he could to denigrate the memory of the great  men
of  past  epochs,  so  that their fame could not eclipse his own:
<ent type='ORG'>``</ent>He assailed mankind of almost every epoch with no less envy and
malice than insolence and cruelty.  He threw down the statues  of
famous men'' and tried to destroy all the texts of Homer.</p>

<p> Caligula  <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>respected neither his own chastity nor that of any
one else.'' He was reckless in his extravagance, and soon emptied
out the imperial treasury of all the funds that old Tiberius  had
squirreled away  there. After that, Caligula tried to replenish
his  coffers  through  a  system  of  spies,  false  accusations,
property seizures, and public auctions.  He also <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>levied new and
unheard-of  taxes,''  to the point that <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>no class of commodities
was exempt from some kind of tax or other.'' Caligula  taxed  all
foodstuffs,  took  a  fortiethof  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>award in any lawsuit, an
eighth of the daily wages of the porters, and demandedthat  the
prostitutes  pay  him  a  daily  fee  equal  to the average price
charged to each individual customer.  (It is  rumored  that  this
part of Caligula's career is under study by those planning George
Bush's second term.) Caligula also opened a brothel in his palace
as  anadditional  source of income, which may prefigure today's
<ent type='ORG'>White <ent type='ORG'>House</ent></ent>  staff.  Among  Caligula's  moresingular  hobbies
Suetonius  includes his love of rolling and wallowing in piles of
gold coins.</p>

<p> Caligula kept his wife, <ent type='GPE'>Caesonia</ent> (describedby  Suetonius  as
<ent type='ORG'>``</ent>neither  beautiful  nor  young'')  with him until the very end.
But his greatest devotion was to his horse, whom he  made  consul
of the<ent type='NORP'>Roman</ent>  state. Ultimately  Caligula  fell  victim  to a
conspiracy of <ent type='ORG'>the Praetorian Guard</ent>,  led  by  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>tribune  Gaius
Chaerea,  a  man  whomCaligula  had  taken  special  delight in
humiliating.s1s3</p>

<p> The authors of the present  study  are  convinced  that  these
references  to<ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>depravityof the <ent type='NORP'>Roman</ent> emperors, and to the
records of that depravity provided by such authors as <ent type='ORG'>Tacitus</ent> and
Suetonius, are directly germane to our present task offollowing
the career of  a  member  of  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>senatorial  class  of  the
Anglo-<ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent> elite through the various stages of hisformation
and ultimate  ascent to imperial power.  The <ent type='NORP'>Roman</ent> Imperial model
is germane because the <ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent> rulingelite  of  today  is  far
closerto  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>world of Tiberius and Caligula than it is to the
world of the <ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent> Revolution or the Constitutional Convention
of 1789. The leitmotif of modern <ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent>  presidential  politics
is  unquestionably an imperial theme, most blatantly expressed by
Bush in his slogan for 1990, <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>The NewWorld  Order,''  and  for
1991,  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='ORG'>``</ent>pax  universalis.'' The central project of the Bush
presidency  is<ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>creation  and  consolidation  of  a  single,
universal  Anglo-<ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent>  (orAnglo-<ent type='NORP'>Saxon</ent>) empire very directly
modelled on the various phases of <ent type='GPE'>the <ent type='NORP'>Roman</ent> Empire</ent>.</p>

<p>The Olympian Delusion</p>

<p> There is  one  other  aspect  of  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>biographical-historical
methodof the <ent type='ORG'>Graeco</ent>-<ent type='NORP'>Roman</ent> world which we have sought to borrow.
Ever  since  Thucydides  composed  hismonumental  work  on  the
PeloponnesianWar, those  who  have  sought  to  imitate  his
style--with the <ent type='NORP'>Roman</ent>  historian  Titus  Livius  prominent  among
them--have  employed  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>device of attributing long speeches to
historical personages, even when it appears  very  unlikely  that
such lengthy orations could have been made by the protagonists at
the time. This has nothing to do with the synthetic dialogue of
current <ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent> political writing,  which  attempts  to  present
historical  events  asa  series of trivial and banal soap-opera
exchanges, which carry on for such  interminable  lengths  as  to
suggest that  the authors are getting paid by the word.  Our idea
of <ent type='ORG'>fidelity</ent> to the classical style has simply been to let  George
Bush speak for  himself  wherever  possible,  through  direct
quotation.  We are convinced that by letting Bush express himself
directly in this way, we afford the reader a  more  faithful--and
damning--account of Bush's actions.</p>

<p> George Bush  might  agreethat  <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>history  is  biography,''
although we suspect that he would not agree with any of our other
conclusions.  There may be a few  peculiarities  of  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>present
work as biography that are worthy of explanation at the outset.</p>

<p> Oneof our basic theses is that George Bush is, and considers
himself to be, an oligarch.  <ent type='ORG'>The  </ent>notion  of  oligarchy  includes
first  of  all the idea of a patrician and wealthy family capable
of introducing its offspring  into  such  elite  institutions  as
Andover, <ent type='ORG'>Yale</ent>,and <ent type='ORG'>Skull</ent> and Bones.  Oligarchy also subsumes the
self-conception of  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>oligarch  as  belonging  to  a  special,
exalted  breed of mankind, one that is superior to the common run
of mankind as a matter of hereditary genetic superiority.  This
mentality generallygoes  togetherwith  a  fascination  for
eugenics, race science and  just  plain  racism  as  <ent type='NORP'>ameans</ent>  of
building  a  case that one's own family tree and racial stock are
indeed superior.  These notions of <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>breeding'' are a constant in
<ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>history  of  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>titled  feudal  aristocracy of <ent type='LOC'>Europe</ent>,
especially <ent type='GPE'>Britain</ent>, towards inclusion in which an individual like
Bush must  necessarily strive.At the very least, oligarchs like
Bush see themselves as demigods occupying a middle ground between
the immortals above and the {hoi polloi} below.  <ent type='ORG'>The  </ent>culmination
of  this  insane delusion, which Bush has demonstrably long since
attained, is the obsessive belief that the principal families  of
<ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>Anglo-<ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent> elite, assembled in their <ent type='ORG'>freemasonic</ent> orders,
by themselves directly constitute an Olympian Pantheon of  living
deities  who  have  the capability of abrogating and disregarding
the laws of  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>universe  according  to  their  own  irrational
caprice. If  we  do not take into account this element of fatal
and megalomaniac hubris, the lunatic Anglo-<ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent>  policies  in
regardto  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='LOC'>Gulf</ent>  War,  international  finance,  or the AIDS
epidemic must defy all comprehension.</p>

<p> Part of the ethos of oligarchism as practiced by  George  Bush
is theemphasis on one's own family pedigree.This accounts for
the attention we dedicate in the opening chapters of this book to
Bush's family tree, reaching back to the nineteenth  century  and
beyond. It  is impossible to gain insight into Bush's mentality
unless we realize that it is important for him to be considered a
cousin, however distant, of Queen Elizabeth II of  the<ent type='ORG'>House</ent>  of
Mountbatten-Windsor and for his wife Barbara to be viewed in some
sense a descendant of President Franklin Pierce.</p>

<p>The Family Firm</p>

<p> Forrelated reasons, it is our special duty to illustrate the
role played in the formation of George Bush as a  personality  by
his  maternal  grandfather  and  uncle, George Herbert Walker and
George Herbert Walker, Jr., and by George H.W. Bush's father, the
late Senator Prescott Bush. In the course of this task,  we  must
speak  at  length about the institution to which George Bush owes
the most, the Wall Street international investment bank of  Brown
Brothers <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>political  and  financial  powerhouse
mentioned above.  For George Bush, Brown  Brothers  <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>  was
and remains the family firm in the deepest sense.  The formidable
power of this bank and its ubiquitous network, wielded by Senator
Prescott Bush up through the time of his death in 1972, and still
activeon George's behalf down to the present day, is the single
most important key to every step  of  George'sbusiness,  covert
operations, and political career.</p>

<p> In  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>case  of  George  Bush,  as  many  who have known him
personally  have  noted,  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='ORG'>networklooms</ent>  much  larger  than
George's own  character and will.  The reader will search in vain
for strong principled commitments in George  Bush's  personality;
<ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>most  that  will  be  found  is  a  series of characteristic
obsessions, of which the most durable are race, vanity,  personal
ambition, and  settling scores with adversaries.  What emerges by
contrast  is  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>decisive  importance  of  Bush's  network of
connections. His  response  to  the <ent type='LOC'>Gulf</ent> crisis of 1991 will be
largely predetermined, not by any great flashes  of  geopolitical
insight,  but rather by his connections to the <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> oligarchy,
to Kissinger, to <ent type='NORP'>Israeli</ent> and <ent type='NORP'>Zionist</ent> circles, to <ent type='GPE'>Texas</ent> oilmen  in
his  fundraising  base,  to  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='NORP'>Saudi Arabian</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Kuwait</ent>i royal
houses.  If the question is one of finance, then the opinions  of
J.  Hugh  Liedtke,  Henry  Kravis,  Robert  Mosbacher,T.  Boone
Pickens, Nicholas Brady, James Baker III and the City  of  <ent type='GPE'>London</ent>
will be  decisive. If covert operations and dirty tricks are on
the agenda, then there is a whole stable of  <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>  old  boys  with
whom he  will  consult,  and so on down the line.  During much of
1989, despite his control over the presidency, Bush appeared as a
weak and passive executive, waiting for his networks to show  him
what it was he was supposed to do.  When <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> reunification and
<ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='ORG'>crumblingof</ent>  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent>  empire  spurred those--primarily
<ent type='NORP'>British</ent>--networks intoaction,  Bush  was  suddenly  capable  of
violent and  daring  adventures.  As his battle for a second term
approaches, Bush may be showing increasing signs of a rage-driven
self-starter capability, especially when it comes to starting new
wars designed to secure his re-election.</p>

<p><ent type='GPE'>The United <ent type='ORG'>State</ent>s</ent> in Decline</p>

<p> Biography  has  <ent type='GPE'>itsown</ent>  inherent  discipline:  <ent type='GPE'>Itmust</ent> be
concerned  with the life of its protagonist, and cannot stray too
far away.  In no way has  it  been  our  intention  tooffer  an
account  of  <ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent> history during the lifetime of George Bush.
The present study neverthelessreflects  manyaspects  of  that
recent historyof  U.S. decline.  It will be noted that Bush has
succeeded in proportion as  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>country  has  failed,and  that
Bush's advancement has proceeded {paripassu}with  the
degradation of the national stage upon which he has operated  and
which he  has come to dominate.  At various phases in his career,
Bush has come into conflict with persons who were  intellectually
and morally  superior  to  him.  <ent type='NORP'>Onesuch</ent>  was  Senator  Ralph
Yarborough, and another was Senator Frank Church. Our study  will
be  found  to  catalogue the constant decline in the qualities of
Bush's adversaries as human types until the 1980s, by which  time
his opponents, as in the case of Al Haig, are no better than Bush
himself.</p>

<p> Theexception  to this trend is Bush's long-standing personal
vendetta against Lyndon <ent type='ORG'>LaRouche</ent>, his most consistent and capable
adversary. <ent type='ORG'>LaRouche</ent>  was  jailed  seven days after Bush's
inauguration  in  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>most  infamous political frameup of recent
U.S. history.  As our study will document, at critical moments in
Bush's career, <ent type='ORG'>LaRouche</ent>'s political interventions have frustrated
some of Bush's best-laid political plans: A very clear example is
<ent type='ORG'>LaRouche</ent>'s role in defeating Bush's 1980 presidential bid in  the
<ent type='GPE'>New Hampshire</ent>  primary.  Over the intervening years, <ent type='ORG'>LaRouche</ent> has
become George Bush's <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>man in <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>iron  mask,''  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>principled
political  adversary  whom  Bush seeks to jail and silence at all
costs.The restoration of justice in this country  must  include
<ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>freeing of Lyndon <ent type='ORG'>LaRouche</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>LaRouche</ent>'s political associates,
and all the other political prisoners of the Bush regime.</p>

<p> As for the political relevance of our project, we  think  that
it is  very  real.  During  the <ent type='LOC'>Gulf</ent> crisis, it would have been
important for the public  to  know  more  about  Bush's  business
dealings  with<ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>Royal  Family  of<ent type='GPE'>Kuwait</ent>.  During  the 1992
presidential campaign, as Wall Street's recent crop ofjunk-bond
assisted  leveraged buyouts line up at the entrance to bankruptcy
court, and  state  workers  all  across  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>United  <ent type='ORG'>State</ent>s  are
informed that the retirement pensions they had been promised will
never be paid, the relations between George Bush and Henry Kravis
will surely  constitute an explosive political issue.  Similarly,
once Bush's <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>Kissingerian</ent> pedigree is recognized,  the
methods  he  is  likely to pursue in regard to situations such as
the planned <ent type='NORP'>Roman</ent>ian-style overthrow  of  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>Castro  regime  in
<ent type='GPE'>Cuba</ent>,  or  theprovocation  of  a  splendid  little  nuclear war
involving <ent type='LOC'>North</ent> <ent type='GPE'>Korea</ent>, or  of  a  new  Indo-Pakistani  war,  will
hardly be mysterious.</p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>Theauthors</ent>  have  been  at  some  pains  to  makethis work
intelligible to readers around the world.  We offer this book  to
those  who  share our aversion to the imperialist-colonialist New
World Order, and our profound horror at the concept <ent type='ORG'>ofa</ent>  return
to  a single, worldwide <ent type='NORP'>Roman</ent> Empire as suggested by Bush's <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>pax
universalis'' slogan.  This work is tangible evidence that  there
is  anopposition to Bush inside <ent type='GPE'>the United <ent type='ORG'>State</ent>s</ent>, and that the
new Caligula is very  vulnerable  indeed  on  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>level  of  the
exposure of his own misdeeds.</p>

<p> It  will  be  argued that this book should have been published
before the 1988 election, when a Bush presidency might have  been
avoided. That  is  certainly true, but it is an objection which
should also be directed to many institutions and  agencies  whose
resources far  surpassour  modest  capabilities.  We can only
remind our fellow citizens that when he asks for their votes  for
his  re-election,  George  Bush  also enters that court of public
opinion in which he is obliged to answer their questions.  They
shouldnot waste this opportunity to grill him on all aspects of
his career and future intentions, since  it  is  Bush  who  comes
forward appealing  for their support.  To aid in this process, we
have provided a list of TwentyQuestions  forCandidate  George
Bush  on  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>campaign  trail,  and  this  will  be found in the
appendix.</p>

<p> We do not delude ourselves that we have  said  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>last  word
about George Bush. But we have for the first time sketched out at
least  some of the most salient features and gathered them into a
comprehensible whole.  We encourage an aroused citizenry, as well
as specialized researchers, to improve upon  what  we  have  been
able to  accomplish.In  sodoing, we recall the words of the
Florentine Giovanni Boccaccio when he  reluctantly  accepted  the
order  of  a powerful king to produce an account of the old <ent type='NORP'>Roman</ent>
Pantheon: <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>If I don't succeed completely in this exposition,  at
least I will provide a stimulus for the better work of others who
are wiser.''--Boccaccio, {Genealogy of the National Gods}
 {To be continued.}</p>

<p> Notes</p>

<p> 1.  George  Bush  andVic  Gold,  {Looking Forward,} (<ent type='GPE'>New York</ent>:
<ent type='ORG'>Doubleday</ent>, 1987), p.  47.</p>

<p>2.
 Fitzhugh Green, {Looking Forward,} (<ent type='GPE'>New York</ent>: Hippocrene, 1989),
p.  53.</p>

<p>3. Harry Hurt III, <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>George Bush, <ent type='ORG'>Plucky Lad</ent>,'' {<ent type='GPE'>Texas</ent>Monthly,}
June, 1983, p.142.</p>

<p>4.  Richard  Ben  Cramer,  <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>How  He Got Here,'' {Esquire,} June,
1991, p.  84.</p>

<p>5. Joe Hyams, {Flight of the Avenger} (<ent type='GPE'>New York</ent>, 1991).</p>

<p>6.
 Nicholas King, {George Bush: A Biography} (<ent type='GPE'>New York</ent>, Dodd, Mead,
1980), p.  xi.</p>

<p>7. Donnie Radcliffe, {Simply Barbara Bush,}  (New  York:  <ent type='ORG'>Warner</ent>,
1989), p.  103.</p>

<p>8. Rainer <ent type='ORG'>Bonhorst</ent>, {George Bush, Der Neue Mann im Weissen Haus,}
(Bergisch Gladbach: Gustav Luebbe Verlag, 1988), pp.  80-81.</p>

<p>9.  See  <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>TheRoar  of  the Crowd,'' {<ent type='GPE'>Texas</ent> Monthly,} November,
1991. See also Jan Jarboe, <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>Meaner Than a Junkyard Dog,'' {<ent type='GPE'>Texas</ent>
Monthly,} April 1991, p.  122 ff.  Here Wyatt observes: <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>I  knew
from  the beginning George Bush came to <ent type='GPE'>Texas</ent> only because he was
politically ambitious.He flew out here on an airplane owned  by
<ent type='ORG'>Dresser Industries</ent>.  His  daddy  wasa  member of the board of
Dresser.''</p>

<p>10. Darwin Payne, {Initiative in Energy}  (NewYork:  Simon  and
Shuster, 1979), p.  233.</p>

<p>11. John  Selby  Watson  (translator),  {Sallust,  Florus,  and
Velleius Paterculus} (<ent type='GPE'>London</ent>: George Bell  andSon,  1879),  pp.
542-46.</p>

<p>12.  Cornelius<ent type='ORG'>Tacitus</ent>,  {<ent type='ORG'>The Annals of</ent> Imperial <ent type='GPE'>Rome</ent>} (Penguin,
1962), pp.  193-221.</p>

<p>13.  Gaius  Suetonius  Tranquillus,  {<ent type='ORG'>The  </ent>Lives  of  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>Twelve
Caesars} (New  York:  Modern  Library,1931),pp.  165-204, {
passim.</p>

<p>Any comments, please send by email, as I get very far  behind  on
this group.</p>

<p>Thanks.</p>

<p> John Covici</p>

<p>coviciccs.covici.com</p>

<p>Article 15244 of alt.activism:
From: covici@ccs.covici.com (John Covici)
<ent type='GPE'>Newsgroups</ent>: alt.activism
Subject: Part 2: George Bush Unauthorized Biography
<info type="Message-ID"> mV3<ent type='GPE'>LeB</ent>1w164w@ccs.covici.com</info>
Date: 15 Jan 92 21:58:09 GMT
Organization: Covici Computer Systems
Lines: 1495</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>The  </ent>followingis  from  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>New  <ent type='ORG'>Fed</ent>eralist serialization of a
forthcoming book concerning George Bush.</p>

<p>For further information or to subscribe to <ent type='ORG'>New <ent type='ORG'>Fed</ent>eralist</ent>, please
contact me by e-mail.</p>

<p>CHAPTER 2 THE HITLER PROJECT</p>

<p>1. Bush Property Seized--Trading with the Enemy</p>

<p>In October 1942, ten months after entering World War II,  <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>
was  <ent type='ORG'>preparingits</ent>  first  assault against <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> military forces.
Prescott Bush was managing partner of  Brown  Brothers<ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>.
His  18-year-old  son George, the future U.S. President, had just
begun training to become a naval pilot.</p>

<p> On October 20, 1942, the U.S.  government ordered <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>seizure
of  <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>  <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>  banking  operations in <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent> City which were
being conducted by Prescott Bush.</p>

<p> Under the {Trading with the Enemy Act},  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>government  took
over  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>{Union  Banking  Corporation,}  in  which  Bush  was a
director.  The U.S. Alien Property Custodian seized Union Banking
Corp.'s stock shares, all of which were owned by  Prescott  Bush,
E.  Roland  <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>Bunny''  <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>,  three  <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> executives, and two
other associates of Bush.s1</p>

<p> The order seizing the bank  <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>vest[ed]  [seized]  all  of  the
capital stock of Union  Banking  Corporation,  aNew  York
corporation,'' and named the holders of its shares as:</p>

<p> sb|<ent type='ORG'>``</ent>E.  Roland <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>--3991 shares.'' <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent> was chairman
and director of Union Banking  Corp.  (<ent type='ORG'>UBC</ent>);  this  <ent type='ORG'>is<ent type='ORG'>``</ent>Bunny</ent>''
<ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>, described by Prescott Bush as a place holder who didn't
get  much  into  banking  affairs;  Prescott managed his personal
investments.</p>

<p> sb|<ent type='ORG'>``</ent>Cornelis <ent type='GPE'>Lievense</ent>--4 shares.'' <ent type='GPE'>Lievense</ent> was president and
director of <ent type='ORG'>UBC</ent>, and a <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent> resident banking functionary  for
the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>s.</p>

<p> sb|<ent type='ORG'>``</ent>Harold D. <ent type='ORG'>Pennington</ent>--1 share.'' <ent type='ORG'>Pennington</ent> was treasurer
and  director  of  <ent type='ORG'>UBC</ent>, and an office manager employed by Bush at
<ent type='ORG'><ent type='ORG'>Brown Brothers</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent></ent>.</p>

<p> sb|<ent type='ORG'>``</ent>Ray Morris--1 share.'' Morris was director of <ent type='ORG'>UBC</ent>, anda
partner of Bush and the <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>s.</p>

<p> sb|<ent type='ORG'>``</ent>Prescott  S.  Bush--1  share.'' Bush was director of <ent type='ORG'>UBC</ent>,
which was co-founded and sponsored by  his  father-in-law  George
Walker; he was senior managing partner for E. Roland <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent> and
<ent type='ORG'>Averell <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent></ent>.</p>

<p> sb|<ent type='ORG'>``</ent>H.J. Kouwenhoven--1 share'' Kouwenhoven was director of
<ent type='ORG'>UBC</ent>; he organized  <ent type='ORG'>UBC</ent>as  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>emissary  of  Fritz  <ent type='ORG'>Thyssen</ent>  in
negotiations with George Walker and <ent type='ORG'>Averell <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent></ent>; he was also
managing  director  of<ent type='ORG'>UBC</ent>'s  <ent type='GPE'>Netherlands</ent>  affiliate  under <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>
occupation;  industrial  executive  in<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>  <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y,and  also
director  and  chief  foreign  financial  executive of the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>
<ent type='ORG'>Steel Trust</ent>.</p>

<p> sb|<ent type='ORG'>``</ent>Johann G. Groeninger--1 share.'' Groeninger was  director
of  <ent type='ORG'>UBC</ent>  and  of  its <ent type='GPE'>Netherlands</ent> affiliate; he was an industrial
executive in <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y.</p>

<p> The order also specified: <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>all of which shares areheld  for
<ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>benefit  of  ...  membersof  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='ORG'>Thyssen</ent> family, [and] is
property of nationals ... of a designated enemy country....''</p>

<p>  By October 26, 1942, U.S.  troops  were  underway  for  <ent type='LOC'>North</ent>
<ent type='LOC'>Africa</ent>.  On  October 28, the government issued orders seizing two
<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> front organizations  run  by  theBush-<ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>  bank:  the
{<ent type='GPE'>Holland</ent>-<ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent>  Trading  Corporation}  and the {Seamless Steel
Equipment Corporation.}s2</p>

<p> U.S. forces landed under fire  nearAlgiers  on  November  8,
1942;  heavy  combat raged throughout November. <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> interests in
the {<ent type='GPE'>Silesia</ent>n-<ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent> Corporation,}  long  managed  by  Prescott
Bush  and  hisfather-in-law  George Herbert Walker, were seized
under the Trading with the Enemy Act on  November  171942.  In
this  action,  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>government announced that it was seizing only
the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> interests, leaving the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>s' U.S. partners to carry  on
the business.s3</p>

<p> These  and  other  actions  taken  by  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>U.S. government in
wartime were, tragically, too little and  too  late.President
Bush'sfamily had already played a central role in financing and
arming Adolf Hitler for his takeover of <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y; in financing and
managing the buildup of <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> war industries for <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>conquest  of
<ent type='LOC'>Europe</ent> and war against the U.S.A.; and in the development of <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>
genocide  theories  and  racial propaganda, with their well-known
results.</p>

<p> The facts presented here must be known, and their implications
reflected upon, for a proper understanding  ofPresident  George
Herbert  Walker  Bush  and  of<ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>danger  to  mankind  that he
represents.  The President's family fortune was largely a  result
of <ent type='NORP'>theHitlerproject</ent>.  <ent type='ORG'>The  </ent>powerful  Anglo-<ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent>  family
associations,  which  later  boosted him into the Central
Intelligence  <ent type='ORG'>Agency</ent> and up to the <ent type='ORG'>White <ent type='ORG'>House</ent></ent>, were his father's
partners in the Hitler project.</p>

<p> President Franklin Roosevelt's Alien Property  Custodian,  Leo
T.  Crowley, signed Vesting Order Number 248 seizing the property
of Prescott  Bush  under  the Trading with Enemy Act.  The order,
published in obscure government record books and kept out of  the
news,s4 explained nothing about the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>s involved; only that the
Union  BankingCorporation was run for the <ent type='ORG'>``</ent><ent type='ORG'>Thyssen</ent> family'' of
<ent type='ORG'>``</ent><ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y and/or <ent type='GPE'>Hungary</ent>''--<ent type='ORG'>``</ent>nationals ... of a designated enemy
country.''</p>

<p> By deciding that Prescott Bush and the other directors of  the
Union  BankingCorp. were legally {front men for the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>s}, the
government avoided the more important historical issue:  In  what
way  {were Hitler's <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>s themselves hired, armed, and instructed
by} the <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>London</ent> clique of which Prescott Bush was  an
executive manager?  Let  us  examine<ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>-Bush Hitler
project from the 1920s until it was partially broken up, to  seek
an answer for that question.</p>

<p>2. Origin and Extent of the Project</p>

<p> Fritz  <ent type='ORG'>Thyssen</ent>  andhis  business  partners  are  universally
recognized as <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>most  important  <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>  financiersof  Adolf
Hitler's  takeover  of<ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y. At the time of the order seizing
the <ent type='ORG'>Thyssen</ent> family's <ent type='ORG'>Union Banking Corp</ent>., Mr. Fritz  <ent type='ORG'>Thyssen</ent>  had
already  published  his famous book, {I Paid Hitler},s5 admitting
that he had financed Adolf Hitler and  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>  movement  since
October  1923.<ent type='ORG'>Thyssen</ent>'s  role  as  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>leading early backer of
Hitler's grab for  power  in  <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y  had  been  noted  by  U.S.
diplomats in <ent type='GPE'>Berlin</ent> in 1932.s6 The order seizing the Bush-<ent type='ORG'>Thyssen</ent>
bank  was  curiously  quiet  and modest about the identity of the
perpetrators who had been nailed.</p>

<p> Buttwo  weeks  before the official order, government
investigators  had  reported  secretly that <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>W. <ent type='ORG'>Averell <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent></ent>
was in <ent type='LOC'>Europe</ent> sometime prior to 1924  and  at  that  time  became
acquainted with  Fritz  <ent type='ORG'>Thyssen</ent>,  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='NORP'>German</ent>  industrialist.''
<ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>Thyssen</ent> agreed to set up a bank for <ent type='ORG'>Thyssen</ent>  in  New
York.  <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>[C]ertain  of[<ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>'s]  associates  would  serve as
directors....'' <ent type='ORG'>Thyssen</ent> agent <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>H.J.  Kouwenhoven ... came to the
United <ent type='ORG'>State</ent>s ... prior to 1924 for conferences with the <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>
Company in this connection....''s7</p>

<p> When exactly  was  <ent type='ORG'>``</ent><ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>  in  <ent type='LOC'>Europe</ent>  sometimeprior  to
1924''? In  fact, he was in <ent type='GPE'>Berlin</ent> in 1922 to set up the <ent type='GPE'>Berlin</ent>
branch of W.A. <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent> &amp; Co. under George Walker's presidency.</p>

<p> The Union Banking  Corporation  wasestablished  formally  in
1924, as a unit in the <ent type='GPE'>Manhattan</ent> offices of W.A.  <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent> &amp; Co.,
interlocking with <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='ORG'>Thyssen</ent>-owned  {Bank  voor  Handel  en
Scheepvaart} (<ent type='ORG'>BHS</ent>)  in<ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='GPE'>Netherlands</ent>.   The investigators
concluded  that  <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>theUnion  BankingCorporation has since its
inception handled funds chiefly supplied to it through <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='NORP'>Dutch</ent>
bank by the <ent type='ORG'>Thyssen</ent> interests for <ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent> investment.''</p>

<p> Thus  by personal agreement between <ent type='ORG'>Averell <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent></ent> and Fritz
<ent type='ORG'>Thyssen</ent> in  1922,  W.A.  <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>  &amp;  Co.  (alias  Union  Banking
Corporation)  would  be transferring funds back and forth between
<ent type='GPE'>New York</ent> and the <ent type='ORG'>``</ent><ent type='ORG'>Thyssen</ent> interests'' in <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y. By putting  up
about  $400000,  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent> organization would be joint owner
and manager of <ent type='ORG'>Thyssen</ent>'s banking operations outside of <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y.</p>

<p> {How important was the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>enterprise  for  whichPresident
Bush's father was the <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent> banker?}</p>

<p> The 1942 U.S. government investigative report said that Bush's
<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>-front  bank  was an interlocking concern with the Vereinigte
Stahlwerke (United  Steel  Works  Corporation  or  {<ent type='NORP'>German</ent>  Steel
Trust}) led  by  Fritz<ent type='ORG'>Thyssen</ent>  and his two brothers.After the
war, congressional investigators probed  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='ORG'>Thyssen</ent>  interests,
Union Banking  Corp.  and  related <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> units.The investigation
showed that <ent type='ORG'>the Vereinigte Stahlwerke</ent> had produced thefollowing
approximate  proportions of total <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> national output: <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>50.8%
of <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y's pig iron; 41.4%  of  <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>  <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y'suniversal
plate;36.0%  of  <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>  <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y's  heavy  plate;  38.5%  of <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>
<ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y's galvanized sheet; 45.5% of  <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>  <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y's  pipes  and
tubes;22.1%  of  <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>  <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y's  wire; 35.0% of <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y's
explosives.''s8</p>

<p> This accounts for many, many <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> submarines,  bombs,  rifles,
gas chambers, etc.</p>

<p> Prescott  Bush became vice president of W.A. <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent> &amp; Co. in
1926. That same year, a friend of <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>  and  Bush  set  upa
giant  new  organization  for  their  client Fritz <ent type='ORG'>Thyssen</ent>, prime
sponsor of politician Adolf Hitler. The new {<ent type='NORP'>German</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Steel Trust</ent>,}
<ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y's largest industrial corporation, was organized  in  1926
by Wall Street banker Clarence <ent type='ORG'>Dillon</ent>. <ent type='ORG'>Dillon</ent> was the old comrade
of  Prescott  Bush's  father  Sam  Bush  from  the <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>Merchants of
Death'' bureau in World War I.</p>

<p> In  return  for  putting  up  $70  millionto create his
organization, majority owner <ent type='ORG'>Thyssen</ent> gave the <ent type='ORG'><ent type='ORG'>Dillon</ent> Read</ent> company
two  or  more  representativeson  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>boardof  the new Steel
Trust.s9</p>

<p> Thus there is a division of labor: <ent type='ORG'>Thyssen</ent>'s own  confidential
accounts,  forpolitical  and related purposes, were run through
the Walker-Bush organization; the <ent type='ORG'>Steel Trust</ent> did  itscorporate
banking through <ent type='ORG'><ent type='ORG'>Dillon</ent> Read</ent>.</p>

<p> TheWalker-Bush  firm's  banking  activities  werenot  just
politically  neutral  money-making  ventures  which  happened  to
coincide  with<ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>aims  of  <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>  <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>s.  All  of the firm's
<ent type='LOC'>Europe</ent>an  business in those days was organized around
anti-democratic political forces.</p>

<p> In  1927,  criticism of their support for totalitarianism drew
this retort from  <ent type='ORG'>BertWalker</ent>,  written  fromKennebunkport  to
Averell  <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>:  <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>It  seems  to  me  that  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>suggestion in
connection with Lord  Bearsted's  views  that  we  withdraw  from
<ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent> smacks  somewhat  of  the impertinent....  I think that we
have drawn our line and should hew to it.''s1s0</p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>Averell <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent></ent> met with  <ent type='GPE'>Italy</ent>'s  fascistdictator,  Benito
Mussolini.  A representative of the firm subsequently telegraphed
good news back to his chief executive Bert Walker:  <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>...  During
these  last  days ... Mussolini ... has examined and approved our
<ent type='GPE'>c[o]ntract</ent> 15 June.''s1s1</p>

<p> <ent type='GPE'>Thegreat</ent>  financial  collapse  of1929-31  shook <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>,
<ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y, and  <ent type='GPE'>Britain</ent>,weakening  all governments.  It also made
the hard-pressed Prescott Bush even more willing to  do  whatever
was necessary  to  retain  his new place in the world.It was in
this  crisis  that  certain  Anglo-<ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent>s  determined  on  the
installation of a Hitler regime in <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y.</p>

<p> W.A.  <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>  &amp; Co., well-positioned for this enterprise and
rich in assets from their <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>  and  <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>nbusiness,  merged
with  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='NORP'>British</ent>-<ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent>  investment house, <ent type='ORG'>Brown Brothers</ent>, on
January 1, 1931.  Bert Walker retired to his own G.H.Walker&amp;
Co.  This left the <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent> brothers, Prescott Bush, and Thatcher
M.  Brown as <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>senior  partners  of<ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>new  Brown  Brothers
<ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent> firm.  (The <ent type='GPE'>London</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>England</ent> branch of the Brown family
firm  continued  operating  under its historic name--Brown,
Shipley.)</p>

<p> Robert  A.  Lovett  also  came  over  as  a partner from Brown
Brothers. His father, E.H. <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>'s lawyer and railroad  chief,
had  been  on  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>War  Industries <ent type='ORG'>Board</ent> with Prescott's father.
Though he remained a partner  in  Brown  Brothers  <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>,  the
juniorLovettsoon  replacedhis father as chief exexcutive of
<ent type='ORG'>Union <ent type='LOC'>Pacific</ent> Railroad</ent>.</p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>Brown Brothers</ent> had a racial tradition that fitted it well  for
the Hitler  project. <ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent> patriots had cursed its name back
in Civil War days.  <ent type='ORG'>Brown Brothers</ent>, with offices  in  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>U.S.A.
and  in  <ent type='GPE'>England</ent>,  had carried on their ships fully 75 percent of
the slave cotton from the <ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent> South  overto  <ent type='NORP'>British</ent>  mill
owners; through  their  usurious  credit  they  controlled  and
manipulated the slave-owners.</p>

<p> Now, in 1931, the virtual dictator of world finance,  Bank  of
<ent type='GPE'>England</ent>  Governor  Montagu  Collet  Norman,  was  a  former Brown
Brothers partner,  whose  grandfather  had  been  bossof  Brown
Brothers during  the U.S. Civil War.  Montagu Norman was known as
the most  avidof  Hitler's  supporters  within  <ent type='NORP'>British</ent>  ruling
circles,  and  Norman's  intimacy with this firm was essential to
his management of the Hitler project.</p>

<p> In 1931, while Prescott Bush ran the <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent> office of  Brown
Brothers <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>,  Prescott's  partner  <ent type='ORG'>wasMontagu</ent>  Norman's
intimate friend Thatcher Brown. The Bank of <ent type='GPE'>England</ent> chief  always
stayedat  the home of Prescott's partner on his hush-hush trips
to <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent>. Prescott Bush  concentrated  on  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>firm's  <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>
actitivites,  and  Thatcher  Brown  saw  to their business in old
<ent type='GPE'>England</ent>, under the guidance of his mentor Montagu Norman.s1s2</p>

<p>3. Hitler's Ladder to Power</p>

<p> Adolf Hitler became Chancellor of <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y  January  30,  1933,
and absolute dictator in March 1933, after two years of expensive
and violent  lobbying  and electioneering.  Two affiliates of the
Bush-<ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent> organization played great parts  in  this  criminal
undertaking:<ent type='ORG'>Thyssen</ent>'s  <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>  <ent type='ORG'>Steel Trust</ent>;and the
<ent type='GPE'>Hamburg</ent>-<ent type='NORP'>Amerika</ent> Line and several of its executives.s1s3</p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>Letus</ent>  look  moreclosely  at  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='ORG'>Bushfamily</ent>'s <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>
partners.</p>

<p> {Fritz  <ent type='ORG'>Thyssen</ent>} told <ent type='ORG'>Allied</ent> interrogators after the war about
some of his financial support for the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> Party:  <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>In  1930  or
1931 ...  I  told  [Hitler's  deputy  Rudolph]Hess ...  I would
arrange a credit for him with a <ent type='NORP'>Dutch</ent> bank in <ent type='GPE'>Rotterdam</ent>, the Bank
fuaur Handel und Schiff [i.e. Bank  voor  Handel  en  Scheepvaart
(<ent type='ORG'>BHS</ent>), <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>-Bush  affiliate].I arranged the credit ...
he would pay it back in three years....  I  chose  a  <ent type='NORP'>Dutch</ent>  bank
because  I  did  not  want to be mixed up with <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> banks in my
position, and because I thought it was better to do business with
a <ent type='NORP'>Dutch</ent> bank, and I thought I would have the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>s a little  more
in my hands....</p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>The credit was about 250-300000 [gold] marks--about the sum
I had  given  before. <ent type='ORG'>The  </ent>loan has been repaid in part to the
<ent type='NORP'>Dutch</ent> bank, but I think some money is still owing on it....''s1s4</p>

<p> The overall total of <ent type='ORG'>Thyssen</ent>'s political donations  and  loans
to  the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>s was well over a million dollars, including funds he
raised from others--in a period  of  terrible  money-shortage  in
<ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y.</p>

<p> {Friedrich  Flick}  was the major co-owner of the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> Steel
Trust with Fritz <ent type='ORG'>Thyssen</ent>,  <ent type='ORG'>Thyssen</ent>'s  longtimecollaborator  and
sometime competitor. In preparation for the war crimes tribunal
at <ent type='GPE'>Nuremberg</ent>, the U.S.government said that Flick was<ent type='ORG'>``</ent>one  of
leading  financiers  and industrialists who from 1932 contributed
large sums to the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> Party ... member of `Circle of Friends' of
Himmler who contributed large sums to the <ent type='ORG'>SS</ent>.''s1s5</p>

<p>  Flick, like <ent type='ORG'>Thyssen</ent>, financed the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>s to  maintain  their
private  armies  called  <ent type='ORG'>Schutzstaffel</ent> (S.S. or <ent type='ORG'>Black Shirts</ent>) and
Sturmabteilung (S.A., storm troops or <ent type='ORG'>Brown Shirts</ent>).</p>

<p> The Flick-<ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>  partnership  was  directly  supervised  by
Prescott  Bush,  President  Bush's  father, and by George Walker,
President Bush's grandfather.</p>

<p> The <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>-Walker <ent type='ORG'>Union Banking Corp</ent>. arrangements  for  the
<ent type='NORP'>German</ent>Steel  Trust had made them bankers for Flick and his vast
operations in <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y by no later than 1926.</p>

<p> The {<ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Fifteen Corporation</ent>} (George Walker,  president,
Prescott  Bushand  Averell  <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>,  sole  directors)  held a
substantial stake in <ent type='ORG'>the <ent type='GPE'>Silesia</ent>n Holding Co</ent>. at the time of  the
merger with  Brown  Brothers,  January1,  1931.  This holding
correlated to <ent type='ORG'>Averell <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent></ent>'s <ent type='GPE'>chairmanshipof</ent>  the
{Consolidated  <ent type='GPE'>Silesia</ent>n  SteelCorporation,}  the <ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent> group
owning one-third of a complex  of  steelmaking,  coal-mining  and
zinc-mining  activities in <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y and <ent type='GPE'>Poland</ent>, in which Friedrich
Flick owned two-thirds.s1s6</p>

<p>  The <ent type='GPE'>Nuremberg</ent> prosecutor characterized Flick as follows:</p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>Proprietor  and  head  <ent type='ORG'>ofa</ent>  large  group of industrial
enterprises (coal and iron mines, steel producing and fabricating
plants) ...  `Wehrwirt<ent type='ORG'>schaft</ent>sfuehrer,'  1938[title awarded to
prominent industrialists for merit in armaments  drive--`Military
Economy Leader']....''s1s7</p>

<p> Forthis  buildup of the Hitler war machine with coal, steel,
and arms production, using slave laborers,  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>  Flick  was
condemned  to  seven  years in prison at the <ent type='GPE'>Nuremberg</ent> trials; he
served three years.  With  friends  in  New  York  and  <ent type='GPE'>London</ent>,
however, Flick lived into the 1970s and died a billionaire.</p>

<p> On  March 19, 1934, Prescott Bush--then director of the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>
<ent type='ORG'>Steel Trust</ent>'s <ent type='ORG'>Union Banking Corp</ent>oration--initiated  analert  to
<ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>absent  <ent type='ORG'>Averell <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent></ent> about a problem which had developed
in the Flick partnership.s1s8 Bush sent <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent> a clipping  from
<ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>{<ent type='GPE'>New York</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Time</ent>s} of that day, which reported that the <ent type='NORP'>Polish</ent>
government  was  fighting  back  against  <ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent> and <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>
stockholders  who  controlled <ent type='ORG'>``</ent><ent type='GPE'>Poland</ent>'s largest industrial unit,
<ent type='ORG'>the Upper <ent type='GPE'>Silesia</ent>n Coal and Steel Company</ent>....''</p>

<p> The {<ent type='ORG'>Time</ent>s} article continued: <ent type='ORG'>``</ent><ent type='ORG'>The  </ent>company  has  long  been
accused of mismanagement,excessive  borrowing,  fictitious
bookkeeping and gambling in securities.  Warrants were issued  in
December for  several  directors  accused  of tax evasions.  They
were <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> citizens and they fled.  They were replaced by <ent type='NORP'>Poles</ent>.
Herr Flick, regarding this as an attempt to  make  thecompany's
board  entirely  <ent type='NORP'>Polish</ent>,  retaliated by restricting credits until
<ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>new  <ent type='NORP'>Polish</ent>  directors  were  unable  to  pay  the workmen
regularly.''</p>

<p> The{<ent type='ORG'>Time</ent>s} noted that the company's mines and mills <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>employ
25000 men and account for 45 percent  of  <ent type='GPE'>Poland</ent>'s  total  steel
output and  12 percent of her coal production.Two-thirds of the
company's stock is owned by Friedrich  Flick,  a  leading  <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>
steel  industrialist,  and the remainder is owned by interests in
<ent type='GPE'>the United <ent type='ORG'>State</ent>s</ent>.''</p>

<p> In view of the fact that a great deal  of  <ent type='NORP'>Polish</ent>  output  was
being  exported  to Hitler's <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y under depression conditions,
the <ent type='NORP'>Polish</ent> government thought that Bush, <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>, and their <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>
partners  should  at  least  pay  fulltaxes  on  their <ent type='NORP'>Polish</ent>
holdings. <ent type='ORG'>The  </ent>U.S.  and  <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> owners responded with a lockout.
The letter to <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent> in <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent> reported a cable from  their
<ent type='LOC'>Europe</ent>an  representative:  <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>Have  undertaken  new  steps  <ent type='GPE'>London</ent>
<ent type='GPE'>Berlin</ent>...  please  establishfriendly  relations  with  <ent type='NORP'>Polish</ent>
Ambassador [in <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>].''</p>

<p> A  1935  <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>  <ent type='ORG'>Fifteen Corporation</ent> memo from George Walker
announced an agreement had been made <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>in  <ent type='GPE'>Berlin</ent>''  to  sell  an
8000  block  of their shares in <ent type='ORG'>Consolidated <ent type='GPE'>Silesia</ent>n Steel</ent>.s1s9
But the dispute with <ent type='GPE'>Poland</ent> did not deter <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>Bush  family  from
continuing its partnership with Flick.</p>

<p> <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>  tanksand  bombs <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>settled'' this dispute in September,
1939 with the invasion of <ent type='GPE'>Poland</ent>, beginning  World  War  II.  The
<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> army had been equipped by Flick, <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>, Walker, and Bush,
with materials essentially stolen from <ent type='GPE'>Poland</ent>.</p>

<p> There were  probably  fewpeopleat  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>time  who  could
appreciate the irony, that when <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent>s  also  attacked  and
invaded  <ent type='GPE'>Poland</ent>  from the <ent type='LOC'>East</ent>, their vehicles were fueled by oil
pumpedfrom  <ent type='GPE'>Baku</ent>  wells  revived  by<ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>/Walker/Bush
enterprise.</p>

<p> Three  years later, nearly a year after the <ent type='NORP'>Japanese</ent> attack on
Pearl Harbor, the U.S. government  ordered  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>seizure  of  the
<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>s'share  in  the<ent type='GPE'>Silesia</ent>n-<ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent>  Corporationunder the
Trading with the Enemy Act. Enemy nationals were said to  own  49
percent  of  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>common stock and 41.67 percent of the preferred
stock of the company.</p>

<p> The order characterized the company as a <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>business enterprise
within <ent type='GPE'>the United <ent type='ORG'>State</ent>s</ent>, owned by [a front company  in]  <ent type='GPE'>Zurich</ent>,
<ent type='GPE'>Switzerland</ent>,  and  held  for the benefit of Bergwerksgesell<ent type='ORG'>schaft</ent>
George von Giesche's Erben, a <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> corporation....''s2s0</p>

<p> Bert Walker was still <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>senior  directorof  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>company,
which  he  hadfounded  back  in  1926  simultaneously  with the
creation of  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='NORP'>German</ent>  Steel  Trust.  Ray  Morris,  Prescott's
partner from <ent type='ORG'>Union Banking Corp</ent>. and <ent type='ORG'><ent type='ORG'>Brown Brothers</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent></ent>, was
also a director.</p>

<p> Theinvestigative  report  prior  to the government crackdown
explained the <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>NATURE OF BUSINE<ent type='ORG'>SS</ent>: The subject corporation is an
<ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent> holding company  for  <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>  and  <ent type='NORP'>Polish</ent>  subsidiaries,
which  own  large  andvaluable  coal and zinc mines in <ent type='GPE'>Silesia</ent>,
<ent type='GPE'>Poland</ent> and <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y. Since September 1939, these  properties  have
been  in  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>possession of and have been operated by the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>
government and have undoubtedly been of  considerable  assistance
to that country in its war effort.''s2s1</p>

<p> Thereportnoted  that  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent>  stockholders hoped to
regain control of the <ent type='LOC'>Europe</ent>an properties after the war.</p>

<p>4. Control of <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Commerce</ent></p>

<p> Bert Walker had arranged the credits <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent> needed  to  take
control  of  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='GPE'>Hamburg</ent>-<ent type='NORP'>Amerika</ent>  Line  back in 1920. Walker had
organized the {<ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent> Ship and <ent type='ORG'>Commerce</ent> Corp.} as a unit of the
W.A.<ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent> &amp; Co., with contractual  power  over
<ent type='GPE'>Hamburg</ent>-<ent type='NORP'>Amerika</ent>'s affairs.</p>

<p> As  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>Hitler  project  went  into  high gear, <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>-Bush
shares in <ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent> Ship and  <ent type='ORG'>Commerce</ent>  Corp.  were  held  by  the
<ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent> Fifteen Corp., run by Prescott Bush and Bert Walker.s2s2</p>

<p> It  was  a  convenient  stroll  for the well-tanned, athletic,
handsome  Prescott  Bush.  From  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='ORG'><ent type='ORG'>Brown Brothers</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent></ent>
skyscraper  at59  Wall  Street--where  he  was  senior managing
partner, confidential investments manager and advisor to  Averell
and  his  brother  <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>Bunny''--he  walked  across  to the <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>
<ent type='ORG'>Fifteen Corporation</ent> at One Wall Street, otherwise known  as  G.H.
Walker&amp; Co.--and around the corner to his subsidiary offices at
39 Broadway, former home of the old  W.A.  <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>  &amp;Co.,  and
still  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>offices  for  <ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent>  Ship and <ent type='ORG'>Commerce</ent>, and of the
<ent type='ORG'>Union Banking Corp</ent>oration.</p>

<p> In many ways, Bush's <ent type='GPE'>Hamburg</ent>-<ent type='NORP'>Amerika</ent> Line was  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>pivot  for
the entire Hitler project.</p>

<p> Averell  <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>  and Bert Walker had gained control over the
steamship company in 1920 in negotiations with its post-World War
I chief executive, {Wilhelm Cuno}, and with <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>line's  bankers,
M.M.  <ent type='GPE'>Warburg</ent>.Cuno  was  thereafter completely dependent on the
Anglo-<ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent>s,  and  became  a  member  of the Anglo-<ent type='NORP'>German</ent>
Friendship <ent type='ORG'>Society</ent>.In the 1930-32  drive  fora  Hitler
dictatorship, Wilhelm Cuno contributed important sums to the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>
Party.s2s3</p>

<p> {Albert Voegler} was  chiefexecutive  of  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='ORG'>Thyssen</ent>-Flick
<ent type='NORP'>German</ent>Steel  Trust for which Bush's <ent type='ORG'>Union Banking Corp</ent>. was the
<ent type='GPE'>New York</ent> office.  He was a director  of  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>Bush-affiliate  <ent type='ORG'>BHS</ent>
Bank in <ent type='GPE'>Rotterdam</ent>, and  a  director  of  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>-Bush
<ent type='GPE'>Hamburg</ent>-<ent type='NORP'>Amerika</ent> Line. Voegler joined <ent type='ORG'>Thyssen</ent> and Flickin  their
heavy  1930-33<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> contributions, and helped organize the final
<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> leap into <ent type='ORG'>national power</ent>.s2s4</p>

<p> The {Schroeder} family of bankers was a linchpin for <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>
activities  of<ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent> and Prescott Bush, closely tied to their
lawyers Allen and John Foster <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent>.</p>

<p> Baron Kurt  von  <ent type='ORG'>Schroeder  </ent>was  co-director  of  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>massive
<ent type='ORG'>Thyssen</ent>-Huettefoundry  alongwith  Johann Groeninger, Prescott
Bush's <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent> bank partner.  Kurt von <ent type='ORG'>Schroeder  </ent>wastreasurer
of  the support organization for the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> Party's private armies,
to which Friedrich Flick contributed.Kurt  von  <ent type='ORG'>Schroeder  </ent>and
Montagu  Norman's  proteaageaaHjalmar Schacht together made the
final arrangments for Hitler to enter the government.s2s5</p>

<p> Baron Rudolph von Schroeder was vice president and director of
the <ent type='GPE'>Hamburg</ent>-<ent type='NORP'>Amerika</ent> Line. Long an  intimate  contact  of  Averell
<ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>'s  in<ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y,  Baron  Rudolph  sent his grandson Baron
Johann Rudolph for a  tour  ofPrescott  Bush's  Brown  Brothers
<ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent> offices in <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent> City in December 1932--on the eve of
their Hitler-triumph.s2s6</p>

<p> Certain  actions  taken directly by the <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>-Bush shipping
line in 1932 must be ranked among the gravest acts of treason  in
this century.</p>

<p> TheU.S.  Embassy  in <ent type='GPE'>Berlin</ent> reported back to <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent> that
the <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>costly election campaigns'' and <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>the cost of maintaining a
private army of 300000 to 400000 men'' had raised questions  as
to the<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>s'financial backers.  The constitutional government
of the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>  republic  <ent type='GPE'>movedto</ent>  defend  national  freedom  by
ordering <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>  Party  private  armies  disbanded. The U.S.
Embassy reported that the {<ent type='GPE'>Hamburg</ent>-<ent type='NORP'>Amerika</ent>  Line  was  purchasing
and distributing propaganda attacks against <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='NORP'>German</ent>
government, for attempting this last-minute crackdown on Hitler's
forces.}s2s7</p>

<p> Thousands of  <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>  opponents  ofHitlerism  were  shot  or
intimidated  by  privately  armed  <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>  BrownShirts.  In  this
connection, we note that  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>original  <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>Merchant  of  Death,''
SamuelPryor,was a founding director of both the Union Banking
Corp. and the <ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent> Ship and <ent type='ORG'>Commerce</ent> Corp.Since  Mr.  Pryor
was  executive committee chairman of <ent type='ORG'><ent type='ORG'>Remington</ent> Arms</ent> and a central
figure in the world's private arms traffic, his use to the Hitler
project was enhanced as the Bush family's partner in  <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>  Party
banking and trans-<ent type='LOC'>Atlantic</ent> shipping.</p>

<p> TheU.S.  <ent type='ORG'>Senate</ent>  arms-traffic investigators probed <ent type='ORG'>Remington</ent>
after it was joined in a cartel agreement on  explosives  to  the
<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> firm  I.G.  <ent type='ORG'>Farben</ent>.  Looking  at  the period leading up to
Hitler's seizure of  power,  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>senators  found  that  <ent type='ORG'>``</ent><ent type='NORP'>German</ent>
political  associations, like the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> and others, are nearly all
armed with <ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent> ...  guns....  Arms of all kinds coming  from
<ent type='GPE'>America</ent>  are  transshipped  in the <ent type='GPE'>Scheldt</ent> to river barges before
the vessels arrive in <ent type='GPE'>Antwerp</ent>. They then can be  carried  through
<ent type='GPE'>Holland</ent> without police inspectionor interference.  The
Hitlerists and <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Communist</ent>s</ent>  arepresumed  to  get  arms  in  this
manner. <ent type='ORG'>The  </ent>principal  armscomingfrom <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> are <ent type='ORG'>Thompson</ent>
submachine guns and revolvers.The number is great.''s2s8</p>

<p> The beginning  of  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>Hitler  regime  brought  some  bizarre
changes to the <ent type='GPE'>Hamburg</ent>-<ent type='NORP'>Amerika</ent> Line--and more betrayals.</p>

<p> Prescott  Bush's <ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent> Ship and <ent type='ORG'>Commerce</ent> Corp. notified Max
<ent type='GPE'>Warburg</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>Hamburg</ent>, <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y, on March 7, 1933, that  <ent type='GPE'>Warburg</ent>  was
to  be<ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>corporation's official, designated representative on
the board of <ent type='GPE'>Hamburg</ent>-<ent type='NORP'>Amerika</ent>.s2s9</p>

<p> Max <ent type='GPE'>Warburg</ent> replied on March 27, 1933, assuring  his  <ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent>
sponsors  thatthe Hitler government was good for <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y: <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>For
the last few years business was considerably better than  we  had
anticipated,  but  a  reactionis  making  itself  felt for some
months.  We are actually suffering also  under<ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>very  active
propaganda against <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y, caused bysome unpleasant
circumstances.These occurrences were the natural consequence of
the very excited  election  campaign,  but  were  extraordinarily
exaggerated in<ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>foreign  press.<ent type='ORG'>The  </ent>Government is firmly
resolved to maintain public peace and order  in  <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y,  andI
feel  perfectly  convinced in this respect that there is no cause
for any alarm whatsoever.''s3s0</p>

<p> This seal of approval for Hitler, coming from  a  famous  <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>,
was  just  what  <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent> and Bush required, for they anticipated
rather serious <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>alarm'' inside <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>U.S.A.  against  their  <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>
operations.</p>

<p> On  March  29,  1933, two days after Max's letter to <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>,
Max's son Erich sent a cable to his cousin <ent type='ORG'>Frederick</ent> M.  <ent type='GPE'>Warburg</ent>,
a director  ofthe <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent> railroad system.  He asked <ent type='ORG'>Frederick</ent>
to <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>use all your influence'' to stop all anti-<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>  activity  in
<ent type='GPE'>America</ent>,  including  <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>atrocity news and unfriendly propaganda in
foreign press, mass meetings, etc.''  <ent type='ORG'>Frederick</ent>  cabled  back  to
Erich: <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>No responsible groups here [are] urging [a] boycott [of]
<ent type='NORP'>German</ent>goods[,]  merely  excited  individuals.''  Two days after
that,  On  March  31,  1933,  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>{<ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent>-<ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish <ent type='ORG'>Committee</ent>,}
controlled  by<ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='GPE'>Warburg</ent>s,and  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>{B'nai B'rith,} heavily
influenced by <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>Sulzbergers'  ({NewYork  <ent type='ORG'>Time</ent>s}),issueda
formal,  official  joint  statement  of  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>two  organizations,
counselling  <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>that  no  <ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent>  boycott  against  <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y be
encouraged,  [and  advising] ... that no further mass meetings be
held or similar forms of agitation be employed.''s3s1</p>

<p> The <ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish <ent type='ORG'>Committee</ent> and the B'nai B'rith (mother  of
<ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='ORG'>``</ent>Anti-DefamationLeague'')  continued  with this hardline,
no-attack-on-Hitler stance all through <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>1930s,  blunting  the
fight mounted by many <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>s and other anti-fascists.</p>

<p> Thus  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>decisive interchange reproduced above, taking place
entirely within the orbit of the <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>/Bush firm, may  explain
something  of  the relationship of George Bush to <ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish
and <ent type='NORP'>Zionist</ent> leaders.  Some of them, in close cooperation with his
family, played an ugly part in the drama of <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>ism. Is this  why
<ent type='ORG'>``</ent>professional<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>-hunters'' have never discovered how the Bush
family made its money?</p>

<p> The executive board of the {<ent type='GPE'>Hamburg</ent><ent type='NORP'>Amerika</ent>  Line}{(<ent type='ORG'>Hapag</ent>)}
met  jointly with the <ent type='LOC'>North</ent> <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> Lloyd company board in <ent type='GPE'>Hamburg</ent>
on September 5, 1933. Under official <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>  supervision,  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>two
firms were  merged.  Prescott Bush's <ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent> Ship and <ent type='ORG'>Commerce</ent>
Corp.installed  <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent>  J.  <ent type='ORG'>Beck</ent>, a longtime <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>
executive,  as manager of freight and operations in <ent type='LOC'>North</ent> <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>
for  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>new  joint  <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>  shipping  lines  {(<ent type='ORG'>Hapag</ent>-Lloyd)})  on
November 4, 1933.</p>

<p> According  to  testimony  of officials of the companies before
<ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent> in 1934, a supervisor from the {<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> Labor  Front}  rode
with  every  ship of the <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>-Bush line; employees of the New
York offices were directly organized into <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>  Labor  Front
organization; <ent type='GPE'>Hamburg</ent>-<ent type='NORP'>Amerika</ent> provided free passage to
individuals going abroad for <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> propaganda  purposes;  and  the
line subsidized pro-<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> newspapers in the U.S.A., as it had done
in <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y against the constitutional <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> government.s3s2</p>

<p> In  mid-1936, Prescott Bush's <ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent> Ship and <ent type='ORG'>Commerce</ent> Corp.
cabled M.M. <ent type='GPE'>Warburg</ent>, asking <ent type='GPE'>Warburg</ent> torepresent  thecompany's
heavyshareinterest at<ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>forthcoming  <ent type='GPE'>Hamburg</ent>-<ent type='NORP'>Amerika</ent>
stockholders meeting. <ent type='ORG'>The  </ent><ent type='GPE'>Warburg</ent>  office  repliedwith  the
information  that  <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>we  represented  you''  at  the stockholders
meeting and <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>exercised on your behalf your voting power  for  <ent type='GPE'>Rm</ent>
[gold marks] 3509600 <ent type='ORG'>Hapag</ent> stock deposited with us.''</p>

<p> The <ent type='GPE'>Warburg</ent>s transmitted a  letter  received  from  Emil
Helfferich, <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> chief executive of both <ent type='ORG'>Hapag</ent>-Lloyd and of the
<ent type='ORG'>Standard</ent> Oil subsidiary in <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y: <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>It is the intention to
continue the relations with Mr.  <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent> on <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>samebasis  as
heretofore....''  In  a  colorful  gesture, <ent type='ORG'>Hapag</ent>'s <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> chairman
Helfferich sent the line's president across  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='LOC'>Atlantic</ent>  ona
Zeppelin to confer with their <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent> string-pullers.</p>

<p> After the meeting with theZeppelin  passenger,  the
<ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>-Bush office replied: <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>I  am  glad  to  learnthat  Mr.
Hellferich  [sic]  hasstated that relations between the <ent type='GPE'>Hamburg</ent>
<ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent> Line and ourselves will be continued on <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>same  basis
as heretofore.''s3s3</p>

<p> Twomonthsbefore moving against Bush's <ent type='ORG'>Union Banking Corp</ent>.,
the U.S.  government ordered the seizure of all property  of  the
<ent type='GPE'>Hamburg</ent>-<ent type='NORP'>Amerika</ent>  Line  and  <ent type='LOC'>North</ent> <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> Lloyd, under the Trading
with the Enemy Act. The investigators noted  in  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>pre-seizure
reportthat  <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent>  J.  <ent type='ORG'>Beck</ent> was still acting as an attorney
representing the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> firm.s3s4</p>

<p> In May 1933, just after the Hitler regime was consolidated, an
agreement was reached in <ent type='GPE'>Berlin</ent> for the coordination of all  <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>
commerce with the U.S.A. The {<ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent> International Co.,} led by
Averell  <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>'s  first cousin Oliver, was to head a syndicate
of 150 firms  and  individuals,  to  conduct  {all  exports  from
Hitler's <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y to <ent type='GPE'>the United <ent type='ORG'>State</ent>s</ent>}.s3s5</p>

<p> This  pact  had  been  negotiated  in  <ent type='GPE'>Berlin</ent> between Hitler's
economics minister, Hjalmar  Schacht,  and  John  Foster  <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent>,
international  attorney  for dozens of <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> enterprises, with the
counsel of Max <ent type='GPE'>Warburg</ent> and Kurt von Schroeder.</p>

<p> John Foster <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent> would later be U.S. Secretary of <ent type='ORG'>State</ent>, and
the great power in <ent type='ORG'>the <ent type='NORP'>Republican</ent> Party</ent> of  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>1950s.  Foster's
friendship  and  that  of  his brother Allen (head of the Central
Intelligence <ent type='ORG'>Agency</ent>), greatly aided Prescott Bush to  become  the
<ent type='NORP'>Republican</ent>  U.S.  senator  from  <ent type='GPE'>Connecticut</ent>. And it was to be of
inestimable value to George Bush, in his ascent to the heights of
<ent type='ORG'>``</ent>covert action government,'' that both of these <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent>  brothers
were the lawyers for the Bush family's far-flung enterprise.</p>

<p> Throughout<ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>1930s,  John  Foster  <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent>  arranged  debt
restructuring for <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> firms under a series of  decrees  issued
by  Adolf Hitler. In these deals, <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent> struck a balance between
the interest owed to selected, larger investors, and the needs of
the growing <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> warmaking apparatus for producing tanks,  poison
gas, etc.</p>

<p> <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent>  wrote  to  <ent type='ORG'>PrescottBush</ent>  in 1937 concerning one such
arrangement.  <ent type='ORG'>The  </ent><ent type='NORP'>German</ent>-<ent type='LOC'>Atlantic</ent>  Cable  Company,  owning  <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>
<ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y's  only  telegraph channel to <ent type='GPE'>the United <ent type='ORG'>State</ent>s</ent>, had made
debt and management  agreements  with  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>Walker-<ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>  bank
during <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>1920s.  A new decree would now void those agreements,
which  had  originallybeen  reached  with  non-<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>corporate
officials. <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent>  asked  Bush,  whomanaged these affairs for
<ent type='ORG'>Averell <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent></ent>, to get Averell's signature on a letter to  <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>
officials, agreeing to the changes.  <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent> wrote:</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>``</ent>Sept.  22,  1937
<ent type='ORG'>``</ent>Mr.  Prescott S. Bush
<ent type='ORG'>``</ent>59 Wall Street, New
  York, N.Y.</p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>Dear <ent type='ORG'>Press</ent>,
 <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>I have looked over the letter of <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='NORP'>German</ent>-<ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent>  [sic]
Cable  Companyto  <ent type='ORG'>Averell <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent></ent>.... It would appear that the
only rights in the matter are those which inure  in  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>bankers
and  that  no  legal  embarrassment  would  result, so far as the
bondholders  are  concerned,  by your acquiescence in the
modification of the bankers' agreement.
 <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>Sincerely yours,
 <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>John Foster <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent>''</p>

<p> <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent>  enclosed  aproposed draft reply, Bush got <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>'s
signature, and the changes went through.s3s6</p>

<p> In conjunction with these arrangements,  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='NORP'>German</ent>  <ent type='LOC'>Atlantic</ent>
Cable  Companyattempted to stop payment on its debts to smaller
<ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent> bondholders.  The money  was  to  be  used  instead  for
arming the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> state, under a decree of the Hitler government.</p>

<p> Despite  the busy efforts of Bush and <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent>, a <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent> court
decided that this particular Hitler <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>law'' was  invalid  in  the
United<ent type='ORG'>State</ent>s;  smallbondholders, not parties to deals between
the bankers and the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>s, were entitled to get paid.s3s7</p>

<p> In this anda  fewother  of  theattempted  swindles,  the
intended victims  cameout  with  their  money.  But  the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>
financial and political reorganization went ahead to  its  tragic
climax.</p>

<p> Forhis part in the Hitler revolution, Prescott Bush was paid
a fortune.</p>

<p> This is the legacy he left to his son, President George Bush.</p>

<p>Notes</p>

<p>1. Office of Alien Property Custodian, Vesting Order Number  248.
<ent type='NORP'>Signedby</ent>  Leo  T.  Crowley,  Alien Property Custodian, executed
October 20, 1942; F.R. Doc.  42-11568; Filed, November 6, 1942. 7
<ent type='ORG'>Fed</ent>. Reg. 9097 (November 7, 1942).
 The {<ent type='GPE'>New York</ent> City Directory of  Directors},  1930s-40s,  list
Prescott  Bushas  a  director  of <ent type='ORG'>Union Banking Corp</ent>. from 1934
through 1943.</p>

<p>2.
 Alien Property Custodian Vesting Order No. 259:  Seamless  Steel
Equipment Corporation; Vesting Order Number 261: <ent type='GPE'>Holland</ent>-<ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent>
Trading Corp.</p>

<p>3.  Alien Property Custodian Vesting Order No. 370:
<ent type='GPE'>Silesia</ent>n-<ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent> Corp.</p>

<p>4. {<ent type='GPE'>New York</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Time</ent>s,} December 16, 1944, ran a five-paragraph page
25 article on actions of the <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent> <ent type='ORG'>State</ent>  Banking  Department.
Only the last sentence refers to the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> bank, as follows: <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>The
Union  BankingCorporation,  39 Broadway, <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent>, has received
authority to change  its  principal  place  ofbusiness  to  120
Broadway.''
 The {<ent type='ORG'>Time</ent>s} omitted <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>factthat  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>Union  Banking
Corporation had been seized by the government  for  trading  with
<ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>enemy, and the fact that 120 Broadway was the address of the
government's Alien Property Custodian.</p>

<p>5.
 Fritz<ent type='ORG'>Thyssen</ent>,  {I  Paid  Hitler},  1941,  reprintedin  (Port
<ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, N.Y.: Kennikat  <ent type='ORG'>Press</ent>,  1972), p.  133.  <ent type='ORG'>Thyssen</ent> says
his contributions began with 100000 marks given in October 1923,
for Hitler's  attempted  <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>putsch''  against  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>constitutional
government.</p>

<p>6. Confidential  memorandum  from  U.S. Embassy, <ent type='GPE'>Berlin</ent>, to the
U.S.  Secretary  of  <ent type='ORG'>State</ent>,  April  20,  1932,on  microfilm  in
{Confidential  Reportsof  U.S. <ent type='ORG'>State</ent> Dept., 1930s, <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y,} at
major U.S.  libraries.</p>

<p>7. October 5, 1942, Memorandum to <ent type='ORG'>the Executive <ent type='ORG'>Committee</ent></ent> of  the
Officeof  Alien  Property Custodian, stamped CONFIDENTIAL, from
the Division of Investigation and Research, Homer  Jones,  Chief.
Now  declassified  in  United <ent type='ORG'>State</ent>s National Archives, Suitland,
<ent type='GPE'>Maryland</ent> annex.  <ent type='ORG'>See Record Group</ent> 131, Alien Property  Custodian,
investigative  reports,  in  file  boxrelating to Vesting Order
Number 248.</p>

<p>8. {Elimination of <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> Resources for War}: HearingsBeforea
Subcommittee  of the <ent type='ORG'>Committee</ent> on Military Affairs, United <ent type='ORG'>State</ent>s
<ent type='ORG'>Senate</ent>, Seventy-Ninth <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>; Part 5, Testimony of [<ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>United
<ent type='ORG'>State</ent>s]  <ent type='ORG'>Treasury</ent>  Department,July  2, 1945. Page 507: Table of
Vereinigte Stahlwerke output, figures are percent of <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> total
as  of1938;  <ent type='ORG'>Thyssen</ent>organization  including Union Banking
Corporation pp.  727-731.</p>

<p>9.  Robert  <ent type='ORG'>Sobel</ent>, {The Life and <ent type='ORG'>Time</ent>s of <ent type='ORG'><ent type='ORG'>Dillon</ent> Read</ent>} (<ent type='GPE'>New York</ent>:
Dutton-Penguin, 1991),pp.  92-111.<ent type='ORG'>The  </ent><ent type='ORG'><ent type='ORG'>Dillon</ent> Read</ent> firm
cooperated in the development of <ent type='ORG'>Sobel</ent>'s book.</p>

<p>10.  George  Walker  to  <ent type='ORG'>Averell <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent></ent>, August 11, 1927, in W.
<ent type='ORG'>Averell <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent></ent> papers, Library  of  <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>(hereafter  <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>WAH
papers'').</p>

<p>11. <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>Iaccarino'' to G. H. Walker, RCA Radiogram Sept. 12, 1927.</p>

<p>12. Andrew Boyle, {Montagu Norman} (<ent type='GPE'>London</ent>: Cassell, 1967).
 Sir Henry Clay, {Lord Norman} (<ent type='GPE'>London</ent>, MacMillan &amp; Co., 1957),
pp.  18, 57, 70-71.
 John  A. Kouwenhouven, {Partners in Banking ... <ent type='ORG'>Brown Brothers</ent>
<ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>} (<ent type='GPE'>Garden City</ent>: <ent type='ORG'>Doubleday</ent> &amp; Co., 1969).</p>

<p>13.
 Coordination of much of <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>Hitler  project  took  place  ata
single New  York address.  The <ent type='ORG'>Union Banking Corp</ent>oration had been
set up by  George  Walker  at  39  Broadway.  Management  of  the
<ent type='GPE'>Hamburg</ent>-<ent type='NORP'>Amerika</ent>  Line,carried  out  through <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>'s <ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent>
Ship and <ent type='ORG'>Commerce</ent> Corp., was also set up by George Walker  at  39
Broadway.</p>

<p>14.  Interrogation  of Fritz <ent type='ORG'>Thyssen</ent>, EF/Me/1 of Sept. 4, 1945 in
U.S.  <ent type='ORG'>Control Council</ent> records, photostat on page 167  in  Anthony
Sutton,  {An  Introduction  to The Order} (Billings, Mt.: Liberty
<ent type='ORG'>House</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Press</ent>, 1986).</p>

<p>15. {<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> Conspiracy and Aggression, Supplement B}, by the Office
of United  <ent type='ORG'>State</ent>s  Chief  of  Counsel  for  Prosecution  of  Axis
Criminality, U. S. Government Printing Office, (<ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, D.C.,
1948), pp.  1597, 1686.</p>

<p>16.  <ent type='ORG'>``</ent><ent type='ORG'>Consolidated <ent type='GPE'>Silesia</ent>n Steel</ent> Corporation - [minutes of the]
Meeting of <ent type='ORG'>Board</ent> of Directors,'' October 31, 1930  (WAH  papers),
shows <ent type='ORG'>Averell <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent></ent> as Chairman of the <ent type='ORG'>Board</ent>.
 Prescott  Bush  to W.A. <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>, Memorandum December 19, 1930
on their <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent> Fifteen Corp.
 Annual Report of United Konigs and <ent type='ORG'>Laura Steel</ent> and Iron  Works
for  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>year1930 (WAH papers) lists <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>Dr. Friedrich Flick ...
<ent type='GPE'>Berlin</ent>'' and <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>William <ent type='ORG'>Averell <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent></ent> ...  New  York''  on  the
<ent type='ORG'>Board</ent> of Directors.
  <ent type='ORG'>``</ent><ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>Fifteen  Coporation  Securities Position February
28, 1931,'' WAH papers.  This  report  shows<ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>  Fifteen
Corporation holding 32576 shares in <ent type='GPE'>Silesia</ent>n Holding Co.  V.T.C.
worth  (in  scarce depression dollars) $1628800, just over half
the value of the <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Fifteen Corporation</ent>'s total holdings.
 The {<ent type='GPE'>New York</ent> City Directory of  Directors}volumes  for  the
1930s  (available  at  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>Library  of  <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>)  show Prescott
Sheldon Bush and  W.Averell  <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>  as  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>directors  of
<ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent> Fifteen Corp.
 <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>Appointments,''  (three  typed  pages) marked <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>Noted May 18
1931 W.A.H.,'' (among the papers from <ent type='ORG'>PrescottBush</ent>'sNew  York
Officeof  <ent type='ORG'><ent type='ORG'>Brown Brothers</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent></ent>, WAH papers), lists a meeting
between <ent type='ORG'>Averell <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent></ent> and Friedrich Flick in  <ent type='GPE'>Berlin</ent>  at  4:00
P.M., Wednesday April 22, 1931.  This was followed immediately by
a meeting with Wilhelm Cuno, chief executive  of  the
<ent type='GPE'>Hamburg</ent>-<ent type='NORP'>Amerika</ent> Line.
 The <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>Report To  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>Stockholders  of  the<ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>  Fifteen
Corporation,'' October19,  1933 (WAH papers) names G.H.  Walker
as president of the corporation.  It shows the<ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>  Fifteen
Corp.'s address as 1 Wall Street--the location of G.H. Walker and
Co.</p>

<p>17.  {<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>  Conspiracy and Aggression, Supplement B}, {op. cit.,}
p.  1686.</p>

<p>18. Jim Flaherty (a <ent type='ORG'>BBH</ent> manager, Prescott Bush's employee), March
19, 1934 to W.A. <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>.
 <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>Dear Averell:
 <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>In Roland's absence <ent type='ORG'>Pres[cott</ent>] thought it adviseable for  me
to  let  you  know that we received the following cable from [our
<ent type='LOC'>Europe</ent>an representative] Rossidated  March  17th  [relating  to
conflict with the <ent type='NORP'>Polish</ent> government]....''</p>

<p>19.  <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>  <ent type='ORG'>Fifteen Corporation</ent> notice to stockholders January
7, 1935, under the name of George Walker, President.</p>

<p>20. Order No. 370: <ent type='GPE'>Silesia</ent>n-<ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent> Corp. Executed November  17,
1942. Signed by Leo T. Crowley, Alien Prop. Custodian.F.R. Doc.
42-14183;  Filed,  December  31,  1942;  8  <ent type='ORG'>Fed</ent>. Reg. 33 (Jan. 1,
1943).
 The order confiscated the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>s' holdings of 98000 shares  of
common and 50000 shares of preferred stock in <ent type='GPE'>Silesia</ent>n-<ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent>.
 The<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>  parent company in Breslau, <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y wrote to Averell
<ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent> at 59 Wall St. on Aug. 5, 1940, with <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>an invitation  to
take part  in  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>regular  meetingof  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>members  of  the
Bergwerksgesellsc[h]aft  Georgvon  Giesche'sErben....'' WAH
papers.</p>

<p>21.  Sept. 25, 1942, Memorandum To <ent type='ORG'>the Executive <ent type='ORG'>Committee</ent></ent> of the
Office of Alien Property Custodian,  stamped  CONFIDENTIAL,  from
<ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>Division  of Investigation and Research, Homer Jones, Chief.
Now declassified in United <ent type='ORG'>State</ent>s  National  Archives,Suitland,
<ent type='GPE'>Maryland</ent> annex. <ent type='ORG'>See Record Group</ent> 131, Alien Property Custodian,
investigative reports, in filebox  relating  to  Vesting  Order
Number 370.</p>

<p>22.  George  Walker  was a director of <ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent> Ship and <ent type='ORG'>Commerce</ent>
from its  organizationthrough  1928.Consult  {New  York  City
<ent type='ORG'>Directory of Directors</ent>}.
 <ent type='ORG'>``</ent><ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>  FifteenCorporation  Securities Position February
28, 1931,'' {op. cit.} The report  lists  46861  shares  in  the
<ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent> Ship &amp; <ent type='ORG'>Commerce</ent> Corp.
 See<ent type='ORG'>``</ent>Message  from  Mr. Bullfin,'' August 30, 1934 (<ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>
Fifteen section, WAH papers) for the joint  supervision  of  Bush
and Walker,respectively director and  president  of  the
corporation.</p>

<p>23. Cuno was later exposed by  Walter  <ent type='ORG'>Funk</ent>,  Third  Reich  <ent type='ORG'>Press</ent>
Chief  and  Under Secretary of <ent type='ORG'>Propaganda</ent>, in <ent type='ORG'>Funk</ent>'s postwar jail
cell at <ent type='GPE'>Nuremberg</ent>; but Cuno had died just as  Hitler  was  taking
power. William  L.  Shirer, L., {The Rise and Fall of the Third
Reich} (<ent type='GPE'>New York</ent>: Simon and Schuster, 1960),  p.  144.  {<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>
Conspiracy and Aggression, Supplement B}, {op. cit.,} p.  1688.</p>

<p>24.  See <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>Elimination of <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> Resources for War,'' {op. cit.,}
pages 881-882 on Voegler.
 SeeAnnualReport of  the
(<ent type='GPE'>Hamburg</ent>-<ent type='NORP'>Amerika</ent>nische-Packetfahrt-Aktien-Gesel  <ent type='ORG'>schaft</ent> (<ent type='ORG'>Hapag</ent> or
<ent type='GPE'>Hamburg</ent>-<ent type='NORP'>Amerika</ent> Line), March 1931, for the board of directors.A
copy is in the <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent> <ent type='ORG'>PublicLibrary</ent>  Annexat  11th  Avenue,
<ent type='GPE'>Manhattan</ent>.</p>

<p>25.  {<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>  Conspiracy and Aggression--Supplement B,} {op. cit.,}
pp.  1178, 1453-1454, 1597, 1599.
  See <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>Elimination of <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> Resources for War,'' {op.  cit.,}
pp.  870-72 on Schroeder; p.  730 on Groeninger.</p>

<p>26. Annual Report of <ent type='GPE'>Hamburg</ent>-<ent type='NORP'>Amerika</ent>, {op. cit.}
 Baron Rudolph Schroeder, Sr. to <ent type='ORG'>Averell <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent></ent>, November 14,
1932.  K[night] W[ooley] handwritten note and draft reply letter,
December 9, 1932.
 In  his  letter, Baron Rudolph refers to the family's <ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent>
affiliate, J. Henry Schroder [name anglicized],  of  which  Allen
<ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent> was a director, and his brother John Foster <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent> was the
principal attorney.
 Baron Bruno Schroder of the <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> branch was adviser to Bank
of  <ent type='GPE'>England</ent>  Governor  MontaguNorman, and Baron Bruno's partner
Frank Cyril Tiarks  was  Norman's  co-directorof  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>Bank  of
<ent type='GPE'>England</ent> throughout  Norman's  career. Kurt  von  Schroeder was
Hjalmar  Schacht's  delegate  to  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>Bank for International
Settlements  in  <ent type='GPE'>Geneva</ent>, where many of the financial arrangements
for the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> regime were made by Montagu Norman, Schacht and  the
Schroeders for several years of the Hitler regime right up to the
outbreak of World War II.</p>

<p>27.
 Confidential memorandum from U.S.  Embassy, <ent type='GPE'>Berlin</ent>, {op. cit.}</p>

<p>28.  U.S.  <ent type='ORG'>Senate</ent> <ent type='ORG'>``</ent><ent type='ORG'>Nye <ent type='ORG'>Committee</ent></ent>'' hearings, Sept. 14, 1934, pp.
1197-1198, extracts from letters of Col. William N. Taylor, dated
June 27, 1932 and January 9, 1933.</p>

<p>29. <ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent> Ship and <ent type='ORG'>Commerce</ent> Corporation to  Dr.  Max  <ent type='GPE'>Warburg</ent>,
March 7, 1933.
 Max<ent type='GPE'>Warburg</ent>  had  brokered<ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>sale  of  <ent type='GPE'>Hamburg</ent>-<ent type='NORP'>Amerika</ent> to
<ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent> and Walker in 1920. Max's brothers controlled<ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>Kuhn
Loeb  investment  banking  house  in <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent>, the firm which had
staked old E.H. <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent> to his 1890s buyout of <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>giant  Union
<ent type='LOC'>Pacific</ent> Railroad.
 Max <ent type='GPE'>Warburg</ent> had long worked with Lord Milner and others of the
racialist <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> Round Table concerning joint projects in <ent type='LOC'>Africa</ent>
and <ent type='LOC'>East</ent>ern  <ent type='LOC'>Europe</ent>.He  was an advisor to Hjalmar Schacht for
several decades and was a top executive of  Hitler's  <ent type='ORG'>Reichsbank</ent>.
<ent type='ORG'>The  </ent>reader may consult David Farrer, {The <ent type='GPE'>Warburg</ent>s: The Story of
A Family} (<ent type='GPE'>New York</ent>: Stein and Day, 1975).</p>

<p>30. Max <ent type='GPE'>Warburg</ent>, at M.M. <ent type='GPE'>Warburg</ent> and  Co.,  <ent type='GPE'>Hamburg</ent>,  to  Averill
[sic]  <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>,  c/o  Messrs.<ent type='ORG'><ent type='ORG'>Brown Brothers</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent></ent> &amp; Co., 59
Wall Street, <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent>, N.Y., March 27, 1933.</p>

<p>31. This correspondence, and the joint statement  of  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish
organizations,are  reproduced  in  <ent type='GPE'>Moshe</ent> R. Gottlieb, {<ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent>
Anti-<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> Resistance, 1933-41: An Historical Analysis} (<ent type='GPE'>New York</ent>:
Ktav Publishing <ent type='ORG'>House</ent>, 1982).</p>

<p>32. {Investigation of <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Propaganda</ent>Activities  and
Investigation  of  Certain  Other  <ent type='ORG'>Propaganda</ent> Activities}: Public
Hearings before  A  Subcommittee  of  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>Special  <ent type='ORG'>Committee</ent>  on
Un-<ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent>  Activities,  United <ent type='ORG'>State</ent>s <ent type='ORG'>House</ent> of Representatives,
Seventy Third <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent> City, July 9-12,  1934--Hearings
No. 73-<ent type='GPE'>NY</ent>-7 (<ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, D.C., U.S. Govt. Printing Office, 1934).
See testimony of Capt. <ent type='ORG'>Frederick</ent> C. <ent type='ORG'>Mensing</ent>, John Schroeder, Paul
von Lilienfeld-Toal, and summaries by <ent type='ORG'>Committee</ent> members.
 See {<ent type='GPE'>New York</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Time</ent>s,} July 16, 1933, p.  12, for organizing of
<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> Labor Front at <ent type='LOC'>North</ent> <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> Lloyd, leading  to
<ent type='GPE'>Hamburg</ent>-<ent type='NORP'>Amerika</ent> after merger.</p>

<p>33. <ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent> Ship and <ent type='ORG'>Commerce</ent> Corporation  telegram  to  Rudolph
Brinckmann at M.M. <ent type='GPE'>Warburg</ent>, June 12, 1936.
 Rudolph  Brinckmannto  <ent type='ORG'>Averell <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent></ent> at 59 Wall St., June
20, 1936, with enclosed note transmitting Helferrich's letter.
 Reply to Dr. Rudolph Brinkmann c/o M.M. <ent type='GPE'>Warburg</ent> andCo,  July
6, 1936,  WAH  papers.  The file copy of this letter carries no
signature, but is presumably from <ent type='ORG'>Averell <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent></ent>.</p>

<p>34. Office of Alien Property Custodian, Vesting Order Number 126.
Signed by Leo T.  Crowley,  Alien  Property  Custodian,  executed
August 28,  1942.  F.R.  Doc.42-8774; Filed September 4, 1942,
10:55 A.M.; 7 F.R. 7061 (Number 176, Sept. 5, 1942.)
 July 18, 1942, Memorandum To the Executive  <ent type='ORG'>Committee</ent>  of  the
Officeof  Alien  Property Custodian, stamped CONFIDENTIAL, from
the Division of Investigation and Research, Homer  Jones,  Chief.
Now  declassified  in  United <ent type='ORG'>State</ent>s National Archives, Suitland,
<ent type='GPE'>Maryland</ent> annex.  <ent type='ORG'>See Record Group</ent> 131, Alien Property  Custodian,
investigative  reports,  in  file  boxrelating to Vesting Order
Number 126.</p>

<p>35. {<ent type='GPE'>New York</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Time</ent>s,} May 20, 1933.  Leading up to this agreement
is a  telegramwhich  somehowescaped  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>shredder.  It  is
addressed  to  <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>  official  <ent type='ORG'>HjalmarSchacht</ent>  at the Mayflower
Hotel, <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, dated May 11,  1933:  <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>Much  disappointed  to
have missed  seeing  you  Tueday afternoon....I hope to see you
either in <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent> or <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent> before you sail.
 with my regards W.A. <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>'' (WAH papers).</p>

<p>36. <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent> to Bush, letter and draft reply in WAH papers.</p>

<p>37. {<ent type='GPE'>New York</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Time</ent>s,} Jan. 19, 1938.</p>

<p>Any comments, please send by email, as I get very far  behind  on
this group.</p>

<p>Thanks.</p>

<p> John Covici</p>

<p>coviciccs.covici.com</p>

<p>Article 15394 of alt.activism:
From: covici@ccs.covici.com (John Covici)
<ent type='GPE'>Newsgroups</ent>: alt.activism
Subject: Part 3: George bush Unauthorized Biography
<info type="Message-ID"> 1VVReB1w164w@ccs.covici.com</info>
Date: 19 Jan 92 01:12:47 GMT
Organization: Covici Computer Systems
Lines: 1544</p>

<p>The following is  part 3 of an unauthorized biography of George Bush
-- a forthcoming book serialized in <ent type='ORG'>New <ent type='ORG'>Fed</ent>eralist</ent>.  This article is
from Issue 1 V6.</p>

<p>For further information, or to subscribe, please contact me by
e-mail.</p>

<p>Chapter  3  RACE  HYGIENE:  Three  Bush  Family  Alliances  <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>The
[government] must put  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>most  modern  medical  means  in  the
service of  this  knowledge....  Those  who  are physically and
mentally  unhealthy  and  unworthy  must  not  perpetuate their
suffering in  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>body  of their children....The prevention of
the faculty and opportunity toprocreate  on  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>part  of  the
physically  degenerateand  mentally sick, over a period of only
600  years,  would  ...  free  humanity  froman immeasurable
misfortune.''s1</p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>``</ent><ent type='ORG'>The  </ent>per  capita  income  gap  between the developed and the
developing countries is increasing, in large part <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>result  of
higher birth  rates in the poorer countries....  Famine in <ent type='GPE'>India</ent>,
unwanted babies in <ent type='GPE'>the United <ent type='ORG'>State</ent>s</ent>, poverty that seemed to form
an unbreakable chain for millions of people--how should we tackle
these problems?....  It is quite clearthat  one  of  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>major
challenges  of<ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>1970s  ...  will  be  to  curb  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>world's
fertility.''</p>

<p>These two quotations are alike in their mock show of concern  for
human  suffering, and in their cynical remedy for it: Big Brother
must  prevent  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='ORG'>``</ent>unworthy''  or  <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>unwanted''  people from
living.
 <ent type='ORG'>Letus</ent>  now further inquire into the family background of our
President, so as to help illustrate how the second quoted author,
{George Bush}s1 came to share the outlook of  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>first,  {Adolf
Hitler}.s2
 We  shall  examine  here  the alliance of the Bush family with
three other families: {Farish, <ent type='ORG'>Draper</ent>} and {<ent type='ORG'>Gray</ent>.}
 The private associations among these families have led to  the
President's relationship  tohis  closest,  most  confidential
advisers.  These alliances were  forged  in  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>earlier  Hitler
project and  its  immediate  aftermath. Understanding them will
help us to explain George  Bush's  obsession  with  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>supposed
overpopulation of the world's non-Anglo-<ent type='NORP'>Saxon</ent>s, and the dangerous
means he has adopted to deal with this <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>problem.''</p>

<p>Bush and Farish</p>

<p> When  George  Bush  was  elected vice president in 1980, <ent type='GPE'>Texas</ent>
mystery man William Stamps Farish III took over management of all
of George Bush's personal wealth in a <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>blind trust.''Known  as
one  of  the richest men in <ent type='GPE'>Texas</ent>, Will Farish keeps his business
affairs under the most intense secrecy.  Only the source  of  his
immense wealth is known, not its employment.s3
 Will Farish has long  been  Bush's  closest  friend  and
confidante.  He is also <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>unique  private  host  to<ent type='GPE'>Britain</ent>'s
Queen Elizabeth: Farish owns and boards the studs which mate with
the Queen's  mares. That is her public rationale when she comes
to <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> and stays in Farish's house.  It is a  vital  link  in
the mind of our <ent type='NORP'>Anglophile</ent> President.
 President  Bush  can count on Farish not to betray the violent
secrets surrounding the Bush family  money.  For  Farish's  own
familyfortune  was  made  in<ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>same  Hitler  project,  in a
nightmarish partnership with George Bush's father.</p>

<p> On March 25, 1942, U.S.  Assistant  Attorney  General  Thurman
Arnoldannounced  that William Stamps Farish (grandfather of the
President's money manager) had pleaded <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>no contest'' to  charges
of  criminal  conspiracy with the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>s. Farish was the principal
manager of a worldwide cartel between <ent type='ORG'>Standard</ent>Oil  Co.  of  New
Jersey and  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>I.G.  <ent type='ORG'>Farben</ent> concern.The merged enterprise had
opened the <ent type='ORG'>Auschwitz</ent> slave  labor  camp  on  June  141940,  to
produce artificial  rubber  and  gasoline  from coal.  The Hitler
government supplied political opponents and <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>s as  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>slaves,
who were worked to near death and then murdered.
 Arnold  disclosed that <ent type='ORG'>Standard</ent> Oil of <ent type='GPE'>New Jersey</ent> (later known
as <ent type='ORG'>Exxon</ent>), of which Farish was president and chief executive, had
agreedto  stop  hiding  from<ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>United  <ent type='ORG'>State</ent>s  patents  for
artificial rubber which the company had provided to the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>s.s4
 A  <ent type='ORG'>Senate</ent>  investigating  committeeunder Senator (later U.S.
President) Harry Truman of <ent type='GPE'>Missouri</ent> had called Arnold to  testify
at  hearings  on  corporations' collaboration with the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>s. The
Senators  expressed  outrage  at  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>cynicalway  Farish was
continuing an alliance with the Hitler regime that had begun back
in  1933,  when Farish became chief of Jersey <ent type='ORG'>Standard</ent>. Didn't he
know there was a war on?
 <ent type='ORG'>The Justice Department</ent> laid before  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>committee  a  letter,
written  to  <ent type='ORG'>Standard</ent>  president  Farish  by  his vice president,
shortly after the beginning of World War II (September1,  1939)
in  <ent type='LOC'>Europe</ent>.  <ent type='ORG'>The  </ent>letter  concerned  <ent type='GPE'>arenewal</ent>  of their earlier
agreements with the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>s:</p>

<p>Report on  <ent type='LOC'>Europe</ent>an  Trip  Oct.  12,  1939  Mr.  W.S.  Farish  30
<ent type='ORG'>Rockefeller</ent> Plaza</p>

<p> Dear Mr. Farish:
  ...  I stayed in <ent type='GPE'>France</ent> until Sept. 17th.... In <ent type='GPE'>England</ent> I met
by appointment the Royal <ent type='NORP'>Dutch</ent> [<ent type='ORG'>Shell</ent>  Oil  Co.]  gentlemen  from
<ent type='GPE'>Holland</ent>, and ... a general agreement was reached on the necessary
changes  in  our relations with the I.G. [<ent type='ORG'>Farben</ent>], in view of the
state of war....  [T]he Royal <ent type='NORP'>Dutch</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Shell</ent>  group  is  essentially
<ent type='NORP'>British</ent>....  <ent type='ORG'>Ialso</ent>  had several meetings with ... the [<ent type='NORP'>British</ent>]
Air Ministry....
 I required help to obtain the necessary permission  to  go  to
<ent type='GPE'>Holland</ent>....  After  discussions  with  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>[<ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent>] Ambassador
[Joseph Kennedy] the situation was cleared  completely....  The
gentlemen  in  <ent type='ORG'>the Air Ministry</ent> ... very kindly offered to assist
me [later] in reentering <ent type='GPE'>England</ent>....
 Pursuant  to  thesearrangements,  I  was  able  to  keep  my
appointments  in  <ent type='GPE'>Holland</ent>  [having flown there on a <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> Royal
<ent type='ORG'>Air Force</ent> bomber], where I had three days of discussion with  the
representatives  of I.G. They delivered to me assignments of some
2000 foreign patents and {we did our best to work  out  complete
plans for a modus <ent type='ORG'>vivendi</ent> which could operate through the term of
the war, whether or not the U.S. came in....} [emphasis added]
 Very truly yours, <ent type='ORG'>F[rank</ent>] A.  Howards5</p>

<p> Here  are  some cold realities behind the tragedy of World War
II, which help explain the Bush-Farish family alliance--and their
peculiar closeness to the Queen of <ent type='GPE'>England</ent>:
 sb|<ent type='ORG'>Shell</ent>  Oil  is  principally  owned  by  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='NORP'>British</ent>  Royal
family. <ent type='ORG'>Shell</ent>'s  chairman,  Sir Henri Deterding, helped sponsor
Hitler's rise to power,s6 by arrangement with the Royal  Family's
Bank  of  <ent type='GPE'>England</ent>  Governor, Montagu Norman. Their ally, <ent type='ORG'>Standard</ent>
Oil, would take part in  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>Hitler  project  right  up  to  the
bloody, gruesome end.
 sb|When  grandfather  Farish  signed  <ent type='ORG'>the Justice Department</ent>'s
consent decree in March 1942, the government had already  started
picking its way through the tangled web of world-monopoly oil and
chemical  agreements  between  <ent type='ORG'>Standard</ent>  Oil  and the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>s. Many
patents and other <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>-owned aspects of the partnership had  been
seized by the U.S. Alien Property Custodian.
 Uncle  Sam  would  not  seize  Prescott  Bush's  Union Banking
Corporation for another seven months.
 The Bush-Farish axis had begun back in 1929. In that year, the
<ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent> bank bought <ent type='ORG'>Dresser Industries</ent>, supplier of oil-pipeline
couplers to <ent type='ORG'>Standard</ent> and other companies.  Prescott Bush became a
director and financialczar  of  Dresser,  installinghis  <ent type='ORG'>Yale</ent>
classmate Neil Mallon as chairman.s7 George Bush would later name
one of his sons after the Dresser executive.
 William S. Farish was the main organizer of <ent type='ORG'>the Humble Oil Co</ent>.
of  <ent type='GPE'>Texas</ent>,  which  Farish merged into the <ent type='ORG'>Standard</ent> Oil Company of
<ent type='GPE'>New Jersey</ent>. Farish  built  up  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>Humble-<ent type='ORG'>Standard</ent>  empire  of
pipelines and refineries in <ent type='GPE'>Texas</ent>.s8
 Thestock  market crashed just after the Bush family got into
the oil business.  The world financial crisis led to  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>merger
of  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>Walker-<ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent> bank with <ent type='ORG'>Brown Brothers</ent> in 1931. Former
Brown partner Montagu Norman and his protege Hjalmar Schacht, who
was to become Hitler's economics minister, paid frantic visits to
<ent type='GPE'>New York</ent> that year and the next, preparing the new Hitler  regime
for <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y.</p>

<p>The <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent> on Eugenics</p>

<p> The mostimportant <ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent>  political  eventin  those
preparations for Hitler  was  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>infamous  Third  International
<ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>  on  Eugenics,  held  at  NewYork's <ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent> Museum of
Natural  History  August 21-23, 1932, supervised by the
International  <ent type='ORG'>Fed</ent>eration  of  Eugenics Societies.s9 This meeting
took up the stubborn persistence of <ent type='NORP'><ent type='LOC'>Africa</ent>n</ent>-<ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent>s  and  other
allegedly  <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>inferior''  and  <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>socially  inadequate''groups in
reproducing, expanding their numbers, and  <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>amalgamating''  with
others. It  was  recommendedthat  these  <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>dangers''  to  the
<ent type='ORG'>``</ent>better'' ethnic groups and to the <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>well-born,'' could be dealt
with by sterilization or <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>cutting off <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>bad  stock''  of  the
<ent type='ORG'>``</ent>unfit.''
 <ent type='GPE'>Italy</ent>'s  fascist  government  sent an official representative.
<ent type='ORG'>Averell <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent></ent>'s sister Mary, director of <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>entertainment'' for
the <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>, lived down in  <ent type='GPE'>Virginia</ent>  fox-hunting  country;  her
state  supplied  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>speaker on <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>racial purity,'' W.A. <ent type='ORG'>Plecker</ent>,
<ent type='GPE'>Virginia</ent> commissioner of vital statistics.  <ent type='ORG'>Plecker</ent>  reportedly
held the delegates spellbound with his account of the struggle to
stop race-mixing and interracial sex in <ent type='GPE'>Virginia</ent>.
 The<ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent> proceedings were dedicated to <ent type='ORG'>Averell <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent></ent>'s
mother; she  had  paidfor  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>founding  of<ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>race-science
movement  in  <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>  back in 1910, building the Eugenics Record
Office as a branch of <ent type='ORG'>the Galton National Laboratory</ent>  in  <ent type='GPE'>London</ent>.
She  and other <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>s were usually escorted to the horse races
by old George Herbert Walker--they shared with the Bushes and the
Farishes a  fascination  with  <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>breeding  thoroughbreds''  among
horses and humans.s1s0
 Averell  <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>  personally  arranged  with  the Walker/Bush
<ent type='GPE'>Hamburg</ent>-<ent type='NORP'>Amerika</ent> Line to transport <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> ideologues from <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y to
<ent type='GPE'>New York</ent> for  this  meeting.s1s1  <ent type='ORG'>The  </ent>most  famous  among  those
transported  was  Dr.  Ernst  Rudin,  psychiatrist  at the Kaiser
Wilhelm Institute for Genealogy and Demography in  <ent type='GPE'>Berlin</ent>,  where
the <ent type='ORG'>Rockefeller</ent>  family  paid  for Dr.Rudin to occupy an entire
floor with his eugenics <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>research.'' Dr. Rudin had addressed the
International  <ent type='ORG'>Fed</ent>eration's  1928  <ent type='GPE'>Munich</ent>  meeting,  speaking  on
<ent type='ORG'>``</ent>Mental Aberration and Race Hygiene,'' while others (<ent type='NORP'>German</ent>s and
<ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent>s)  spoke  on race-mixing and sterilization of the unfit.
Rudin had led the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> delegation to <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>1930  Mental  Hygiene
<ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent> in <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, D.C.
 At the <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>s' 1932 <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent> Eugenics <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>, Ernst Rudin
was unanimously elected President of the International <ent type='ORG'>Fed</ent>eration
of  Eugenics  Societies. This was recognition of Rudin as founder
of the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Society</ent> for  Race  Hygiene,  with  his  co-founder,
Eugenics <ent type='ORG'>Fed</ent>eration vice president Alfred Ploetz.
 As  depression-maddened  financiersschemed in <ent type='GPE'>Berlin</ent> and New
York, Rudin  was  now  official  leader  of  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>world  eugenics
movement. Componentsof  his  movement  included  groups  with
overlapping leadership, dedicated to:
 sb|sterilization  of mental patients (<ent type='ORG'>``</ent>mental hygiene
societies'');
 sb|execution  of  the insane, criminals and the terminally ill
(<ent type='ORG'>``</ent>euthanasia societies''); and
 sb|eugenical race-purification  by  prevention  of  births  to
parents  from  inferior blood stocks (<ent type='ORG'>``</ent>birth control
societies'').</p>

<p> Before the <ent type='ORG'>Auschwitz</ent> death camp became a household word, these
<ent type='NORP'>British</ent>-<ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent>-<ent type='LOC'>Europe</ent>an groups called openly for  the
elimination  of  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='ORG'>``</ent>unfit''  by  means  including  force  and
violence.s1s2
 Ten months later, in June  1933,  Hitler's  interior  minister
Wilhelm Frick spoke to a eugenics meeting in the new Third Reich.
Frick  called  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='NORP'>German</ent>s  a<ent type='ORG'>``</ent>degenerate''race,  denouncing
one-fifth of <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y's parentsfor  producing<ent type='ORG'>``</ent>feeble-minded''
and <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>defective'' children.  The following month, on a commission
by  Frick,  Dr. Ernst Rudin wrote the <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>Law for the Prevention of
Hereditary Diseases in Posterity,'' the sterilization law modeled
on previous U.S. statutes in <ent type='GPE'>Virginia</ent> and other states.
 Special courts were soon established for the sterilization  of
<ent type='NORP'>German</ent> mental  patients,  the blind, the deaf, and alcoholics.A
quarter million  people  in  these  categorieswere  sterilized.
Rudin, Ploetz, and their colleagues trained a whole generation of
physicians and psychiatrists--as sterilizers and as killers.
 When <ent type='NORP'>thewar</ent> started, <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>eugenicists,  doctors,  and
psychiatrists staffed the new <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>T4'' agency,  which  planned  and
supervised  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>mass  killings: first at <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>euthanasia centers,''
where <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>same  categories  which  had  firstbeen  subject  to
sterilization  were now to be murdered, their brains sent in lots
of 200 to experimental psychiatrists; then at slave camps such as
<ent type='ORG'>Auschwitz</ent>; and finally, for  <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>s  andother  race  victims,  at
straight  extermination  <ent type='ORG'>campsin</ent>  <ent type='GPE'>Poland</ent>, such as Treblinka and
Belsen.s1s3
 In 1933, as what Hitler called  his<ent type='ORG'>``</ent>New  Order''appeared,
John D. <ent type='ORG'>Rockefeller</ent>,Jr.  appointedWilliam  S.  Farish the
chairman of <ent type='ORG'>Standard</ent> Oil Co.  of <ent type='GPE'>New Jersey</ent> (in 1937 he was  made
president and  chief  executive).  Farish  moved his offices to
<ent type='ORG'>Rockefeller</ent> Center, <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent>, where he spent a good deal of  time
with Hermann Schmitz, chairman of I.G. <ent type='ORG'>Farben</ent>; his company paid a
publicity man,Ivy  Lee,  to write pro-I.G.  <ent type='ORG'>Farben</ent> and pro-<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>
propaganda and get it into the U.S. press.
 Now that he was outside of <ent type='GPE'>Texas</ent>, Farish found himself in  the
shipping business--like  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>Bush  family.  He hired <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>
crews for <ent type='ORG'>Standard</ent> Oil tankers.  And he hired {Emil  Helfferich,}
chairman  of  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>Walker/Bush/<ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>  <ent type='GPE'>Hamburg</ent>-<ent type='NORP'>Amerika</ent> Line, as
chairman also of the <ent type='ORG'>Standard</ent> Oil Company subsidiary in  <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y.
Karl  Lindemann,  board  member of <ent type='GPE'>Hamburg</ent>-<ent type='NORP'>Amerika</ent>, also became a
top Farish-<ent type='ORG'>Standard</ent> executive in <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y.s1s4
 This interlock between their <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> operations put Farish
together with Prescott Bush ina  small,  select  group  of  men
operating from  abroad  through  Hitler's  <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>revolution,''  and
calculating that they would never be punished.
 In 1939, Farish's daughter Martha married  Averell  <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>'s
nephew, Edward <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent> Gerry, and Farish in-laws became Prescott
Bush's partners at 59 Broadway.s1s5
 Both  Emil  Helfferich  andKarl Lindemann were authorized to
write checks to Heinrich Himmler, chief of  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>  <ent type='ORG'>SS</ent>,  ona
special <ent type='ORG'>Standard</ent>  Oil  account. This account was managed by the
<ent type='NORP'>German</ent>-<ent type='NORP'>British</ent>-<ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent> banker, Kurt von Schroeder. According  to
U.S. intelligence  documents reviewed by author Anthony Sutton,
Helfferich continued his payments to the <ent type='ORG'>SS</ent> into 1944,when  the
<ent type='ORG'>SS</ent>  was  supervising  the mass murder at the <ent type='ORG'>Standard</ent>-I.G. <ent type='ORG'>Farben</ent>
<ent type='ORG'>Auschwitz</ent> and  other  death  camps.  Helfferich told <ent type='ORG'>Allied</ent>
interrogators  after  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>warthat  these were not his personal
contributions--they were corporate <ent type='ORG'>Standard</ent> Oil funds.s1s6
 After  pleading  <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>no  contest''  to charges of criminal
conspiracy  with  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>s,  WilliamStampsFarishwas fined
$5000. (Similar fines were levied against  <ent type='ORG'>Standard</ent>  Oil--$5000
each  for  the parent company and for several subsidiaries.) This
of course did not interfere with <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>millionsof  dollars  that
<ent type='ORG'>Farishhad</ent> acquired in conjunction with Hitler's New Order, as a
large stockholder, chairman, and president of <ent type='ORG'>Standard</ent>Oil.  All
<ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>government  sought  was the use of patents which his company
had given to the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>s--the <ent type='ORG'>Auschwitz</ent> patents--but  had  withheld
from the U.S. military and industry.
 Buta  warwas  on, and if young men were to be asked to die
fighting Hitler something more was needed.  Farish  was  hauled
before<ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='ORG'>Senate</ent>  committee investigating the national defense
program.  The committee  chairman,  Senator  Harry  Truman,  told
newsmen  before  Farish  testified:  <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>I  think  this  approaches
treason.''s1s7
 Farish began breaking apart at these hearings.  He shouted his
<ent type='ORG'>``</ent>indignation''  at  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>senators,  and  claimed  hewas not
<ent type='ORG'>``</ent>disloyal.''
 After  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>March-April hearings ended, more dirt came gushing
out of <ent type='ORG'>the Justice Department</ent> and  the<ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>  on  Farish  and
<ent type='ORG'>Standard</ent>  Oil.<ent type='ORG'>Farishhad</ent> deceived the U.S. <ent type='ORG'>Navy</ent> to prevent the
<ent type='ORG'>Navy</ent> from acquiring certain patents, while supplying them to  the
<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>  war  machine;  meanwhile,  he  was  supplying  gasoline and
tetraethyl  lead  to  <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y's submarines and air force.
Communications between <ent type='ORG'>Standard</ent> and I.G. <ent type='ORG'>Farben</ent> from the outbreak
of  World  WarII  were  released  to<ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='ORG'>Senate</ent>, showing that
Farish's organization had arranged to deceive the U.S. government
into passing over <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>-owned assets:  They  would  nominally  buy
I.G.'sshare  in  certain  patents because <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>in the event of war
between ourselves and <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y ...  it  would  certainly  be  very
undesireable  to  havethis  20 percent <ent type='ORG'>Standard</ent>-I.G. pass to an
alien property custodian of the U.S. who  might  sell  it  to  an
unfriendly interest.''s1s8
 John  D.  <ent type='ORG'>Rockefeller</ent>,  Jr. (father of David, Nelson, and John
D.  <ent type='ORG'>Rockefeller</ent> III), the controlling owner of <ent type='ORG'>Standard</ent> Oil, told
<ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>Rooseveltadministrationthat  he  knewnothing  of the
day-to-day  affairs  of  his company, that all these matters were
handled by Farish and other executives.s1s9
 In August, Farish was brought back for more testimony.  He was
now frequently accused of lying.  Farish was  crushed  under  the
intense, public grilling;  he  became  morose,  ashen.  While
Prescott Bush escaped publicity when <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>government  seized  his
<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> banking organization in October, Farish had been nailed.  He
collapsed and died of a heart attack on November 29, 1942.
 The Farish family was devastated by the exposure.  Son William
StampsFarish,  Jr.,  a  lieutenant  in  <ent type='ORG'>the <ent type='ORG'>Army</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Air Force</ent></ent>, was
humiliated by the public knowledge that his  father  was  fueling
the enemy's aircraft; he died in a training accident in <ent type='GPE'>Texas</ent> six
months later.s2s0
 With  this  double  death,  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>fortune  comprising  much  of
<ent type='ORG'>Standard</ent> Oil's profits from <ent type='GPE'>Texas</ent> and <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y was now to  be
settled upon the littlefour-year-old  grandson,  William
(<ent type='ORG'>``</ent>Will'') Stamps Farish III. Will Farish grew up a recluse,  the
most  secretive  multimillionaire  in  <ent type='GPE'>Texas</ent>, with investments of
<ent type='ORG'>``</ent>that money'' in a multitude of foreign countries, and a host of
exoticcontacts  overlapping  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>intelligence  andfinancial
worlds--particularly in <ent type='GPE'>Britain</ent>.
 The Bush-Farish  axis started George Bush's career.After his
1948 graduation  from  <ent type='ORG'>Yale</ent>  (and  the<ent type='ORG'>Skull</ent>  and  Bones  secret
society),  George  Bush flew down to <ent type='GPE'>Texas</ent> on a corporate jet and
was employed by his father's <ent type='ORG'>Dresser Industries</ent>. In a  couple  of
years  he  gothelp  from  his  uncle,  George  Walker, Jr., and
Farish's <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> banker  friends,  to  set  him  up  in  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>oil
property speculation  business.  Soon  thereafter,  George Bush
founded the Zapata Oil Company, which put oil drilling rigs  into
certain locations of great strategic interest to  the
Anglo-<ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent> intelligence community.
 Twenty-five-year-old Will Farish was personal aide  to  Zapata
chairman  George  Bushin  Bush's unsuccessful 1964 campaign for
<ent type='ORG'>Senate</ent>. Farish used <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>that <ent type='ORG'>Auschwitz</ent> money'' to back George  Bush
financially,  investing  in  Zapata.  When  Bush  was  elected to
<ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent> in 1966, Farish joined the Zapata board.s2s1
 When George Bush became  U.S.  vicepresident  in  1980,  the
Farishand  Bush family fortunes were again completely, secretly
commingled.  As we shall see, the old  projects  were  now  being
revived on a breathtaking scale.</p>

<p>Bush and <ent type='ORG'>Draper</ent></p>

<p> Twenty years  before  he  was  U.S.  President,  George Bush
brought  two  <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>race-science''professors  in front of the
<ent type='NORP'>Republican</ent>  Task  Force  on  Earth  Resources  and Population. As
chairman  of  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>Task  Force,  then-<ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>man  Bush invited
Professors  William  Shockley and Arthur Jensen to explain to the
committee how allegedly runaway birth-rates for <ent type='NORP'><ent type='LOC'>Africa</ent>n</ent>-<ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent>s
were <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>down-breeding'' the <ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent> population.
 Afterwards, Bush personally summed up  for  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>  the
testimony  hisblack-inferiority advocates had given to the Task
Force.s2s2 George Bush held his hearings on the threatposed  by
black  babies on August 5, 1969, while much of the world was in a
better frame of mind--celebrating  mankind's  progressfrom  the
first moon landing 16 days earlier.  Bush's obsessive thinking on
this  subject  was guided by his family's friend, Gen. William H.
<ent type='ORG'>Draper</ent>, Jr., the founder and chairman of  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>Population  Crisis
<ent type='ORG'>Committee</ent>, and vice chairman of  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>Planned  Parenthood
<ent type='ORG'>Fed</ent>eration. <ent type='ORG'>Draper</ent> had long been steering U.S. public  discussion
about the so-called <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>population bomb'' in the non-white areas of
the world.
 If  <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>man  Bush had explained to his colleagues {how his
family had come to know General <ent type='ORG'>Draper</ent>,} they would perhaps  have
felt  some  alarm, or even panic, and paid more healthy attention
to Bush's presentation.  Unfortunately,the <ent type='ORG'>Draper</ent>-Bush
population doctrine is now official U.S. foreign policy.
 William  H. <ent type='ORG'>Draper</ent>, Jr. had joined the Bush team in 1927, when
he was hired by <ent type='ORG'><ent type='ORG'>Dillon</ent> Read</ent> &amp; Co., <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent>  investment  bankers.
<ent type='ORG'>Draper</ent>was  put  intoa  new job slot at the firm: handling the
<ent type='ORG'>Thyssen</ent> account.
 We recall that in 1924, Fritz <ent type='ORG'>Thyssen</ent> set up his Union Banking
Corporation in George  HerbertWalker's  bankat  39Broadway,
<ent type='GPE'>Manhattan</ent>.  <ent type='ORG'>Dillon</ent>  Read &amp; Co.'s boss, Clarence <ent type='ORG'>Dillon</ent>, had begun
working with Fritz <ent type='ORG'>Thyssen</ent> some time after <ent type='ORG'>Averell <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent></ent> first
met with <ent type='ORG'>Thyssen</ent>--at about the time <ent type='ORG'>Thyssen</ent> began financing Adolf
Hitler's political career.
 In January 1926, <ent type='ORG'><ent type='ORG'>Dillon</ent> Read</ent> created <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>{<ent type='NORP'>German</ent>  Credit  and
Investment Corporation}  in  <ent type='GPE'>Newark</ent>,New  Jersey  and  <ent type='GPE'>Berlin</ent>,
<ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y, as <ent type='ORG'>Thyssen</ent>'s short-term banker.  That same year,  <ent type='ORG'>Dillon</ent>
Read  created  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>{Vereinigte Stahlwerke} (<ent type='NORP'>German</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Steel Trust</ent>),
incorporating the <ent type='ORG'>Thyssen</ent> family interests under the direction of
<ent type='GPE'>New York</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>London</ent> finance.s2s3
 William H. <ent type='ORG'>Draper</ent>, Jr. was made director, vice president,  and
assistant treasurer of the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> Credit and Investment Corp. His
business was short-term loans and financial management tricks for
<ent type='ORG'>Thyssen</ent>  and  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='NORP'>German</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Steel Trust</ent>. <ent type='ORG'>Draper</ent>'s clients sponsored
Hitler's terroristic takeover; his clients led the buildup of the
<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> war industry;  his  clients  madewar  against  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>United
<ent type='ORG'>State</ent>s. The <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>s were <ent type='ORG'>Draper</ent>'s direct partners in <ent type='GPE'>Berlin</ent> and New
Jersey:  Alexander  Kreuter,  residingin <ent type='GPE'>Berlin</ent>, was president;
Frederic Brandi, whose father was a top  coal  executive  in  the
<ent type='NORP'>German</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Steel Trust</ent>, moved to <ent type='GPE'>the United <ent type='ORG'>State</ent>s</ent> in 1926 and served
as <ent type='ORG'>Draper</ent>'s co-director in <ent type='GPE'>Newark</ent>.
 <ent type='ORG'>Draper</ent>'s  role  wascrucial  for  <ent type='ORG'><ent type='ORG'>Dillon</ent> Read</ent> &amp; Co., for whom
<ent type='ORG'>Draper</ent> was a partner and eventually vice president. <ent type='ORG'>The  </ent><ent type='NORP'>German</ent>
Creditand  Investment  Corp.(<ent type='ORG'>GCI</ent>)  was a <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>front'' for <ent type='ORG'>Dillon</ent>
Read: It had the same <ent type='GPE'>New Jersey</ent> address as U.S. &amp;  International
Securities  Corp. (<ent type='ORG'>USIS</ent>), and the same man served as treasurer of
both firms.s2s4
 Clarence <ent type='ORG'>Dillon</ent> and his son C.  Douglas <ent type='ORG'>Dillon</ent> weredirectors
of  <ent type='ORG'>USIS</ent>,  which  was spotlighted when Clarence <ent type='ORG'>Dillon</ent> was hauled
before the <ent type='ORG'>Senate</ent> Banking <ent type='ORG'>Committee</ent>'s famous <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>Pecora''  hearings
in  1933.  <ent type='ORG'>USIS</ent>  was  shown  to  be  one of the great speculative
pyramid schemes which had swindled stockholders  of  hundreds  of
millions of  dollars. These investment policies had rotted the
U.S. economy to the core, and led to the Great Depression of  the
1930s.
 But William H.<ent type='ORG'>Draper</ent>, Jr.'s  <ent type='ORG'>GCI</ent>  <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>front''  was  not
{apparently} affiliated with the <ent type='ORG'>USIS</ent> <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>front'' or  with  <ent type='ORG'>Dillon</ent>,
and <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='ORG'>GCI</ent>  escaped  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>congressmen's limited scrutiny.  This
oversight was to prove most unfortunate, particularly to  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>50
million people who subsequently died in World War II.
 <ent type='ORG'>Dillon</ent>  Read  hiredpublicrelations  man Ivy Lee to prepare
their executives for their testimony and to confuse  and  further
baffle<ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>congressmen.s2s5 Lee apparently took enough time out
from his duties as image-maker for William S. Farish and the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>
I.G.  <ent type='ORG'>Farben</ent> Co.; he managed the congressional thinking  so  that
the congressmen did  not  disturb  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='ORG'>Draper</ent>  operation  in
<ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y--and did not  meddle  with  <ent type='ORG'>Thyssen</ent>,  or  interfere  with
Hitler's U.S. moneymen.
 Thus,  in  1932, <ent type='GPE'>Willam</ent> H. <ent type='ORG'>Draper</ent>, Jr. was free to finance the
International Eugenics <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent> as a  <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>Supporting  Member.''s2s6
Was heusing  his  own income as a <ent type='ORG'>Thyssen</ent> trust banker?  Or did
the funds come from <ent type='ORG'><ent type='ORG'>Dillon</ent> Read</ent> corporate accounts, perhaps to be
written off income tax as <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>expenses  for  <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>  project:  race
purification''?  <ent type='ORG'>Draper</ent> helped select Ernst Rudin as chief of the
world  eugenics  movement, who used his office to promote what he
called Adolf Hitler's <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>holy, national and  international  racial
hygienic mission.''s2s7
 W.S.  Farish  was  publiclyexposed  in  1942, humiliated and
destroyed.  Just before Farish died, Prescott Bush's <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> banking
office was quietly seized and shut down. <ent type='ORG'>ButPrescott</ent>'s  close
friendand  partner  in  the <ent type='ORG'>Thyssen</ent>-Hitler business, William H.
<ent type='ORG'>Draper</ent>, Jr., {neither died normoved  out  of<ent type='NORP'>German</ent>affairs.}
<ent type='ORG'>Draper</ent>listedhimself  as  adirector of the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> Credit and
Investment Corp. through 1942, and the firm  was  not  liquidated
until November1943.s2s8  Buta  war was on.<ent type='ORG'>Draper</ent>, a colonel
from previous military service, went off to <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='LOC'>Pacific</ent>  theater
and became a general.
 General  <ent type='ORG'>Draper</ent>  apparentlyhad  ahobby:magic--illusions,
sleight of hand, etc.--and he was a  member  of  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='ORG'>Society</ent>  of
<ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent>  Magicians.  This  isnot  irrelevant to his subsequent
career.
 The <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> regime surrendered in May 1945. In July 1945, General
<ent type='ORG'>Draper</ent> was called to <ent type='LOC'>Europe</ent> by the <ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent>  military  government
authorities in  <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y.  <ent type='ORG'>Draper</ent>  was  appointed  head  of  the
Economics Division of  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>U.S.  Control  Commission.  He  was
assigned to  take  apart the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> corporate cartels.  There is an
astonishing but perfectly logical rationale to this--<ent type='ORG'>Draper</ent>  knew
a lot  about the subject!  General <ent type='ORG'>Draper</ent>, who had spent about 15
years  financing  and  managing  the dirtiest of the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>
enterprises,  was  now authorized to decide {who was exposed, who
lost and who kept his business, and in practical effect, who  was
prosecuted for war crimes.}s2s9
 (<ent type='ORG'>Draper</ent> was not unique  within  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>postwar  occupation
government.  Consider the case of John J. McCloy, U.S. Military
Governor  and  High  Commissioner  of  <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y,  1949-1952. Under
instructions from his Wall Street law firm, McCloy had lived  for
a  year in <ent type='GPE'>Italy</ent>, serving as an adviser to the fascist government
of Benito  Mussolini.  An intimate collaborator of the
<ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>/Bush  bank,  McCloy had sat in Adolf Hitler's box at the
1936  Olympic  games  in  <ent type='GPE'>Berlin</ent>,  at  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>invitationof <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>
chieftains Rudolf Hess and Hermann Goering.)s3s0</p>

<p> William H. <ent type='ORG'>Draper</ent>, Jr., as a <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>conservative,'' was paired with
<ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='ORG'>``</ent>liberal''  U.S.<ent type='ORG'>Treasury</ent>  Secretary Henry Morgenthau in a
vicious game. Morgenthau  demanded  that  <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y  be  utterly
destroyed  as a nation, that its industry be dismantled and it be
reduced to a purely rural country.  As the economic boss in  1945
and  1946,  <ent type='ORG'>Draper</ent> <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>protected'' <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y from the Morgenthau Plan
... but at a price.
 <ent type='ORG'>Draper</ent> and his colleagues demanded that <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y and <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>world
accept<ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>{collective  guilt  of  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='NORP'>German</ent>  people} as {the
}explanation for the rise of Hitler's New Order, and the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> war
crimes.  This, of  course,  was  rather  convenient  for  General
<ent type='ORG'>Draper</ent> himself,  as  it  was  for  theBush family.  It is still
convenient decades  later,  allowing  Prescott's  son,President
Bush,  to lecture <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y on the danger of Hitlerism. <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>s are
too slow, it seems, to accept his New World Order.
 After several  years  of  government  service  (often  working
directly  for  Averell<ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent> in the <ent type='LOC'>North</ent> <ent type='LOC'>Atlantic</ent> Alliance),
<ent type='ORG'>Draper</ent> was appointed in 1958 chairman of a committee which was to
advise President Dwight Eisenhower on the proper course for  U.S.
military aid to other countries.  At that time, Prescott Bush was
a  U.S.  senator from <ent type='GPE'>Connecticut</ent>, a confidential friend and golf
partner with National  Security  Director  Gordon  <ent type='ORG'>Gray</ent>,  and  an
important golf partner with Dwight  Eisenhoweras  well.
Prescott's old lawyer from the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> days, John Foster <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent>, was
Secretary of <ent type='ORG'>State</ent>, and his brother Allen <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent>, formerly of the
Schroder bank, was head of the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>.
 This friendly environment emboldened  our  General  <ent type='ORG'>Draper</ent>  to
pull off  a  stunt  with his military aid advisery committee.  He
changed the subject under study.  The following year, <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='ORG'>Draper</ent>
committee recommended  that  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>U.S.  government react to the
supposed threat of the <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>population  explosion''  by  formulating
plans to  depopulate  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>poorer  countries.The growth of the
world's non-white population, he proposed, should be regarded  as
dangerous to the national security of <ent type='GPE'>the United <ent type='ORG'>State</ent>s</ent>!s3s1
 President Eisenhower  rejected the recommendation.  But in the
next decade,  General  <ent type='ORG'>Draper</ent>  founded<ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='ORG'>``</ent>Population  Crisis
<ent type='ORG'>Committee</ent>'' and the <ent type='ORG'>``</ent><ent type='ORG'>Draper</ent> Fund,'' joining with the <ent type='ORG'>Rockefeller</ent>
and <ent type='ORG'>DuPont</ent> families to  promote  eugenics  as  <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>population
control.''  <ent type='ORG'>The  </ent>administration  of  PresidentLyndon Johnson,
advised  by  <ent type='ORG'>Draper</ent> on the subject, began financing birth control
in the tropical countries through <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='ORG'>Agency</ent>  for  International
Development.
 General William <ent type='ORG'>Draper</ent>  was  George  Bush's  guru  on  the
population question.s3s2 But there was also <ent type='ORG'>Draper</ent>'s  money--from
that  uniquelyhorrible source--and <ent type='ORG'>Draper</ent>'s connections on Wall
Street and abroad.  <ent type='ORG'>Draper</ent>'s son and heir, William H. <ent type='ORG'>Draper</ent> III,
was  co-chairman  for  finance(chiefof  fundraising)  of  the
Bush-for-President  national  campaign organization in 1980. With
George Bush in the <ent type='ORG'>White <ent type='ORG'>House</ent></ent>, the younger <ent type='ORG'>Draper</ent> heads  up  the
depopulation  activities  of  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>United  Nations throughout the
world.
 <ent type='ORG'>Draper</ent> was vice president of <ent type='ORG'><ent type='ORG'>Dillon</ent> Read</ent>  until  1953.  During
<ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>1950s  and  1960s,  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>chief  executive there was Frederic
Brandi, the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> who was  <ent type='ORG'>Draper</ent>'s  co-director  for<ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>
investments  and  his  personal  contact  man with the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> Steel
Trust.Nicholas  Brady  was  Brandi'spartner  from  1954,  and
replaced him  as  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>firm's  chief executive in 1971.  Nicholas
Brady, who knows where all the bodies are buried, was chairman of
his friend George Bush's 1980 election campaign  in  New  Jersey,
and  has  been United <ent type='ORG'>State</ent>s <ent type='ORG'>Treasury</ent> Secretary throughout Bush's
presidency.s3s3</p>

<p>Bush and Grey</p>

<p> The U.S. <ent type='ORG'>Agency</ent> forInternational  Development  (<ent type='ORG'>U<ent type='ORG'>SA</ent>ID</ent>)  says
that  surgical sterilization is the Bush administration's <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>first
choice'' method of population reduction in the Third World.s3s4
 <ent type='ORG'>The United Nations Population Fund</ent> claims that 37  percent  of
contraception  users  in  Ibero-<ent type='GPE'>America</ent>  and  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='LOC'>Caribbean</ent> have
already been surgically sterilized.  In a 1991 report, William H.
<ent type='ORG'>Draper</ent> III's U.N. agency asserts that 254 million couples will be
surgically sterilized over the course of the 1990s; and  that  if
present  trends  continue, 80 percent of the women in <ent type='GPE'>Puerto Rico</ent>
and <ent type='GPE'>Panama</ent> will be surgically sterilized.s3s5
 The U.S. government pays directly for these sterilizations.
 <ent type='GPE'>Mexico</ent> is first among targeted nations, on a  list  which  was
drawn up  in  July  1991, at a <ent type='ORG'>U<ent type='ORG'>SA</ent>ID</ent> strategy session.<ent type='GPE'>India</ent> and
<ent type='GPE'>Brazil</ent> are second and third priorities, respectively.
 On contract with the Bush administration, U.S.  personnel  are
working  from  bases  in <ent type='GPE'>Mexico</ent> to perform surgery on millions of
<ent type='NORP'>Mexican</ent> men and women.The acknowledged strategy in this program
is to sterilize those young adults who have not already completed
their families.
 George Bush has a rather deep-seated  personal  feeling  about
this project, in particular as it pits him against Pope John Paul
II in <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> countries such as <ent type='GPE'>Mexico</ent>. (See Chapter 4 below, on
the origin of a Bush-family grudge in this regard.)
 Thespending  for birth control in the non-white countries is
one of<ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>few  items  that  is  headed  upwards  in<ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>Bush
administration budget.  As its 1992 budget was being set, <ent type='ORG'>U<ent type='ORG'>SA</ent>ID</ent>
said its <ent type='ORG'>Population Account</ent> would  receive  $300  million,  a  20
percent increase  over the previous year.  Within this project, a
significant  sum  is  spent  on political and psychological
manipulations of target nations, and rather blatant subversion of
their religions and governments.s3s6
 These activities might be expected to cause serious objections
from <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>victimized  nationalities,  or  fromU.S. taxpayers,
especially if the program is somehow given widespread publicity.
 Quite aside from moral considerations, {legal} questions would
naturally arise, which could be summed up: {How does George  Bush
think he can get away with this?}
 In this matter <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>President  has  expert  advice.  Mr.
(Clayland) Boyden <ent type='ORG'>Gray</ent> has been counsel to George Bush since  the
1980 election.As chief legal officer in the <ent type='ORG'>White <ent type='ORG'>House</ent></ent>, Boyden
<ent type='ORG'>Gray</ent>  can walk the President through the dangers and complexities
of waging such unusual warfare against Third  World  populations.
<ent type='ORG'>Gray</ent> knows how these things are done.
 When  Boyden  <ent type='ORG'>Gray</ent>  was  four  and  five years old, his father
organized  thepilotproject forthe presentworldwide
sterilization  program,  from  the <ent type='ORG'>Gray</ent> family household in <ent type='LOC'>North</ent>
<ent type='GPE'>Carolina</ent>.
 It started in 1946. The eugenics movement was  looking  fora
way to begin again in <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>.
 <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>  <ent type='ORG'>deathcamps</ent>  such as <ent type='ORG'>Auschwitz</ent> had just then seared the
conscience of the world.  The Sterilization  League  of  <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>,
which  had  changed  its  nameduring<ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>war to <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>Birthright,
Inc.,'' wanted to start up again.  First  theyhad  to  overcome
public nervousness about  crackpots  proposing  toeliminate
<ent type='ORG'>``</ent>inferior'' and <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>defective''people.  TheLeaguetried  to
surface  in  <ent type='GPE'>Iowa</ent>,  but  had  to  backoff  because  of negative
publicity: a little boy had recently been  sterilized  there  and
had died from the operation.
 They  decided  on  <ent type='LOC'>North</ent> <ent type='GPE'>Carolina</ent>, where the <ent type='ORG'>Gray</ent> family could
play the perfect host.s3s7  Through  <ent type='NORP'>British</ent>  imperialcontacts,
Boyden<ent type='ORG'>Gray</ent>'s grandfather Bowman <ent type='ORG'>Gray</ent> had become principal owner
of the R.J. Reynolds Tobacco Co. Boyden's  father,  Gordon  <ent type='ORG'>Gray</ent>,
had recently founded the Bowman <ent type='ORG'>Gray</ent> (memorial) <ent type='ORG'>Medical School</ent> in
Winston-Salem, using  his  inherited cigarette stock shares.  The
medical school was already a eugenics center.
 As the experiment  began,  Gordon  <ent type='ORG'>Gray</ent>'s  great  aunt,  Alice
Shelton  <ent type='ORG'>Gray</ent>,who  had raised him from childhood, was living in
his household.Aunt Alice hadfounded  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='ORG'>``</ent>Human  Betterment
League,''  the<ent type='LOC'>North</ent>  <ent type='GPE'>Carolina</ent>  branch of the national eugenical
sterilization movement.
 Aunt  Alicewas  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>official  supervisorof  the 1946-47
experiment.  <ent type='ORG'>Working</ent> under Miss <ent type='ORG'>Gray</ent> was Dr. Claude Nash Herndon,
whom  Gordon  <ent type='ORG'>Gray</ent>  had  made  assistant  professor  of <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>medical
genetics'' at Bowman <ent type='ORG'>Gray</ent> medical school.
 Dr. Clarence Gamble, heir  to  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>Proctorand  Gamble  soap
fortune, was the sterilizers' national field operations chief.
 The experiment  worked  as follows.{All children enrolled in
the school district of Winston-Salem, N.C., were given a  special
<ent type='ORG'>``</ent>intelligencetest.'' Those children who scored below a certain
arbitrary low mark were then cut open and surgically sterilized.}
 We quote now from the official  story  of  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>project:  <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>In
Winston-Salem  and in [nearby] <ent type='GPE'>Orange County</ent>, <ent type='LOC'>North</ent> <ent type='GPE'>Carolina</ent>, the
[<ent type='ORG'>Sterilization League</ent>'s]  field  committee  had  participated  in
testing  projects  to  identify school age children who should be
considered for sterilization.  The project in Orange  County  was
conducted by the University of <ent type='LOC'>North</ent> <ent type='GPE'>Carolina</ent> and was financed by
a  `Mr.  Hanes,' a friend of Clarence Gamble and supporter of the
field work project in <ent type='LOC'>North</ent> <ent type='GPE'>Carolina</ent>. <ent type='ORG'>The  </ent>Winston-Salem  project
was  also financed by Hanes. [<ent type='ORG'>``</ent>Hanes'' was underwear mogul James
Gordon Hanes,  a  trustee  of  Bowman  <ent type='ORG'>Gray</ent>  Medical  School  and
treasurer of Alice <ent type='ORG'>Gray</ent>'s group]....
 <ent type='ORG'>``</ent><ent type='ORG'>The  </ent>medical  school  hada  long  history  of  interest in
eugenics  and  had  compiled  extensive  histories  of families
carrying inheritable  disease. In 1946, Dr. C. Nash Herndon ...
made a statement to the press on  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>use  ofsterilization  to
prevent the spread of inheritable diseases....
 <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>The first step after giving the mental tests to grade school
children was to interpret and make public the results.In Orange
County the results indicated that three percent of the school age
children were either insane or feebleminded....  [Then] the field
committee  hired  a  social worker to review each case ... and to
present any cases in which sterilization  was  indicated  to  the
<ent type='ORG'>State</ent>  Eugenics  <ent type='ORG'>Board</ent>,  whichunder  <ent type='LOC'>North</ent> <ent type='GPE'>Carolina</ent> law had the
authority to order sterilization....''
 Race science experimenter Dr.  Claude  NashHerndon  provided
more details in an interview in 1990:s3s8
 <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>Alice <ent type='ORG'>Gray</ent>  was  the general supervisor of the project.  She
and  Hanes  sent  out  letterspromoting  theprogram  to the
commissioners  of all 100 counties in <ent type='LOC'>North</ent> <ent type='GPE'>Carolina</ent>.... What did
I do?  Nothing besides riding herd  on<ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>whole  thing!  The
social workers operated out of my office.  I was at the time also
director of  outpatient  services  at  <ent type='LOC'>North</ent><ent type='GPE'>Carolina</ent>  Baptist
Hospital. We  would  see  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>[targeted]  parents  and  children
there....  I.Q.  tests  wererun  on  all  the children in the
Winston-Salem public school system.  Only  theones  who  scored
reallylow [were targeted for sterilization], the real bottom of
the barrel, like below 70.
 <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>Did we do sterilizations on young children?  Yes. This was a
relatively minor operation....It  was  usually  not  until  the
child was eight or ten years old.  For the boys, you just make an
incision and  tie  thetube....  Wemore  often performed the
operation on girls than with boys.  Of course, you  have  to  cut
open the abdomen, but again, it is relatively minor.''
 Dr.Herndon  remarked  coolly  that  <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>we  had  a  very  good
relationship with the press'' for  theproject.  This  is  not
surprising,  since Gordon <ent type='ORG'>Gray</ent> owned the {Winston-Salem Journal,}
the {<ent type='GPE'>Twin City Sentinel</ent>,} and radio station WSJS.
 In 1950 and 1951, John Foster <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent>,  thenchairman  of  the
<ent type='ORG'>Rockefeller</ent> Foundation,  led John D.  <ent type='ORG'>Rockefeller</ent> III on a series
of world tours, focusing on the need to stop the expansion of the
non-white populations.In November 1952, <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent> and  <ent type='ORG'>Rockefeller</ent>
set  up  the <ent type='ORG'>Population Council</ent>, with tens of millions of dollars
from the <ent type='ORG'>Rockefeller</ent> family.
 At that point, the <ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent> Eugenics <ent type='ORG'>Society</ent>,  still  cautious
from  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>recent  badpublicity  vis-a-vis Hitler, left its old
headquarters  at  <ent type='ORG'>Yale</ent>University. The <ent type='ORG'>Society</ent> moved its
headquarters  into  the office of the <ent type='ORG'>Population Council</ent>, and the
two groups melded together.  <ent type='ORG'>The  </ent>long-time  secretary  of  the
Eugenics  <ent type='ORG'>Society</ent>,  <ent type='ORG'>Frederick</ent> Osborne, became the first president
of the <ent type='ORG'>Population Council</ent>.  The <ent type='ORG'>Gray</ent>  family'schild-sterilizer,
Dr. C.  Nash Herndon, became president of the <ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent> Eugenics
<ent type='ORG'>Society</ent>  in  1953,  <ent type='ORG'>asits</ent>  work  expanded under <ent type='ORG'>Rockefeller</ent>
patronage.
 Meanwhile, the International Planned Parenthood <ent type='ORG'>Fed</ent>eration was
founded  in  <ent type='GPE'>London</ent>,  in  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>officesof  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='NORP'>British</ent> Eugenics
<ent type='ORG'>Society</ent>.
 The undead enemy  from  World  War  II,  renamed  <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>Population
Control,'' had now been revived.
 George Bush was U.S. ambassador to <ent type='ORG'>the United Nations</ent> in 1972,
when  with  prodding from Bush and his friends, <ent type='GPE'>the United <ent type='ORG'>State</ent>s</ent>
<ent type='ORG'>Agency</ent> for  International  Developmentfirst  made  an  official
contract with the old <ent type='ORG'>Sterilization League</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>. The league
had  changed  its  name  twiceagain,and  was  now  called the
<ent type='ORG'>``</ent>Association for Voluntary Surgical  Contraception.''<ent type='ORG'>The  </ent>U.S.
government  began  paying  <ent type='ORG'>theold</ent>  fascist  group  to sterilize
non-whites in foreign countries.
 The <ent type='ORG'>Gray</ent> family experiment had succeeded.
 In 1988, the U.S. <ent type='ORG'>Agency</ent> for <ent type='ORG'>International Development</ent>  signed
its  latest  contract  with  the old <ent type='ORG'>Sterilization League</ent> (a.k.a.
<ent type='ORG'>``</ent>Association  for  Voluntary  Sterilization''),  committing  the
U.S.  government to spend $80 million over five years.
 Having  gotten  away  with  sterilizing  several hundred <ent type='LOC'>North</ent>
<ent type='GPE'>Carolina</ent> school children, <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>not usually less than  eight  to  ten
years  old,''  the identical group is now authorized by President
Bush to do it to 58 countries in <ent type='LOC'>Asia</ent>, <ent type='LOC'>Africa</ent>, and Ibero-<ent type='GPE'>America</ent>.
The group modestly claims  it  has  directly  sterilized  only2
million  people,  with87  percent  of  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>bill  paid  by U.S.
taxpayers.
 Meanwhile, Dr. Clarence Gamble, Boyden  <ent type='ORG'>Gray</ent>'s  favorite  soap
manufacturer,  formed  his own <ent type='ORG'>``</ent><ent type='ORG'>Pathfinder Fund</ent>'' as a split-off
from the Sterlization  League.Gamble's  Pathfinder  Fund,  with
additional  millions  from  <ent type='ORG'>U<ent type='ORG'>SA</ent>ID</ent>, concentrates on penetration of
local social groups in the non-white  countries,  to  break  down
psychological resistance to the surgical sterilization teams.</p>

<p>Notes</p>

<p>1.  Phyllis  Tilson Piotrow, {World Population Crisis: The United
<ent type='ORG'>State</ent>sResponse} (<ent type='GPE'>New York</ent>: Praeger Publishers, 1973),
<ent type='ORG'>``</ent>Forward'' by George H.W. Bush, pp.  vii-viii.</p>

<p>2.
 <ent type='ORG'>AdolfHitler</ent>,  {<ent type='ORG'>MeinKampf</ent>} (<ent type='GPE'>Boston</ent>, Houghton Mifflin Company,
1971), p.  404.</p>

<p>3. <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>The Ten  Richest  People  in  <ent type='GPE'>Houston</ent>,''  in  {<ent type='GPE'>Houston</ent>  Post
Magazine,} March 11, 1984. <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>$150 milion to $250 million from ...
inheritance,  plus  <ent type='ORG'>subsequentinvestments</ent>  ...  chief heir to a
family fortune in oil stock....  As to his  financial  interests,
he is ...  coy.  He once described one of his businesses as a
company that `invests in and oversees a lot of smallercompanies
... in a lot of foreign countries.'|''</p>

<p>4.  <ent type='ORG'>The  </ent>announcementswere  made  in testimony before a Special
<ent type='ORG'>Committee</ent> of the U.S. <ent type='ORG'>Senate</ent> Investigating theNational  Defense
Program.  The hearings on <ent type='ORG'>Standard</ent> Oil were held March 5, 24, 26,
27, 31, and April 1, 2, 3 and 7, 1942. Available  on  microfiche,
law  section,  Libraryof  <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>.  See also {<ent type='GPE'>New York</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Time</ent>s,}
March 26 and March 27, 1942, and {<ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent> Evening Star,} March
26 and March 27, 1942.</p>

<p>5. {Ibid.,} Exhibit No. 368, printed  on  pp. 4584-87  of  the
hearing record.  Seealso  Charles  Higham,{Trading With The
Enemy} (<ent type='GPE'>New York</ent>: <ent type='ORG'>Delacorte <ent type='ORG'>Press</ent></ent>, 1983), p.  36.</p>

<p>6. Confidential memorandum  from  U.S.  Embassy,  <ent type='GPE'>Berlin</ent>,  {op.
cit.,} chapter2.  Sir  Henri  Deterding  was  among  the most
notorious pro-<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>s of the early war period.</p>

<p>7. See sections on Prescott Bush in Darwin Payne, {Initiative  in
Energy: <ent type='ORG'>Dresser Industries</ent>, Inc.} (<ent type='GPE'>New York</ent>: Distributed by Simon
and Schuster, 1979) (published by the <ent type='ORG'>Dresser Company</ent>).</p>

<p>8.  William  Stamps  Farish  obituary, {<ent type='GPE'>New York</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Time</ent>s,} Nov. 30,
1942.</p>

<p>9. {A Decade of Progress in Eugenics: Scientific  Papers  of  the
Third  International <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent> of Eugenics held at <ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent> Museum
of Natural History <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent>,  August  21-23,  1932.}  (Baltimore:
Williams &amp; Wilkins Company, September, 1934).
 Theterm  <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>eugenics''  <ent type='GPE'>istaken</ent>  from  the <ent type='NORP'>Greek</ent> to signify
<ent type='ORG'>``</ent>good birth'' or <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>well-born,'' as <ent type='ORG'>inaristocrat</ent>.  Its  basic
assumption  isthat  those  who are not <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>well-born'' should not
exist.</p>

<p>10.
 See  among  other  such  letters,  George  Herbert  Walker, 39
Broadway,  N.Y., to W. A. <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>London</ent>, February 21, 1925, in
W.A. <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent> papers.</p>

<p>11.
 <ent type='ORG'>Averell <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent></ent> to Dr. Charles B. Davenport,  President,  The
International  <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>  of  Eugenics,Cold Spring Harbor, L.I.,
N.Y.:</p>

<p> January 21, 1932
 Dear Dr. Davenport:
 I will be  only  too  glad  to  putyou  in  touchwith  the
<ent type='GPE'>Hamburg</ent>-<ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent>  Linethey  may be able to co-operate in making
suggestions which will keep the expenses to a minimum.  I  have
referred  your letter to Mr. Emil Lederer [of the <ent type='GPE'>Hamburg</ent>-<ent type='NORP'>Amerika</ent>
executive board in <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent>] with the request that he communicate
with you.</p>

<p> Davenport to Mr. W.A.  <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>, 59Wall  Street,  New  York,
N.Y.</p>

<p> January 23, 1932
 Dear Mr. <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>:
 Thank  you  very much for your kind letter of January 21st and
the action you took which has resulted at once in a  letter  from
Mr.  Emil Lederer. This letter will serve as a starting point for
correspondence, which I hope  will  enable  more  of  our  <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>
colleagues  tocome to <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> on the occasion of the congresses
of eugenics and genetics, than otherwise.</p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>ional  hearingsin  1934  established  that
<ent type='GPE'>Hamburg</ent>-<ent type='NORP'>Amerika</ent> routinely provided free transatlantic passage for
those carrying out <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> propaganda chores.  See {Investigation of
<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>  <ent type='ORG'>Propaganda</ent>  Activities  and  Investigation of Certain Other
<ent type='ORG'>Propaganda</ent> Activities,} {op. cit.,} chapter 2.</p>

<p>12.
 Alexis <ent type='ORG'>Carrel</ent>, {Man  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>Unknown}  (New  York:  Halcyon  <ent type='ORG'>House</ent>,
published  by  arrangement  with  Harper  &amp;  Brothers, 1935), pp.
318-19.
 The battle cry of the New Order was sounded in 1935with  the
publication  of  {Man  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>Unknown,} by Dr. Alexis <ent type='ORG'>Carrel</ent> of the
<ent type='ORG'>Rockefeller</ent> Institute in <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent>. This Nobel  Prize-winner  said
<ent type='ORG'>``</ent>enormous  sums  are now required to maintain prisons and insane
asylums.... Why  do  we  preserve  these  useless  and  harmful
beings?  This  fact  must  be squarely faced.  Why should society
not dispose of the criminals and the insane in a more  economical
manner? ... The community must be protected against troublesome
and dangerouselements....  Perhaps prisons should be
abolished....<ent type='ORG'>The  </ent>conditioning  of the petty criminal with the
whip, or some more scientific procedure, followed by a short stay
in hospital, would probably suffice to insure order.  [Criminals,
including those] who have ...  misled  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>public  onimportant
matters, should be humanely and economically disposed of in small
euthanasic institutions  supplied  with  proper gases.A similar
treatment could be advantageously applied to <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>insane,  guilty
of criminal acts.''
 <ent type='ORG'>Carrel</ent>  claimed  tohave  transplanted  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>head of a dog to
another dog and kept it alive for quite some time.</p>

<p>13.
 Bernhard <ent type='ORG'>Schreiber</ent>, {The Men Behind Hitler: A <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> Warning  to
the World,}  <ent type='GPE'>France</ent>: La Hay-Mureaux, ca.  1975), English language
edition supplied by H.&amp; P. Tadeusz, 369 Edgewere  Road,  <ent type='GPE'>London</ent>
W2.  Acopy  of  this book is now held by <ent type='ORG'>Union College Library</ent>,
<ent type='GPE'>Syracuse</ent>, N.Y.</p>

<p>14.
 Higham, {op. cit.,} p.  35.</p>

<p>15.
 Engagement announced Feb. 10, 1939, {<ent type='GPE'>New York</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Time</ent>s,}p.  20.
See  also  {Directory  of Directors} for <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent> City, 1930s and
1940s.</p>

<p>16.
 Higham, {op.  cit.,}  pp.  20,  22  and  other  references  to
Schroeder and Lindemann.
 Anthony  Sutton,  {Wall  Street  and the Rise of Hitler} (Seal
Beach: '76 <ent type='ORG'>Press</ent>, 1976). Sutton is also  a  good  source  on  the
<ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>s.</p>

<p>17.
 {<ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent> Evening Star,} March 27, 1942, p.1.</p>

<p>18. Higham, {op. cit.} p.  50.</p>

<p>19.
 {Ibid.,} p.  48.</p>

<p>20.
 {<ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent> Post,}  April  29, 1990, p.  F4. Higham, {op. cit.,}
pp.  52-53.</p>

<p>21.
 Zapata  annual  reports,  1950s-1960s, Library of <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>
microforms.</p>

<p>22.
 See  {<ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>ional  Record}  for  Bush  speech  in the <ent type='ORG'>House</ent> of
Representatives, Sept. 4, 1969. Bush inserted in <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>record  the
testimony given before his Task Force on August 5, 1969.</p>

<p>23. <ent type='ORG'>Sobel</ent>,  {op.  cit.,} pp.  92-111. See also Boyle, {op. cit.,}
chapter 1, concerning the Morgan-led Dawes <ent type='ORG'>Committee</ent> of <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y's
foreign creditors.
 Like <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Dillon</ent> used the Schroeder and <ent type='GPE'>Warburg</ent> banks  to
strike his  <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>  bargains. All <ent type='ORG'><ent type='ORG'>Dillon</ent> Read</ent> &amp; Co. affairs in
<ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y were supervised by  J.P.  Morgan  &amp;  Co.  partner  Thomas
Lamont,  and  were authorized by Bank of <ent type='GPE'>England</ent> Governor Montagu
Norman.</p>

<p>24. See {Poor's Register of Directors and Executives,} (<ent type='GPE'>New York</ent>:
Poor's Publishing Company, late 1920s, '30s and '40s).See  also
{<ent type='ORG'>Standard</ent>  Corporation Records} (<ent type='GPE'>New York</ent>: <ent type='ORG'>Standard</ent> &amp; Poor), 1935
edition pp. 2571-25,and  1938  edition  pp.  7436-38, for
description  and  history  of  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='NORP'>German</ent>  Credit and Investment
Corporation. For Frederic Brandi, See also <ent type='ORG'>Sobel</ent>, {op. cit.,}  p.
213-214.</p>

<p>25. <ent type='ORG'>Sobel</ent>, {op.  cit.,} pp.  180, 186.Ivy Lee had been hired to
improve <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='ORG'>Rockefeller</ent>  family  image,  particularlydifficult
after  their  1914 massacre of striking miners and pregnant women
in <ent type='GPE'>Ludlow</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Colorado</ent>. Lee got old John D.  <ent type='ORG'>Rockefeller</ent> to pass out
dimes to poor people lined up at his porch.</p>

<p>26.
 ThirdInternational  Eugenics  <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>  papers {op. cit.,}
footnote 7, p.512, <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>Supporting Members.''</p>

<p>27.
 <ent type='ORG'>Schreiber</ent>, {op. cit.,} p.  160. The Third Int. Eugenics <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>
papers, p.   526,  lists  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>officers  of  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>International
<ent type='ORG'>Fed</ent>eration as of publication date in September, 1934.Rudin  is
listed as president--a year after hehas  written  the
sterilization law for Hitler.</p>

<p>28.
 {<ent type='ORG'>Directory of Directors</ent> for <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent> City,} 1942. Interview with
Nancy Bowles, librarian of <ent type='ORG'><ent type='ORG'>Dillon</ent> Read</ent> &amp; Co.</p>

<p>29.
 Higham, {op. cit.,} p.  129, 212-15, 219-23.</p>

<p>30.
 Walter Isaacson and Evan Thomas, {The Wise Men: Six Friends  and
<ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>World  They Made--Acheson, Bohlen, <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>, Kennan, Lovett,
McCloy} (<ent type='GPE'>New York</ent>: Simon and Schuster, 1986), pp.  122, 305.</p>

<p>31.
 Piotrow, {op. cit.,} pp.  36-42.</p>

<p>32.
 {Ibid.,} p.  viii.  <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>As chairman of the special <ent type='NORP'>Republican</ent> Task
Force on Population and Earth Resources, I was impressed  by  the
arguments  of  William H. <ent type='ORG'>Draper</ent>, Jr.... General <ent type='ORG'>Draper</ent> continues
to lead through his tireless work for the U.N. Population Fund.''</p>

<p>33.
 <ent type='ORG'>Sobel</ent>, {op. cit.,} pp.  298, 354.</p>

<p>34.
 Interview July 16, 1991, with Joanne Grossi,  an  official  with
the <ent type='ORG'>U<ent type='ORG'>SA</ent>ID</ent>'s Population Office.</p>

<p>35. Dr. Nafis Sadik, <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>The <ent type='ORG'>State</ent> of World Population,'' 1991, New
York, United Nations Population Fund.</p>

<p>36.
 See  {User's Guide to the Office of Population,} 1991, Office of
Population, Bureau forScience  and  Technology,  United  <ent type='ORG'>State</ent>s
<ent type='ORG'>Agency</ent>for  International  Development.  Available from S&amp;T/POP,
Room 811 <ent type='ORG'>SA</ent>-18, <ent type='ORG'>U<ent type='ORG'>SA</ent>ID</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent> D.C. 20523-1819.</p>

<p>37. <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>History of  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>Association  for  Voluntary  Sterilization
[formerly  Sterilization  League  of  <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>], 1935-64,'' thesis
submitted to the faculty of the graduate school of the University
of  <ent type='GPE'>Minnesota</ent>  by  William  Ray  Van  Essendelft,  March, 1978,
available on microfilm, Library of <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>. This is the official
history,  written  with  full  cooperation  ofthe Sterilization
League.</p>

<p>38.
 Interview with Dr. C. Nash Herndon, June 20, 1990.</p>

<p>Any comments, please send by email, as I get very far  behind  on
this group.</p>

<p>Thanks.</p>

<p> John Covici</p>

<p>coviciccs.covici.com</p>

<p>Article 15412 of alt.activism:
From: covici@ccs.covici.com (John Covici)
<ent type='GPE'>Newsgroups</ent>: alt.activism
Subject: Part 4: George Bush Unauthorized Biography
<info type="Message-ID"> uNcTeB1w164w@ccs.covici.com</info>
Date: 19 Jan 92 20:12:41 GMT
Organization: Covici Computer Systems
Lines: 1271</p>

<p>The following is part of a not yet published book being serialized in
<ent type='ORG'>New <ent type='ORG'>Fed</ent>eralist</ent>.  For further information, or to subscribe, please
contact me by e-mail.</p>

<p>CHAPTER  4:  <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>THE  CENTER  OFPOWER  IS  IN  <ent type='GPE'>WASHINGTON</ent>'' Brown
Brothers <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent> &amp; Co. 59 Wall Street, New  York  Cable  Address
<ent type='ORG'>``</ent>Shipley-<ent type='GPE'>New York</ent>'' Business Established 1818
 Private Bankers</p>

<p>September 5, 1944</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>The  </ent>Honorable W. A. <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent> <ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent> Ambassador to the U.S.S.R.
<ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent> Embassy, <ent type='GPE'>Moscow</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent></p>

<p>Dear Averell:</p>

<p> Thinking that possibly <ent type='ORG'>Bullitt</ent>'s article in <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>recent  issue
of  <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>LIFE''  may not have come to your attention, I have clipped
it and am sending it to you, feeling that it will interest you.
At present writing all is well here.</p>

<p>With warm regards, I am, Sincerely yours,</p>

<p>  Pres</p>

<p> `At present writing all is well here.'' Thus the ambassador to
<ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent> was  reassured  by  themanaging  partner  of  his  firm,
Prescott  Bush.  Only  22  anda  half  months  before, the U.S.
government  had  seized  and  shut down the Union Banking
Corporation, which had been operated on behalf of <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y by
Bush  and  the<ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>s. But that was behind them now, and they
were safe.  There would be  nopublicity  on  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>-Bush
sponsorship of Hitlerism.
 Prescott's  son  George,  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>future U.S. President, was also
safe.  Three days before this note to <ent type='GPE'>Moscow</ent> was written,  George
Bush  had parachuted from a <ent type='ORG'>Navy</ent> bomber airplane over the <ent type='LOC'>Pacific</ent>
Ocean, killing his two crew  members  when  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>unpiloted  plane
crashed.
 Five  months  later, in February 1945, Prescott's boss Averell
<ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent> escorted President Franklin  Roosevelt  to  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>fateful
summit meetingwith  <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent>  leader  Joseph Stalin at <ent type='GPE'>Yalta</ent>.  In
April Roosevelt died.  The agreement reached  at  <ent type='GPE'>Yalta</ent>,  calling
for  free  elections  in  <ent type='GPE'>Poland</ent>  once<ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>war ended, was never
enforced.
 Over the next eight years (1945 through 1952),  Prescott  Bush
was <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>'sanchorin  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>New  York  financial world.  The
increasingly powerful Mr. <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent> and his  allies  gave  <ent type='LOC'>East</ent>ern
<ent type='LOC'>Europe</ent> over  to  <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent>  dictatorship.  A  Cold  Warwas  then
undertaken, to <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>counterbalance'' the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent>s.
 This  <ent type='NORP'>British</ent>-inspired  strategy  paid several nightmarish
dividends.  <ent type='LOC'>East</ent>ern  <ent type='LOC'>Europe</ent>  was to remain enslaved.  <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y was
<ent type='ORG'>``</ent>permanently'' divided.  Anglo-<ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent>  power was jointly
exercised  over  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>non-<ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>Free World.'' The confidential
functions of the <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> and <ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent>  governments  were  merged.
The <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent> clique took possession of the U.S. national security
apparatus, and in doing so, they opened the gate and let the Bush
family in.
  - * * * -</p>

<p> Following  his  services  to  <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y's  <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>  Party,  Averell
<ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent> spentseveral  yearsmediating  between  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='NORP'>British</ent>,
<ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent>, and <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> governments in the war to stop the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>s. He
was ambassador to <ent type='GPE'>Moscow</ent> from 1943 to 1946.</p>

<p> President  Harry Truman, whom <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent> and his friends held in
amused contempt, appointed <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent> U.S.  ambassador  to  <ent type='GPE'>Britain</ent>
in 1946.
 <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>  was  at  lunch  with  former  <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> Prime Minister
Winston <ent type='ORG'>Churchill</ent>  oneday  in  1946,when  Truman  telephoned.
<ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>  asked  <ent type='ORG'>Churchill</ent>  if he should accept Truman's offer to
come back to the U.S. as  Secretary  of  <ent type='ORG'>Commerce</ent>.  According  to
<ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>'s  account, <ent type='ORG'>Churchill</ent> told him: <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>Absolutely. The center
of power is in <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>.''s1</p>

<p> <ent type='LOC'>Jupiter</ent> Island</p>

<p> The reorganization of the <ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent> government after World  War
II--<ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>creation  of  the U.S. <ent type='ORG'>Central Intelligence</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Agency</ent> along
<ent type='NORP'>British</ent> lines, for example--had devastating consequences.  We are
concerned  here  with  only  certain  aspects  of  that overall
transformation,  thosematters  of  policy and family which gave
shape to the life and mind of George Bush, and gave him access to
power.
 It was in these postwar years that George Bush  attended  <ent type='ORG'>Yale</ent>
University,  and  was  inducted into the <ent type='ORG'>Skull</ent> and Bones society.
<ent type='ORG'>The  </ent>Bush  family's  home  at  that  time was in <ent type='GPE'>Greenwich</ent>,
<ent type='GPE'>Connecticut</ent>. But it was just then that George's parents, Prescott
and  Dorothy  Walker  Bush,  were wintering in a peculiar spot in
<ent type='GPE'>Florida</ent>, a place that is  excluded  from  mention  in  literature
originating from Bush circles.
 Certain  national  news  accounts  early  in 1991 featured the
observations on President Bush's childhood by his elderly  mother
Dorothy.  She  was  said to be a resident of <ent type='LOC'>Hobe Sound</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Florida</ent>.
More precisely, the President's mother lived in a  hyper-security
arrangement  created  a half-century earlier by <ent type='ORG'>Averell <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent></ent>,
adjacent to <ent type='LOC'>Hobe Sound</ent>. Its correct name is <ent type='LOC'>Jupiter</ent> Island.
 During his political career,  George  Bush  has  claimed  many
different <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>home'' states, including <ent type='GPE'>Texas</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Maine</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Massachusetts</ent>,
and <ent type='GPE'>Connecticut</ent>.  Ithas  not  been expedient for him to claim
<ent type='GPE'>Florida</ent>, though that state has a vital link to his  role  in  the
world, as  we shall see.  And George Bush's home base in <ent type='GPE'>Florida</ent>,
throughout his adult life, has been <ent type='LOC'>Jupiter</ent> Island.
 The unique, bizarre setup on <ent type='LOC'>Jupiter</ent>  Island  <ent type='GPE'>beganin</ent>  1931,
following <ent type='GPE'>themergerof</ent>  W.A.  <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>  and  Co.with  the
<ent type='NORP'>British</ent>-<ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent> firm <ent type='ORG'>Brown Brothers</ent>.
 The reader will recall Mr. Samuel  Pryor,  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='ORG'>``</ent>Merchant  of
Death.''  A  partner  with  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>s, Prescott Bush, George
Walker, and <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> boss  Fritz  <ent type='ORG'>Thyssen</ent>  in  banking  and  shipping
enterprises,  Sam  Pryor remained executive committee chairman of
<ent type='ORG'><ent type='ORG'>Remington</ent> Arms</ent>. In this period, the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> private armies  (<ent type='ORG'>SA</ent>  and
<ent type='ORG'>SS</ent>)  were  supplied  with <ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent> arms--most likely by Pryor and
his company--as they moved  tooverthrow  the<ent type='NORP'>German</ent>republic.
Such  gun-running as an instrument of national policy would later
become notorious in the <ent type='ORG'>``</ent><ent type='GPE'>Iran</ent>-Contra'' affair.
 Sam Pryor's daughter Permelia married <ent type='ORG'>Yale</ent> graduate Joseph  V.
Reed  on  the last day of 1927. Reed immediately went to work for
Prescott Bush  and  George  Walker,  as  an  apprentice  at  W.A.
<ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent> and Co.
 During World  War  II,  Joseph  V. Reed  had  served in the
<ent type='ORG'>``</ent>special services'' section of the U.S.  <ent type='ORG'>Army</ent>SignalCorps.A
specialist  insecurity, codes and espionage, Reed later wrote a
book entitled {Fun with Cryptograms}.s2</p>

<p> Sam Pryor had had property around  Hobe  Sound,  <ent type='GPE'>Florida</ent>,  for
some time.  In  1931, Joseph and Permelia Pryor Reed bought the
entirety of <ent type='LOC'>Jupiter</ent> Island.
 This  is  atypically  beautiful  <ent type='LOC'>Atlantic</ent>coast<ent type='ORG'>``</ent>barrier
island,'' a  half-milewide  and nine miles long.  The middle of
<ent type='LOC'>Jupiter</ent> Islandlies  just  off  Hobe  Sound.  <ent type='ORG'>The  </ent>south  bridge
connects  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>island  with  the town of <ent type='LOC'>Jupiter</ent>, to the north of
<ent type='GPE'>Palm Beach</ent>. It is about 90 minutes by auto from  <ent type='GPE'>Miami</ent>--today,a
few minutes by helicopter.
 Early in 1991, a newspaper reporter asked a friend of the Bush
family about security  arrangements  on  <ent type='LOC'>Jupiter</ent>  Island.  He
responded, <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>If you called up the <ent type='ORG'>White <ent type='ORG'>House</ent></ent>,would  they  tell
you how  many  security  people  they had?  It's not that <ent type='LOC'>Jupiter</ent>
Island is the <ent type='ORG'>White <ent type='ORG'>House</ent></ent>, although he [GeorgeBush]  does  come
down frequently.''
 <ent type='ORG'>Butfor</ent>  several  decades  before Bush was President, <ent type='LOC'>Jupiter</ent>
Islandhad  an  ordinance requiring the registration and
fingerprinting of all housekeepers,  gardeners,  and  other
non-residents working on the island.  The <ent type='LOC'>Jupiter</ent>  Island  police
department says that there are sensors in the two main roads that
can track  every automobile on the island.  If a car stops in the
street, the police will be  there  within  oneor  two  minutes.
<ent type='ORG'>Surveillance</ent>  is  a  duty of all employees of the Town of <ent type='LOC'>Jupiter</ent>
Island. News reporters are to  be  prevented  from  visiting  the
island.s3
 To  create  this astonishing private club, Joseph and Permelia
Pryor Reed sold land only to those who would fit  in. Permelia
Reed was still the grande dame of the island when George Bush was
inaugurated  <ent type='ORG'>Presidentin</ent>  1989. In recognition of the fact that
the Reeds know where {all} the bodies are buried, President  Bush
appointed  Permelia's son, Joseph V. Reed, Jr., chief of protocol
for the U.S. <ent type='ORG'>State</ent> Dept., in charge of private arrangements  with
foreign dignitaries.
 Averell  <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent> made <ent type='LOC'>Jupiter</ent> Island a staging ground for his
1940s takeover of the U.S. national security apparatus. It  was
in  that  connection  that  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>island  became possibly the most
secretive private place in <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>.
 Let us briefly survey the neighborhood, back then in  1946-48,
to  see  some  of  theuses various of the residents had for the
<ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent> clique.</p>

<p> Residence on <ent type='LOC'>Jupiter</ent> Island</p>

<p> sb|<ent type='LOC'>Jupiter</ent> Islander {RobertA.  Lovett,}s4,  Prescott  Bush's
partner  at <ent type='ORG'><ent type='ORG'>Brown Brothers</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent></ent>, had been Assistant Secretary
of War for Air from 1941 to 1945. Lovett was the leading <ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent>
advocate of <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>policy  of  terror-bombing  of  civilians.  He
organized  <ent type='ORG'>theStrategic</ent>  Bombing  Survey,  carried  out for the
<ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent> and <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> governments by the staff of  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='ORG'>Prudential</ent>
Insurance  Company,  guided  by  <ent type='GPE'>London</ent>'s  Tavistock  Psychiatric
Clinic.
 In the postwar  period,  Prescott  Bush  was  associated  with
<ent type='ORG'>Prudential</ent>  Insurance,one  of Lovett's intelligence channels to
the <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> secret services.  Prescott was listed  by  <ent type='ORG'>Prudential</ent>
as  a  director  of  the company for about two years in the early
1950s.
 Their Strategic Bombing Survey failed to demonstrate any  real
military advantage accruing from suchoutrages  as  the
fire-bombing  of <ent type='GPE'>Dresden</ent>, <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y. But the <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>ites
nevertheless  persisted  in  the advocacy of terror from the air.
They glorified this as <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>psychological warfare,'' a part  of  the
utopian  military  doctrine  opposed  to  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>views  of military
traditionalists such as Gen. Douglas <ent type='ORG'>MacArthur</ent>.
 Robert  Lovett  later  advised  President  Lyndon  Johnson  to
terror-bomb  <ent type='GPE'>Vietnam</ent>.  President George Bush revived the doctrine
with the bombing of civilian areas in <ent type='GPE'>Panama</ent>, and the destruction
of <ent type='GPE'>Baghdad</ent>.
 On October 22, 1945, Secretary of War Robert Patterson created
the Lovett <ent type='ORG'>Committee</ent>, chaired by Robert A. Lovett, to advise  the
government on  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>post-World  War  II  organization  of  U.S.
intelligence activities.  The existence  of  this  committee  was
unknown  to the public until an official <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> history was released
from secrecy in 1989. But the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>'s  author  (who  wasPresident
Bush'sprep school history teacher; see chapter 5) gives no real
details of the Lovett <ent type='ORG'>Committee</ent>'s  functioning,  claiming:  <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>The
recordof  the testimony of the Lovett <ent type='ORG'>Committee</ent>, unfortunately,
was not in the archives of  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>agency  when  this  account  was
written.''s5
 The<ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>'s  self-history  does  inform  us  of the advice that
Lovett provided to  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>Truman  cabinet,  as  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>official  War
Department intelligence proposal.
 Lovett  decided  that  there  should  be  aseparate  Central
Intelligence <ent type='ORG'>Agency</ent>. The new agency would  <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>consult''with  the
armed  forces,but  it must be the sole collecting agency in the
field of foreign espionage and counterespionage.  The new  agency
shouldhave an independent budget, and its appropriations should
be granted by <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent> without public hearings.
 Lovett appeared before the Secretaries of <ent type='ORG'>State</ent>, War, and <ent type='ORG'>Navy</ent>
on November 14, 1945. He spoke highly of the <ent type='ORG'>FBI</ent>'s  work  because
it  had  <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>thebest personality file in the world.'' Lovett said
the <ent type='ORG'>FBI</ent> was expert at producing false documents, an  art  <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>which
we  developed  so  successfully  during  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>war and at which we
becameoutstandingly  adept.''  Lovett  pressed  for  a  virtual
resumption of the wartime <ent type='ORG'>Office of Strategic Services</ent> (O<ent type='ORG'>SS</ent>) in a
new <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>.
 U.S.  military  traditionalists  centered  around Gen. Douglas
<ent type='ORG'>MacArthur</ent> opposed Lovett's proposal.  The continuation of the O<ent type='ORG'>SS</ent>
had been attacked at the end of the war on the groundsthat  the
O<ent type='ORG'>SS</ent>  was  entirely  under  <ent type='NORP'>British</ent>  control,  and  that  it would
constitute an <ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent> Gestapo.s6 But the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> was established  in
1947  according  to the prescription of Robert Lovett, of <ent type='LOC'>Jupiter</ent>
Island.
 sb|{Charles Payson} and his wife, {Joan <ent type='ORG'>Whitney</ent> Payson,}  were
extended  family members of <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>'s and business associates of
the Bush family.
 Joan's aunt, Gertrude Vanderbilt <ent type='ORG'>Whitney</ent>, was  a  relative  of
<ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>s.  Gertrude's son, Cornelius Vanderbilt (<ent type='ORG'>``</ent>Sonny'')
<ent type='ORG'>Whitney</ent>, long-time chairman of Pan <ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent> Airways (Prescott was
a <ent type='ORG'>Pan Am</ent> director), became assistant secretary of  theU.S.  Air
Force  in  1947.  Sonny's wife Marie had divorced him and married
<ent type='ORG'>Averell <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent></ent> in 1930. Joan and Sonny's uncle, Air Marshal Sir
Thomas Elmhirst, was director of intelligence for the <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> Air
Force from 1945 to 1947.
 Joan's  brother,  John  Hay(<ent type='ORG'>``</ent>Jock'')  <ent type='ORG'>Whitney</ent>,  was  to  be
ambassador  toGreat <ent type='GPE'>Britain</ent> from 1955 to 1961 ... when it would
be vital for Prescott and George Bush  to  have  such  a  friend.
Joan'sfather,  grandfather, and uncle were members of the <ent type='ORG'>Skull</ent>
and Bones secret society.
 Charles Payson organized a uranium refinery in 1948. Later, he
was  chairman  of  Vitro  Corporation,makers of parts for
submarine-launched  ballistic  missiles,  equipment for frequency
surveillance  and  torpedo guidance, and other subsurface
weaponry.
 <ent type='GPE'>Naval</ent>  warfare  <ent type='GPE'>haslong</ent>  been a preoccupation of the <ent type='NORP'>British</ent>
Empire.  <ent type='NORP'>British</ent>  penetration  of  theU.S.  <ent type='GPE'>Naval</ent>  Intelligence
service  has  been  particularly heavy since the tenure of Joan's
<ent type='NORP'>Anglophile</ent> grandfather, William C. <ent type='ORG'>Whitney</ent>, as secretary  of  the
<ent type='ORG'>Navy</ent>  for  President  Grover  Cleveland.  This traditional covert
<ent type='NORP'>British</ent> orientation in the U.S. <ent type='ORG'>Navy</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Naval</ent> Intelligence and  the
<ent type='ORG'>Navy</ent>'sincluded  service,  the <ent type='ORG'>Marine Corps</ent>, forms a backdrop to
the career of George  Bush--and  to  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>whole  neighborhood  on
<ent type='LOC'>Jupiter</ent>  Island.  <ent type='GPE'>Naval</ent>  Intelligence maintained direct relations
with gangster boss  Meyer  Lansky  forAnglo-<ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent>political
operations in  <ent type='GPE'>Cuba</ent>  during  World  War  II,well  before  the
establishment of the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>. Lansky officially moved to  <ent type='GPE'>Florida</ent>  in
1953.s7
 sb|{George  HerbertWalker, Jr.} (<ent type='ORG'>Skull</ent> and Bones, 1927), was
extremely close to his nephew George Bush, helping to sponsor his
entry into the oil business in the 1950s.  <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>Uncle  Herbie''  was
also  a  partner  of Joan <ent type='ORG'>Whitney</ent> Payson when they co-founded the
<ent type='GPE'>New York</ent> Mets baseball team in 1960.  His son, G.H.  Walker  III,
was  a<ent type='ORG'>Yale</ent>  classmate  of  {Nicholas Brady} and Moreau D. Brown
(Thatcher Brown's grandson), forming what was called  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='ORG'>``</ent><ent type='ORG'>Yale</ent>
Mafia'' on Wall Street.
 sb|{Walter S. Carpenter, Jr.} had been chairman of the finance
committee of<ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>Du  Pont  Corporation  (1930-40).In  1933,
Carpenter oversaw <ent type='ORG'>Du Pont</ent>'s purchase of <ent type='ORG'><ent type='ORG'>Remington</ent> Arms</ent>from  Sam
Pryor and the <ent type='ORG'>Rockefeller</ent>s, and led <ent type='ORG'>Du Pont</ent> into partnership with
<ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>  I.G. <ent type='ORG'>Farben</ent> company for the manufacture of explosives.
Carpenter became <ent type='ORG'>Du Pont</ent>'s president in 1940. His cartel with the
<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>s was broken up by<ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>U.S.  government.  Nevertheless,
Carpenter remained Du  Pont's  president,  as  thecompany's
technicians participated massively in <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='GPE'>Manhattan</ent>  Project  to
produce <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>first  atomic bomb.  He was chairman of <ent type='ORG'>Du Pont</ent> from
1948 to 1962, retaining high-level  access  toU.S.strategic
activities.
 Walter  Carpenter  and  Prescott Bush were fellow activists in
the Mental Hygiene <ent type='ORG'>Society</ent>. Originating  at  <ent type='ORG'>Yale</ent>  University  in
1908,  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>movement had been organized into the World <ent type='ORG'>Fed</ent>eration
of Mental Health by Montague Norman, himself  a  frequent  mental
patient,  former  Brown  Brothers  partner  and  Bank  of <ent type='GPE'>England</ent>
Governor. Norman had  appointed  as  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>federation'<ent type='ORG'>schairman</ent>,
Brigadier  John  Rawlings Rees, director of the <ent type='ORG'>Tavistock Clinic</ent>,
chief psychiatrist  and  psychologicalwarfare  expert  for  the
<ent type='NORP'>British</ent> intelligence  services.  Prescott was a director of the
society in <ent type='GPE'>Connecticut</ent>; Carpenter was a director in <ent type='GPE'>Delaware</ent>.
 sb|{Paul <ent type='ORG'>Mellon</ent>} was the leading heir to <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='ORG'>Mellon</ent>  fortune,
and  along-time  neighbor  of <ent type='ORG'>Averell <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent></ent>'s in <ent type='GPE'>Middleburg</ent>,
<ent type='GPE'>Virginia</ent>, as well as  <ent type='LOC'>Jupiter</ent>  Island,<ent type='GPE'>Florida</ent>.  Paul's  father,
Andrew<ent type='ORG'>Mellon</ent>, U.S. treasury secretary 1921-32, had approved the
transactions of <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>, Pryor, and Bush with <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='GPE'>Warburg</ent>s  and
the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>s.  Paul <ent type='ORG'>Mellon</ent>'s son-in-law, {David K.E.  Bruce,} worked
in Prescott  Bush's  W.A. <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent> &amp; Co. during the late 1920s;
was head of the <ent type='GPE'>London</ent> branch of U.S.  intelligence during  World
War  II;  and  was  Averell  <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>'s  Assistant  Secretary  of
<ent type='ORG'>Commerce</ent> in 1947-48.  <ent type='ORG'>Mellon</ent> family money and participation would
be instrumental in many domestic U.S. projects of the new Central
Intelligence <ent type='ORG'>Agency</ent>.
 sb|{Carll Tucker} manufactured electronic  guidanceequipment
for  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='ORG'>Navy</ent>.  With  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='ORG'>Mellon</ent>s, Tucker was an owner of South
<ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent> oil properties. Mrs.  Tucker  was  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>great-aunt  of
{Nicholas  Brady,}  later  George  Bush's <ent type='GPE'>Iran</ent>-Contra partner and
U.S. treasury secretary.  Their son Carll Tucker, Jr. (<ent type='ORG'>Skull</ent>  and
Bones,1947), was among the 15 Bonesmen who selected George Bush
for induction in the class of 1948.
 sb|{C.  Douglas <ent type='ORG'>Dillon</ent>} was the boss  of  William  H.  <ent type='ORG'>Draper</ent>,
Jr. in  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='ORG'>Draper</ent>-<ent type='ORG'>PrescottBush</ent>-Fritz  <ent type='ORG'>Thyssen</ent>  <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> banking
scheme of the 1930s and 40s. His father, Clarence <ent type='ORG'>Dillon</ent>, created
<ent type='ORG'>the Vereinigte Stahlwerke</ent> (<ent type='ORG'>Thyssen</ent>'s <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Steel Trust</ent>) in 1926.
C. Douglas <ent type='ORG'>Dillon</ent> made{Nicholas  Brady}  thechairman  of  the
<ent type='ORG'><ent type='ORG'>Dillon</ent> Read</ent> firm in 1971 and himself continued as chairman of the
Executive  <ent type='ORG'>Committee</ent>.  C. Douglas <ent type='ORG'>Dillon</ent> would be a vital ally of
his neighbor Prescott Bush during the Eisenhower administration.
 sb|{Publisher Nelson <ent type='ORG'>Doubleday</ent>} headed his family's publishing
firm, founded under the auspices of J.P. Morgan and other <ent type='NORP'>British</ent>
Empire representatives. <ent type='NORP'>WhenGeorgeBush</ent>'s<ent type='ORG'>``</ent>Uncle  Herbie''
died,  <ent type='ORG'>Doubleday</ent>  took over as majority owner and chief executive
of the <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent> Mets baseball team.
 Some other specialized corporate owners  had  theirplace  in
<ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>'s strange club.
 sb|{George  W.  <ent type='ORG'>Merck</ent>,}  chairman  of  <ent type='ORG'>Merck</ent>  &amp;  Co., drug and
chemical manufacturers, was director of the War Research Service:
<ent type='ORG'>Merck</ent> was the official chief of all U.S. research into biological
warfare from 1942 until at least the end of World War  II.  After
1944,  <ent type='ORG'>Merck</ent>'sorganization  was  placed under the U.S. Chemical
Warfare Service. His family firm in <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y and <ent type='GPE'>the United <ent type='ORG'>State</ent>s</ent>
was famous for its manufacture of morphine.
 sb|{James H. McGraw, Jr.,} chairman of McGraw Hill  Publishing
Company,  was a member of the advisory board to the U.S. Chemical
Warfare Service and a member of  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='ORG'>Army</ent>  Ordnance  Association
<ent type='ORG'>Committee</ent> on Endowment.
 sb|{Fred  H.  Haggerson,}  chairmanof  Union  Carbide Corp.,
produced munitions, chemicals, and firearms.
 sb|{A.L.  Cole} was useful to  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='LOC'>Jupiter</ent>Islanders  as  an
executive  of  {<ent type='ORG'>Readers <ent type='ORG'>Digest</ent></ent>.} In 1965, just after performing a
rather dirty favor for George Bush [which will be discussed ina
comingchapter--ed.],Cole  became  chairmanof  the executive
committee  of  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>{<ent type='ORG'>Digest</ent>,}  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>world's largest-circulation
periodical.
 From the late 1940s, <ent type='LOC'>Jupiter</ent> Island has served as a center for
the direction  of  covert  action  by  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>U.S.  government and,
indeed, for the covert management of  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>government.  <ent type='LOC'>Jupiter</ent>
Islandwill  reappear later on, in our account of George Bush in
the <ent type='GPE'>Iran</ent>-Contra affair.</p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>Target</ent>: <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent></p>

<p> George Bush graduated from <ent type='ORG'>Yale</ent> in 1948. He soon  entered  the
family's  Dresser  oilsupplyconcern  in  <ent type='GPE'>Texas</ent>.  We shall now
briefly describe the forces that descended  on<ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>,  D.C.
duringthose  years when Bush, with the assistance of family and
powerful friends, was becoming <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>established in business  on  his
own.''
 From  1948  to 1950, Prescott Bush's boss <ent type='ORG'>Averell <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent></ent> was
U.S.  <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>ambassador-at-large'' to <ent type='LOC'>Europe</ent>. He  was  a  non-military
<ent type='ORG'>``</ent>Theater   Commander,''   <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent> administratorof  the
multi-billion-dollar  Marshall Plan, participating in all
military/strategic  decision-makingby the Anglo-<ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent>
alliance.
 The U.S. secretary of defense, James Forrestal, <ent type='GPE'>hadbecomea</ent>
problem to the <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>ites. Forrestal had long been an executive
at  <ent type='ORG'>Dillon</ent>  Read  on Wall Street. But in recent years he had gone
astray.  As secretary of the navy in 1944, Forrestal proposed the
racial integration of the <ent type='ORG'>Navy</ent>. As defense secretary, he  pressed
for  integration  in  the armed forces and this eventually became
the U.S. policy.
 Forrestal  opposed  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>utopians'  strategy  of appeasement
coupled with  brinkmanship. He was simply opposed to communism.
On March 28, 1949, Forrestal was forced out of office  and  flown
on  an <ent type='ORG'>Air Force</ent> plane to <ent type='GPE'>Florida</ent>. He was taken to <ent type='ORG'>``</ent><ent type='LOC'>Hobe Sound</ent>''
(<ent type='LOC'>Jupiter</ent> Island), where Robert Lovett and  an  army  psychiatrist
dealt with him.s8
 He  was  flown  back to <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, locked in Walter Reed <ent type='ORG'>Army</ent>
Hospital and given insulin shock treatments for alleged  <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>mental
exhaustion.''  He  wasdeniedall visitors except his estranged
wife and children--his son had been Averell  <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>'s  aide  in
<ent type='GPE'>Moscow</ent>.  On May 22, Forrestal's body was found, his bathrobe cord
tied tightly around  his  neck,  afterhe  had  plunged  froma
sixteenth-story hospital  window. The chief psychiatrist called
the death a suicide even before any  investigation  was  started.
The results  of the <ent type='ORG'>Army</ent>'s inquest were kept secret.  Forrestal's
diaries were published, 80  percent  deleted,  after  a  year  of
direct government censorship and rewriting.
  - * * * -
 <ent type='LOC'>North</ent>  <ent type='GPE'>Korea</ent>n  troops  invaded <ent type='GPE'>South <ent type='GPE'>Korea</ent></ent> in June 1950, after
U.S.  Secretary of <ent type='ORG'>State</ent>  DeanAcheson  (<ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>'s  very  close
friend)  publicly  specified  that  <ent type='GPE'>Korea</ent>  would not be defended.
With a new war on, <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>  came  back  to  serve  asPresident
Truman's adviser, to <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>oversee national security affairs.''
 <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent> replaced Clark Clifford, who had been special counsel
to Truman.  Clifford, however, remained close to <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent> and his
partners as  they  gained  more  and  more power.  Clifford later
wrote about his cordial relations with Prescott Bush:
 <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>Prescott Bush ... had become  oneof  myfrequent  golfing
partners  in  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>fifties,  and  I  had both liked and respected
him....  Bush had a  splendid  singingvoice,and  particularly
loved quartet  singing.  In the fifties, he organized a quartet
that  <ent type='GPE'>includedmy</ent>  daughter  Joyce....  Theywouldsing in
<ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>,  and, on occasion, he invited the group to <ent type='LOC'>Hobe Sound</ent>
in <ent type='GPE'>Florida</ent> to perform. His  son  [George],  though,  had  never
struck me  as a strong or forceful person.  In 1988, he presented
himself successfully to the voters as an outsider--no small trick
for a man whose roots wound through <ent type='GPE'>Connecticut</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Yale</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Texas</ent> oil,
<ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>,  a  patrician  background, wealth, and the Vice
Presidency.''s9</p>

<p> With  Forrestal  out  of  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>way,<ent type='ORG'>Averell <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent></ent> and Dean
Acheson drove to <ent type='GPE'>Leesburg</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Virginia</ent>, on July 1, 1950, to hire the
<ent type='NORP'>British</ent>-backed U.S. Gen.  George  C.  <ent type='ORG'>Marshallas</ent>  secretary  of
defense. At  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>same time, Prescott's partner, Robert Lovett,
himself became assistant secretary of defense.
 Lovett, Marshall,  <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>,  and  Acheson  went  to  work  to
unhorse Gen. Douglas<ent type='ORG'>MacArthur</ent>,  commander  of U.S.forces in
<ent type='LOC'>Asia</ent>. <ent type='ORG'>MacArthur</ent> kept Wall  Street's  intelligence  agencies  away
from his command, and favored real independence for the non-white
nations.  Lovett called for <ent type='ORG'>MacArthur</ent>'s firing on March 23, 1951,
citing<ent type='ORG'>MacArthur</ent>'s insistence on defeating the <ent type='NORP'>Communist</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Chinese</ent>
invaders in <ent type='GPE'>Korea</ent>. <ent type='ORG'>MacArthur</ent>'s famous  message,  that  there  was
<ent type='ORG'>``</ent>no  substitute  for victory,'' was read in <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent> on April 5;
<ent type='ORG'>MacArthur</ent> was fired on April 10, 1951.
 That September, Robert Lovett replaced Marshall  assecretary
of defense.  Meanwhile, <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent> was named director of the Mutual
Security  <ent type='ORG'>Agency</ent>, making him the U.S. chief of the Anglo-<ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent>
military alliance.  By  now,BrownBrothers <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent> was
everything but commander-in-chief.
  - * * * -
 These  were,  of  course,  exciting times for the Bush family,
whose wagon was hitched to  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>financial  gods  of  <ent type='ORG'>Olympus</ent>--to
<ent type='LOC'>Jupiter</ent>, that is.</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>Brown Brothers</ent><ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>  &amp; Co.  59 Wall Street, <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent> 5, N.Y.
Business Established 1818 Cable Address <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>Shipley-<ent type='GPE'>New York</ent>''
 Private Bankers
 April 2, 1951</p>

<p>The Honorable W.A. <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>, The <ent type='ORG'>White <ent type='ORG'>House</ent></ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, D.C.</p>

<p>Dear Averell:
 I was sorry to miss you  in<ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>  but  appreciate  your
cordial note.  I shall hope for better luck another time.
 I hope you had a good rest at <ent type='LOC'>Hobe Sound</ent>.
 With affectionate regard, I am,
 Sincerely yours,</p>

<p>  Pres [signed]
 Prescott S. Bush</p>

<p> A  central focus of the <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent> security regime in <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>
(1950-53)  was<ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>organization  of  covertoperations, and
<ent type='ORG'>``</ent>psychological  warfare.''  <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>,together with his lawyers
and business partners, Allen and John Foster <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent>,  wanted  the
government's  secret  servicesto  conduct  extensive propaganda
campaigns and mass-psychology experiments within the U.S.A.,  and
<ent type='ORG'>paramilitary campaignsabroad</ent>.  This would supposedly ensure a
stableworld-wide  environment favorable to Anglo-<ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent>
financial and political interests.
 The <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent> security  regime  created  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>Psychological
Strategy <ent type='ORG'>Board</ent> (<ent type='ORG'>PSB</ent>) in 1951. The man appointed director  of  the
<ent type='ORG'>PSB</ent>, Gordon <ent type='ORG'>Gray</ent>, is familiar to the reader as the sponsor of the
child  sterilization  experiments, carried out by the <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>ite
eugenics movement in <ent type='LOC'>North</ent> <ent type='GPE'>Carolina</ent> following World War II.
 Gordon <ent type='ORG'>Gray</ent> was an avid <ent type='NORP'>Anglophile</ent>, whose  father  had  gotten
controlling ownership  of  theR.J.Reynolds  Tobacco Company
through alliance with the <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> Imperial tobacco cartel's  U.S.
representatives, <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>Duke  family  of<ent type='LOC'>North</ent> <ent type='GPE'>Carolina</ent>.  Gordon's
brother, R.J. Reynolds chairman Bowman <ent type='ORG'>Gray</ent> Jr., was also a naval
intelligence officer, known around <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent> as the <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>founder of
operational intelligence.'' Gordon <ent type='ORG'>Gray</ent> became a close friend and
political ally of  Prescott  Bush;  and  <ent type='ORG'>Gray</ent>'s  son  became  for
Prescott's  son,  George, his lawyer and the shield of his covert
policy.
 ButPresident  Harry  Truman,  as  malleable ashe was,
constituted anobstacle  to  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>covert  warriors. An insular
<ent type='GPE'>Missouri</ent> politician vaguely favorable to <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>U.S.  Constitution,
he  remained  skeptical  aboutsecretservice  activities  that
reminded him of the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> Gestapo.
 So, <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>covert operations'' could not fully take off  withouta
change of  the <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent> regime.  And it was with the <ent type='NORP'>Republican</ent>
Party that Prescott Bush was to get his turn.</p>

<p> Prescott Runs for <ent type='ORG'>Senate</ent></p>

<p> Prescott had made his first attempt to enter national politics
in  1950,  as  his  partners  took  control  of  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>levers of
governmental power.  Remaining  in  charge  of  Brown  Brothers
<ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>, he ran against <ent type='GPE'>Connecticut</ent>'sWilliam  Benton  for  his
seat in  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>U.S.  <ent type='ORG'>Senate</ent>. (The race was actually for a two-year
unexpired  term,  leftempty  by  thedeath  of  the previous
senator).
 In  those days, <ent type='GPE'>Wisconsin</ent>'s drunken Senator Joseph R. McCarthy
was making a circus-like crusade against communist  influence  in
<ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>. <ent type='GPE'>McCarthyattacked</ent>  liberals  and  leftists,  <ent type='ORG'>State</ent>
Department personnel, politicians, <ent type='ORG'>andHollywood</ent>  figures.  He
generally  left  unscathed the Wall Street and <ent type='GPE'>London</ent> strategists
who donated<ent type='LOC'>East</ent>ern <ent type='LOC'>Europe</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>China</ent>  tocommunist
dictatorship--like George Bush, their geopolitics was beyond left
and right.
 Prescott  Bush  <ent type='GPE'>hadno</ent>  public  ties  to  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>notorious  Joe
McCarthy, and appeared to be neutral about his crusade.  But  the
<ent type='GPE'>Wisconsin</ent> senator had his  uses.Joe  McCarthy  came  into
<ent type='GPE'>Connecticut</ent> three times  that  year  to  campaign  forBush  and
against  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Democrat</ent>s</ent>.  Bushhimself  made charges of <ent type='ORG'>``</ent><ent type='GPE'>Korea</ent>,
Communism and Corruption'' into a slick campaign  phrase  against
Benton, which then turned up as a national <ent type='NORP'>Republican</ent> slogan.
 The response  was disappointing.  Only small crowds turned out
to hear Joe McCarthy,  and  Benton  was  not  hurt.  McCarthy's
pro-Bush  rally  in  <ent type='GPE'>New Haven</ent>, in a hall that seated 6000, drew
only 376 people.  Benton joked on the radio that  <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>200  of  them
were my spies.''
 Prescott  Bush resigned from the <ent type='ORG'>Yale</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Board</ent> of Fellows for his
campaign, and the board published a statement to the effect  that
<ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='ORG'>``</ent><ent type='ORG'>Yale</ent>  vote''  should  support  Bush--despite the fact that
Benton was a <ent type='ORG'>Yale</ent> man, and in many ways identical in  outlook  to
Bush. <ent type='ORG'>Yale</ent>'s Whiffenpoofsingers  appeared  regularly  for
Prescott's campaign.  None of this  was  particularly  effective,
however, with the voting population.s1s0
 Then Papa  Bush  ran into a completely unexpected problem.  At
that time, the old <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent> eugenics  movementwas  centered  at
<ent type='ORG'>Yale</ent> University. Prescott Bush was a <ent type='ORG'>Yale</ent> trustee, and his former
Brown  Brothers  <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>  partner,  Lawrence  Tighe,  was <ent type='ORG'>Yale</ent>'s
treasurer.  In that connection, a slight  glimmer  of  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>truth
about  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>Bush-<ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent> firm's <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> activities now made its way
into the campaign.
 Notonly was the <ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent> Eugenics <ent type='ORG'>Society</ent> itself
headquartered  at  <ent type='ORG'>Yale</ent>,  but  all  parts  of this undead fascist
movement had a busy home at <ent type='ORG'>Yale</ent>.  Thecoercive  psychiatry  and
sterilization  advocates had made the <ent type='ORG'>Yale</ent>/<ent type='GPE'>New Haven</ent> Hospital and
<ent type='ORG'>Yale</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Medical School</ent> their laboratories for hands-on  practice  in
brain surgery  and  psychological experimentation.  And the Birth
Control League was there, which had long trumpeted theneed  for
eugenical  births--fewer  births  for  parentswith <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>inferior''
bloodlines.  Prescott's partner Tighe was a <ent type='GPE'>Connecticut</ent>  director
of  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>league, and the <ent type='GPE'>Connecticut</ent> league's medical advisor was
the eugenics advocate, Dr.  Winternitz of <ent type='ORG'>Yale</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Medical School</ent>.
 Now in 1950, people who knew  something  about  Prescott  Bush
knew  that  hehad very unsavory roots in the eugenics movement.
There were  then,  just  after<ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>anti-Hitler  war,few  open
advocates ofsterilization  of  <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>unfit''  or  <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>unnecessary''
people.  (That would be revived later, with the help  of  General
<ent type='ORG'>Draper</ent>and his friend George Bush.) But <ent type='ORG'>the Birth Control League</ent>
was public--just about then itwas  changing  its  name  to  the
euphemistic <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>Planned Parenthood.''
 Then, very late in the 1950 senatorial campaign, Prescott Bush
was publicly exposed for being an activist in that section of the
old fascist  eugenics  movement.  Prescott Bush lost the election
by about 1000 out of 862000 votes.  He and  his  family  blamed
the defeat  on<ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>exposeaa.  <ent type='ORG'>The  </ent>defeat was burned into the
family's memory, leaving a bitterness and perhaps  a  desire  for
revenge.
 In  his  foreword  to  a  population  control propaganda book,
George Bush wrote  about  that1950  election:  <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>My  own  first
awareness  of  birth control as a public policy issue came with a
jolt in 1950 when my father was running for United <ent type='ORG'>State</ent>s  <ent type='ORG'>Senate</ent>
in <ent type='GPE'>Connecticut</ent>.  Drew <ent type='ORG'>Pearson</ent>, on the Sunday before Election day,
`revealed' that my father wasinvolved with Planned
Parenthod....  Many political observers felt a sufficient  number
of  voters  were  swayed  by  his alleged contacts with the birth
controllers to cost him the election....''s1s1
 Prescott Bush gave a graphic description ofthese  events  in
his  <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>oral  history'' interview at <ent type='ORG'>Columbia University</ent>: <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>In the
1950 campaign, when I ran against Benton,  thevery  last  week,
Drew  <ent type='ORG'>Pearson</ent>,famouscolumnist, was running a radio program at
that time....  In this particular broadcast, just at <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>end  of
our  campaign [<ent type='ORG'>Pearson</ent> said]: <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>I predict that Benton will retain
his seat in <ent type='GPE'>the United <ent type='ORG'>State</ent>s</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Senate</ent>, because it  has  just  been
made  known that Prescott Bush, his opponent, is president of the
Birth Control <ent type='ORG'>Society</ent>'' or  chairman,  member  of  theboard  of
directors,  or something, <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>of the Birth Control <ent type='ORG'>Society</ent>. In this
country,  and  of  course  with  <ent type='GPE'>Connecticut</ent>'s heavy <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>
population,  and its laws against birth control ... this is going
to be too much for Bush to rise above.Benton will  be  elected.
I predict.''
 Thenext  Sunday, they handed out, at these <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> Churches
in <ent type='GPE'>Waterbury</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Torrington</ent> and  <ent type='GPE'>Bridgeport</ent>,  handbills,  quoting
Drew  <ent type='ORG'>Pearson</ent>'s  statement  on the radio about Prescott Bush, you
see--I predict.  Well, my telephone started ringing  that  Sunday
at home, and when I'd answer, or Dotty [Prescott's wife, George's
mother]  wouldanswer--<ent type='ORG'>``</ent>Is  this  true,  what  they  say  about
Prescott Bush?This can't be true.  Is it true?''
 She'd say, <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>No, it isn't true.'' Of course, it  wasn't  true.
But  you  never  catchup with a thing like this--the election's
just day after tomorrow, you see?  So there's no  doubt,  in  the
estimate  of  our  political leaders, that this one thing cost me
many thousand votes--whether it was 1, 3, 5  or  10  thousand  we
don't know,  we  can't possibly tell, but it was enough.  To have
overcome that thousand vote, it would only have  had  to  be  600
switch [sic].
 [Mrs.  Bushthen  corrected  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>timing  in  Prescott Bush's
recollections.]
 <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>I'd forgotten the exact sequence, but that was it....  The
state  then--and  I  think  still  is--probably  about 55 percent
<ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> population,  with  all  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='NORP'>Italian</ent>  derivation  people
[sic],and <ent type='NORP'>Polish</ent> is very heavy, and the <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> church is very
dominant here, and the archbishop was death on this birth control
thing. They  fought  repeal  every  time  itcame  up  in  the
legislature,  and {we never did get rid of that prohibition until
just a year or two ago,} as I recall it [emphasis added].s1s2</p>

<p> Prescott  Bush  wasdefeated,  while  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>other <ent type='NORP'>Republican</ent>
candidates  fared  well in <ent type='GPE'>Connecticut</ent>. He attributed his loss to
the <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> Church. After all, he had dependable friends in  the
news media.  <ent type='ORG'>The  </ent>{New  York<ent type='ORG'>Time</ent>s}loved  him  for his bland
pleasantness.  He just about owned <ent type='ORG'>CBS</ent>. Twenty  years  earlier,
Prescott  Bushhad  personally  organized  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>credit  to allow
William S. Paley to buy the <ent type='ORG'>CBS</ent> (radio, later television) network
outright.  In return,  Prescott  was  made  a  director  and  the
financial  leader of <ent type='ORG'>CBS</ent>; Paley himself became a devoted follower
and servitor of <ent type='ORG'>Averell <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent></ent>.
 Well, when he tried again, Prescott Bush would not  leave  the
outcome to the blind whims of the public.
 Prescott  Bush  moved into action in 1952 as a national leader
of the push to give <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='NORP'>Republican</ent>  presidential  nomination  to
Gen. Dwight D. (<ent type='ORG'>``</ent>Ike'') Eisenhower. Among the other team members
were  Bush's  Hitler-era  lawyer  John Foster <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent>, and <ent type='LOC'>Jupiter</ent>
Islander C. Douglas <ent type='ORG'>Dillon</ent>.
 <ent type='ORG'>Dillon</ent> and his father were the pivots as  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>-<ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent>
combination readied  Ike for the presidency.  As a friend put it:
<ent type='ORG'>``</ent>When the <ent type='ORG'>Dillon</ent>s ... invited [Eisenhower] to dinner it  was  to
introduce him to Wall Street bankers and lawyers.''s1s3
 Ike's higher level backers believed, correctly, that Ike would
not  interferewith  even  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>dirtiest  of their covert action
programs.  The bland, pleasant Prescott  Bush  was  infrom  the
beginning:  a  friend  to  Ike,  and  an  original  backer of his
presidency.
 On July 28, 1952, as <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>election  approached,  <ent type='GPE'>Connecticut</ent>'s
senior U.S.  senator, James O'Brien McMahon, died at the age of
48. (McMahon had been Assistant U.S. Attorney General, in  charge
of  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='ORG'>Criminal Division</ent>, from 1935 to 1939. Was there a chance
he might someday speak out about the unpunished  <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>-era  crimes
of the wealthy and powerful?)
 This  was  {extremely}  convenient  for  Prescott.  He got the
<ent type='NORP'>Republican</ent> nomination for U.S. senatorat  a  specialdelegated
meeting, with backing by<ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='ORG'>Yale</ent>-dominated  state  party
leadership.  Now he would run  in  a  special  election  for  the
suddenly vacant  <ent type='ORG'>Senate</ent>  seat. He could expect to be swept into
office, since he would be on the same  electoral  ticket  as  the
popular  war  hero,  General  Ike.  Bya  technicality, he would
instantly become <ent type='GPE'>Connecticut</ent>'s senior senator, with  extra  power
in  <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>.  And  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>next regularly scheduled senatorial race
would be in 1956 (whenMcMahon's  term  wouldhave  ended),  so
Prescott  could  run again in that presidential election year ...
once again on Ike's coattails!</p>

<p> With this arrangement, things worked out very  smoothly.  In
Eisenhower's  1952  election  victory,Ike  won <ent type='GPE'>Connecticut</ent> by a
margin of 129507 votes out of 1092471. Prescott Bush  came  in
last  among  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>statewide  <ent type='NORP'>Republican</ent>s,  butmanaged to win by
30373out  of  1088799,  his  margin  nearly  100000  behind
Eisenhower. He took the traditionally <ent type='NORP'>Republican</ent> towns.
 In  Eisenhower's  1956  re-election,  Ike  won  <ent type='GPE'>Connecticut</ent> by
303036 out of 1114954 votes, the largest  presidential  margin
in <ent type='GPE'>Connecticut</ent>'s history.  Prescott Bush managed to win again, by
129544  votesout  of  1085206--his  margin this time 290082
smaller than Eisenhower's.s1s4
 In January 1963, when this electoral strategy had been  played
out  and  his  second  term  expired,  Prescott Bush retired from
government and returned to <ent type='ORG'><ent type='ORG'>Brown Brothers</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent></ent>.
 The 1952 Eisenhower victory made John Foster <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent>Secretary
of  <ent type='ORG'>State</ent>,  and  his  brother  Allen  <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent> head of the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>. The
reigning <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent> brothers were the <ent type='ORG'>``</ent><ent type='NORP'>Republican</ent>'' replacements for
their  client  and businesspartner, <ent type='ORG'>``</ent><ent type='NORP'>Democrat</ent>'' Averell
<ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>. Occasionalpublicposturings aside, their strategic
commitments were identical to his.
 Undoubtedly the most important work accomplished  by  Prescott
Bush in the new regime was on the golf links.
 Those  who  remember  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>Eisenhower presidency know that Ike
played ...  quite a bit of golf!  <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Democrat</ent>s</ent> sneered  at  him  for
mindlessness,  <ent type='NORP'>Republican</ent>s  defended  him for taking this healthy
recreation.  Golf was Ike's ruling passion. And  there  at  his
side was the loyal, bland, pleasant Senator Prescott Bush, former
president  of  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>U.S. Golf Association, son-in-law of the very
man who had reformulated the rules of the game.
 Prescott Bush was Dwight Eisenhower's favorite  golf  partner.
Prescott  could  reassure  Ikeabout  his  counselors, allay his
concerns, and monitor his  moods.  Ike  was  very  grateful  to
Prescott, who never revealed the President's scores.
 <ent type='ORG'>Thepublicimage</ent> of his relationship to the President may be
gleaned from a 1956 newspaper profile of Prescott Bush's role  in
the party.  <ent type='ORG'>The  </ent>{New  York  <ent type='ORG'>Time</ent>s,}which 11 years before had
consciously protected him from public exposure as a <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>  banker,
fawned overhim  in  an  article  entitled,  <ent type='ORG'>``</ent><ent type='ORG'>HisPlatform</ent>:
Eisenhower'':<ent type='ORG'>``</ent>A tall, lean, well-dressed man who  looks  exactly
like what he is--a wealthy product of <ent type='ORG'>the Ivy League</ent>--is chairman
of the<ent type='NORP'>Republican</ent>  Convention's  platform  committee. As such,
Prescott Bush, <ent type='GPE'>Connecticut</ent>'s senior United <ent type='ORG'>State</ent>s Senator, <ent type='GPE'>hasa</ent>
difficult  task:  he  has to take one word and expand it to about
5000.
 <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>The one word, of course, is  `Ike'--but  no  party  platform
could ever be so simple and direct....
 <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>Thus  it  is  that  Senator  Bushand  his fellow committee
members ... find themselves confronted with the job  of  wrapping
around<ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>name  Eisenhower sufficient verbiage to persuade the
public that it is the principles of the party, and not<ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>grin
of  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>man  at  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>head  of  it,  which  makes  itworthy of
endorsement in [the] November [election].
 <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>For this task Prescott  Bush,  a  singularly  practical  and
direct conservative,  may  notbe entirely fitted.  It is likely
that left to his own devices he would simply  offer  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>country
the one word and let it go at that.
 <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>He  is  ...  convinced  that  this would be enough to do the
trick ... if only the game were played that way.</p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>Since it is not, he can be expected to preside with dignity,
fairness and dispatch over the sessions  that  will  prepare  the
party credo for the 1956 campaign.
 <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>If  by  chance  there  should  beany  conflicts within the
committee ...  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>Senator's  past  can  offer  a  clue  to  his
conduct.
 <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>Aformer<ent type='ORG'>Yale</ent>  Glee  Club  and second bass in the All-<ent type='ORG'>Time</ent>
Whiffenpoofs  Quartet,he is ...[called] `the hottest
close-harmony man at <ent type='ORG'>Yale</ent> in a span of twenty-five years.'
 <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>Close  harmony  being a <ent type='NORP'>Republican</ent> specialty under President
Eisenhower, the hottest close-harmony man at <ent type='ORG'>Yale</ent> in  twenty-five
years  would seem to be an ideal choice for the convention job he
holds at <ent type='GPE'>San Francisco</ent>....
 <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>[In addition to his business  background,he]  also  played
golf, competing  in  a number of tournaments.  For eight years he
was a member of the executive committee of <ent type='GPE'>the United <ent type='ORG'>State</ent>s</ent> Golf
Association....
 <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>As a Senator, <ent type='GPE'>Connecticut</ent>'s senior  spokeman  in  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>upper
house  has  followed  conservative  policies  consistent with his
business background.
 He resigned all his corporate directorships, took a leave from
<ent type='ORG'>Brown Brothers</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>, and proceeded to go down theline  for
the Eisenhower program....
 <ent type='ORG'>``</ent>Around  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='ORG'>Senate</ent>,  he  is  known  as  a  man who does his
committee work faithfully, defends  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='ORG'>Administration</ent>  stoutly,
and fits well into theclublike  atmosphere  of  Capitol
Hill....''s1s5
 {To be continued.}</p>

<p>  Notes</p>

<p>1.
 Walter Isaacson and Evan Thomas, {The Wise Men}: Six Friends and
the World They Made--Acheson, Bohlen, <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent>,  Kennan,  Lovett,
McCloy} (<ent type='GPE'>New York</ent>: Simon and Schuster, 1986), p.  377.</p>

<p>2.
 Reed  was  better known in high society as a minor diplomat, the
founder of the Triton <ent type='ORG'>Press</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>presidentof  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent><ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent>
Shakespeare Theater.</p>

<p>3.
 {<ent type='GPE'>Palm Beach</ent> Post,} January 13, 1991.</p>

<p>4.
 For  Lovett'sresidency  there  see  Isaacson  and Thomas, {op.
cit.,} p.  417. Some <ent type='LOC'>Jupiter</ent> Island residencies were verified  by
their  inclusion  in  <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>1947 membership list of the <ent type='LOC'>Hobe Sound</ent>
Yacht Club, in the <ent type='ORG'>Harriman</ent> papers, Library of<ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>;  others
were established from interviews with  long-time  <ent type='LOC'>Jupiter</ent>
Islanders.</p>

<p>5.
 Arthur  Burr  Darling,  {<ent type='ORG'>The  </ent>CentralIntelligence  <ent type='ORG'>Agency</ent>:  An
Instrument of Government,to 1950}, (College Station:
Pennsylvania <ent type='ORG'>State</ent> University, 1990), p.  59.</p>

<p>6. The {<ent type='ORG'><ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> Tribune</ent>}, Feb 9, 1945,for  example,  warned  of
<ent type='ORG'>``</ent>Creation  of an all-powerful intelligence service to spy on the
postwar world and to pry into <ent type='ORG'>the  </ent>lives  of  citizensat  home.
{Cf. Anthony Cave Brown, {Wild Bill Donovan: The Last Hero}, (New
York: <ent type='ORG'>Time</ent>s  Books,  1982), p.625, on warnings to FDR about the
<ent type='NORP'>British</ent> control of U.S. intelligence.</p>

<p>7. Dennis Eisenberg, Uri Dan, Eli Landau, {Meyer Lansky: Mogul of
the Mob} (<ent type='GPE'>New York</ent>: Paddington <ent type='ORG'>Press</ent>, 1979) pp.  227-28.</p>

<p>8. See John Ranelagh, {The <ent type='ORG'>Agency</ent>: The Rise and  Decline  of  the
<ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>}, (<ent type='GPE'>New York</ent>: Simon and Schuster, 1987), pp.  131-32.</p>

<p>9.  Clark  Clifford, {Counsel to the President} (<ent type='GPE'>New York</ent>: Random
<ent type='ORG'>House</ent>, 1991).</p>

<p>10. Sidney Hyman, {The Life  of  William  Benton}  (<ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>:  The
University of <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Press</ent>, 1969), pp.  438-41.</p>

<p>11.  Phyllis Tilson Piotrow, {World Population Crisis: The United
<ent type='ORG'>State</ent>sResponse} (<ent type='GPE'>New York</ent>: Praeger Publishers, 1973),
<ent type='ORG'>``</ent>Forward'' by George H.W. Bush, p.  vii.</p>

<p>12.  Interviewwith  <ent type='ORG'>PrescottBush</ent> in the Oral History Research
Project conducted by  <ent type='ORG'>ColumbiaUniversity</ent>  in1966,  Eisenhower
<ent type='ORG'>Administration</ent> Part II; pp.  62-4.</p>

<p>13.  Herbert  S.  Parmet,  {Eisenhower and the <ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n</ent> Crusades}
(<ent type='GPE'>New York</ent>: <ent type='ORG'>The Macmillan Company</ent>, 1972), p.  14.</p>

<p>14. {<ent type='GPE'>New York</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Time</ent>s}, Sept. 6, 1952, Nov. 5, 1952, Nov. 7, 1956.</p>

<p>15. {<ent type='GPE'>New York</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Time</ent>s}, Aug. 21, 1956.</p>

<p>Any comments, please send by email, as I get very far  behind  on
this group.</p>

<p>Thanks.</p>

<p> John Covici

coviciccs.covici.com
</p></xml>