<xml><p>
  <ent type='ORG'>CHRONOLOGY</ent> OF SECRET SOCIETIES
  Excerpted from THE OCCULT CONSPIRACY
  by Michael Howard
  Published by Destiny Books
  Pages 179 - 183
  ------------------------------------------------------------------</p>

<p>  40000 BCE
  Early establishment of Mystery schools, as depicted in the <ent type='LOC'>Lascaux</ent>
  cave paintings.</p>

<p>  30000 BCE
  According to some occult traditions this period saw the
  colonization of <ent type='LOC'>Asia</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Australasia</ent> by the inhabitants of the
  lost continent of <ent type='GPE'>Lemuria</ent> or Mu.  Goddess worship and matriaarchal
  cultures established worldwide.</p>

<p>  10000 BCE
  Evidence suggestive of early contact between extraterrestials and
  Stone Age tribes in <ent type='GPE'>Tibet</ent>.</p>

<p>  9000 - 8000 BCE
  Estimated date of the destruction of Atlantis, according to some
  occult traditions.  <ent type='ORG'>The Atlantean</ent> priesthood flee to establish
  colonies in the <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> Isles, <ent type='LOC'>Western Europe</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>North Africa</ent> and
  <ent type='LOC'>South America</ent>.  Rise of the Northern Mystery Tradition centered on
  the island of Thule and the <ent type='NORP'>Aryan</ent> culture.  Invention of the runic
  alphabet.</p>

<p>  5000 BCE
  First primitive cities established in <ent type='LOC'>the Middle East</ent>.
  Agriculture begins with domestication of animals such as sheep and
  goats.  Possible contact between extraterrestials and early
  <ent type='NORP'>Sumerian</ent> culture.</p>

<p>  5000 - 3000 BCE
  Formation of the two lands in pre-dynastic <ent type='GPE'>Egypt</ent> ruled by
  outsiders (Isis and <ent type='ORG'>Osiris</ent>).  The <ent type='GPE'>Egypt</ent>ian pantheon of gods
  established including Horus, Thoth, Set, Ra, Ptah and Hathor.
  Pharoahs regarded as the divine representatives of the Gods.</p>

<p>  3000 - 2000 BCE
  Building of burial mounds and chambered tombs in <ent type='LOC'>Western Europe</ent>
  and the <ent type='LOC'>Mediterranean</ent> area; the <ent type='LOC'>Sphinx</ent> and <ent type='LOC'>the Great Pyramids</ent> of
  <ent type='GPE'>Giza</ent> and Cheops of <ent type='GPE'>Egypt</ent>; and <ent type='ORG'>the ziggurat</ent> (Towers of Babel) in
  Ur.  <ent type='ORG'>Sarmoung Brotherhood</ent> founded in <ent type='GPE'>Babylon</ent>.</p>

<p>  2000 - 1000 BCE
  Reign of <ent type='ORG'>Thothmes III</ent> in <ent type='GPE'>Egypt</ent> (c. 1480).  <ent type='ORG'>Foundation</ent> of the
  Rosicrucian <ent type='ORG'>Order</ent>.  Reign of Akhenaton (c. 1370) who establishes
  the mystical Brotherhood of Aton dedicated to the worship of the
  <ent type='ORG'>Sun</ent> as a symbol of the Supreme Creator.  Erection of Stonehenge
  and other megalithic stone circles in the <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> Isles.  Reign of
  Ankhenaton's son Tutankhamun who re-establishes the old pantheon
  of <ent type='GPE'>Egypt</ent>ian gods and goddesses.  Moses leads Children of Israel
  out of slavery in <ent type='GPE'>Egypt</ent> during the reign of Ramses II to the
  promised land of <ent type='GPE'>Canaan</ent>.</p>

<p>  1000 - 500 BCE
  <ent type='ORG'>Foundation</ent> of the <ent type='NORP'>Dionysian</ent> Artificers.  The building of <ent type='GPE'>Solomon</ent>'s
  temple (c. 950).  Establishment of the city states of <ent type='GPE'>Greece</ent> and
  the <ent type='ORG'>Olympic</ent> pantheon of gods to replace earlier Nature worship.
  First temples erected in <ent type='GPE'>Mexico</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Peru</ent> and southwest <ent type='LOC'>North America</ent>.
  <ent type='NORP'>Celts</ent> invade <ent type='LOC'>Western Europe</ent>.  Decline of Goddess worship and rise
  of patriarchal sky gods personified by priest-kings.  <ent type='GPE'>Rome</ent> founded
  in 750.</p>

<p>  500 BCE - 001 CE
  <ent type='NORP'>Celtic</ent> culture established in <ent type='GPE'>Britain</ent>.  The foundation of Druidic
  wisdom colleges in <ent type='GPE'>Gaul</ent> and the <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> Isles.  Odin recognized as
  major god in the Northern Mysteries replacing the Mother Goddess
  and is credited with inventing the runes.  Buddha, Lao Tze,
  Confucius, Pythagoras, Plato and Zoroaster preach their new
  religions and philosophies.  Maya culture in <ent type='LOC'>South America</ent>.
  Establishment of <ent type='NORP'>Eleusinian</ent> mystery cults.  Rise of the Essene
  sect in <ent type='GPE'>Palestine</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Judea</ent>.  Birth of Jesus of <ent type='GPE'>Nazareth</ent>.</p>

<p>  001 - 400 CE
  Jesus possibly travels to <ent type='GPE'>India</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Tibet</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Britain</ent> to be initiated
  into the esoteric traditions of <ent type='LOC'>East</ent> and West.  Crucified for his
  radical political and religious ideas (c. 33).  Joseph of
  Arimanthea establishes first <ent type='NORP'>Celtic</ent> Church at Glastonbury (c. 37).
  Invasion of <ent type='GPE'>Britain</ent> by <ent type='NORP'>Roman</ent> legions and suppression of the Druids
  (40 - 60).  Paul travels to <ent type='LOC'>Asia</ent> Minor and <ent type='GPE'>Greece</ent> preaching his
  version of the gospel (50).  <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> revolt against <ent type='NORP'>Roman</ent> rule led
  by Zealots (66).  <ent type='ORG'>Essenes</ent> suppressed and Dead Sea Scrolls hidden
  in caves.  <ent type='GPE'>Temple</ent> in <ent type='GPE'>Jerusalem</ent> destroyed by <ent type='NORP'>Roman</ent>s (70).  New
  testament written.  The Nazarenes break away from Judasim to found
  <ent type='ORG'>the Christian Church</ent> (c. 80).  Ormus is converted to Esoteric
  <ent type='NORP'>Christianity</ent> by Mark.  Mithrasim and the Mysteries of Isis compete
  with <ent type='NORP'>Christianity</ent> in the <ent type='NORP'>Roman</ent> Empire.  Mani, a <ent type='NORP'>Persian</ent> high
  priest of <ent type='NORP'>Zoroastrianism</ent>, is crucified (276).  Emperor Constantine
  declares <ent type='NORP'>Christianity</ent> the official religion of the <ent type='NORP'>Roman</ent> Empire.
  <ent type='ORG'>The Council</ent> of Nicea defines heresy, condemns <ent type='NORP'>pagan</ent>ism and lays
  the theological foundation for the <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> or <ent type='ORG'>Universal Church</ent>
  (325).  Constantine's successor Julian the Apostate (361 - 363)
  briefly re-establishes the <ent type='NORP'>pagan</ent> old religion.  Emperor Theodosius
  outlaws the worship of the <ent type='NORP'>pagan</ent> gods in <ent type='GPE'>Rome</ent> and closes the <ent type='NORP'>pagan</ent>
  temples (378).  Invasion of <ent type='GPE'>Rome</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Greece</ent> and <ent type='LOC'>Europe</ent> by the
  barbarians led by Atilla the Hun (395-480).  Withdrawal of the
  <ent type='NORP'>Roman</ent> legions from <ent type='GPE'>Britain</ent> (395).  <ent type='ORG'>Foundation</ent> of <ent type='ORG'>the Order</ent> of
  Comacine by ex-members of the <ent type='NORP'>Roman</ent> College of Architects.</p>

<p>  500 - 1000 CE
  Mohammed founds <ent type='ORG'>Islam</ent> (dies 632).  <ent type='NORP'>Celtic</ent> Church outlawed by
  Council of Whitby (664).  <ent type='ORG'>Foundation</ent> of first <ent type='NORP'>Sufi</ent> secret
  societies (c. 700).  First written translation of <ent type='ORG'>Emerald Tablet</ent>
  of Hermes Trismegistus.  <ent type='ORG'>Charlemagne</ent> founds alleged first
  Rosicrucian Lodge in <ent type='GPE'>Toulouse</ent> (898).  <ent type='ORG'>Foundation</ent> of <ent type='ORG'>the Cathars</ent>,
  Druzes and <ent type='GPE'>Yezedi</ent> (900).  Heretical <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> monks found first
  Rosicrucian college (1000).</p>

<p>  1000 - 1400 CE
  <ent type='ORG'>Foundation</ent> of <ent type='ORG'>the Order</ent> of the Devoted of Assassins by
  Hasan-i-Sabbah (1034-1124) and <ent type='ORG'>the Order</ent> of St John (1050).  First
  Crusade to the Holy Land (1095).  Capture of the city of <ent type='GPE'>Jerusalem</ent>
  by Godfrey de Bouillan, founder of the Priory of <ent type='GPE'>Sion</ent> (1099).
  Assassins infiltrate Thuggee cult in <ent type='GPE'>India</ent>.  <ent type='ORG'>Foundation</ent> of the
  <ent type='ORG'>Order</ent> of the Knights of the <ent type='GPE'>Temple</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>Solomon</ent> in <ent type='GPE'>Jerusalem</ent> (1118).
  Charter granted to the Priory of <ent type='GPE'>Sion</ent> by Pope Alexander II (1178).
  Crusade launched against Cathars (1208).  Inquistion created to
  fight heresy (1215).  Massacre of <ent type='ORG'>the Cathars</ent> at Montsegur in
  <ent type='LOC'>Southern France</ent> (1241).  Troubadours practising their cult of
  courtly love.  Occult schools teaching the <ent type='GPE'>Cabbala</ent> and alchemy
  established in <ent type='GPE'>Spain</ent> by the <ent type='ORG'>Moors</ent>.  Count Rudolf von <ent type='GPE'>Hapsburg</ent>
  crowned as Holy <ent type='NORP'>Roman</ent> Emperor (1273).  <ent type='ORG'>Knights Templars</ent> arrested
  by King Philip of <ent type='GPE'>France</ent> on charges of devil worship, heresy and
  sexual perversion (1307).  Last official Grand Master of the
  <ent type='ORG'>Templar</ent>s, Jacques de Molay, burnt at the stake and <ent type='ORG'>the Order</ent> goes
  underground (1314).</p>

<p>  1400 - 1600 CE
  Alleged life of Christian Rosenkreutz (1379-1482).  <ent type='ORG'>Foundation</ent>
  of <ent type='ORG'>the Order</ent> of the Garter by Edward III (1348).  First
  publication of the Corpus Heremeticum by the <ent type='ORG'>Medici</ent> family in
  <ent type='GPE'>Italy</ent> (1460).  Publication of Malleus Malifiracum and the papal
  bull of Pope Innocent which began the medieval witch hunting
  hysteria (1484 and 1486).  Martin Luther begins Reformation
  (1521).  Henry Agrippa refers to <ent type='ORG'>the Templars</ent> as Gnostics and
  worshippers of the phallic god Priapus (1530).  Life of Dr John
  Dee (1527-1608).  <ent type='ORG'>Foundation</ent> of the <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> Secret Service by Sir
  Francis Walsingham.  Birth of Johann Valenti Andrea (1586).  Life
  of Sir Francis Bacon (1561-1626).  Defeat of the Spanish Armada,
  with magical help from the <ent type='ORG'>New Forest Witches</ent> (1588).</p>

<p>  1600 - 1700 CE
  <ent type='ORG'>Foundation</ent> of <ent type='ORG'>the Virginia Company</ent> by James I (1606).  The
  <ent type='NORP'>Roman</ent>ovs become Czars of <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent> (1613).  Publication of
  Rosicrucian manifesto (1614).  Life of Elias Ashmole (1617-1692).
  Voyage of the <ent type='ORG'>Mayflower</ent> to <ent type='LOC'>New England</ent> and the publication of Sir
  Francis Bacon's novel The New Atlantis (1620).  Establishment of
  the <ent type='NORP'>pagan</ent> community of <ent type='GPE'>Merrymount</ent> in <ent type='GPE'>Massachusetts</ent> by Thomas
  Morton.  <ent type='NORP'>English</ent> Civil War begins (1642).  First <ent type='NORP'>English</ent> <ent type='GPE'>Mason</ent>
  guild accepts non-stonemasons into its meetings (c. 1646).
  Charles I convicted of treason and beheaded (1649).  Oliver
  Cromwell allegedly makes pact with the Devil in order to retain
  power.  Introduction of Freemasonry to <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> colonies by <ent type='NORP'>Dutch</ent>
  settlers (1658).  <ent type='ORG'>Order</ent> of <ent type='NORP'>Pietists</ent> founded in <ent type='GPE'>Pennsylvania</ent>
  (1694).</p>

<p>  1700 - 1800 CE
  Birth of the Comte de Saint-Germain (1710).  <ent type='GPE'>Mason</ent>ic Grand Lodge
  of <ent type='GPE'>England</ent> and Druid <ent type='ORG'>Order</ent> founded (1717).  First <ent type='GPE'>Mason</ent>ic lodge
  founded in <ent type='GPE'>France</ent> (1721)&gt;  Benjamin <ent type='ORG'>Franklin</ent> initiated as <ent type='GPE'>Mason</ent>
  (1731).  Chevalier Alexander Ramsey informs <ent type='NORP'>French</ent> <ent type='GPE'>Mason</ent>s that
  they are heirs to the <ent type='ORG'>Templar</ent> tradition (1736).  <ent type='NORP'>Roman</ent> Church
  condemns <ent type='GPE'>Mason</ent>ry (1738).  Birth of Count Cagliostro.  Comte de
  Saint-Germain involved in <ent type='NORP'>Jacobite</ent> plot to restore <ent type='ORG'>Stuart dynasty</ent>
  to the <ent type='NORP'>English</ent> Throne (1743).  Society of <ent type='ORG'>Flagellants</ent> and Skopski
  founded in <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent> (1750).  George <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent> initiated as a <ent type='GPE'>Mason</ent>
  (1752).  Sir Francis Dashwood founds the Hell Fire Club.  <ent type='ORG'>Franklin</ent>
  visits <ent type='GPE'>England</ent> to discuss the future of <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> colonies with
  Dashwood (1758).  <ent type='ORG'>Foundation</ent> of the Rite of the Strict Observance
  by Baron von Hund based on the <ent type='ORG'>Templar</ent> tradition.  Frederick of
  <ent type='GPE'>Prussia</ent> founds <ent type='ORG'>Order</ent> of the Architects of <ent type='LOC'>Africa</ent> and uses the
  title <ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent> to describe his neo-<ent type='GPE'>Mason</ent>ic lodges (1768).
  <ent type='ORG'>Franklin</ent> elected Grand Master of the Nine Sisters lodge in <ent type='GPE'>Paris</ent>
  (1770).  <ent type='LOC'>Grand Orient</ent> founded in <ent type='GPE'>France</ent> (1771).  <ent type='ORG'>Boston Tea Party</ent>
  (1773).  <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent> appointed Commander-in-Chief of the new
  <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> Army (1775).  <ent type='ORG'>Order</ent> of Perfectibilists or <ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent>
  founded.  <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> Revolution (1776).  Czar Peter founds the
  Secret Circle (1778).  Supposed death of the Comte Saint-Germain
  (1784).  Grand <ent type='GPE'>Mason</ent>ic <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent> allegedly plots <ent type='NORP'>French</ent> Revolution.
  Cagliostro involved in <ent type='ORG'>Diamond Necklace Affair</ent>.  <ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent> banned
  in <ent type='GPE'>Bavaria</ent> and goes underground (1785).  <ent type='NORP'>French</ent> Revolution (1789).
  <ent type='GPE'>Illuminist</ent> conspiracy to overthrow the <ent type='GPE'>Hapsburg</ent>s (1794).</p>

<p>  1800 - 1900 CE
  Count Grabinka founds secret society in St. <ent type='GPE'>Petersburg</ent> based on
  <ent type='NORP'>Martinism</ent> and Rosicrucianism (1803).  <ent type='NORP'>French</ent> <ent type='NORP'>republican</ent> plot to
  assassinate Napoleon by placing a bomb under his coach, led by
  occultist Fabre d'Olivet.  Emperor Napoleon takes control of
  <ent type='NORP'>French</ent> <ent type='GPE'>Mason</ent>ry (1805).  Revived <ent type='ORG'>Templar</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Order</ent> in <ent type='GPE'>France</ent> celebrates
  the martyrdom of Jacques de Molay with public requiem (1808).
  <ent type='ORG'>Foundation</ent> of <ent type='ORG'>the Order</ent> of Sublime Perfects (1809).  Eliphas Levi
  (1810-1875) reveals the secret symbolism of the <ent type='ORG'>Templar</ent> idol
  Baphomet.  Czar Alexander I and Emperor Francis von <ent type='GPE'>Hapsburg</ent> unite
  to defeat <ent type='NORP'>Italian</ent> revolution incited by secret societies.  John
  Quincy Adams, initiate of <ent type='ORG'>the Dragon Society</ent>, is elected US
  President (1820).  Czar Alexander outlaws <ent type='GPE'>Mason</ent>ry in <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>
  (1822).  <ent type='ORG'>Decembrist</ent> secret society attempts coup when Czar
  Alexander allegedly dies (1825).  Anti<ent type='GPE'>Mason</ent>ic Party founded in US
  to combat secret societies in <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> politics (1828).  Wagner
  joins the Vaterlandsverein, a secret society dedicated to the
  formation of a pan-<ent type='LOC'>Europe</ent>an federation of nations.  <ent type='GPE'>Mason</ent>ic
  convention at <ent type='GPE'>Strasbourg</ent> allegedly plots second <ent type='NORP'>French</ent> Revolution
  (1848).  Napoleon III condemns <ent type='LOC'>Grand Orient</ent> for dabbling in
  radical politics (1850).  Paschal Randolph founds Hermetic
  Brotherhood of the Light (1858).  Abraham Lincoln is assassinated
  (1865).  <ent type='ORG'>Klu Klux Klan</ent> founded (1866).  Society of <ent type='NORP'>Rosicrucians</ent> in
  <ent type='GPE'>Anglia</ent> founded (1867).  <ent type='ORG'>Foundation</ent> of <ent type='ORG'>the Theosophical Society</ent> by
  Madame Blavasky on instructions of the Great White Brotherhood.
  Birth of Aleister Crowley (1875).  Mysterious suicide of ArchDuke
  Rudolph von <ent type='GPE'>Hapsburg</ent> at a hunting lodge at <ent type='GPE'>Mayerling</ent> (1889).
  <ent type='ORG'>Foundation</ent> of the Hermetic <ent type='ORG'>Order</ent> of the Golden Dawn (1888).
  Assassination of <ent type='ORG'>Empress</ent> Elizabeth von <ent type='GPE'>Hapsburg</ent> by anarchist
  (1898).</p>

<p>  1900 - 1897 CE
  <ent type='ORG'>Foundation</ent> of the Ordo Templi Orientis (1900).  International
  <ent type='ORG'>Order</ent> of CoFreemasonry founded in 1902.  Publication of The
  Protocols of the Wise Men of Zion in <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent> (1905).  <ent type='ORG'>Foundation</ent> of
  the Ancient and Mystical <ent type='ORG'>Order</ent> of the Rose Crucis (1909).  Black
  Hand Society founded in 1911.  Aleister Crowley accepted as head
  of the <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> OTO.  <ent type='ORG'>Order</ent> of the <ent type='GPE'>Temple</ent> of the Rosy Cross founded
  in 1912.  Assassination of ArchDuke Franz Ferdinand and
  Archduchess Sophia von Hapsberg.  Attempted murder of Rasputin.
  WWI begins in 1914.  <ent type='ORG'>Kaiser Wilhelm</ent> abdicates.  <ent type='GPE'>Hapsburg</ent> dynasty
  is overthrown.  <ent type='ORG'>Bolshevik Revolution</ent> in <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent> (1917-1918).
  <ent type='ORG'>Foundation</ent> of <ent type='ORG'>German Workers Party</ent> by <ent type='ORG'>Thule Society</ent> (1919).
  Hitler joins GWP and changes its name to the National Socialist
  Party (1920).  Crowley employed by MI6.  Cardinal Roncalli, later
  Pope John XXIII, allegedly joins Rosicrucian <ent type='ORG'>Order</ent>.  Hitler
  becomes first chancellor of the Third Reich (1933).  Roosevelt
  places <ent type='GPE'>Illuminist</ent> symbol of eye in triangle on the dollar bill
  (1935).  <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> invasion of <ent type='GPE'>England</ent> prevented by <ent type='ORG'>New Forest Witches</ent>
  (1940).  Rudolf Hess lured to <ent type='GPE'>Britain</ent> on peace mission by fake
  astrological data (1941).  <ent type='ORG'>Order</ent> of the <ent type='GPE'>Temple</ent> revived in <ent type='GPE'>France</ent>
  (1952).  <ent type='ORG'>First Bilderberg</ent> meeting in 1954.  <ent type='ORG'>Foundation</ent> of the P2
  Lodge (1960).  Death of Pope Paul VI, election and alleged murder
  of Pope John Paul I, and election of Pope John Paul II (1978).
  Exposure of P2 conspiracy.  Attempt to assassinate John Paul II
  (1981).  L'Ordre Internationale Chevelresque Tradition Solaire
  founded on instructions of the revived <ent type='ORG'>Order</ent> of the <ent type='GPE'>Temple</ent> in
  <ent type='GPE'>France</ent> (1984).</p>

<p>  <special>EOF</special>
  5 January 1991</p>

</xml>