<xml><p>   35 page printout, pages 56 to 88 of 322
   CHAPTER II</p>

<p>    H<ent type='ORG'>EB</ent>REW HOLY FORGERIES</p>

<p>   "<ent type='GPE'>Hinneh</ent> lash-sheqer asah et sheqer sepharim -- Behold, the
lying pen of the scribes hath wrought lies." Jeremiah, viii. 8.</p>

<p>   <ent type='ORG'>SUNDRY</ent> HOLY H<ent type='ORG'>EB</ent>REW men of old, we are told on the authority of
the name of the pseudo-first <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish</ent>-<ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> Pope, "spake as they
were moved by the Holy Ghost" (2 Peter, i, 21). These literary
movings of the <ent type='ORG'>Spirit</ent> were sometime reduced to writing in "Sacred
<ent type='NORP'>Scriptures</ent>"; and again later <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> authority assures: "All
scripture is given by inspiration of God" (2 Tim. iii, 16), --
though this is a falsified rendition: the true reading is: "Every
scripture suitable for edification is divinely inspired," as the
original <ent type='NORP'>Greek</ent> text is quoted by Father <ent type='NORP'>Tertullian</ent>. (<ent type='ORG'>ANF</ent>. iv, 16.)</p>

<p>   It is the popular supposition that the 66 -- (<ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> Bible
73) -- "little books" which comprise the Bible as we know it, are
the whole sum of Hebrew and <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> "sacred writings," which have
claimed and have been accorded the sanction of Divine inspiration
and "treated by the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> as canonical." The term "canonical" in
ecclesiastical parlance means <ent type='ORG'>Books</ent> accepted as divinely inspired;
books which "were definitely canonized, or adjudged to have a
<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>iquely Divine or authoritative quality," as is the authorative
definition. (CE. iii, 267.) "Canonicity depends on inspiration."
(<ent type='ORG'>EB</ent>. i, 653.) The holy Hebrew "canon" was closed, or the last
inspired Book of the Old Testament written, according to <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish</ent>
"Tradition," by Ezra, about 444 B.C. (Ib. i, 658, 662.) In truth,
however, several of the <ent type='ORG'>Books</ent> of the Old Testament were written
much later, and were never heard of by Ezra; and "some fo<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>d their
way in, others not, on gro<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>ds of taste -- the taste of the
period," says Wellhausen. (Einleit<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>g, p. 652, 6th Ed.)</p>

<p>   The popular idea is that when the "moving" of the above
inspired 66 sacred writings was ended, the moving <ent type='ORG'>Spirit</ent> retired
from the field of Hebrew, and later of <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> literature, and
thus closed the "sacred canon" of the respective Hebrew and
<ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> Testaments. This will be seen to be a mistake, in the
judgment of the True <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>, according to which the <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>s</ent>
evidently did not know their own inspired writings, and curiously
omitted from their "canon" a number of divinely "moved" books and
scraps of books, which the better-instructed <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> has
adopted as full of inspiration into its own present official Bible,
as we shall notice in its place. There is also a much greater
number of such books, of both Hebrew and <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> origin, which
the inspired <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> formerly and for ages regarded as inspired and
"canonical," but which it now repudiates as "apocryphal" and
acknowledges as forgeries; as we shall also duly note.</p>

<p>   There is, indeed, an eminence mass of religious writings, the
work of <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish</ent> or <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> priests or professional religious
persons, or composite productions of both sets of forgers, which
are generally known as "apocrypha" or pious forgeries; but which
each and all have been held by the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> through many ages of
faith as of the highest inspired sanctity and accredited with the
full rank of "canonical" truth of God.</p>

<p>   Bank of Wisdom
    Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
    56
.
   FORGERY IN <ent type='ORG'>CHRISTIANITY</ent></p>

<p>   The term apocryphal or forged "takes in those compositions
which profess to have been written either by <ent type='NORP'>Biblical</ent> personages or
men in intimate relation with them." (CE. i, 601.) "Since these
[apocryphal] books were forgeries, the epithet in common parlance
today denotes any story or document which is false or spurious, ...
apocryphal in the disparaging sense of bearing names to which they
have no right; all come <ent type='ORG'>un</ent>der the definition above, for each of
then has at one tine or another been treated as canonical." (<ent type='ORG'>EB</ent>. i,
249-250.)</p>

<p>   That the above 66 (or 73) <ent type='ORG'>Books</ent> of the accepted Bible of
<ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent>ity come exactly, both as to manner of spurious origin and
matter of fictional content, within the above definition of
apocrypha or forgery, shall be made exceedingly evident. A brief
review of these acknowledged religious forgeries in the name of God
and of his inspired biographers, will afford a curious and
instructive study of the workings of the fervid, credulous and
contorted priestly mind, reckless of truth, and shed a floodlight
of <ent type='ORG'>un</ent>derstanding on the origins and incredibility of the so-called
"canonical" <ent type='ORG'>Books</ent> of the Bible, Hebrew and <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> alike.</p>

<p>   While speaking here immediately of the <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish</ent> Apocrypha or
pious forgeries, it is to be noted and borne in mind that it is the
Holy-Ghost-guided True <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> which alone has accepted
and cherished these spurious productions of <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish</ent> priestcraft --
(scornfully repudiated by the <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>s</ent>), has adulterated and re-forged
them to more definite deceptive purposes of <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> propaganda,
and has outdone <ent type='ORG'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ry</ent> by adding innumerable like forgeries, -- "a
whole literature" of fabrications -- to its own spurious
hagiography, or sacred writings. There will thus occur some
necessary and <ent type='ORG'>un</ent>avoidable over-lappings of <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish</ent> and <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent>
forgeries in the course of our treatment.</p>

<p>   "It must be confessed," admits the <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> Encyclopedia,
"that the early Fathers and the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>, during the first three
centuries, were more indulgent towards <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish</ent> pseudograph [i.e.
forged writings] circulating <ent type='ORG'>un</ent>der venerable Old Testament, names.
The Book of <ent type='GPE'>Henoch</ent> [Enoch] and the Assumption of Moses had been
cited by the canonical Epistle of Jude. Many Fathers admitted the
inspiration of <ent type='ORG'>Fourth Esdras</ent>. Not to mention the Shepherd of
Hermas, the Acts of St. Paul (at least in the Thecla portion) and
the Apocalypse of St. Peter were highly revered at this and later
periods. ... In the Middle Ages ... many pseudographic [i.e.
forged] writings enjoyed a high degree of favor among both clerics
and laity." (CE. i, 615.)</p>

<p>   A curious and edifying side-light on the chronic clerical
flair for forgery is thrown by a sentence from the paragraph above
quoted from the <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> Encyclopedia. The earliest papal decree
condemning certain of these pious forgeries is itself a <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent>
forgery! "The so-called '<ent type='ORG'>Decretum de recipiendis</ent> et non recipiendis
libris,' which contained a catalogue of some half-h<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>dred works
condemned as apocryphal, was attributed to Pope Gelasius (495),
but, in reality is a compilation dating from the beginning of the
Sixth century." (CE,. i, 615.)</p>

<p>   Bank of Wisdom
    Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
    57
.
   FORGERY IN <ent type='ORG'>CHRISTIANITY</ent></p>

<p>   And, be it noted, these <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> forgeries were not at all
condemned by the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> as forgeries and pious lies, but simply
because they contained some dogmatic doctrines which were regarded
by the <ent type='NORP'>Orthodox</ent> as "heresies" they were condemned "always, however,
with a preoccupation against heresy." And again in the same
article: "Undoubtedly it was the large use heretical Circles,
especially the Gnostics made of this insinuating literature which
first called out the animadversions of the official guardians of
doctrinal purity." (lb. p. 615.)</p>

<p>   The same authority cautiously and clerically explains, that
"ancient literature, especially in the <ent type='LOC'>Orient</ent>, used methods much
more free and clastic than those permitted by our modern and
occidetital culture. Pseudographic [falsified] compositions was in
vogue among the <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>s</ent> in the two centuries before Christ and for
some time later. This holds good for the so-called 'Wisdom of
<ent type='ORG'>Solomon</ent>,' written in and belonging to the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>'s sacred cannon.
-- [This admits that this book of the <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> Bible is spurious.]
In other cases, where the assumed name did not stand as a symbol of
a type of a certain kind of literature, the intention was not
without a degree of at least literary dishonesty." (Ib. p. 601.)</p>

<p>   Apocryphal religious literature consists of several classes,
one of the most important subdivisions being that designated as
"apocalyptic," and which consists of "pretended prophecies and
revelations of both <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish</ent> and <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> authorship, and dating
from about 200 B.C. to about 150 A.D.," the latter being the
approximate date of the new "canonical" <ent type='ORG'>Books</ent> of the New Testament,
Their general subject is the problem of the final triumph of what
is called <ent type='GPE'>the <ent type='GPE'>King</ent>dom of God</ent>. Speaking particularly of the
apocalypses, the best known of which are the Hebrew Book of Daniel,
written about 165 B.C., and the <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish</ent>-<ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> Book of Revelation
imputed to the Apostle John of Patmos, a recent secular authority
(corroborated at all points by clerical authorities) points out
that many if not all of the <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish</ent> apocalypses are adulterated with
"alterations and interpolations by <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> hands, making the
alleged predictions, point more definitely to Jesus," which pious
tempering "gave certain of these <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish</ent> works a very wide
circulation in the early <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>. ... The revelations and
predictions are set forth as though actually received and written
or spoken by ancient worthies, as Enoch, Moses, etc. ... They were
once widely accepted as genuine prophecies, and fo<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>d a warm
reception in <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish</ent> and early <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> circles." (The New
International, Encyclopedia, vol. i, p. 745.) This form of pious
fraud is admitted as quite the expected thing: "Naturally baaing
itself upon the Pentateuch and the Prophets, it clothed itself
fictitiously with the authority of a patriarch or prophet who was
made to reveal the transcendent future" (CE. i, 602), -- most
usually long ex post facto.</p>

<p>   The vast and varied extent of <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish</ent>-<ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> forgery of
religious books is shown by the groupings <ent type='ORG'>un</ent>der which the several
kinds of apocrypha forgeries are quite exhaustively considered in
the technical works treating of them, such as the <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>
Encyclopedia and <ent type='ORG'>the Encyclopedia</ent> Biblica, as well as the more
popular Britannica and New International Encyclopedias, where the
subject is fully discussed. "Speaking broadly," says the first, </p>

<p>   Bank of Wisdom
    Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
    58
.
   FORGERY IN <ent type='ORG'>CHRISTIANITY</ent></p>

<p>"The Apocrypha of <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish</ent> origin are coextensive with what are
styled of the Old Testament, and those of <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> origin the
apocrypha of the New Testament. The subject will be treated
["according to their origin"] -- as follows: (I) Apocrypha of
<ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish</ent> origin: (II) <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish</ent> Apocrypha with <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> accretions;
(III) apocrypha of <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> origin, comprising (1) apocryphal
Gospels; (2) Pilate literature and other apocrypha concerning
Christ; (3) apocryphal Acts of Apostles; (4) apocryphal doctrinal
works; (5) apocryphal Epistles; (6) apocryphal Apocalypses, (IV)
the apocrypha and the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>." (CE. i, 601.)</p>

<p>   What a catalogue of confessed ecclesiastical forgers, and
fraud in the name of God, Christ and his Apostles, and the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>
of God, for the propaganda of priestly frauds as "our Most Holy
Faith"!</p>

<p>   What will probably -- In view of the foregoing and what is yet
to come -- be appreciated by many as a peculiarly rare bit of
apocrypha (in its secondary sense) is the following, uttered
apparently with the due and usual ecclesiastical solemnity, in the
celebrated <ent type='ORG'>Dictatus</ent> of Pope Gregory VII (1073-1085), stating the
presumptuous pretenses of the Papacy:</p>

<p>  "The <ent type='NORP'>Roman</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> has never erred, nor will it err to all
   eternity. No one may be considered a <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> who
   does not agree with the <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>. No book is
   authoritative <ent type='ORG'>un</ent>less it has received the papal sanction. ... </p>

<p>  The pope is the only person whose feet are to be kissed
   by all princes"; "the Pope may depose emperors and absolve
   subjects from allegiance to an <ent type='ORG'>un</ent>just ruler." (Cited by
   Robinson, 'The Ordeal of Civilization, pp. 126, 128; <ent type='ORG'>Library</ent>
   of Original Sources, vol. iv, p. 126-321.)</p>

<p>   This puts the stamp of canonical inspiration and verity on
some dozen <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish</ent> books and parts of books of the <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> Bible
which the <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>s</ent> and the whole body of otherwise discordant sects of
<ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Protestant</ent>s</ent> hesitate not <ent type='ORG'>un</ent>animously to prono<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>ce apocryphal and
forged. These "apocrypha" are either entire rejected <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish</ent> books,
all doubtless with <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> "interpolations," or apocryphal
chapters or parts, interpolated probably by the same industry into
the equally apocryphal books of the accepted <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish</ent> canon. The
names of these books, original and interpolations, and which are
not included in the Hebrew Old Testament, -- but are in the True
<ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> Bible, -- are: Tobit, Judith, Baruch, with the Epistle of
Jeremiah, <ent type='ORG'>Wisdom of <ent type='ORG'>Solomon</ent></ent>, Wisdom of Jesus son of Sirach (or
<ent type='ORG'>Ecclesiastics</ent>), I and II Maccabees, Prayer of <ent type='ORG'>Manasseh</ent>, Additions
to Esther, and Additions to the Book of Daniel, consisting of the
Prayer of Azarias, the Song of the Three Holy Children (in the
Fiery Furnace), the History of Susannah, the History of Bel and the
Dragon, and s<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>dry such precious fables. (See CE. iii, pp. 267,
270; iv, 624, passim.) These are all included in the <ent type='NORP'>Greek</ent>
Septuagint and in the <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Latin</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Vulgate</ent></ent>, were read as Scripture in
early <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>, and were declared by <ent type='ORG'>the <ent type='ORG'>Co<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>cil</ent> of Trent</ent>,
at its Fourth Session, in 1546, -- <ent type='ORG'>un</ent>der the Curse of God on all
skeptical doubters, -- to be "inspired and canonical"; and they are
so held by the <ent type='NORP'>Roman</ent>, and some of the <ent type='NORP'>Greek</ent> and <ent type='LOC'>Orient</ent>al <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> </p>

<p>   Bank of Wisdom
    Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
    59
.
   FORGERY IN <ent type='ORG'>CHRISTIANITY</ent></p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>es, but are declared "apocrypha" and forged by <ent type='ORG'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ry</ent> and all
the rest of <ent type='ORG'>Christendom</ent>. To several of these extra-revelations of
<ent type='NORP'>Judaism</ent> included in the <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> True Bible, head-notes apologetic
for their inclusion are attached, of which that to the celebrated
Book of Tobit or Tobias is typical: "<ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Protestant</ent>s</ent> have left it out
of their modern Bibles, alleging that it is not in the canon of the
<ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>s</ent>. But the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> of Christ, which received the <ent type='NORP'>Scriptures</ent> not
from the <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>s</ent>, but from the Apostles of Christ, -- [who were all
<ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>s</ent>, to believe the <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> record] -- by traditions from them,
has allowed this book a place in the <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> [sic] Bible from the
beginning." (See Cath. Bible, Tobit, et passim). We may admire in
synopsis the divine inspiration of</p>

<p>   THE INSPIRED FABLE OF TOBIT</p>

<p>   This Book of Tobit, or Tobias, scoffed both by <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>s</ent> and
<ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Protestant</ent>s</ent> as a ridiculous fable, but held by all <ent type='ORG'>True Believers</ent>
as a precious revelation of God, to disbelieve which is to be
damned, is a veritable treasure-trove of exalted heavenly
inspiration, for the preservation of which <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent> and Gentile alike
may be dubiously grateful to the pious "tradition" of the Apostles
of Christ, as above said. This Tobias was a very pious and stubborn
<ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent>ite</ent> of the Captivity, who, before departing, had cached all
his available cash with his kinsman Gabelus, of Rages, a city of
the <ent type='NORP'>Medes</ent>, "taking a note of his hand" for its repayment on demand.
While captive in a strange and pagan land, Tobias wan visited by a
piteous calamity, for "as he was sleeping, hot d<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>g out of a
swallows nest fell upon his eves, and he was made blind"; which
affliction Tobias looked reverently to the Lord as visiting upon
him as "revenge for my sins"; as a result Tobias became extremely
poor, and his wife took in work. At that time there lived in the
city of Rages another pious <ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent>ite</ent> by name Raguel, who had a
marriageable -- or rather muchly married daughter, Sara, who was
<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>der grave reproach and even imputation of murder, "Because she
had been given to seven husbands, and a devil named Asmodeus had
killed them, at their first going in <ent type='ORG'>un</ent>to her," so that she
complained that though sevenfold a widow she remained yet a virgin.</p>

<p>   At this j<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>cture Tobias bethought himself of the good money he
had left with <ent type='ORG'>Gabelus of Rages</ent>, and after much palaver decided to
send his son, Tobias, Jr., a comely youth, with the note of hand in
his pocket, and his dog (name <ent type='ORG'>un</ent>revealed), on the long journey to
recoup the fort<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>e of ten talents of silver. As Tobias, Jr. started
on the journey, a beautiful yo<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>g man, who was really the Archangel
Raphael, met him and introduced himself as Azarias, son of Ananias,
-- (Ananias must have written the acco<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>t) -- and offered to
accompany and guide him upon his journey, which offer was
gratefully accepted. As the two journeyed they came to the river
<ent type='ORG'>Tigris</ent>; Tobias waded in to wash his feet, when, lo, "a monstrous
fish came up to devour him," whereat Tobias called to his companion
for help. The Angel told him to take the monster fish by the gill
and haul him out, which Tobias seems to have had no trouble in
doing. The Angel then directed Tobias to open the yet live and
"panting" fish, "and lay up his heart, his gall, and his liver, for
thee; for these are necessary for useful medicines"; this done,
they cooked the fish and carried it all along for provisions for
the trip. As they journeyed, Tobias asked the Angel what these </p>

<p>   Bank of Wisdom
    Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
    60
.
   FORGERY IN <ent type='ORG'>CHRISTIANITY</ent></p>

<p>medicinal scraps were good for; "and the Angel answering said, if
thou put a little piece of its heart upon coals, the smoke thereof
<ent type='GPE'>driveth</ent> away all kinds of devils, either from man or from woman, so
that they come no more to them. And the gull is good for anointing
the eyes, in which there is a white speck, and they shall be
cured."</p>

<p>   So discoursing pleasantly and instructively, the twain arrived
at Rages, and the Angel guided Tobias straight to the house of
Raguel and his daughter Sara, his sole heiress, and told Tobias to
ask for her in marriage. Tobias said that he was afraid of Sara,
for he had heard of what happened to those seven other men; but the
Angel reassured him, that he would show him how to overcome the
devil Asmodeus; that he should marry Sara and go to bed with her
for three nights, but should continently confine his activities "to
nothing else but to prayers with her", and, assured the Angel, on
the first night "lay the liver of the fish on the fire, and the
devil shall be driven away," other holy marvels happening on the
succeeding nights; "and when the third night is past, thou shalt
take the virgin with the fear of the Lord, moved rather for love of
children than for lust." The affair was arranged according to these
prescriptions; with Sara and her parents; after the wedding supper,
the newlyweds were left alone in their boudoir; Tobias did nothing
but pray and put a part of the fish liver in the fire, whereupon
"the Angel Raphael took the devil, and bo<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>d him in the desert of
<ent type='GPE'>Upper <ent type='GPE'>Egypt</ent></ent>"; then both prayed some more, the fervid prayers being
repeated verbatim. In the morning, Raguel, out of force of habit,
called his servants and ordered them to go into the garden and dig
an eighth grave for the reception of Tobias; when the maidservant
went to the room to arrange for the removal of the corpse, she to
her great surprise "fo<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>d them safe and so<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>d, sleeping both
together." The empty grave was filled up, a big banquet prepared,
and the happy bridal couple spent two weeks with the bride's
family, while the Angel took the note of hand, went to Gabelus,
collected the money, and paid it over to Tobias; Raguel gave Tobias
one-half of all his property, and executed a writing to give him
one-half of the remainder upon the death of Raguel and wife. Tobias
sent the Angel back to Gabelus, to invite him to his wedding, and
the Angel made him Come.</p>

<p>   To proceed swiftly to the climax of marvel, Tobias; and the
Angel, leaving the hymeneal cortege to follow as best it could,
with such impedimenta of wealth, hastened back to the home of
Tobias, Sr., where blind father and the mother were in great grief
over the supposed loss of their son and the money with him. But at
the behest of the Angel, Tobias, Jr. ran into the house, though
"the dog, which had been with them in the way, ran before, and
coming as if he had brought the news, showed his joy by his fawning
and wagging his tail," an act which has since become habitual with
dogs which have enough tail to wag. After kissing his mother and
father, as the Angel had suggested, Tobias, Jr. took the remaining
fish gall out of his traveling bag, and anointed with it the eyes
of his father; "and he stayed about half an hour; and a white skin
began to come out of his eyes, like the skin of an egg. And Tobias
took hold of it, and drew it from his eyes, and immediately he
recovered his sight. And they glorified God," and Tobias, Sr.
dutifully said "I bless thee, Lord God of <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent>, because thou hast</p>

<p>   Bank of Wisdom
    Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
    61
.
   FORGERY IN <ent type='ORG'>CHRISTIANITY</ent></p>

<p>chastised me, and thou hast saved me: and behold I see Tobias my
son." Then, "after seven days Sara his son's wife, and all the
family arrived safe, and the cattle, and the camels, and ab<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>dance
of money of his wife's, and that money also which he had received
of Gabelus"; they all feasted for seven days "and rejoiced with all
great joy"; then, when Tobias, Sr. suggested doing something
handsome for the "holy man" through whom all their good fort<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>e had
come, the Angel introduced himself as really not Azariah, son of
Ananias, but "The Angel Raphael, one of the Seven, who stand before
the Lord"; and he explained, "I seemed indeed to eat, and to drink
with you, but I use an invisible meat and drink, which cannot be
seen by men"; thereupon in true angel style he dissipated into thin
air and they could see him no more. The whole Tobias family then,
"lying prostrate for three hours upon their face, blessed God: and
rising up they told all his wonderful works." Thus endeth happily
the reading of the lesson, dictated by the Holy Ghost to the pious
Ananias who recorded it for the edification of <ent type='ORG'>True Believers</ent>. Let
us pray that it is true.</p>

<p>    THE PROOF OF THE PUDDING</p>

<p>   Until <ent type='ORG'>the <ent type='ORG'>Co<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>cil</ent> of Trent</ent>, in 1546, there was no infallibly
defined sanction of inspiration of these <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish</ent> "apocrypha"; like
the "canon" sacred <ent type='ORG'>Books</ent> of the Hebrew Bible, all alike were more
or lest; eclectically accepted and used in the True <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>; but, as
said: "The <ent type='ORG'>Tridentine</ent> decree from which the above list is extracted
was the first infallible and effectually promulgated prono<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>cement
on the Canon, addressed to the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> <ent type='ORG'>un</ent>iversal. Being dogmatic in
its purport, it implies that the Apostles bequeathed the same Canon
to the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> as a part of the depositum fidei. ... We should
search the pages of the New, Testament in vain for any trace of
such action. ... We affirm that such a status points to Apostolic
sanction, which in turn must have rested on revelation either by
Christ or the Holy <ent type='ORG'>Spirit</ent>." (CE. iii, 270.)</p>

<p>   This is luminous clerical reasoning: a lot of anonymous <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish</ent>
fables, derided by <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>s</ent> and all the rest of the world for want of
even common plausibility of fact or truth, and as to which the
"inspired" <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> books said to emanate from Apostles, are
silent as the grave, are declared after 1500 years to have the ear-
marks of Apostolic sanction, which "must have" been fo<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>ded on
divine revelation to them "either by Christ or the Holy <ent type='ORG'>Spirit</ent>," --
which the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> claims are one and the same person; and it is
curious that the "infallible" <ent type='ORG'>Co<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>cil</ent> couldn't say which was which,
but vaguely and <ent type='ORG'>un</ent>certainly opined it must have been one or the
other. So much for infallible cock-suredness as to "inspiration" of
holy <ent type='NORP'>Scriptures</ent>. Even the Old Testament itself, says our logician
of inspiration, "reveals no formal notion of inspiration," though,
again, "the later <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>s</ent> must have possessed the idea." (Ib. p. 269.)
The cursory notice which we shall take of the Old Testament books
will serve to confirm that they reveal no notion at all of
inspiration; that the later <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>s</ent> must have had the idea that they
were inspired, does not much help the case for them.</p>

<p>   In addition to these rejected <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish</ent> books admitted into full
canonical fellowship by the inerrant True <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>, there are several
other <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish</ent> apocrypha which are only semi-canonical and admitted </p>

<p>   Bank of Wisdom
    Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
    62
.
   FORGERY IN <ent type='ORG'>CHRISTIANITY</ent></p>

<p>into a sort of bar-sinister fellowship with the legitimates. They
have a place in the <ent type='NORP'>Orthodox</ent> Bible for the "edification" of the
Faithful, but are usually printed in the Appendix as suggestive to
the devout that they will not be damned for not fully believing
these particular forgeries,</p>

<p>   Among these are two very celebrated books forged in the name
of the great Restorer of <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent>, Ezra, <ent type='ORG'>un</ent>der the titles of Third
and <ent type='ORG'>Fourth Esdras</ent>, as the name is written in the True Bibles.
"<ent type='ORG'>Third Esdras</ent>," says <ent type='ORG'>the Encyclopedia</ent>, "Is, one of the three
<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>canonical books appended to the official edition of the <ent type='ORG'>Vulgate</ent>.
... It enjoyed exceptional favor in the early ages of the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>,
being quoted as Scripture with implicit faith by the leading <ent type='NORP'>Greek</ent>
and <ent type='NORP'>Latin</ent> Fathers." (CE,. i, 605.) In like errant faith was
regarded its companion forgery, <ent type='ORG'>Fourth Esdras</ent>, of which the same
ecclesiastical authority says: "The personage serving as the screen
of the author of this book is Esdras (Ezra). ... Both <ent type='NORP'>Greek</ent> and
<ent type='NORP'>Latin</ent> Fathers cite it as prophetical. ... Notwithstanding this
widespread reverence for it, in early times, it is a REMARKABLE
FACT that the book never got a foothold in the Canon or liturgy of
the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> ... and even after <ent type='ORG'>the <ent type='ORG'>Co<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>cil</ent> of Trent</ent>, together with
<ent type='ORG'>Third Esdras</ent>. it was placed in the appendix to the official edition
of the <ent type='ORG'>Vulgate</ent>. ... The dominant critical dating assigns it to a
<ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent> writing in the reign of <ent type='NORP'>Domitian</ent>, A.D. 81-98," -- the "screen"
Ezra being gathered to his fathers since about 444 B.C. (Ib. p.
603-604; v, 537-8; <ent type='ORG'>EB</ent>. i, 653, 1393.) It is curious that it is
regarded as "remarkable" that the Holy Ghost did not "fall" for
this particular forgery, when it did for so many others!</p>

<p>   EZRA "RESTORES" THE LAW</p>

<p>   A remarkable apocryphal tale relating to the Hebrew <ent type='NORP'>Scriptures</ent>
is enshrined by pseudo-inspiration in chapter 14 of this Fourth of
Esdras, regarding the miraculous restoration of Hebrew Holy Writ
after its total perishment. In the calamity of the capture and
destruction of <ent type='GPE'>the Holy City</ent> by Nebuchadnezzar, 586 B.C., the
Temple of <ent type='ORG'>Solomon</ent> was destroyed, together with the entire
collection of the sacred Rolls of <ent type='NORP'>Scriptures</ent>, so that not a scratch
of inspired pen remained to tell the tale of theocratic Hebrew
history and its "revealed" religion. This inconsolable and
apparently irreparable loss affected the holy People all the time
of the of the <ent type='GPE'><ent type='GPE'>Babylon</ent>ian</ent> captivity. But upon their return to the
restored City of God, and over a century after their loss, God, we
are told in <ent type='ORG'>Fourth Esdras</ent>, inspired Ezra and commissioned him to
reproduce the sacred lost <ent type='ORG'>Books</ent>, which, judging from the result, of
his inspired labors, were many more than the supposed twenty and
two of the supposed old Hebrew canon. Accordingly Ezra, employing
five scribes, dictated to them (from inspired memory) the textual
contents of the lost sacred books, and in just forty days and
nights reproduced a total of 94 sacred books, of which he
designated 24 as the sacred canon, the remaining 70 being termed
esoteric and reserved fir the use of only the wisest. This inspired
fable was eagerly accepted for truth by the early <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> Fathers,
many of whom, from Irenaeus on, "admitted its inspiration"; and it
was frequently quoted and commented on as canonical by such <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>
luminaries as <ent type='NORP'>Tertullian</ent>, St. Ambrose, Clement Alexandrensis,  </p>

<p>   Bank of Wisdom
    Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
    63
.
   FORGERY IN <ent type='ORG'>CHRISTIANITY</ent></p>

<p>Origen, Eusebius, St. Jerome, et als., and was prevalently accepted
as Scripture throughout the scholastic period. (<ent type='ORG'>EB</ent>. i, 654, 139 2-
94; CE. i 537-8, 601-615.)</p>

<p>   This legend, however, had, through a better <ent type='ORG'>un</ent>derstanding of
"the powers of ordinary human memory," quite faded out by the time
of the Reformation, but only to make way for a more modern and
rationalistic one, invented by the <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Levita</ent>, who died in 1549.
According to his new fable Ezra and the Talmudic "Men of Great
Synagogue" simply <ent type='ORG'>un</ent>ited into one volume the 24 books which <ent type='ORG'>un</ent>til
that time had circulated separately, and divided them into the
three great divisions yet recognized, of the Law the Prophets, and
the Hagiography or holy writings. This fabulous statement of <ent type='ORG'>Levita</ent>
"became the authoritative doctrine of the orthodoxy of the
seventeenth and eighteenth centuries." (<ent type='ORG'>EB</ent>. i, 654.) This new
legend is cited simply to show how prone is the credulous clerical
mind to accept as truth the most baseless fables; and how, when one
of their precious bubbles of faith is pricked by tardy exposure or
common sense, they eagerly catch at the next which comes floating
by.</p>

<p>    THE "FINDING OF THE LAW"</p>

<p>   Another ancient priestly fiction, which to this day passes
current among the credulous as inspired truth of God, is the fabled
"finding of the Law" as recorded in the Word of God. We are all
familiar with the notable "finding" by the late lamented Prophet.
Joseph Smith -- thereto led by the Angel Moroni -- of the golden
plates containing the hieroglyphic text of Book of <ent type='NORP'>Mormon</ent>, near
<ent type='GPE'>Palmyra</ent> N.Y. in 1823-1827. (Book of <ent type='NORP'>Mormon</ent>, Introd.) History
repeated itself. A like remarkable discovery was made in the year
621 B.C., this time by a priest, with the help of a witch or lady
fort<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>e-teller. As related in 2 <ent type='ORG'><ent type='GPE'>King</ent>s xxii</ent>, corroborated by 2
Chronicles xxxiv, in the eighteenth year of the "good king" Josiah
of <ent type='GPE'>Judah</ent>, while some repair work was being done in the Temple,
<ent type='GPE'>Hilkiah</ent> the priest of a sudden "fo<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>d the book of the law of Yahweh
given by Moses," over 800 years before, and never heard of since.
<ent type='GPE'>Hilkiah</ent> called in <ent type='LOC'>Shaphan</ent> the scribe, and they took the great
"find" to Josiah the <ent type='GPE'>King</ent>. To verify the veracity of the high-
priest, Huldah the lady prophet was consulted; being intimately
familiar with the sentiments of God, she at once declared that
Yahweh was very angry about it, "because," as the <ent type='GPE'>King</ent> said, "our
fathers have not hearkened <ent type='ORG'>un</ent>to the words of this book, to do after
all that is written in this book"; and the <ent type='GPE'>King</ent> at once set about
to carry into effect the laws prescribed in <ent type='GPE'>Deut</ent>eronomy, -- just
then for the first time in the history of <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent> ever heard of or
acted upon. This "book of the law given to Moses" 800 years before
was doubtless the priestly work of <ent type='GPE'>Hilkiah</ent>, palmed off <ent type='ORG'>un</ent>der the
potent name of Moses to force its very reluctant observance and
belief on the superstitious <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>s</ent>. That this is the fact is the
consensus of the scholars, as summarized in <ent type='ORG'>the Encyclopedia</ent>
Biblies, and any modern work of O.T. criticism. An examination of
the Bible texts themselves, as made in my previous work,
demonstrates that this holy "law of Mosses" was totally <ent type='ORG'>un</ent>known and
<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>observed through all the History of <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent> from its beginnings
<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>til Josiah, and was composed by his priests and enlarged into the
present Pentateuch during and after the captivity in <ent type='GPE'>Babylon</ent>.</p>

<p>   Bank of Wisdom
    Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
    64
.
   FORGERY IN <ent type='ORG'>CHRISTIANITY</ent></p>

<p>   THE "SEPTUAGINT" TRANSLATION INTO GREEK</p>

<p>   As priestly forged tales were fabricated to acco<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>t for the
origin and preservation of the sacred Hebrew <ent type='ORG'>Books</ent>, so like pious
fraud was adopted to acco<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>t for their very notable translation
into <ent type='NORP'>Greek</ent>, in what is known as the Sepuagint, Version. After the
conquests by Alexander the Great and his establishment of the city
of <ent type='GPE'>Alexandria</ent> in <ent type='GPE'>Egypt</ent>, immense numbers of <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>s</ent> were settled in the
new city, which quickly became the commercial and intellectual
center of the ancient world, with <ent type='NORP'>Greek</ent> the <ent type='ORG'>un</ent>iversal language. The
holy Hebrew language had became a dead language to the <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>s</ent> of the
"Dispersion"; their synagogue services could not be conducted in
the mother tongue. The <ent type='GPE'>Alexandria</ent>n <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>s</ent> were accordingly <ent type='ORG'>un</ent>der
necessity to render the "Law" into <ent type='NORP'>Greek</ent> for their public use; and
this was gradually done by such of them as thought themselves able
to do such work. But this common-place mode of rendering the sacred
Hebrew into a Gentile speech did not satisfy the pious wonder-
craving <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish</ent> mind. Accordingly, somewhere about 200 B.C., an
anonymous <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent> invented a more satisfactory tale, which has had
incalculable influence on the <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> faith and dogmas. This
pious <ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent>ite</ent> had the customary recourse to religions forgery; he
forged a letter in the name of one <ent type='ORG'>Aristeas</ent>, an official of <ent type='NORP'>Ptolemy</ent>
II, <ent type='GPE'>Philadelphus</ent>, the <ent type='NORP'>Greek</ent> king of <ent type='GPE'>Egypt</ent>, 285-247 B.C., purporting
to be addressed to his brother, <ent type='NORP'>Philocrates</ent>, and giving a marvelous
history of the Translation.</p>

<p>   Here, in substance, is what we read of the first origin of the
Version, limited therein to the "law" of Moses, as first related by
Josephus. <ent type='NORP'>Ptolemy</ent> had recently established a library at <ent type='GPE'>Alexandria</ent>,
which he purposed should contain a copy of every obtainable
literary work extant. This <ent type='ORG'>Library</ent> became the most extensive and
celebrated of the ancient world, containing some 700000 manuscript
books at the time it was savagely destroyed, in 391 A.D., by the
benighted <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> zeal and fury of Bishop Theophilus of
<ent type='GPE'>Alexandria</ent> and his crazy monks of <ent type='ORG'>Nitria</ent>, as related in <ent type='GPE'>King</ent>sley's
Hypatia or any history of the times. CE. xiv, 625.) At the
suggestion of <ent type='ORG'>Demetrius</ent>, his Librarian, fables the pseudo-<ent type='ORG'>Aristeas</ent>
through Josephus, that he should enrich the <ent type='ORG'>Library</ent> with a copy of
the sacred law of the <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>s</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Ptolemy</ent> wrote to Eleazar the chief
priest at <ent type='GPE'>Jerusalem</ent>, sending the letter and magnificent presents
"to God" by the hand of a delegation including <ent type='ORG'>Aristeas</ent>, requesting
a copy of the Law and a number of learned <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>s</ent> competent to
translate it into <ent type='NORP'>Greek</ent>. The embassy was successful; a richly
ornamented copy of the holy law, written in letters of gold, was
sent to the <ent type='GPE'>King</ent>, together with seventy-two Doctors of <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent>,
deputed to deliver the Book and to carry out the wishes of the
<ent type='GPE'>King</ent>. They were received with great honor, says pseudo-<ent type='ORG'>Aristeas</ent>,
and duly feted for several days; they were then conducted across
the long causeway to <ent type='LOC'>the Island of <ent type='LOC'>Pharos</ent></ent> to the place which was
prepared for them, "which was a house that was built near the
shore, and was a quiet place, and fit for their discoursing
together about their work, ... Accordingly they made an accurate
interpretation, with great zeal and great pains," working <ent type='ORG'>un</ent>til the
ninth hour each day, and visiting <ent type='NORP'>Ptolemy</ent> every morning. "Now when
the Law was transcribed, and the labor of interpretation was over,
which came to its conclusion in seventy-two days," the work was
read over to the assembled <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>s</ent>, who rejoiced that "the </p>

<p>   Bank of Wisdom
    Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
    65
.
   FORGERY IN <ent type='ORG'>CHRISTIANITY</ent></p>

<p>interpretation was happily finished"; they were enjoined to report
any errors or emissions which they might discover, to the
"Seventy," who would make the necessary corrections in their work.
(Josephus, Antiq. <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>s</ent>, Bk. XII, chap. 2; CE. xiii, 722.) Thus the
translation wag only of "The Law," the Five <ent type='ORG'>Books</ent> of Moses; and it
was open team-work, all the Seventy-two working together, comparing
and discussing as they proceeded, and expressly enjoining the <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>s</ent>
to note and report for correction all errors of omission or
commission which they might discover.</p>

<p>   Thus the pseudo-<ent type='ORG'>Aristeas</ent>, as cited by Josephus; though, as a
matter of fact, this Septuagint Version, so-called because of the
legendary Seventy-(two), was in the grossest manner inaccurate, and
imported innumerable errors into the <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> religion which was
based upon and propagated for several centuries only through the
Septuagint texts. Indeed, "the text of the Septuagint was regarded
as so <ent type='ORG'>un</ent>reliable, because of its freedom in rendering, and of the
alterations which had been introduced into it, etc., that, during
the second century of our era it was discarded by the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>." (CE.
iv, 625.) We shall notice the fearful error of Isaiah's "virgin-
birth" text; for other well-known instances, it makes out <ent type='ORG'>Creation</ent>
1195 years earlier than the Hebrew and <ent type='ORG'>Vulgate</ent>, 4004 B.C., and the
venerable <ent type='ORG'>Methuselah</ent> is made to survive the Flood by fourteen
years.</p>

<p>   Despite, however, its patently legendary character, the
pseudo-<ent type='ORG'>Aristeas</ent>' acco<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>t, the forged letter and the story, were
eagerly accepted as genuine and authentic by Fathers, Popes and
ecclesiastic writers <ent type='ORG'>un</ent>til the sixteenth century, when their
spurious character was revealed by the nascent modern criticism.
"The authenticity of the letter, called in question first by Louis
Vives (1492-1540), professor at Louvain, is now <ent type='ORG'>un</ent>iversally
denied." (CE. xiii, 722.)</p>

<p>   The Fathers, however, could not rest content with this
<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>varnished original fabrication in the name of <ent type='ORG'>Aristeas</ent>, of an
ordinary human and errant translation of the "Law"; they avidly set
about embellishing it in the accepted clerical style, adding
fanciful and lying details to emphasize the miraculous and inspired
origin of the Version. As this notable instance serves admirably to
illustrate the childish and <ent type='ORG'>un</ent>critical credulity of the Fathers,
their reckless disregard of truth, their chronic zest for any
<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>truth or fable quotable to pander to the glory of God and enhance
the pious superstition of the Faithful, let us here watch the
growth of this simple human yarn of the <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish</ent> aristeas-forger into
the wonderful and ever more embellished miracle as it passes from
Father to Father, -- exactly as the Gospel-fables grew from "Mark"
to "John." According to Fathers <ent type='NORP'>Tertullian</ent>, St. Augustine, St.
Jerome, et als., the 72 were inspired by God each severally for the
entire work; in translating they did not consult with one another;
they had been shut up <ent type='ORG'>incom<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>icados</ent> in separate cells on <ent type='LOC'>Pharos</ent>,
either singly or in pairs, and their several translations, when
finished and compared, were fo<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>d to agree entirely both as to
sense and the expressions employed, with the original Hebrew text
and with each other (St. Clement of <ent type='GPE'>Alexandria</ent>, St. Irenaeus,
Justin Martyr). Finally, the 72 translated not only the Law, but
the entire Old Testament, -- several of whose <ent type='ORG'>Books</ent> were not yet at
the time written.</p>

<p>   Bank of Wisdom
    Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
    66
.
   FORGERY IN <ent type='ORG'>CHRISTIANITY</ent></p>

<p>   Father Justin Martyr adds near-eye-witness verification to the
false and already embroidered history, saying that the "Seventy"
were, by order of the <ent type='GPE'>King</ent>, "shut up in as many separate cells, and
were obliged by him, each to translate the whole Bible apart, and
without any comm<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>ication with each other, yet all their several
translations were fo<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>d to agree verbatim from the beginning to the
end, and were by that means demonstrated to be of divine
inspiration"; and he adds, for confirmation of faith! -- like Paul,
protesting he is not lying in anticipation of the accusation:
"These things, ye men of <ent type='GPE'>Greece</ent>, are no fable, nor do we narrate
fictions; but we ourselves having been in <ent type='GPE'>Alexandria</ent>, saw the
remains of the little [cells] at the <ent type='LOC'>Pharos</ent> still preserved." (Ad
Graec. ch. xiii; <ent type='ORG'>ANF</ent>. i, 278-9.) But in repeating the tale to the
<ent type='NORP'>Roman</ent> Emperor, Father Justin makes the <ent type='ORG'>un</ent>happy bl<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>der of saying,
that <ent type='NORP'>Ptolemy</ent> "sent to Herod, who was at that time king of the <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>s</ent>,
requesting that the books of the prophets [pseudo-<ent type='ORG'>Aristeas</ent> said the
"Law"] be sent to him; and the king did indeed send them" (I Apol.
ch. xxxi; <ent type='ORG'>ANF</ent>. i, 173); whereas Herod lived some 300 years after
<ent type='NORP'>Ptolemy</ent> died. This forged fable is time and again repeated as sober
truth. Bishop Saint Irenaeus emphasizes the miraculous nature of
the translation of all the <ent type='ORG'>Books</ent>, saying that when the 72 identical
translations were compared, "God was indeed glorified, and the
<ent type='NORP'>Scriptures</ent> were acknowledged an truly divine; ... even the <ent type='GPE'>Gentiles</ent>
present perceived that the <ent type='NORP'>Scriptures</ent> had been interpreted by the
inspiration of God. And there was nothing astonishing in God having
done this. ... He inspired Esdras the priest (after the return from
captivity) to recast all the words of the former prophets, and to
reestablish with the people of God the Mosaic legislation." (Adv.
Haer. III, xxi, 2; <ent type='ORG'>ANF</ent>. i, 451-2.)</p>

<p>   In the course of a century or two before the <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> Era,
the other Hebrew sacred books were likewise translated into <ent type='NORP'>Greek</ent>
for the use of the <ent type='NORP'>Greek</ent>-speaking <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>s</ent> of "the Dispersion,"
together with numbers of the forged <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish</ent> apocrypha, and all these
were added to the rolls of "<ent type='NORP'>Scriptures</ent>." This final and adulterated
form of the Septuagint "was the vehicle which conveyed these
additional <ent type='NORP'>Scriptures</ent> [i.e. the apocryphal Tobias, etc.] into the
<ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>." (CE. iii, 271.) This vagary of the Holy Ghost in
certifying the ill-translated and tempered Septuagint for the
fo<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>dations of <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> Faith, was very disastrous, as CE. points
out: "The <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> had adopted the Septuagint as its own; this
differed from the Hebrew not only by the addition of several books
and passages but also by innumerable variations of text, due partly
to the ordinary process of corruption in the transcription of
ancient books, partly to the culpable temerity, as Origen called
it, of correctors who used not a little freedom in making
'corrections,' additions, and suppressions, partly to mistakes in
translation, and finally in great part to the fact that the
original Septuagint had been made from a Hebrew text quite
different from that fixed at <ent type='GPE'>Jamnia</ent> as the one standard by the
<ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish</ent> Rabbis." (CE. vii, 316.) So Yahveh only knows what he
actually said and did in the 4004 years up to the time his Son came
to try to "redeem" his people from some of the tangles of his Holy
Law.</p>

<p>   Matters grew worse as time progressed: the ex-<ent type='NORP'>Pagan</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Greek</ent>
Fathers who fo<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>ded <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent>ity, propagated the new Faith for
several centuries only from the tortuous texts of this falsified </p>

<p>   Bank of Wisdom
    Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
    67
.
   FORGERY IN <ent type='ORG'>CHRISTIANITY</ent></p>

<p>Septuagint, which was the only Old Testament "<ent type='NORP'>Scriptures</ent>" known to
and used by them as the source of the "prophecies fulfilled by
Jesus Christ" and the holy mysteries of the <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish</ent>-<ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> Faith.
"Copies of the Septuagint." says CE., "were multiplied, and, as
might be expected, many changes, deliberate as well as invol<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>tary,
crept in." (CE. xiii, 723.) Indeed, the itch for Scripture-
scribbling was so rife among such ex-<ent type='NORP'>Pagan</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent>s as could
write and get hold of a copy, that St. Augustine complains: "It is
possible to enumerate those who have translated the <ent type='NORP'>Scriptures</ent> from
Hebrew into <ent type='NORP'>Greek</ent>, but not those who have translated them into
<ent type='NORP'>Latin</ent>. In sooth, in the curly days of the faith whoso possessed a
<ent type='NORP'>Greek</ent> manuscript and thought he had some knowledge of both tongues
was daring enough to <ent type='ORG'>un</ent>dertake a translation." (De Doct. Christ.
II, xi; CE. ix, 20.) So the Faith was fo<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>ded on befuddlement of
the Blessed Word of God as any nondescript scribbler palmed it off
to be.</p>

<p>   We shall more than ab<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>dantly see that Holy <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> never
possessed or used a single book of "Scripture" or other document of
importance, to the glory of God and the glorification of the
<ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>, which was not a rank original forgery and bristled besides
with "many deliberate changes" or forged interpolations.</p>

<p>   THE SEPTUAGINT AND THE "VIRGIN-BIRTH" FRAUD</p>

<p>   The most colossal of the bl<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>ders of the Septuagint
translators, supplemented by the most insidious, persistent and
purposeful falsification of text, is instanced in the false
translation of the notoriously false pretended "prophecy" of Isaiah
vii, 14, -- frauds which have had the most disastrous and fatal
consequences for <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent>ity, and to humanity <ent type='ORG'>un</ent>der its blight;
the present exposure of which should instanter destroy the false
Faith built on these frauds.</p>

<p>   The <ent type='NORP'>Greek</ent> priest who forged the "Gospel according to St.
Matthew," having before him the false Septuagint translation of
Isaiah, fables the <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish</ent> Mary yielding to the embraces of the
Angel Gabriel to engender Jesus, and backs it up by appeal to the
Septuagint translation of Isaiah vii, 14:</p>

<p>   "Behold, a virgin shall be with child, and shall bring forth
a son, and they shall call his name Emmanuel." (Matt. i, 23.)</p>

<p>   Isaiah's original Hebrew, with the mistranslated words
<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>derscored, reads: "<ent type='GPE'>Hinneh</ent> ha-almah harah ve-yeldeth ben ve-karath
shem-o immanuel"; -- which, falsely translated by the false pen of
the pious translators, r<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>s thus in the English: "Behold, a virgin
shall conceive and bear a son, and shall call his name Immanuel"
(Isa. vii, 14.) The Hebrew words ha-almah mean simply the yo<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>g
woman; and harah is the Hebrew past or perfect tense, "conceived,"
which in Hebrew, as in English, represents past and completed
action. Honestly translated, the verse reads: "Behold, the yo<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>g
woman has conceived -- [is with child) -- and beareth a son and
calleth his name Immanuel."</p>

<p>   Almah means simply a yo<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>g woman, of marriageable age, whether
married or not, or a virgin or not; in a broad general sense 
exactly like girl or maid in English, when we say shop-girl, </p>

<p>   Bank of Wisdom
    Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
    68
.
   FORGERY IN <ent type='ORG'>CHRISTIANITY</ent></p>

<p>parlor-maid, bar-maid, without reference to or vouching for her
technical virginity, which, in Hebrew, is always expressed by the
word bethulah. But in the Septuagint translation into <ent type='NORP'>Greek</ent>, the
Hebrew almah was erroneously rendered into the <ent type='NORP'>Greek</ent> parthenos,
virgin, with the definite article 'ha' in Hebrew, and e in <ent type='NORP'>Greek</ent>,
(the), rendered into the indefinite "a" by later falsifying
translators. (See Is It God's Word? pp. 277-279; <ent type='ORG'>EB</ent>. ii, 2162; New
Commentary on the Holy Scripture, Pt. I, p. 439.) And St. Jerome
falsely used the <ent type='NORP'>Latin</ent> word virgo.</p>

<p>   "As early as the second century B.C.," says the distinguished
Hebrew scholar and critic, <ent type='ORG'>Salomon Reinach</ent>, "the <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>s</ent> perceived the
error and pointed it out to the <ent type='NORP'>Greek</ent>s; but the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> knowingly
persisted in the false reading, and for over fifteen centuries she
has cl<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>g to her error." (Orpheus, p, 197.) The truth of this
accusation of conscious persistence in known error through the
centuries is proved by confession of St. Jerome, who made the
celebrated <ent type='ORG'>Vulgate</ent> translation from the Hebrew into <ent type='NORP'>Latin</ent>, and
intentionally "cl<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>g to the error," though Jerome well knew that it
was an error and false; and thus he perpetuated through fifteen
h<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>dred years the myth of the "prophetic virgin birth" of Jesus
called Christ.</p>

<p>   Being criticized by many for this falsification, St. Jerome
thus replies to one of his critics, <ent type='ORG'>Juvianus</ent>: "I know that the <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>s</ent>
are accustomed to meet us with the objection that in Hebrew the
word Almah does not mean a virgin, but a yo<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>g woman. And, to speak
truth, a virgin is properly called <ent type='ORG'>Bethulah</ent>, but a yo<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>g woman, or
a girl, is not Almah, but Naarah"! (Jerome, Adv. Javianum I, 32;
N&amp;PNF, vi, 370.) So insistent was the criticism, that he was driven
to write a book on the subject, in which he makes a very notable
confession of the inherent incredibility of the Holy Ghost
paternity-story "For who at that time would have believed the
Virgin's word that she had conceived of the Holy Ghost, and that
the angel Gabriel had come and anno<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>ced the purpose of God? and
would not all have given their opinion against her as an
adulteress, like Susanna? For at the present day, now that the
whole world has embraced the faith, the <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>s</ent> argue, that when
Isaiah says, 'Behold, a virgin shall conceive and bear a son,' the
Hebrew the Hebrew word denotes a yo<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>g woman, not a virgin, that is
to say, the word is ALMAH, not <ent type='ORG'>BETHULAH</ent>"! (Jerome, The Perpetual
Virginity of Blessed Mary, N&amp;PNF, vi, 336.)</p>

<p>   So the <ent type='NORP'>Greek</ent> Father or priest who forged the false "virgin-
birth" interpolation into the manuscript of "Matthew," drags in
maybe ignorantly the false Septuagint translation of Isaiah vii,
14, which the <ent type='NORP'>Latin</ent> Father St. Jerome purposely perpetuated as a
pious "lie to the glory of God." The <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>King</ent> James
Versions purposely retain this false translation; the Revised
Version keeps it in, but with a gesture of honesty, which is itself
a fraud, sticks into the margin in fine type, after the words "a
virgin" and "shall conceive," the words, "Or, the maiden is with
child and beareth," -- which not one in thousands would ever see or
<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>derstand the significance of. So it is not some indefinite "a
virgin" who 750 years in the future "shall conceive" and "shall
bear" a son whose name she "shall call" Immanuel, Jesus; but it was
some known and definite yo<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>g female, married or <ent type='ORG'>un</ent>-married -- but </p>

<p>   Bank of Wisdom
    Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
    69
.
   FORGERY IN <ent type='ORG'>CHRISTIANITY</ent></p>

<p>not a "virgin" -- who had already conceived and was already
pregnant, and who beareth a son and calleth his name Immanuel, ...
who should be the "sign" which "my lord" should give to Ahaz of the
truth of Isaiah's false prophecy regarding the pending war with
<ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Syria</ent>, as related in Isaiah vii, and of which the total
falsity is proven in 2 Chronicles xxviii, as all may read.</p>

<p>   Although Papal Infallibility has declared that "it will never
be lawful to grant ... that the sacred writers could have made a
mistake" (Leo XIII, Eneyc. Provid. Deus; CE. ii, 543), yet, the
fraud being notorious and exposed to the scorn of the world, and
being driven by force of modern criticism, CE. definitely and
positively -- though with the usual clerical soft-soaping,
confesses this age-long clerical fraud and falsification of Holy
Writ, and relegates it to the j<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>k-heap of discredited -- but not
discarded -- dogmatic myth:</p>

<p>   "<ent type='NORP'>Modern</ent> theology does not grant that Isaiah vii, 14, contains
a real prophecy fulfilled in the virgin birth of Christ; it must
maintain, therefore, that St. Matthew mis<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>derstood the passage
when he said: 'Now all this was done that it might be fulfilled
which the Lord spoke by the prophet, saying, Behold, a virgin shall
be with child, and bring forth a son, etc."! (CE. xv, 451.)</p>

<p>   Thus is apparent, and confessed, the dishonesty of "Matthew"
and of the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> of Christ in perverting this idle, false and
falsified text of Isaiah into a "prophecy of the virgin birth of
Jesus Christ," and in persisting in retaining this falsity in their
dishonest Bibles as the basis of their own bogus theology <ent type='ORG'>un</ent>to this
day of the Twentieth Century. The <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>, full knowing its falsity,
yet, clings to this precious lie of <ent type='ORG'>Virgin Birth</ent> and all the
concatenated consequences. Thus it declares its own condemnation as
false. Some other viciously false translations of sacred Scripture
will be duly noticed in their place.</p>

<p>   As Thomas Jefferson prophetically wrote, -- as is being
verified:</p>

<p>   "The day will come when the mystical generation of Jesus by
the Supreme Being as his father, in the womb of a virgin, will be
classed with the fable of the generation of Minerva in the brain of
<ent type='LOC'>Jupiter</ent>"!</p>

<p>    OTHER H<ent type='ORG'>EB</ent>REW SACRED FORGERIES</p>

<p>   The marvels of the canonical apocrypha of the Hebrew sacred
<ent type='ORG'>Books</ent>, or of the whole 94 miraculously "restored" by Ezra, could
not slake the thirst of the <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish</ent> intellect for such edifying
histories, and their priests were very industrious in supplying the
demands of piety and marvel-craving. Making use, as above admitted,
of the most "venerable Old Testament names," they forged a
voluminous literature of fanciful and fantastic fairy-tales in the
guise of sacred history, revelations, oracles or predictions, all
solemnly "set forth as thought actually received, and written or
spoken by ancient worthies, as Enoch, Moses, etc., which were
widely accepted as genuine, and fo<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>d a warm reception in <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish</ent>
and early <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> circles." Scarcely is there a <ent type='NORP'>Biblical</ent> notable </p>

<p>   Bank of Wisdom
    Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
    70
.
   FORGERY IN <ent type='ORG'>CHRISTIANITY</ent></p>

<p>of <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent> in whose name these pious false writings were not forged,
including Adam and Eve and most of the ante- and post-Diuvian
<ent type='ORG'>Patriarchs</ent>. It is impossible here to much more than mention the
names of some of the principal ones of these extra-canonical
apocrypha and forgeries of the <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>s</ent>, as listed in the <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>
Encyclopedia and <ent type='ORG'>the Encyclopedia</ent> Biblica, most of them worked over
with surcharge of added <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> forgeries, to adapt them to their
pious propaganda.</p>

<p>   The names of these "intriguing" volumes of forgotten lore,
listed somewhat after the order of their distinguished pretended
authors and times, are: <ent type='ORG'>Life of Adam</ent> and Eve; Testament of Adam;
The Book of <ent type='ORG'>Creation</ent>; the <ent type='ORG'>Books</ent> of Seth (son of Adam); Book of
Enoch (grandson of Adam); Secrets of Enoch; Parables of Enoch; Book
of Lamech; Book of Noah; Book of <ent type='NORP'>Zoroaster</ent> (identified with Ham,
son of Noah); Apocalypse of Noah; Apocalypse of Abraham; Testament
of Abraham; Testament of Isaac; Testament of Jacob; The Testaments
of the Twelve <ent type='ORG'>Patriarchs</ent>; Testament of the Three <ent type='ORG'>Patriarchs</ent>;
Testament of Naphthali; The Prayer of Menassch; The Prayer of
Joseph; The Story of Asenath (wife of Joseph); Prayer of Asenath;
The Marriage of Asenath; The Assumption of Moses; The Testament of
Moses; Book of Jannes and Mambres (the <ent type='GPE'>Egypt</ent>ian magicians with whom
Moses contended); Penitence of Jannes and Mambres; The Magical
<ent type='ORG'>Books</ent> of Moses; The Book of Jubilees. or Little <ent type='ORG'>Genesis</ent>; Book of Og
the Giant, Treatise of the <ent type='ORG'>Giants</ent>, Josippon; Book of Jasher; The
Liber Antiquitatem Bibliarum, ascribed to Philo; The Chronicles of
Jerameel; Testament of Job; Psalm CLI of David, "when he fought
with Goliath"; Testament of <ent type='ORG'>Solomon</ent>; The Contradictio Salomonis (a
contest in wisdom between <ent type='ORG'>Solomon</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Hiram</ent>); The Psalms of
<ent type='ORG'>Solomon</ent>; Apocalypse of Elijah; Apocalypse of Baruch; The Rest of
the Words of Baruch; History of Daniel; Apocalypse of Daniel;
Visions of Daniel; Additions to Daniel, viz.: The History of
Susanne (Chap. 13), the Song of the Three Children, Story of Bel
and the Dragon (Chap. 14); Tobit; Judith; Additions to Esther; The
Martyrdom of Isaiah; The Ascension of Isaiah; III and IV Esdras;
Apocalypse of Esdras; Story of the Three <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Pagan</ent>s</ent>, in I Esdras; I,
II, III, and IV Mitceabee"; The Prophecy of Eldad and Medad;
Apocalypse of Zephaniah, Stories of Artaphanus; Eupolemus; Story of
<ent type='NORP'>Aphikia</ent>, wife of Jesus Sirach; The Letter of <ent type='ORG'>Aristeas</ent> to
<ent type='NORP'>Philocrates</ent>; The Sibylline Oracles.</p>

<p>   Quite half of the above <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish</ent> false-writings, separately
listed <ent type='ORG'>un</ent>der the grouping of "<ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish</ent> with <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> Accretions,"
the <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> Encyclopedia describes with comments such as "recast
or freely interpolated by <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent>s," "many <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent>
interpolations," etc., "presenting in their ensemble a fairly full
Christology" (CE. i, 606). If the pious <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent>s, <ent type='ORG'>confessedly</ent>,
committed so many and so extensive forgeries and frauds to adapt
these popular <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish</ent> fairy-tales of their God and holy Worthies to
the new <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> Jesus and his Apostles, we need feel no surprise
when we discover these same <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent>s forging outright new wonder-
tales of their Christ <ent type='ORG'>un</ent>der the fiction of the most noted <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent>
names and in the guise of inspired Gospels, Epistles, Acts and
Apocalypses.</p>

<p>   Bank of Wisdom
    Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
    71
.
   FORGERY IN <ent type='ORG'>CHRISTIANITY</ent></p>

<p>    THE "INSPIRED" H<ent type='ORG'>EB</ent>REW SCRIPTURES</p>

<p>   The processes of the formation of the Hebrew Old Testament
<ent type='NORP'>Scriptures</ent> are, however, interesting and intriguing, if sacred
tradition is true. According to priestly lore, the man Moses,
"learned in all the wisdom of the <ent type='GPE'>Egypt</ent>ians" (another <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent>
assurance; Acts vii, 22), sat down in <ent type='LOC'>the <ent type='ORG'>Wilderness</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>Sinai</ent></ent> and
<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>der divine inspiration wrote his Five <ent type='ORG'>Books</ent> of prehistorical
history, codes of post-exilic divine Law, and chronicles of
contemporary and future notable events, including four different
names of his father-in-law -- (Wz.: Jethro, Ex. iii, 1; Reuel, Ex.
ii, 18; Jether, Ex. iv, 18, and Raguel, Num. x, 29, while a fifth
name, <ent type='ORG'>Hobab</ent>, is awarded him in Judges iv, II), together with a
graphic acco<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>t of his own death and burial, and of the whole month
afterwards spent by all <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent> mourning his death. He also records
the death of his brother Aaron at Mt. Hor (Num. xx, 28; xxxiii,
38), just six months before his own death; though, in amazing
contradiction, he elsewhere records Aaron as having died at <ent type='ORG'>Mosera</ent>,
just after leaving <ent type='GPE'>Sinai</ent> (<ent type='GPE'>Deut</ent>. x, 6), thirty-nine years previously
-- and thus nullifies the entire history of the wonderful career
and deeds of Aaron as high priest during the whole 40 years of
wandering in the <ent type='ORG'>Wilderness</ent>, of which the <ent type='ORG'>Books</ent> of Exodus,
Leviticus and Numbers are largely filled; as also many other
matters and things occurring for some centuries after his death,
and known as "post-Mosaica" to the scholars.</p>

<p>   Joshua, the successor of Moses, next wrote the history of his
life and times, working in, too, a sketch of his own death and
f<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>eral obsequies (Josh. xxiv, 29-30), and quoting the celebrated
miracle of the n<ent type='ORG'>un</ent> standing still, of which he says, "Is it not
written in the Book of Jasher?" -- which Book of Jasher was not
itself written <ent type='ORG'>un</ent>til several h<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>dred years later, at least in or
after the time of David; for it is recorded: "And he [David] bade
them teach the children of <ent type='GPE'>Judah</ent> the use of the bow; behold, it is
written in the Book of Jasher." (2 Sam. i, 18.)</p>

<p>   The Book of Judges was written by nobody knows whom, nor when,
except that it was long "post-exilic." It relates that, "Now the
children of <ent type='GPE'>Judah</ent> had fought against <ent type='GPE'>Jerusalem</ent>, and had taken it"
(Jud. i, 18); whereas it was not <ent type='ORG'>un</ent>til David had reigned seven
years and six months in <ent type='GPE'>Hebron</ent>, that "the <ent type='GPE'>King</ent> and his men went to
<ent type='GPE'>Jerusalem</ent>" and failed to capture it, "nevertheless, David took the
stronghold of Zion, and called it <ent type='GPE'>the City of</ent> David." (2 Sam. v,
5-9.) It is further recorded in Judges that the tribe of Dan made
a silver idol of the Hebrew God and hired a grandson of Moses to
serve it, and "he and his sons were priests to the tribe of Dan
<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>til the captivity of the land" (Jud. xviii, 30) -- about a
thousand years later.</p>

<p>   The gifted Samuel. Prophet of the heathen High Places of Baal
worship, gives his name and inspiration to two books of mythical
history written piecemeal <ent type='ORG'>un</ent>til the "return from captivity," as
above indicated, and early in his work he records the historic
episode of the calling up of his own ghost from the dead by the
famous <ent type='ORG'>Witch of En</ent>-dor. (I Sam. xviii, 1, 7-19.)</p>

<p>   Bank of Wisdom
    Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
    72
.
   FORGERY IN <ent type='ORG'>CHRISTIANITY</ent></p>

<p>   The ex-bandit David, "man after God's own heart" -- after
murdering a man to get his adulterous wife, and engendering of her
his all-wise son and hero, <ent type='ORG'>Solomon</ent>, wrote the 150 songs of the
Hebrew Hymn Book, many of his psalms singing of the long posthumous
<ent type='GPE'><ent type='GPE'>Babylon</ent>ian</ent> Captivity.</p>

<p>   <ent type='ORG'>Solomon</ent> himself, who was son-in-law to nearly everybody in the
heathen nations ro<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>d about who had eligible daughters, wrote the
wisdom of the ages into his Book of Proverbs, though not one of
them is by <ent type='ORG'>Solomon</ent>, and in his lighter (headed or hearted) spells
penned his erotic Canticles, which for realistic lubricity quite
outdo Boccaccio, and would be really <ent type='ORG'>un</ent>mailable <ent type='ORG'>un</ent>der the <ent type='ORG'>Postal</ent>
laws if they weren't in the Holy Bible and clerically captioned
"The <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>'s Love <ent type='ORG'>un</ent>to Christ." These are indeed but one
collection out of the great many pornographic stories of The Holy
Ghost's Decameron, enshrined in God's Holy Word for delectation of
the Puritans of Faith.</p>

<p>   Other divinely inspired and anonymous writers, falsely
entitling their effusions <ent type='ORG'>un</ent>der the names of this or that Prophet
or other wholly fictitious personage, as Job, Esther, Ruth, Daniel,
gave forth yet other inspired histories, books of oracles or
prophecies, apocalypses or high powered visions into <ent type='ORG'>Futurity</ent>, and
a miscellany of sacred novels, love-stories and nondescript musings
or ravings known collectively as the hagiographa or holy writings
of the <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>s</ent>. All these together, now thirty-nine in number,
comprise the Hebrew Bible or Old Testament. It being out of
question to review each of these here, it may be stated with
assurance that not one of them bears the name of its true author;
that every one of them is a composite work of many hands
"interpolating" the most anachronistic and contradictory matters
into the original writings, and often reciting as accomplished
facts things which occurred many centuries after the time of the
supposed writer, as Psalms, isaiah, Daniel, and the so-called
"historical" books. For scientific detailed demonstration of this
<ent type='ORG'>the Encyclopedia</ent> Biblica digests the most competent authorities; my
own Is It God's Word? makes the proofs from the sacred texts
themselves. See the recent "Religions Book of the Month Club's"
notable Unraveling the Book of <ent type='ORG'>Books</ent>, by <ent type='ORG'>Trattner</ent>. (1929.)</p>

<p>   But as the <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> religion depends more vitally on <ent type='ORG'>Genesis</ent>
and Moses than on all the other sacred writings and writers, we may
appeal to the admissions of CE., thereto driven by force of modern
criticism, for the destruction and abandonment of the Moses Myths.</p>

<p>   "It is true that the Pentateuch, so long attributed to Moses,
is now held by the vast majority of non-<ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>, and by an
increasing number of <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>, scholars to be a compilation of four
independent sources put together in final shape soon after the
Captivity." (CE. i, 622.)</p>

<p>   This scores strongly for Hebrew-<ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> forgery and fraud in
attributing this primitive system of Bible "science" and barbarous
law to a god as a pretext for priestly domination of the
superstitious people. That God-given forged law thus prescribes for
priestcraft: "The man that will do presumptuously, and will not
hearken <ent type='ORG'>un</ent>to the priest, ... even that man shall die." (<ent type='GPE'>Deut</ent>. xvii,</p>

<p>   Bank of Wisdom
    Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
    73
.
   FORGERY IN <ent type='ORG'>CHRISTIANITY</ent></p>

<p>12.) The whole Five <ent type='ORG'>Books</ent> of Moses are thus a confessed forgery in
the names of Moses and of God; every one of the Thus saith the Lord
a thousand times repeated, with speeches and laws put into the
mouth of the God, are false and forged. Speaking of the
"difficulty, in the present condition of Old Testament criticism,
of recognizing more than a small portion of the Peritateuch as
documentary evidence contemporary with Moses," -- who, if he ever
lived, which may be confidently denied, -- never wrote a line of
it, CE. further confesses to the natural evolution -- not the
"divine revelation" -- of the Hebrew mythology into a (no less
mythological) monotheistic religion: "The <ent type='NORP'>Hegelian</ent> principle of
evolution ... applied to religion, has powerfully helped to beget
a tendency to regard the religion of <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent> as evolved by processes
not transcending nature, from a polytheistic worship of the
elements to a spiritual and ethical monotheism." (CE. i, 493.) But
this finally and very late evolved monotheism is neither a tardy
divine revelation to the <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>s</ent>, nor a novel invention by them; it
was a thousand years antedated by Amenhotep IV and Tut-ankh-amen in
<ent type='GPE'>Egypt</ent>, -- nor were even they the pioneers. We have seen the
admission that the <ent type='NORP'>Zoroastrian</ent> Mithra religion was "a divinely
revealed Monotheism" (CE., ii, 156). But the <ent type='ORG'>Hebrews</ent> were confessed
and notorious idolaters and polytheists <ent type='ORG'>un</ent>til after the Captivity;
that fact is a thousand times alleged throughout the <ent type='NORP'>Scriptures</ent> as
the sole reason for their troubles and captivity. As above
suggested, and as thoroughly demonstrated by the texts in my other
book, the Hebrew God Yahveh was but one of the many gods worshipped
by the <ent type='ORG'>Hebrews</ent>; and Yahveh never claimed more than to be a "God
above all gods," to be preferred before them all; -- as at <ent type='GPE'>Sinai</ent> he
enacted: "Thou shalt have no other gods before [in preference to]
me," -- thus admitting the other gods.</p>

<p>    FORGERY BY CONTRADICTIONS</p>

<p>   Contradictions throughout the Bible, Old and New Testaments
alike, abo<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>d by the many thousands, and in virtually every book of
both Testaments, -- as every one knows who has read the Bible even
casually. See some thousand and more of the most notorious and
vital ones as cited in "deadly parallel" in my Is It God's Word? as
one of the most conclusive proofs of <ent type='ORG'>un</ent>inspired human origin and of
confusion worse confo<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>ded of tinkering, "interpolation" and
forgery outright, by the pious priests of <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Judah</ent>, and the
Ezra "school" of forgers of the "Law and the Prophets."</p>

<p>    OUR "PHONY" CHRISTIAN ERA</p>

<p>   "It was a monk of the 6th century, named Dionysiug Exiguus
(Dennis the Little), who fixed our present <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> era, laying
down that Jesus Christ was born on the 25th of December, A.U.C.
753, and commencing the new era from the following year, 754. That
date, as we shall see, cannot be correct and, instead of being an
improvement on, is farther from the truth than the dates assigned
by the early Fathers, St. Irenaeus and <ent type='NORP'>Tertullian</ent>, who fixed the
date of the Nativity in the 41st year of Augustus, that is to say,
3 years B.C., or A.U.C, 751 ... All this points to the fact that
Herod died in the year 4 B.C., and that our Savior must have been
born before that date ... Our Savior was born some time before
Herod's death, probably two years or more. So that, if Herod died </p>

<p>   Bank of Wisdom
    Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
    74
.
   FORGERY IN <ent type='ORG'>CHRISTIANITY</ent></p>

<p>in the year 4 B.C., we should be taken to 6 or 7 B.C. as the year
of the Nativity" (CE. 735-6).</p>

<p>   This, of course, discredits the date given by the inspiration
of [71] Luke, and demonstrates that both he and Matthew merely
alleged fictitious dates for what in all human probability was a
purely fictitious event. The new Era of Christ was, however, very
slow in gaining recognition; the first official secular document
dating by it was a charter of <ent type='ORG'>Charlemagne</ent>, after 800 A.D., and it
did not come into general use <ent type='ORG'>un</ent>til about 1000 A.D. I may mention
a fiery sermon I once heard, in which the expo<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>der of truth
vindicated the glory of God by declaiming that every <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent> and
Infidel confessed to Jesus Christ every time he dated a letter or
mentioned the year of an event. Being simply a hearer of the Word,
I could not rise to suggest, that by the same token we confess more
to the <ent type='NORP'>Pagan</ent> gods than to the <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent>, -- for more than half the
months and every day of the week are named for <ent type='NORP'>Pagan</ent> deities, and
we name them much more often than we do the years of grace and
salvation of Christ. After this bad start from Gospel error and
contradiction, we now turn to further evidences of "Gospel truth"
in contradictions and forgery.</p>

<p>   Among the most signal of these incessant contradictions and
scientific impossibilities of Divine Inspiration, are those
relating to the capital matter, -- for the credit of the <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent>
Religion, of the time and manner of <ent type='ORG'>Creation</ent> of earth and Man,
based on Holy Writ and on the "chronology" worked out, with several
h<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>dred disparate results, from the inspired pedigrees of the ante-
Diluvian <ent type='ORG'>Patriarchs</ent>. So fatally important is this to <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent>ity,
that the 'True <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> -- "which never deceived anyone" and "has
never erred," -- speaking through CE., thus admits that
<ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent>ity stands or falls with -- "the literal, historical sense
of the first three chapters of <ent type='ORG'>Genesis</ent> in as far as they bear on
the facts touching the fo<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>dations of the <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> religion, e.g.,
the creation of all things by God at the beginning of time, the
especial creation of man, the formation of the first woman from the
first man, the <ent type='ORG'>un</ent>ity of the human race"! (Papal <ent type='NORP'>Biblical</ent>
Commission, J<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>e 30, 1909; CE. vii, 313). Thus: No Adam and Eve, no
Garden of <ent type='LOC'>Eden</ent> and Talking Snake, no "Fall" and Curse -- therefore:
No Savior Jesus Christ, no Plan of Salvation, no truth in the
<ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> Religion! The fatal point is elucidated with inexorable
logic and dogmatic truth by the "Reformed" ex-Father Peter Martyr:
"So important is it to comprehend the work of creation that we see
the creed of the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> take this as its starting point. Were this
Article taken away, there would be no original sin; the promise of
Christ would become void, and all the vital force of our religion
would be destroyed"! Father Luther inherited the same faith and
bequeathed it to his dissident following: "Moses spoke properly and
plainly, and neither allegorically nor figuratively; and therefore
the world with all creatures was created in six days." Calvin, in
his "Commentary on <ent type='ORG'>Genesis</ent>," argues that the <ent type='ORG'>Genesis</ent> acco<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>t of
<ent type='ORG'>Creation</ent> is literally true, and warns those who dare to believe
otherwise, and thus "basely insult the Creator, to expect a Judge
who will annihilate them." Again he says: "We know on the authority
of Moses, that longer ago than 6000 years the world did not exist."
So too, the Westminster Confession of Faith, in full <ent type='NORP'>Protestant</ent>
force and effect today -- specially lays it down as "necessary to </p>

<p>   Bank of Wisdom
    Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
    75
.
   FORGERY IN <ent type='ORG'>CHRISTIANITY</ent></p>

<p>salvation to believe that all things visible and invisible were
created not only out of nothing but exactly in six days." And the
<ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>es have murdered co<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>tless thousands to impress this
beautiful impossible truth.</p>

<p>   Notwithstanding the crushing disproofs of those primitive
forged "Fables of Moses," by every fact of astronomy, geology,
anthropology, biology, and <ent type='ORG'>kindred sciences</ent>, known to schoolboys
today, Faith clings fatuously to its fetches: <ent type='GPE'>Arkansas</ent> ("Now
laugh!"), <ent type='GPE'>Mississippi</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Tennessee</ent>, three <ent type='GPE'>States</ent> of the Twentieth
Century <ent type='GPE'>United <ent type='GPE'>States</ent></ent>, have made it crime by Law to teach the
sciences which discredit the <ent type='ORG'>Genesis</ent> Myths, upon which <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent>
Superstition utterly depends;, and like medieval laws are sought to
be imposed in all our <ent type='GPE'>States</ent>. The True <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>, like all the others,
still fo<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>ds its "Faith and Morals" upon these old Hebrew forgeries
of <ent type='ORG'>Genesis</ent> and peddles them to its Faithful; but it knows better.
Thus the whole True Faith is shipwrecked by these heretical
confessions of CE., forced from it by the truths of heretical
<ent type='NORP'>Modern</ent>ism, in full face of the fierce inspired fulminations of the
Syllabus of Errors: "In an article on Bible chronology it is hardly
necessary in these days to discuss the date of the <ent type='ORG'>Creation</ent>. At
least two h<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>dred dates have been suggested, varying from 3483 to
6934 year B.C. all based on the supposition that the Bible enables
us to settle the point. But it does nothing of the kind. ... The
literal interpretation has now been entirely abandoned; and the
world is admitted to be of immense antiquity"! (CE. iii, 731.)
Again the "sacred science" of <ent type='ORG'>Genesis</ent> and of <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent>ity is
further admitted to be false, and the fabulous "Septuagint" Bible
on which <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent>ity was fo<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>ded before the era of the second
century forgeries of Gospels and Epistles, to be a holy fraud, in
these further excerpts accrediting the true revelations of modern
Science as against those of Moses:</p>

<p>   "The church ... does not attach decisive influence to the
chronology of the <ent type='ORG'>Vulgate</ent>, the official version of the Western
<ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>, since in the Martyrology for Christmas day, the creation of
Adam is put down in the year 5199 B.C., which is the reading of the
Septuagint. It is, however, certain that we cannot confine the
years of man's sojourn on earth to that usually set down. ...
Various explanations have been given of chapter v (<ent type='ORG'>Genesis</ent>) to
explain the short time it seems to allow between the <ent type='ORG'>Creation</ent> and
the Flood. ... The total number of years in the Hebrew, <ent type='ORG'>Samaritan</ent>,
and Septuagint differs, in the Hebrew it being 1656, in the
<ent type='ORG'>Samaritan</ent> 1307, and in the Septuagint 2242. ... According to
Science the length of this period was much greater than appears
from the genealogical table. ... In any case, whether we follow the
traditional or critical view, the numbers obtained from the
genealogy of the <ent type='ORG'>Patriarchs</ent> in chapter xi must be greatly
augmented, in order to allow time for such a development of
civilization, language, and race type as had been reached by the
time of Abraham." (CE. iii, 731-3.)</p>

<p>    FORGERY BY FALSE TRANSLATIONS</p>

<p>   We have noted the capital forgery wrought by the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> in
consciously and <ent type='ORG'>un</ent>conscionably adopting and perpetuating the false
translation in the Septuagint, of the "virgin shall conceive" </p>

<p>   Bank of Wisdom
    Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
    76
.
   FORGERY IN <ent type='ORG'>CHRISTIANITY</ent></p>

<p>pretended prophecy of Isaiah vii, 14. Indisputably the whole forged
fabric of supernatural <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent>ity is based on, and depends upon,
this one monumental forgery falsely used to give credit to the
<ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> forgery of "the Gospel according to Matthew" as to the
Divine and miraculous "Virgin birth of Jesus Christ." Out of scores
of other notoriously falsified translations of the sacred Old
Testament texts, attention is here called only to several of the
most signal ones which vitally affect and destroy the validity of
the most essential pretensions of truth of the <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> religion.
These frauds of translation and others, have been thoroughly
examined and supported by numerous texts from the original Hebrew,
and falsified verses of the English versions, in my 'Is It God's
Word?,' to which references must be made for a more complete
treatment than is here pertinent. Those now cited in summary are
all of them deliberate falsifications and forgeries in translation
which go to the vitals of the <ent type='GPE'>Hebrao</ent>-<ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> system of holy
imposture.</p>

<p>   If the Hebrew originals had been truthfully translated, we
should have no such false pretenses for faith as the Hebrew One God
anciently revealed to Adam, and to Moses, no Adam, no man "but
little lower than the angels" because of his immortal soul, no
<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>ique "revelation' of the "Ineffable Name" Jehovah to Moses; all
that we would have, -- all that the Hebrew texts reveal -- is a
primitive polytheistic idolatry of the crudest and most
superstitious order. Let us see.</p>

<p>    (a) The "God" Forgery</p>

<p>   The first sentence of the translated Bibles is a falsification
and forgery of the highest importance. We read with awed solemnity
of faith: "In the beginning God created the heaven and the earth"
(Gen. i, 1). The Hebrew word for God is el; the plural is elohim,
gods. The Hebrew text of <ent type='ORG'>Genesis</ent> i, 1, reads: "Bereshith bara
elohim," etc., -- "In-beginning created gods the-heavens and-the-
earth." And, in the same chapter we read in Hebrew honestly
translated, -- thirty times the word "elohim" gods, to whom are
attributed all the works of creation in the six peculiar "days" of
<ent type='ORG'>Genesis</ent>. This is plainly evident from the Hebrew texts of <ent type='ORG'>Genesis</ent>
i, which even false intention could not hide in the translation,
"And-said elohim (gods), let-<ent type='GPE'>US</ent>-make man (adam) in-image-OUR,
after-likeness-OUR" (i, 26). And when "adam" had eaten of the
forbidden fruit of the tree of knowledge, "the Lord God" said,
"Behold, the-man has become like one of <ent type='GPE'>US</ent>, to know good and evil"
(iii, 27). And when <ent type='ORG'>the Tower of Babel</ent> was abuilding, "The Lord
[Heb. Yahveh] said ... Come, let <ent type='GPE'>US</ent> go down," etc. And thus, some
2570 times the plural, elohim, gods, is used in the Hebrew texts,
but is always falsely translated "God" in the false singular, when
speaking of the Hebrew deity, Yahveh.</p>

<p>   In the three <ent type='ORG'>Genesis</ent> verses above quoted, we have three
different designations of the Hebrew deity or deities: elohim,
gods, falsely translated "God"; "Lord God" (Heb. Yahveh-elohim);
and "Lord" (Heb. Yahveh). Yahveh is the proper name of the Hebrew
God, in English rendered Jehovah: Yahveh-elohim is a Hebrew
"construct-form" honestly meaning "Yahveh-of-the-gods." Invariably
(with rare exceptions to be noted), these personal names are </p>

<p>   Bank of Wisdom
    Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
    77
.
   FORGERY IN <ent type='ORG'>CHRISTIANITY</ent></p>

<p>falsely rendered "Lord" and "Lord God," respectively, for purposes
of pious fraud which we shall now expose to the shame of a theology
of imposture. We will return to this after noting a pair of others.</p>

<p>   (b) The "Adam" Forgery</p>

<p>   There was no first man "Adam," according to the Hebrew texts
of the story. The word adam in Hebrew is a common no<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>, meaning man
in a generic sense; in <ent type='ORG'>Genesis</ent> i, 26, we have read: "And elohim
(gods) said, Let us make adam (man)"; and so "elohim created ha-
adam (the-man); ... male and female created he them" (i. 27). And
in the second story, where man is first made alone: "Yahveh formed
ha-adan (the-man) out of the dust of ha-<ent type='GPE'>adamah</ent>-the gro<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>d" (ii, 7).
Man is called in Hebrew adam because formed out of <ent type='GPE'>adamah</ent>, the
gro<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>d; just as in <ent type='NORP'>Latin</ent> man is called homo because formed from
humus, the gro<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>d, -- homo ex humo, in the epigram of Father
Lactantius. (Lact., Divine Institutes, ii, 58; <ent type='ORG'>ANF</ent>. vii, 58.) The
forging by the common no<ent type='ORG'>un</ent> adam into a mythical proper name Adam,
was a post-exilic fraud in the forging of fictitious genealogies
from "in the beginning" to Father Abraham.</p>

<p>   (c) The "Soul" Forgery</p>

<p>   In <ent type='ORG'>Genesis</ent> i is the acco<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>t of the creation of elohim -- gods
-- on the fifth day, of "<ent type='GPE'>nephesh hayyah</ent> -- the moving creature that
hath life," and of "<ent type='GPE'>nephesh hayyah</ent> -- every living creature" -- out
of the waters (i, 20, 21); and on the sixth day of "<ent type='GPE'>nephesh hayyah</ent>
-- the living creature" out of the gro<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>d (i, 24); and he gave to
ha-adam -- the-man dominion over "kol nephesh hagyah, -- everything
wherein there is life," (i, 30.) So reads the Hebrew text -- all
these dumb animal living creatures are by God called "nephesh
hayyah," "literally "living soul," as will be fo<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>d stuck into the
margins of the Authorized Version. In chapter ii we have the
history of ha-adam made from ha-<ent type='GPE'>adamah</ent>; and, in wonderful contrast
to these lowly "living creatures" (<ent type='GPE'>nephesh hayyah</ent>), Yahveh-clohim
"breathed into his nostrils nishmath hayyim -- (living breaths),
and ha-adam became <ent type='GPE'>nephesh hayyah</ent> -- a living soul"! (ii, 7.) In
Hebrew nephesh everywhere and simply means soul, and hayyah
(living) is the feminine singular adjective from hai, life. Man,
therefore, was created exactly the same as the other animals; all
had or were <ent type='GPE'>nephesh hayyah</ent> -- living souls, indistinctly. The
"false pen of the scribes," who in translation made the dumb
animals merely living creatures, and "<ent type='ORG'>Creation</ent>'s micro-cosmical
masterpiece, Man," a "living soul," falsely altered these plain
words so as to deceive into a belief of a special God-breathed soul
in man, far different from the brute animal that perisheth.</p>

<p>   (d) The "Mosaic Revelation" Forgery</p>

<p>   When Yahveh appeared to Moses in the Burning Bush, and
anno<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>ced himself as "the God of thy fathers," he was a total
stranger to Moses; Moses did not at all know him, had never heard
of him; so that he asked, "What is thy name?" -- so that he could
report it to the people back home in <ent type='GPE'>Egypt</ent>, who had never heard it.
After some intermission, the God came directly to the point, and
declared -- l quote the exact words --  one of the most notorious
falsities in Holy Writ:</p>

<p>   Bank of Wisdom
    Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
    78
.
   FORGERY IN <ent type='ORG'>CHRISTIANITY</ent></p>

<p>   "And elohim spake <ent type='ORG'>un</ent>to Moses, and said <ent type='ORG'>un</ent>to him., anoki Yahveh
-- I am the Lord!</p>

<p>   "And I appeared <ent type='ORG'>un</ent>to Abraham, <ent type='ORG'>un</ent>to Isaac, and <ent type='ORG'>un</ent>to Jacob, by
the name of el-shaddai, but by my name Yahvch (<ent type='ORG'>JEHOVAH</ent>) was I not
known to them." (Ex. vi, 2, 8.)</p>

<p>   Here we have the positive averment of the Hebrew God himself
to the effect that here, for the first time since the world began,
is "revealed" to mankind the "ineffable name" of Yahveh, here first
appearing in the Bible translations, and there printed as <ent type='ORG'>JEHOVAH</ent>
in capital letters; for more vivid and awe-inspiring impression.
But this is a capital Lie of the Lord, or of his biographer who
imputed it to him. In verse 4 of <ent type='ORG'>Genesis</ent> ii, the name YAHVEH first
appears; "in the day that Yahveh-elohim made the earth and the
heavens." Its first recorded use in the mouth of a mystical
personage, was when Mother Eve "conceived, and bare Cain, and said,
I have gotten a man from Yahveh -- the Lord." (Gen. iv, 1.) One
h<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>dred and fifty-six times the personal name YAHVEH occurs in the
Book of <ent type='ORG'>Genesis</ent> alone; and scores of times in the mouths of
Abraham, of Isaac, and of Jacob, as any one may read in <ent type='ORG'>Genesis</ent>,
with the assurance that every single time that the title "the Lord"
and "the Lord God" appears, it is a false translation by the
priests for the Hebrew personal name YAHVEH. Throughout the Hebrew
"<ent type='NORP'>Scriptures</ent>" the Divine Name thousands of times occurs: "The sacred
name occurs in <ent type='ORG'>Genesis</ent> about 156 times; ... in ro<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>d numbers it is
fo<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>d in the Old Testament 6000 times, either alone or in
conj<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>ction with another Divine name." (CE. viii, 829, 331.) More
exactly, "What is called the Tetragrammaton, YHVH, appears in the
Old Testament 6823 times as the proper name of God as the God of
<ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent>. As such it serves to distinguish him from the gods of the
other nations." (<ent type='ORG'>EB</ent>. iii, 3320.) Thus was the Hebrew tribal god
YAHVEH distinguished from Bel, and <ent type='ORG'>Chemosh</ent>, and <ent type='ORG'>Dagon</ent>, and Shamash,
and the scores of "gods of the nations"; just as Bill distinguishes
its bearer from Tom, Dick, and Harry. This was precisely the Hebrew
usage -- to distinguish one heathen god from another. And this the
false translators sought to hide, giving names to all the "other
gods," but suppressing a name for the Hebrew deity, who as "the
Lord," or "the Lord God," was high and <ent type='ORG'>un</ent>ique, "a god above all
gods," -- the one and only true God.</p>

<p>   But yet more malicious and evil-intentioned of deception: 6828
times is the name of the Hebrew God concealed by false rendition
for the deliberate purpose of forging the whole Hebrew Bible, as
translated, into semblance of harmony with the false avowal of
Exodus vi, 3, that "by my name YAHVEH was I not know <ent type='ORG'>un</ent>to them."
<ent type='ORG'>Search</ent> as one may, outside Exodus vi, 3, the god-name YAHVEH
(Jehovah) is never to be fo<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>d in the translations in a single
instance, except in Psalm lxxxiii, 18, and Isaiah xii, 2 and xxvi,
4. The false translations thus "make truth to be a liar," the lie
of Exodus vi, 3 to seem the truth; and a barbarous heathen tribal
god among a h<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>dred neighbor and competitive gods to be the
nameless One Lord God of the <ent type='ORG'>Universe</ent>. The Hebrew-<ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> One God
is a patent Forgery and Myth; a mycological Father-god can have no
"only begotten Son"; Jesus Christ is a myths even before he is
mythically born in the fancies of the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> Fathers, as we shall
soon have ample evidence to prove.</p>

<p>   Bank of Wisdom
    Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
    79
.
   FORGERY IN <ent type='ORG'>CHRISTIANITY</ent></p>

<p>   With respect to the mythical Hebrew-<ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> God or gods, we
may safely say, as says Father Justin Martyr apropos of the other
mythic <ent type='NORP'>Pagan</ent> gods: "And we confess that we are atheists, so far as
gods of this sort are concerned." (First Apology, ch. vi; <ent type='ORG'>ANF</ent>. i,
169.)</p>

<p>    THE ANCIENT IDEA OF "HISTORY"</p>

<p>   We may pause a moment to catch a vitutable view which will be
of great aid to <ent type='ORG'>un</ent>derstanding the mental processes of the ancient
writers in their portrayal of events, real or fanciful, which they
set about to record as "history." These pioneers of historical
literature lived in an age of simple-minded credulity, and
everything which they saw recorded or heard related, however
extravagant and seemingly incredible or impossible, passed all as
perfectly good history in their receptive and <ent type='ORG'>un</ent>critical minds.
Speaking of the legendary, the traditional, the supernatural
stories, myths, folk-lore and fables, -- "in short, everything
which seemed to testify to the past," -- which formed the raw
material of the early historians, <ent type='ORG'>the Encyclopedia</ent> Biblica gives a
graphic picture of primitive history-writing, not only <ent type='NORP'>Hebraic</ent> but
Gentilic:</p>

<p>   "Their sources, like those of the <ent type='NORP'>Greek</ent> logographers with whom
it is natural to compare them, were poems, genealogies, often
representing clan-groupings, tribal and local traditions of diverse
kinds, such as furnish the materials for most of the Book of
Judges; the historical traditions of sanctuaries; the sacred
legends of holy places, relating theophanies and other revelations,
the erection of the altar or sacred stone, the. origin of popular
usages -- e.g. Bethel; laws; myths of foreign or native origin;
folk-lore and fable, -- in short, everything which seemed to
testify of the past.</p>

<p>   "To us the greater part of this material is not in any proper
sense historical at all; but for the early <ent type='NORP'><ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent>ite</ent> as for the
early <ent type='NORP'>Greek</ent> historian it was otherwise; our distinctions between
authentic history, legendary history, pure legend, and myth, he
made as little as he recognized our distinction of natural and
supernatural. It was all history to him; and if one part of it had
a better attestation than another, it was certainly the sacred
history as it was told at the ancient sanctuaries of the land.</p>

<p>   The early Hebrew historians did not affix their names to their
works; they had, indeed, no idea of authorship. The traditions and
legends which they collected were common property, and did not
cease to be so when they were committed to writing; the written
book was in every sense the property of the scribe or the possessor
of the roll. Only a part of the great volume of tradition was
included in the first books. <ent type='ORG'>Transcribers</ent> freely added new matter
from the same sources on which the original authors had drawn, the
traditions of their own locality or sanctuary, variants of
historical traditions or legend. Every new copy was thus in some
measure a fresh rescension. ... Scribes compared different copies,
and combined their contents according to their own judgment or
interests. ... Of records or monuments there are but a few traces,
and these for the most part doubtful." (<ent type='ORG'>EB</ent>. ii, 2075-76.)</p>

<p>   Bank of Wisdom
    Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
    80
.
   FORGERY IN <ent type='ORG'>CHRISTIANITY</ent></p>

<p>   To say nothing now of the Old or New Testament "canonical" and
"apocryphal" literature, co<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>tless examples of this imaginative
method of history-writing abo<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>d in all the ancient writers, as all
who are familiar with such classics as <ent type='ORG'>Herodotus</ent>, Thucydides,
Xenophon, Josephus, Livy, will readily recall. One of the most
inveterate forms of imaginative creation on the part of the old
historiographers was the invention of sayings and whole speeches
which, just as do the fiction-writers of today, they put entire
into the mouths of the personages of whom they were writing, which
discourses they not only invented whole, but always wrought them in
the style and manner of the writer and his epoch, and not in those
of their ancient subjects. All are familiar with such instances in
Homer, Dante, Shakespeare and Milton, and which we all known are
pure inventions of those writers. Naming several of the ancient
historians above mentioned, and others, a distinguished philosopher
of history thus describes the art:</p>

<p>  "Such speeches as we find in Thucydides (for example), of
   which we can positively assert that they are not bona-fide
   records. ... Thus Livy puts into the mouths of the old <ent type='NORP'>Roman</ent>
   <ent type='GPE'>King</ent>s, Consuls, and generals, such orations as would be
   delivered by an accomplished advocate of the Livian era... In
   the same way he gives us descriptions of battles, as if he had
   been an actual spectator; but whose features would serve well
   enough for battles in any period." (Hegel, The Philosophy of
   History, i). 2.)</p>

<p>   Speaking of much later times, and of a different class, but
like type, of writers, Hegel again says: "In the Middle Ages, we
except the <ent type='ORG'>Bishops</ent>, who were placed in the very center of the
political world, the <ent type='ORG'>Monks</ent> monopolized this category as maine
chroniclers." (Ib. p. 3.)</p>

<p>   As typical illustration of the principles and practices above
described of the best of the ancient writers, but more especially
as an example of the kind of "history" written by the most learned
and illustrious historian of <ent type='ORG'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ry</ent>, fellow-co<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>tryman and
contemporary of the supposed Apostolic writers of the New Testament
books, it is of the highest significance to cite some of the solemn
historical recordation of Josephus, from two of his most famous
works; they will make more appreciated at their real value some of
the inspired historical recitals of contemporaneous sacred
history.'</p>

<p>   In his Antiquities of the <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>s</ent> Josephus follows closely the
subject matter and order of narration of the early Old Testament,
books, beginning with the <ent type='ORG'>Creation</ent>, giving the full substance of
those histories, and adding quaint comments all his own and
expansions and embellishments <ent type='ORG'>un</ent>known to or <ent type='ORG'>un</ent>recorded by Moses. In
<ent type='LOC'>Eden</ent>, not only the Talking Snake could speak, but all the now dumb
animals: "All living creatures had one language, at that time" (I,
i, 4). After our parents had eaten of <ent type='ORG'>the Fruit of Knowledge</ent> and,
discovering themselves naked, hid themselves from the Creator,
"This behavior surprised God," who delivers a lengthy speech of
reprieval not recorded by Moses (Ib.); and such orations are
plentiful and detailed between God and all the other notables who
came into personal contact with him; a gem is his oration to Noah. </p>

<p>   Bank of Wisdom
    Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
    81
.
   FORGERY IN <ent type='ORG'>CHRISTIANITY</ent></p>

<p>He relates the wars waged by the wicked posterity of Cain, to the
great distress of Adam, who predicted the two-fold destruction of
the earth, once by water and again by fire. As the <ent type='NORP'>Sethites</ent> were
good people and intelligent, and had made great discoveries in
astronomy, which they wished preserved for such posterity as might
survive the yet future Flood, "they made two pillars, the one of
brick, the other of stone; they inscribed their discoveries on them
both, that in case the pillar of brick should be destroyed by the
Flood, the pillar of stone might remain, and exhibit these
discoveries to mankind; and also inform them that there was another
pillar of brick erected by them. Now this remains in the land of
Siriad to this day." (lb., I, ii, 2.) He relates with naive and
realistic garnishment the tale of Sodom, and Lot and his daughters,
and of Lot's wife turned to a pillar of salt, which is Gospel
truth, "for I have seen it, and it remains at this day"! (Ib. 1,
xi, 4.) These historical drolleries might be quoted ad <ent type='ORG'>infinitum</ent>
from <ent type='ORG'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ry</ent>'s greatest historian.</p>

<p>   The name of <ent type='ORG'>Solomon</ent> was most potent conjure in the <ent type='LOC'>Orient</ent>
through all the succeeding centuries; the spells and charms,
amulets and fetishes inscribed with his mystic symbol and
prono<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>ced in his name, were the terror of all the devils who so
populated the <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish</ent> mind, and the <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent>. A noted instance of
the potency of this Name, exhibited before the <ent type='NORP'>Roman</ent> Emperor
<ent type='NORP'>Vespasian</ent> and his court and army, and witnessed by Josephus
himself, so circumstantial, so faith-compelling, so artless and
childishly fabling, that I am constrained to quote it for the
<ent type='ORG'>lightit</ent> sheds on the "historical" methods of the "age of apocryphal
literature":</p>

<p>  "God also enabled him [<ent type='ORG'>Solomon</ent>] to learn that skill which
   expels demons, which is a science useful and sensitive to men.
   He composed such incantations also by which distempers are
   alleviated. And he left behind him the manner of using
   exorcisms, by which they drive away demons, so that they never
   return, and this method of cure is of great force <ent type='ORG'>un</ent>to this
   day; for I have seen a certain man of my own co<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>try, whose
   name was Eleazar, relieving people that were demoniacs in the
   presence of <ent type='NORP'>Vespasian</ent>, and his sons, and his captains, and the
   whole multitude of his soldiers. The manner of the cure was
   this: he put a ring, that had a root of one of the sorts
   mentioned by <ent type='ORG'>Solomon</ent>, to the nostrils of the demoniac, after
   which he drew out the demon through his nostrils; and when the
   man fell down immediately, he abjured him to return into him
   no more, making still mention of <ent type='ORG'>Solomon</ent>, and reciting the
   incantation which he composed. And when Eleazar would persuade
   and demonstrate to the spectators that he had such a power, he
   set a little way off a cup or basin full of water, and
   commanded the demon, as he went out of the man, to overturn
   it, and thereby to let the spectators know that he had left
   the man; and when this was done, the skill and wisdom of
   <ent type='ORG'>Solomon</ent> was shown very manifestly; for which reason it is,
   that all men may know the vastness of <ent type='ORG'>Solomon</ent>'s abilities, and
   how he was beloved of God, and that the extraordinary virtues
   of every kind with which this king was endowed, may not be
   <ent type='ORG'>un</ent>known to any people <ent type='ORG'>un</ent>der the s<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>; for this reason, I say,
   it is that we have proceeded to speak so largely of these
   matters." (Josephus, Antiq. <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>s</ent>, Bk. VIII, Ch. ii, 5;
   Whiston's trans.)
   Bank of Wisdom
    Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
    82
.
   FORGERY IN <ent type='ORG'>CHRISTIANITY</ent>
   
   This is followed by the full text of the autograph letters
between <ent type='ORG'>Solomon</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Hiram</ent> regarding the building of the Temple.</p>

<p>   Whether the same kind of root of <ent type='ORG'>Solomon</ent>'s magical powers just
above used by Eleazar, or one of another species of like power, it
was very difficult to obtain and the quest was attended with many
dangers, which of course enhanced the value and potency of its
magic; but here is Josephus's solemn description of the plant and
acco<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>t of the eerie and risky manner of securing this treasure,
known locally as <ent type='GPE'>Baaras</ent> root:</p>

<p>  "Its color is like that of flame, and toward evening it
   sends out a certain ray like lightning: it is not easily taken
   by such as would do it, but recedes from their hands, nor will
   yield itself to be taken quietly, <ent type='ORG'>un</ent>til either the urine of a
   woman, or blood, be poured upon it; nay, even then it is
   certain death to those that touch it, <ent type='ORG'>un</ent>less anyone take and
   hang the root itself down from his hand, and so carry it away.
   It may also be taken another way, without danger, which is
   this: they dig a trench quite ro<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>d about it, till the hidden
   part of the root be very small, then they tie a dog to it,
   and, when the dog tries hard to follow him that tied him, this
   root is easily plucked up, but the dog dies immediately, as if
   it were instead of the man that would take the plant away nor
   after this need anyone be afraid of taking it into their
   hands. Yet, after all this pains in getting, it is only
   valuable on acco<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>t of one virtue it hath, that if it be only
   brought to sick persons, it quickly drives away those called
   demons, which are no other than the spirits of the wicked,
   that enter into any men that are alive and kill them, <ent type='ORG'>un</ent>less
   they can obtain some help against them." (Josephus, Wars of
   the <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>s</ent>, Book VII. Chap. iv, 3.)</p>

<p>   Instead of artful mendacity, some readers, in view of this,
may charitably impute artless simplicity of wit to some of the
devil-exorcising fable-mongers of the New Testament, the pious
Fathers who forged its <ent type='ORG'>Books</ent>.</p>

<p>   If such examples are abo<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>ding in the most brilliant of <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish</ent>
historians, distinguished for nobility of lineage, for
statesmanship and for literary ability, what may be expected from
the admittedly "ignorant and <ent type='ORG'>un</ent>learned men" such as traditionally
wrote those Gospels and Epistles of the <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent>s? We may now
appreciate the full significance of the admission of the <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>
Encyclopedia, speaking of the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> Fathers and writers through
all the Ages of Faith "before the eighteenth century," of whom it
says:</p>

<p>  The early ecclesiastical writers were <ent type='ORG'>un</ent>conscious of
   nearly all the problems to which criticism has given rise. ...
   Looking at the Divine side, they deemed as of trifling acco<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>t
   questions of authorship, date, composition, accepting
   <ent type='ORG'>un</ent>reservedly for these points such traditions as the <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish</ent>
   <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> had handed down. ... The Fathers saw in every sentence
   of the scripture a pregnant oracle of God. Apparent
   contradictions and other difficulties were solved without
   taking possible human imperfections into view. Except in </p>

<p>   Bank of Wisdom
    Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
    83
.
   FORGERY IN <ent type='ORG'>CHRISTIANITY</ent></p>

<p>   regard to the preservation of the sacred text there was
   nothing to elicit a critical view of the Bible in the age of
   the Fathers, and this applies also to the <ent type='NORP'>Scholastic</ent> period."
   (CE. iv, 492.)</p>

<p>   CHRISTIAN "REVELATIONS" IN JEWISH FORGERIES</p>

<p>   <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent>s no doubt believe in simple faith that the wonderful
inspired truths of their New Testament were original prono<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>cements
of Jesus Christ or directly revealed by him to his holy apostles,
who in turn revealed them to the populace for the first time as the
"good news" of the new religion for the salvation of sinful man.
Even a brief glance at a few of the most, notable of the <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish</ent>
forgeries of the "age of apocryphal literature" will dispel that
pious belief, and show the most characteristic and essential
doctrines and dogmas of <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent>ity to be but refurbished vagaries
of the fanciful and fabulous tpectulations of already existing
<ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish</ent> apocryphal writings of the times just preceding and within
the new <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> era. These writings were put forth falsely as the
utterances of long since dead or wholly legendary Old Testament
notables, and were neither inspired nor revealed heavenly truth,
but simply vain and forged speculations of their fantastic writers.
We shall see the cardinal tenets of "revealed" <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent>ity in a
glance at a few of these <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish</ent> pseudographs, and let the <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent>
apologist explain.</p>

<p>   This literature is of the highest value today because of the
light it throws on the growth of esehatological and <ent type='ORG'>Messianic</ent>
doctrines among the <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish</ent> people just previous to the rise of
<ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent>ity, especially since these doctrines have, in a purified
form, fo<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>d a permanete place in the <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> system." (New Int.
Enyc. i, 745.)</p>

<p>   The Book of Enoch, forged in the name of the grandson of Adam,
is the fragmentary remains of a whole literature which circulated
<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>der the pretended authorship of that mythical Patriarch. In its
present form, the work, of 104 chapters, is composed of five <ent type='ORG'>Books</ent>,
with the following titles, of which those of <ent type='ORG'>Books</ent> 3 and 4 are of
particular significance, namely: 1. The Rape of Women by Fallen
Angels, and the <ent type='ORG'>Giants</ent> that were Begotten of Them; 2. The Visions
of Enoch beg<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>; 3. The Visions continued, with Views of the 
essiah's <ent type='GPE'>King</ent>dom; 4. Man's Destiny revealed in Dreams from the
beginning to the End of the <ent type='ORG'>Messianic</ent> <ent type='GPE'>King</ent>dom; 5. The Warnings of
Enoch to his own Family and to Mankind. This work is a composite of
at least five <ent type='ORG'>un</ent>known <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish</ent> writers, and was composed during the
last two centuries B.C. The forged Book of Enoch is quoted as
genuine and inspired in the <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> Epistle of Jude (14, ef
seq.), and as "Scripture" in the near canonical Epistle of
Barnabas; with the early <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> Fathers and Apologists, among whom
Justin Martyr, Irenaeus, Athenagoras, <ent type='NORP'>Tertullian</ent>, Clement of
<ent type='GPE'>Alexandria</ent>, <ent type='NORP'>Anatolius</ent>, Origen, St, Augustine, etc., "it, had all
the wright of a canonical book," but was finally condemned as a
forgery by the forged Apostolic Constitutions, -- an instance of
the very dubious divine guidance of the inspired <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> against all
error. Father <ent type='NORP'>Tertullian</ent> devotes an entire chapter "Concerning the
Genuineness of the Prophecy of Enoch." in which he gives fantastic
patristic reasons as to how the Book survived Noah's Flood, either </p>

<p>   Bank of Wisdom
    Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
    84
.
   FORGERY IN <ent type='ORG'>CHRISTIANITY</ent></p>

<p>by the providence of Noah himself or by the Providence of God as in
the mythical case of Esdras. In answer to the scoffing objections
that the <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>s</ent> rejected the Book, "I suppose," he seriously argues,
"that they do not think that, having been published before the
Deluge, it could have safely survived that world-wide calamity, the
abolisher of all things." But, he urges, "let them recall to their
memory that Noah, the survivor of the deluge, was the great-grand-
son of Enoch himself," and that Noah probably preserved it at the
behest of <ent type='ORG'>Methuselah</ent>. But, again, "If Noah had not preserved it in
this way, there would still be this consideration to warrant our
assertion of the genuineness of this Scripture: he could equally
renewed it, <ent type='ORG'>un</ent>der the <ent type='ORG'>Spirit</ent>'s inspiration, after it, had been
destroyed by the violence of the Deluge, as, after the destruction
of <ent type='GPE'>Jerusalem</ent> by the <ent type='GPE'><ent type='GPE'>Babylon</ent>ian</ent> storming of it, every document of
the <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish</ent> literature is generally agreed to have been restored
through Ezra." But the good Father had other and equally cogent
clerical reasons for accepting the Book as inspired Scripture: "But
since Enoch in the same Scripture has preached likewise concerning
the Lord, nothing at all must be rejected by us which pertains to
us; and we read that 'every Scripture suitable for edification is
divinely inspired.' ... To these considerations is added the fact
that Enoch possesses a testimony in the Apostle Jude." (On the
Apparel of Women, II, ii; <ent type='ORG'>ANF</ent>. iv, 15-16.) By this excerpt from the
pious Father may be judged the value of the "testimony" of Apostles
and <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> Fathers as to the inspiration, truth and authenticity of
holy "<ent type='NORP'>Scriptures</ent>," -- which is nil.</p>

<p>   Of the immense significance of these forged <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish</ent> "sacred
writings" in general upon <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> "revelation," and of the
fabulous Book of Enoch in particular, with its elaborated myth of
the Messiah, CE. thus confesses: "<ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish</ent> Apocalyptic is an attempt
to supply the place of prophecy, which had been dead for centuries,
and has its roots in the sacred oracles of <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent>. ... Naturally
basing itself upon the Pentateuch and the Prophets, it clothed
itself fictitiously with the authority of a patriarch or prophet
who was made to reveal the transcendent future. ... Messianism of
Course plays an important part in apocalyptic eschatology, and the
idea of the Messiahs in certain books received a very high
development. ... The parables of <ent type='GPE'>Henoch</ent>, with their pre-existent
Messiahs, mark the highest point of development -- (hence not
Divine Revelation) -- of the <ent type='ORG'>Messianic</ent> concept to be fo<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>d in the
whole range of Hebrew literature." (CE. i, 601, 602.) From these
<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>inspired ravings of <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish</ent> forgers came thus the "divine
revelation" of the co-eternal "Son of God" worked up instead of the
old "revealed" human <ent type='GPE'>King</ent> "of the seed of David."</p>

<p>   The forged Book of Enoch, thus vouched for, is notable for
being "the earliest appearance of the Messiah in non-canonical
literature." It is of the greatest importance for its doctrine of
the <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish</ent> Messiah, who here appears as wholly an earthly human
deliverer and <ent type='GPE'>King</ent> over <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent> forever, and for the origin of the
exalted titles applied to the Messiah in the New Testament <ent type='ORG'>Books</ent>,
as well as of a number of supposedly distinctive <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent>
doctrines, first "revealed" by Jesus the Christ. In this Book we
first find the lofty titles: "Christ" or "the Anointed One," "Son
of Man," "the Righteous One," "the Elect One," -- all of which were
boldly plagiarized by the later <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent>s and bestowed on Jesus of</p>

<p>   Bank of Wisdom
    Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
    85
.
   FORGERY IN <ent type='ORG'>CHRISTIANITY</ent></p>

<p>Nazareth The Messiah, just as in the New Testament of later times,
exists from the beginning (48, 2); he sits on the throne of God
(453); and all judgment is committed <ent type='ORG'>un</ent>to him (69, 27). The
acceptance of Enoch as a <ent type='ORG'>Messianic</ent> prophet by the <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent>s led to
his rejection by the <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>s</ent>. Here is the earliest invention of the
<ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> Hell of fire and brimstone for eternal torture: "The
wicked shall go down into the Sheol of darkness and fire and dwell
there forever"; this being "one of the earliest mentions of Sheol
as a hell of torment" (CE. i, 602-3; <ent type='ORG'>EB</ent>. i, 223-5). It is the
oldest piece of <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish</ent> literature which teaches the general
resurrection of <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent>, a doctrine expanded to include <ent type='GPE'>Gentiles</ent> in
later "interpolations" into New Testament books. It abo<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>ds in such
"<ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent>" doctrines as the <ent type='ORG'>Messianic</ent> <ent type='GPE'>King</ent>dom, Hell, the
Resurrection, and Demonology, the Seven Heavens, and the
<ent type='ORG'>Millennium</ent>, all of which have here their apocryphal <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish</ent>
promulgation, after being plagiarized bodily from the <ent type='NORP'>Persian</ent> and
<ent type='GPE'><ent type='GPE'>Babylon</ent>ian</ent> myths superstitions, as we have seen confessed. There
are numerous quotations, phrases, clauses, or thoughts derived from
Enoch, or of closest kin with it, in several of the New Testament
Gospels and Epistles, which may be readily fo<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>d and compared as
catalogued in the authorities below cited; -- <ent type='NORP'>Pagan</ent>-<ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish</ent> myths
and doctrines which shared in molding the analogous New Testament
"revelations" or formed the necessary link in the development of
doctrines from the Old to the New Testament. The CE. says of the
Book of Enoch:</p>

<p>  "It had left its imprint on the New Testament and the
   works of the early Fathers. ... Clement of <ent type='GPE'>Alexandria</ent>,
   <ent type='NORP'>Tertullian</ent>, Origen, and even St. Augustine suppose the work to
   be a genuine one of the patriarch. ... The work is a
   compilation, and its component parts were written in <ent type='GPE'>Palestine</ent>
   by <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>s</ent> of the orthodox school ... in the latter part of the.
   second century before Christ. (See CE. i, 602. passim; <ent type='ORG'>EB</ent>. v,
   220-224.)</p>

<p>   In <ent type='ORG'>Fourth Esdras</ent>, as in the Apocalypse of Baruch, we find for
the first time, the fatal phrase and doctrine, "all mankind sinned
with Adam" (CE. i, 604), whence Paul forged his fearful and
accursed dogma of original sin and eternal damnation. Fourth
Marcabees, erroneously ascribed by Eusebius and others to Josephus,
dates from about 4 B.C., just after the death of Harod. It is
strongly indoctrinated with the <ent type='NORP'>Stoic</ent> philosophy, from which the
author "derived his four cardinal virtues, Prudence, Justice,
Fortitude, Temperance; and it was through Fourth Maccabees that
this category was appropriated by early <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> ascetical
writers" (CE. i, 605-6), and later "canonized" by the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>. (CE.
xi, 391.)</p>

<p>   The Assumption of Moses was forged in the name of that worthy
as its genuine author, about the beginning of, or early in the
<ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> era, with the ostensible purpose of confirming the Mosaic
Laws in <ent type='GPE'>Deut</ent>eronomy. It gives the parting comm<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>ications of Moses
to his successor, Joshua, and <ent type='ORG'>un</ent>folds, in a series of oretended
predictions, delivered in written from, the course of <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent>'s
history down to Herold's time. Here is fo<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>d the legend of the
dispute between Michael Archangel and Satan over the body of Moses,
which the <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> Epistle of Jude (v. 9) cites as God-inspired </p>

<p>   Bank of Wisdom
    Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
    86
.
   FORGERY IN <ent type='ORG'>CHRISTIANITY</ent></p>

<p>truth. (CE. i, 602-3.) The book of Jubilees, or little <ent type='ORG'>Geneses</ent>, is
a fabricated embellishment of the Old Testament <ent type='ORG'>Genesis</ent>, written in
the name of Moses somewhere between 135 B.C., or 60 A.D., and
purports to be a revelation made to Moses by the 'Angel of the
Face' of events from Adam to Moses' own day; the <ent type='ORG'>Patriarchs</ent> are
made the exponents of the writer's own <ent type='NORP'>Pharisaic</ent> views and hopes.
It is quoted as good "Scripture" by <ent type='NORP'>Greek</ent> and <ent type='NORP'>Latin</ent> Fathers down to
the twelfth century, when its forged character was discovered.</p>

<p>   One of the most important of apocryphal forgeries is the
Apocalypse of Baruch, "a pseudograph with evident <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent>
interpolations" (CE. i, 604), written by a <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish</ent> Pharisee about
50-90 A.D., who speaks in the first person in the name of Baruch,
secretary of the Prophet Jeremiah. The book begins by declaring
that the word of the Lord came to him in the 25th year of <ent type='GPE'>King</ent>
Jeconiah, -- who reigned only three months, and was carried away
captive to <ent type='GPE'>Babylon</ent> eleven years before the fall of <ent type='GPE'>Jerusalem</ent>, 586
B.C., which event the forgery bewails; it is filled with the
<ent type='ORG'>Messianic</ent> hopes of <ent type='ORG'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ry</ent> at the time of the fall of <ent type='GPE'>Jerusalem</ent> in 70
A.D. The book furnishes a setting and backgro<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>d of many
distinctive New Testament doctrines and problems, treating of
Original Sin, which it traces to the sin of Adam, Forgiveness,
Works, Justification, Free Will, etc., and this enables us to
estimate the contributions made in this respect by <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish</ent> forgeries
to inspired <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> thought as developed in the so-called Pauline
Epistles, -- which Paul never wrote. Some notable Fathers, such as
Athenagoras, St. Justin Martyr, and St. Irenaeus, cite <ent type='GPE'>Beruch</ent> as a
Prophet, and vouch for him as on the same footing as Jeremiah, just
as Irenaeus vouches for Susanna and Bel and the Dragon as the
inspired work of Daniel. (CE. i, 604; iii, 271; <ent type='ORG'>EB</ent>. i 220.)</p>

<p>   Father Justin, in several chapters, accuse the <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>s</ent> of having
"removed from Esdras and Jeremiah passages clearly mentioning the
Savior," as also from Psalms; he says: "they have altogether taken
away many <ent type='NORP'>Scriptures</ent> from the translation affected by those Seventy
elders who were with <ent type='NORP'>Ptolemy</ent>, and by which this very man was
crucified is proved to have been set forth expressly as God, and
man, and as having been crucified, and as dying." (Dial. Trypho,
chs. lxxi-lxxiv; <ent type='ORG'>ANF</ent>. i, 234-235.) But these passages, says
Middleton, were never in the Hebrew <ent type='NORP'>Scriptures</ent>; "they were not
erased by the <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>s</ent>, but added [to their copies] by the <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent>s,
or forged by Justin." (Op. cit., 41, 42.)</p>

<p>   To which extent these pious <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish</ent> forgeries formed the
backgro<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>d and basis of the <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> doctrines and dogmas of
pretended direct "revelation," and informed the thought and
utterance of Jesus Christ -- the raw material and working tools of
the <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> propagandist, may be realized from this
acknowledgement:</p>

<p>   "The most important and valuable of the extant <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish</ent>
apocrypha are those which contain the visions and revelations of
the <ent type='ORG'>un</ent>seen world and the <ent type='ORG'>Messianic</ent> future. <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish</ent> apocryphal
literature is a theme which deserves the attention of all
interested in the development of the religion of <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent>, that body
of concepts and tendencies in which are fixed the roots of the
great doctrinal principles of <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent>ity itself, just as its
Divine Fo<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>der took his temporal generation from the stock of 
orthodox <ent type='NORP'>Judaism</ent>.
   Bank of Wisdom
    Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
    87
.
   FORGERY IN <ent type='ORG'>CHRISTIANITY</ent></p>

<p>   The <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish</ent> apocryphas furnish the completing links in the
progress of <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish</ent> theology and fill what would otherwise be a gap,
though a small one, between the advanced stage marked by the
deutero-canonical -- [i.e. long doubted but finally accepted] --
books and its full maturity so relatively perfect that Jesus could
suppose as existing in the popular consciousness, without teaching
de novo, the doctrines of Future Retribution, the Resurrection of
the body, and the existence, nature and office of angels." (CE. i,
601.)</p>

<p>   All these divine and "revealed" doctrines of <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> faith
we have seen to be originally heathen <ent type='NORP'>Zoroastrian</ent> mythology, taken
over first by the <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>s</ent>, then boldly plagiarized by the ex-<ent type='NORP'>Pagan</ent>
<ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent>s. Dean Milman, of St. Paul's, thus describes the
<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>iversality of these notions among the heathens and the borrowing
by the <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>s</ent> and <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent>s of what were originally <ent type='NORP'>Pagan</ent>
superstitions -- now become articles of <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> revelation:</p>

<p>  "Satan, angels, immortality, resurrection -- all <ent type='NORP'>Persian</ent>
   and <ent type='NORP'>Zoroastrian</ent> doctrines imbibed by the <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>s</ent>. ... During the
   whole life of Christ, and the early propagation of the
   religion, it must be borne in mind, that they took place in an
   age, and among a people, which superstition had made so
   familiar with what were supposed to be preternatural events,
   that the wonders awakened no emotion, or were speedily
   superseded by some new demand on the every-ready belief."
   (Milman, History of <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent>ity, I, 93.)</p>

<p>   Thus, again, the most precious <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> truths, of supposed
divine "revelation" through God, Christ and apostles -- were
plagiarizations from forged <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish</ent> pseudo-<ent type='NORP'>Scriptures</ent>, taken over
into them from long contact with the <ent type='NORP'>Zoroastrian</ent> Pensions. These
myths and superstitions Jesus the Son of God fo<ent type='ORG'>un</ent>d ready at hand
"in the popular consciousness" of the ignorant wonder-craving
<ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish</ent> peasantry; and, Lo, our "revealed" <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> religion! We
may begin to suspect the later "inspired" books of the "Apostles"
as not beyond the taint of <ent type='NORP'>Pagan</ent> superstition and of the suspicion
of <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> forgery.</p>

<div>    ****   ****</div>

<p>  Reproducible Electronic Publishing can defeat censorship.</p>

<p>    <ent type='GPE'>The UNITED STATES of America</ent>
    must again become
   The Free Market-Place of Ideas.</p>

<p> The Bank of Wisdom is always looking for more of these old,
hidden, suppressed and forgotten books that contain needed facts
and information for today. If you have such books please contact
us, we need to give them back to America.</p>

<div>    ****   ****</div>

<p>   Bank of Wisdom
    Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
    88
 </p></xml>