<xml>
<p>FROM: Barbara Bennett
SUBJECT: <ent type='ORG'>The <ent type='ORG'>Social Security</ent></ent> Number</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>SSA</ent> has continually emphasized the fact that the <ent type='ORG'>SSN</ent> identifies a particular
record only and <ent type='ORG'>the <ent type='ORG'>Social Security</ent> Card</ent> indicates the person whose record
is identified by that number. In no way can <ent type='ORG'>the <ent type='ORG'>Social Security</ent> Card</ent> identify
the bearer. From 1946 to 1972 the legend "Not for Identification" was printed
on the face of the card. However, many people ignored the message and the
legend was eventually dropped. The social security number is the most widely
used and carefully controlled number in the country, which makes it an
attractive identifier.</p>

<p>With the exception of the restrictions imposed on <ent type='ORG'>Federal</ent> and some <ent type='ORG'>State</ent>
and local organizations by the Privacy Act of 1974, organizations requiring
a unique identifier for purposes of controlling their records are not
prohibited from using (with the consent of the holder) the <ent type='ORG'>SSN</ent>. <ent type='ORG'>SSA</ent> records
are confidential and knowledge of a person's <ent type='ORG'>SSN</ent> does not give the user access
to information in <ent type='ORG'>SSA</ent> files which is confidential by law.</p>

<p>Many commercial enterprises have used the <ent type='ORG'>SSN</ent> in various promotional efforts.
These uses are not authorized by <ent type='ORG'>SSA</ent>, but <ent type='ORG'>SSA</ent> has no authority to prohibit
such activities as most are not illegal. Some of these unauthorized uses are:
<ent type='ORG'>SSN</ent> contests; skip-tracers; sale or distribution of plastic or metal cards;
pocketbook numbers (the numbers used on sample social security cards in
wallets); misleading advertising, commercial enterprises charging fees for
<ent type='ORG'>SSN</ent> services; identification of personal property.</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>The <ent type='ORG'>Social Security</ent></ent> Number (<ent type='ORG'>SSN</ent>) is composed of 3 parts, XXX-XX-XXXX, called
the <ent type='LOC'>Area</ent>, Group, and Serial.  For the most part, (there are exceptions), the
<ent type='LOC'>Area</ent> is determined by where the individual APPLIED for <ent type='ORG'>SSN</ent> (before 1972) or
<ent type='ORG'>RESI<ent type='GPE'>DE</ent>D</ent> at time of application (after 1972). The areas are assigned follows:</p>

<p>000   unused 387-399 WI  528-529 <ent type='GPE'>UT</ent>
001-003 NH 400-407 KY  530   <ent type='GPE'>NV</ent>
004-007 ME 408-415 <ent type='GPE'>TN</ent>  531-539 <ent type='GPE'>WA</ent>
008-009 <ent type='GPE'>VT</ent> 416-424 <ent type='GPE'>AL</ent>  540-544 OR
010-034 <ent type='GPE'>MA</ent> 425-428 <ent type='ORG'>MS</ent>  545-573 <ent type='GPE'>CA</ent>
035-039 RI 429-432 AR  574   <ent type='GPE'>AK</ent>
040-049 CT 433-439 <ent type='GPE'>LA</ent>  575-576 HI
050-134 <ent type='GPE'>NY</ent> 440-448 OK  577-579 DC
135-158 <ent type='GPE'>NJ</ent> 449-467 <ent type='GPE'>TX</ent>  580   <ent type='GPE'>VI Virgin Islands</ent>
159-211 <ent type='GPE'>PA</ent> 468-477 <ent type='GPE'>MN</ent>  581-584 PR <ent type='GPE'>Puerto Rico</ent>
212-220 <ent type='GPE'>MD</ent> 478-485 <ent type='GPE'>IA</ent>  585   <ent type='GPE'>NM</ent>
221-222 <ent type='GPE'>DE</ent> 486-500 <ent type='GPE'>MO</ent>  586   <ent type='ORG'>PI Pacific Islands</ent>*
223-231 <ent type='GPE'>VA</ent> 501-502 ND  587-588 <ent type='ORG'>MS</ent>
232-236 <ent type='GPE'>WV</ent> 503-504 <ent type='GPE'>SD</ent>  589-595 <ent type='GPE'>FL</ent>
237-246 <ent type='GPE'>NC</ent> 505-508 NE  596-599 PR <ent type='GPE'>Puerto Rico</ent>
247-251 <ent type='GPE'>SC</ent> 509-515 <ent type='GPE'>KS</ent>  600-601 <ent type='GPE'>AZ</ent>
252-260 <ent type='GPE'>GA</ent> 516-517 <ent type='GPE'>MT</ent>  602-626 <ent type='GPE'>CA</ent>
261-267 <ent type='GPE'>FL</ent> 518-519 ID  *<ent type='GPE'>Guam</ent>, American Samoa,
268-302 <ent type='GPE'>OH</ent> 520   WY   Northern Mariana Islands,
303-317 IN 521-524 CO   Philippine Islands
318-361 IL 525   <ent type='GPE'>NM</ent>
362-386 <ent type='GPE'>MI</ent> 526-527 <ent type='GPE'>AZ</ent></p>

<p>627-699 unassigned, for future use</p>

<p>700-728 <ent type='ORG'>Railroad</ent> workers through 1963, then discontinued
729-899 unassigned, for future use
900-999 not valid <ent type='ORG'>SSN</ent>s, but were used for program purposes
  when state aid to the aged, blind and disabled was
  converted to a federal program administered by <ent type='ORG'>SSA</ent>.</p>

<p>As the <ent type='LOC'>Area</ent>s assigned to a locality are exhausted, new areas from the pool
are assigned. This is why some states have non-contiguous groups of <ent type='LOC'>Area</ent>s.</p>

<p>The Group portion of the <ent type='ORG'>SSN</ent> has no meaning other than to
determine whether or not a number has been assigned. <ent type='ORG'>SSA</ent>
publishes a list every month of the highest group assigned for
each <ent type='ORG'>SSN</ent> <ent type='LOC'>Area</ent>.  The order of assignment for the <ent type='ORG'>Groups</ent> is: odd
numbers under 10, even numbers over 9, even numbers under 9
except for 00 which is never used, and odd numbers over 10. For
example, if the highest group assigned for area 999 is 72, then
we know that the number 999-04-1234 is an invalid number because
even <ent type='ORG'>Groups</ent> under 9 have not yet been assigned.</p>

<p>The Serial portion of the <ent type='ORG'>SSN</ent> has no meaning. The Serial is not
assigned in strictly numerical order. The Serial 0000 is never assigned.</p>

<p>Before 1973, <ent type='ORG'><ent type='ORG'>Social Security</ent> Cards</ent> with pre-printed numbers were issued to
each local <ent type='ORG'>SSA</ent> office. The numbers were assigned by the local office. In 1973,
<ent type='ORG'>SSN</ent> assignment was automated and outstanding stocks of pre-printed cards were
destroyed. All <ent type='ORG'>SSN</ent>s are now assigned by computer from headquarters. There are
rare cases in which the computer system can be forced to accept a
manual assignment such as a person refusing a number with 666 in it!</p>

<p>A pamphlet entitled "<ent type='ORG'>The <ent type='ORG'>Social Security</ent></ent> Number" (Pub. No.
05-10633) provides an explanation of the <ent type='ORG'>SSN</ent>'s structure and
the method of assigning and validating <ent type='ORG'>Social Security</ent> numbers.</p>
</xml>