<xml><p>WRONG NUMBER FILENAME:  WTCBOMB3.ZIP

["By way of deception shall you Conquer." -- <ent type='ORG'>Mossad</ent>'s motto

Victor <ent type='ORG'>Ostrovsky</ent> was a career <ent type='ORG'>Mossad</ent> agent.  He left <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent>'s
secret police agency and returned to his native <ent type='GPE'>Canada</ent>, where he
wrote his best-selling book _By Way of Deception_.  He is the
only <ent type='ORG'>Mossad</ent> agent to leave the agency, discuss its covert
activities, and survive for more than one year.

"<ent type='ORG'>Mossad</ent>" means "by way of deception" in Hebrew.  - C.M.]



   [From _The Village Voice_, April 6, 1993]

   BY WAY OF DECEPTION?

   By Robert I. Friedman


Renegade <ent type='ORG'>Mossad</ent> agent Victor <ent type='ORG'>Ostrovsky</ent> told the Voice that <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent>i
intelligence may have been behind <ent type='ORG'>the World <ent type='ORG'>Trade Center</ent></ent> bombing.  <ent type='ORG'>Mossad</ent>
had motive and opportunity, says <ent type='ORG'>Ostrovsky</ent>, whose book about his spy days
caused a furor in <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent> as it climbed the best-seller charts in <ent type='LOC'>Europe</ent> and
<ent type='GPE'>America</ent>.  <ent type='ORG'>Ostrovsky</ent> admits he doesn't have "a shred of evidence" to support
his theory, which in my view is extremely dubious.

But consider:  Prime Minister Yizthak Rabin summarily expels to a snow-
covered mountain in <ent type='GPE'>Lebanon</ent> some 400 <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Palestinian</ent>s</ent> suspected of aiding and
abetting <ent type='ORG'>Hamas</ent>, a fundamentalist group in the occupied territories that
killed six <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent>i soldiers in November.  The expulsion was "a big PR
mistake," says <ent type='ORG'>Ostrovsky</ent>, noting that the international media and most
foreign governments severely criticized <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent>.

Meanwhile, the intifada had taken a new deadly turn.  Spurred by the
expulsion, <ent type='NORP'>Palestinian</ent> fundamentalists killed 12 <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent>is this month, the
highest single-month casualty figure since December 1987, when the intifada
started.  Desperate to crack down on the <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Palestinian</ent>s</ent> in the territories,
and draw media attention away from 400 freezing <ent type='NORP'>Palestinian</ent> deportees,
Rabin needed a plan to discredit <ent type='NORP'>Muslims</ent> in general and <ent type='NORP'><ent type='NORP'>Palestinian</ent>s</ent> in
particular so that <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent> would emerge in the media as a hero.

<ent type='ORG'>Mossad</ent>, says <ent type='ORG'>Ostrovsky</ent>, then concocted a devious scheme.  First <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent>i
intelligence leaks to Judy Miller of <ent type='ORG'>The New York <ent type='ORG'>Times</ent></ent> that <ent type='ORG'>Hamas</ent> is
headquartered in <ent type='GPE'>Fairfax</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Virginia</ent>, and is sending instructions to the
territories via fax and courier.  The <ent type='ORG'>Times</ent> publishes the account on the
front page, using as a news hook the fact that <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent> had just arrested
three <ent type='NORP'>Arab</ent> <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>ns from <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> who were in the territories organizing
<ent type='ORG'>Hamas</ent> terror cells.  Following the <ent type='ORG'>Times</ent> story, the <ent type='ORG'>ADL</ent> and other <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent>
institutions start carping about <ent type='NORP'>Palestinian</ent> Islamic terror cells operating
in <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>.

Having prepared public opinion and having already infiltrated the radical
mosques in <ent type='GPE'>New Jersey</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Brooklyn</ent> where Abdel Rahman preached and
disciples like <ent type='ORG'>El Sayyid Nosair</ent> prayed, <ent type='ORG'>Mossad</ent>, says <ent type='ORG'>Ostrovsky</ent>, almost
certainly recruited a close associate of the rabble-rousing <ent type='NORP'>Egyptian</ent> blind
man.  The insider is recruited In what <ent type='ORG'>Ostrovsky</ent> calls a "false flag
operation." The <ent type='NORP'>Arab</ent> "thinks he is being recruited by an <ent type='NORP'>Iranian</ent> agent or a
<ent type='NORP'>Libyan</ent>," says <ent type='ORG'>Ostrovsky</ent>.  He never suspects he is actually being "run" by
<ent type='ORG'>Mossad</ent>.

The <ent type='ORG'>Mossad</ent> "handler" then masterminds the world <ent type='ORG'>Trade Center</ent> bombing.  But
the bomb, says <ent type='ORG'>Ostrovsky</ent>, is never meant to detonate.  <ent type='ORG'>Mossad</ent> is supposed
to call the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> in the <ent type='GPE'>nick</ent> of time, becoming instant heroes.  "I can just
see the experts sitting on television saying the tower would not sustain
the brunt of this one-ton truck bomb." The bomb may have exploded
prematurely, <ent type='ORG'>Ostrovsky</ent> explains.

<ent type='ORG'>Ostrovsky</ent> points out correctly that in the past the <ent type='ORG'>Mossad</ent> has effectively
used this modus operandi.  In the early 1950s, <ent type='ORG'>Mossad</ent> recruited agents to
bomb <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n buildings in <ent type='GPE'>Cairo</ent>, hoping to drive a wedge between the U.S.
and Gamel Abdul Nasser.  When the facts became known in <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent>, the scandal
brought down the government.  According to <ent type='ORG'>Ostrovsky</ent>, in 1984 <ent type='ORG'>Mossad</ent>
detonated bombs outside of the U.S. embassy in Riyadh, <ent type='NORP'>Saudi</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Arab</ent>ia's
capital city, claiming credit in the name of an unknown radical <ent type='NORP'>Saudi</ent>
resistance group.  <ent type='ORG'>Ostrovsky</ent>, a member of <ent type='ORG'>Mossad</ent> at the time, says the
purpose was to weaken U.S./<ent type='NORP'>Saudi</ent> relations by showing' the U.S. that the
regime was fragile and about to fall.

But none of this explains why <ent type='ORG'>Mossad</ent> would put tens of thousands of
<ent type='GPE'>America</ent>ns -- presumably many of them <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> -- at risk.

     - R.I.F.


WRONG NUMBER FILENAME:  WTCBOMB3.TXT

</p></xml>