<xml><p>    48 page printout, pages 148 to 195 of 322
    CHAPTER V</p>

<p>   THE "GOSPEL" FORGERIES</p>

<p>"Whether a Church which stands convicted of having forged its
<ent type='person'>Creed</ent>, would have any scruple of forging its <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s, is a problem
that the reader will solve according to the influence of prejudice
or probability on his mind." <ent type='person'>Taylor</ent>, <ent type='person'>Diegesis</ent>, p. 10.</p>

<p>   LET us now take up the holy Evangels and <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Epistle</ent>s</ent> of Christ-
propaganda. After even our cursory examination of the welter of
<ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s, Acts, <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Epistle</ent>s</ent> and other pious frauds of Christian
missionary-work, all admittedly forged by holy hands in the early
Christian "age of apocryphal literature" in the names of <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent>
Christ himself, of the Twelve pseudo-apostles and other Worthies,
including Mother Eve, even the most credulous and uncritical
<ent type='person'>Bel</ent>iever must feel the intrusion of some question: How came the
four "<ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s according to" <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Matt</ent>hew</ent>, <ent type='person'>Mark</ent>, <ent type='person'>Luke</ent>, <ent type='person'>John</ent>, to be
sometime accepted as genuine and inspired? and, Why are there only
Four out of so much greater a number, as we have seen in
circulation and acceptance? The questions are pertinent, and shall
be given fair answer.</p>

<p>   This entire aggregation of forged religious writings, under
the guise of genuine <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s, Acts, <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Epistle</ent>s</ent>, Apocalypses, falsely
attributed to apostolic writers, is know together as "Old Christian
Literature," whether now called "canonical" or apocryphal. Of it
EB. says that this present distinction "does not, in point of fact,
rest upon any real difference in the character or origin of the
writings concerned, but only upon the assumption of their differing
values as sacred or non-sacred books." (EB. iii, 3481.)
Furthermore, the common characteristic and motive of them all is
thus described, or explained: "To compose 'letters' under another
name, especially under the name of persons whose living
presentment, or real or supposed spiritual equipment, it, was
proposed to set before the reader, was then just us usual as was
the other practice of introducing the same persons into narratives
and reporting their 'words' in the manner of which we have
examples, in the case of <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent>, in the <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s, and, in the case of
<ent type='person'>Peter</ent>, <ent type='person'>Paul</ent>, and other apostles, in the Acts." (EB. iii, 3481.)</p>

<p>   "The <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent> has come down to us," says Bishop <ent type='person'>Irenaeus</ent> (about
185 A.D.), which the apostles did at one time proclaim in public, 
and, at a later period, by the will of God, handed down to us in
the <ent type='person'>Scripture</ent>s, to be the ground and pillar of our faith. ... For,
after our Lord rose from the dead [the apostles] departed to the
ends of the earth, preaching the glad tidings of the good things
sent from God to us, who indeed do equally and individually possess
the <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent> of God." (Iren., Adv. Haer, Bk. III, ch. i; ANF. i,
414.) Bishop <ent type='person'>Irenaeus</ent> and <ent type='person'>Bishop <ent type='person'>Papias</ent></ent> have both averred that the
Christ lived to old age (even as late as 98-117 A.D.), flatly
denying thus as "heresy" the <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent> stories as to his crucifixion
at about thirty years of age. In any event, the <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Apostle</ent>s</ent>, according
to the record, scattered "to the ends of the earth, preaching,"
orally, before they wrote anything at all.</p>

<p>   But, says CE., although "the New Testament was not written all
at once, the books that compose it appeared one after another in
the space of fifty years, i.e., in the second half of the first </p>

<p>   Bank of Wisdom
    Box 926, Louisville, KY 40201
    148
.
   FORGERY IN CHRISTIANITY</p>

<p>century." (CE. xiv, 530.) That this last clause is untrue will be
fully and readily demonstrated. This statement, too, contradicts
Bishops <ent type='person'>Papias</ent> and <ent type='person'>Irenaeus</ent>, who are, positively, the only two of
the second century <ent type='person'>Fathers</ent> who up to their times at all mention
written <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s or their supposed authors, as we have seen and
shall more particularly notice.</p>

<p>   And CE. says, as is true, of the earliest existing manuscripts
of any New Testament books: "We have New Testament MSS. written not
much more than 300 years after the composition of the books"; and
it admits (though with much diminution of truth, as we shall see):
"And in them we find numerous differences, though but few of them
are important." (CE. xiv, 526.) In this CE. at another place, and
speaking much more nearly the truth, contradicts itself, saying:
"The existence of numerous and, at times, considerable differences
between the four canonical <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s is a fact which has long been
noticed and which all scholars readily admit. ... Those evangelical
records (SS. <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Matt</ent>hew</ent>, <ent type='person'>Mark</ent>, <ent type='person'>Luke</ent>) whose mutual resemblances are
obvious and striking, and ... the narrative (that of St. <ent type='person'>John</ent>)
whose relation with the other three is that of dissimilarity rather
than that of likeness." (CE. vi, 658.)</p>

<p>   But the so-called "canonical" books of the New Testament, as
of the Old, are a mess of contradictions and confusions of text, to
the present estimate of 150000 and more "variant readings," as is
well known and admitted. Thus CE.: "It is easy to understand how
numerous would be the readings of a text transcribed as often as
the Bible, and, as only one reading can represent the original, it
follows that all the others are necessarily faulty. Mill estimated
the variants of the New Testament at 30000, and since the
discovery of so many MSS. unknown to Mill, this number has greatly
increased." (CE. iv, 498.) Who, then, is "inspired" to distinguish
true from false readings, and thus to know what <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> Christ and
his entourage really said and did, or what some copyist's error or
priest's forgery make them say or do, falsely? Of the chaos and
juggling of sacred texts in the Great Dioceses of Africa, CE. says:
"There never existed in early Christian Africa an official Latin
text known to all the Churches, or used by the faithful to the
exclusion of all others. The African bishops willingly allowed
corrections to be made in a copy of the Sacred <ent type='person'>Scripture</ent>s, or even
a reference, when necessary, to the Greek text. With some
exceptions, it was the Septuagint text that prevailed, for the
O.T., until the fourth century. In the case of the New, the MSS.
were of the Western type. On this basis there arose a variety of
translations and interpretations. ... Apart from the discrepancies
to be found in two quotations from the same text in the works of
two different authors, and sometimes of the same author, we now
know that of several books of <ent type='person'>Scripture</ent> there were versions wholly
independent of each other." (CE. i, 193.)</p>

<p>   Bishop <ent type='person'>Victor</ent> of Tunnunum, who died about 569 A.D. and whose
work, says CE., "is of great historical value," says that in the
fifth century, "In the consulship of Messala, at the command of the
Emperor <ent type='person'>Anastasius</ent>, the Holy <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s, as written Idiotis
Evangelists, are corrected and amended." (<ent type='person'>Victor</ent> of T., Chronica,
p. 89-90; cited by Dr. Mills, Prolegom. to R.V., p. 98.) This would
indicate some very substantial tinkering with Holy Writ; which </p>

<p>   Bank of Wisdom
    Box 926, Louisville, KY 40201
    149
.
   FORGERY IN CHRISTIANITY</p>

<p>process was a continuing one, for, says CE., "Under Sixtus V (1585-
90) and <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Clement</ent> VIII</ent> (1592-1605) the Latin <ent type='person'>Vulgate</ent> after years of
revision attained its present shape." (CE., xii, 769.) And the
<ent type='person'>Vulgate</ent>, which was fiercely denounced as fearfully corrupt, was
only given sanction of divinity by the Council of Trent in 1546,
under the Curse of God against any who questioned it. Though this
amendatory tinkering of their two Holinesses was after the Council
of Trent had put the final Seal of the Holy Ghost on the <ent type='person'>Vulgate</ent> in
1546!</p>

<p>   STILL TINKERING AT IT!</p>

<p>   The ancient clerical trick of tempering with the "Word of God"
and amending its plenary Divine Inspiration and <ent type='person'>Inerrancy</ent>, goes on
apace today, even to the extent of putting a veneer of civilization
on the barbarian Hebrew God, and warping his own barbarian words so
as to make a semblance of a "God of Mercy" out of the self-styled
"Jealous God" of Holy Writ.</p>

<p>   In 1902, after the sacred Council of Trent, in 1546, had put
the Curse of God on any further tinkering with the Inerrant Bible,
His Holiness <ent type='person'>Leo XIII</ent> appointed a Commission of Cardinals, known as
the Pontifical Biblical Commission, to further amend Divine
Inspiration; in 1907, "the Commission, with the approval of the
sovereign pontiff, invited the Benedictine Order to undertake a
collection of the variant readings of the Latin <ent type='person'>Vulgate</ent> as a remote
preparation for a thoroughly amended edition." (CE. ii, 557.) This
august body has recently laid before His Holiness, after all these
years of labor, the revised text of the revelations of <ent type='person'>Moses</ent> in the
Book of Genesis; and is now worrying with <ent type='person'>Exodus</ent> and the "Ten
Commandments" in chapter XX thereof.</p>

<p>   Associated Press dispatches published to the world today,
relate that "the Vatican's International Commission on the revision
of the Bible [is] taking steps to correct one of the most famous
Biblical passages, <ent type='person'>Exodus</ent> xx, 5, now believed to have been
mistranslated"! (N.Y. Times, May 18, 1930.) The actual text, and
"what the Vatican Commission thinks it should read," are here
quoted so that all may judge of the immense farce and fraud of this
capital falsification; -- the material tampering being indicated by
italics.</p>

<p>   <ent type='person'>Exodus</ent> xx, 5 -- as is.</p>

<p>  "For I the Lord thy God am a Jealous God, visiting the
   iniquities of the fathers upon the children unto the third and
   fourth generation of then that hate me"; ...</p>

<p>   Ditto -- as falsified.</p>

<p>  "For I, the Lord thy God, am a God of loving-kindness and
   mercy, considering the errors of the fathers as mitigating
   circumstances in judging the children unto the third and
   fourth generation"!</p>

<p>   Even a fool knows that no set of words, humanly or divinely
devisable, could bear such enormity of contrary translation; this </p>

<p>   Bank of Wisdom
    Box 926, Louisville, KY 40201
    150
.
   FORGERY IN CHRISTIANITY</p>

<p>is self-evident. The simple Hebrew words of verse 5 do not admit of
a word of tampering in translation. Even the present translations
into modern languages make apparent the correctness of the familiar
rendering. The words of verse 5 -- "visiting the iniquities ... of
them that hate me," close with a semicolon, followed immediately by
their antithesis: -- "And showing mercy [Heb. chesed] unto
thousands of them that love me, and keep my commandments." (v. 6;
<ent type='person'>Deut</ent>. v. 9, 10.) The "Jealous God" pursues the progeny of those
"that hate" him, and "shows mercy ... to them that love" him. The
inspired "correction" of the "mistranslation" leaves verse 6
meaningless and redundant.</p>

<p>   But the two simple Hebrew words chiefly involved make this
fraudulent "correction" ridiculous and impossible. In Hebrew,
<ent type='person'>Yahweh</ent> says from Sinai: "<ent type='person'>Anoki yahweh</ent> elohe-ka EL QANNA -- I <ent type='person'>Yahweh</ent>
thy God [am a] Jealous God." The only false translation in this
verse is "Lord thy God" for the 6000-times falsified "<ent type='person'>Yahweh</ent> thy
God," as elsewhere noted. Always "qanna" means "jealous' -- and is
used of the "jealous god," husband, wife, etc. The "joker" in this
false "correction" is apparent from the word "chesed -- mercy,"
hundreds of times used in Holy Writ. There is no Hebrew word
meaning "loving-kindness"; this is a fanciful rendering given by
the pious translators to the same old word "chesed -- mercy." Even
the Infallible One knows -- or can look in a Hebrew dictionary or
concordance and see -- that "el qanna ... visiting iniquity" --
cannot be twisted into "et chesed and chesed ... showing chesed --
mercy" to only those that love him. And how many thousands of
"corrections" of words "now believed mistranslated," would be
necessary to whitewash the barbarian <ent type='person'>Yahweh</ent> of Holy Writ into a
"whited sepulchre" of civilized deity!</p>

<p>   SOME TESTS FOR FORGERY</p>

<p>   We have seen the debauchery of forgery out of which the Four
<ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s were born. This makes pertinent the critical statement of
one of the latest authorities on the subject: "Few genuine texts
have come down to us from beyond the Middle Ages -- most documents
reaching us in the form of later copies made by scribes in
monasteries"; and he adds: "The mere fact that documents have been
accepted for centuries does not itself protect them from the tests
of historical criticism." (Shotwell, See of <ent type='person'>Peter</ent>, Gen. Introd.
xix, xxii.) It is pertinent to add here a paragraph from CE. which
states with entire accuracy the elementary principles upon which
literary criticism rests; due to the application of just these
principles by honest and fearless critics, the Bible has been
stripped of every clerical pretense of inspired inerrancy and of
even common literary and historical honesty; so that even the
inerrant Church has been driven to confess countless errors and
forgeries; even, as we have seen, to the frank repudiation of the
fables of Creation, the Mosaic authorship of the <ent type='person'>Pentateuch</ent>, and
the divine revelation of the Hebrew religion, which is thus shown
to be a very human evolution. These critical principles have
destroyed the vast mass of Hebrew and Christian apocrypha; and may
now be applied to the New Testament booklets which yet make false
pretense to divine inspiration of truth. Says CE.:</p>

<p>   Bank of Wisdom
    Box 926, Louisville, KY 40201
    151
.
   FORGERY IN CHRISTIANITY</p>

<p>  "Some broad principles [of literary criticism] are
   universally admitted by critical scholars. A fundamental one
   is that a literary work always betrays the imprint of the age
   and environment in which it was produced; another is that a
   plurality of authors is proved by well-marked differences of
   diction and style, at least when they coincide with
   distinctions of viewpoint or discrepancies in a double
   treatment of the same subject. A third received canon holds to
   a radical dissimilarity between ancient Semitic and modern
   Occidental, or Aryan, methods of composition." (CE. iv. 492.)</p>

<p>   The lines last above in italics point to the most fatal of all
proofs -- that of "double treatment" or forged "interpolations,"
than which nothing is clearer evidence of tampering and later
fraudulent alterations of text. The most radical dissimilarity
between the ancient Semitic methods of religious composition and
our modern Occidental notions of literary honesty -- or even of
intelligent forgery -- is, that the Hebrew and Greek religious
forgers were so ignorant or careless of the principles of
criticism, that they "interpolated" their fraudulent new matter
into old manuscripts without taking care to erase or suppress the
previous statements glaringly contradicted by the new
interpolations. Though, as the great masses of the ignorant
Faithful couldn't read, it may have suited the design of the
priests to retain both contradictory matters, either of which might
be used according to occasion to impose on their credulous Flocks.</p>

<p>   When, therefore, in the same document, two statements of
alleged fact or doctrine are found, one of which is in glaring
contradiction of the other, one or the other is inevitably false
and to a moral certainty the work of a later and different hand.
When, furthermore, one of the statements is consonant with the time
and conditions under which it was supposedly written, or to which
it refers, and the contradictory "betrays the imprint of the age
and environment in which it was written," later and different from
that of the original, and/or betrays "distinctions of viewpoint or
discrepancies" from the earlier version, inevitably the latter
convicts itself of being forged. With these established and
admitted principles in mind, we may now look a bit closely at these
questioned documents of the Four <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s.</p>

<p>    THE GOSPEL TITLES</p>

<p>   These Four are themselves forgeries and apocryphal "in. the
sinister sense of bearing names to which they have no right," as
well as by their contents being false, with many forged
"interpolations" or spurious additions. Even if the Four <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s
were themselves genuine, as we shall see they are not, yet
admittedly their present titles are not original and given to them
by the writers. The present clerical position, seeking to save the
works, is that, like the Acts of the <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Apostle</ent>s</ent>, "the name was
subsequently attached to the book, just as the headings of the
several <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s were affixed to them." (CE. i, 117.) More
particularly speaking of the <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent> titles, the same authority
says: "The first four historical books of the New Testament are
supplied with titles (<ent type='person'>Gospel</ent> According to [Gr. kata] <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Matt</ent>hew</ent>,
According to <ent type='person'>Mark</ent>, etc.) which, however ancient, do not go back to </p>

<p>   Bank of Wisdom
    Box 926, Louisville, KY 40201
    152
.
   FORGERY IN CHRISTIANITY</p>

<p>the respective authors of those sacred writings. ... That, however,
they do not go back to the first century of the Christian era, or
at least that they are not original, is a position generally held
at the present day. ... It thus appears that the titles of the
<ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s are not traceable to the Evangelists themselves." (CE. vi,
655, 656.) The very fact that the late second century <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>-titles
are of <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s "according to" this or that alleged apostle, rather
than "The <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent> of <ent type='person'>Mark</ent>" etc., is itself confession and plenary
proof that "<ent type='person'>Mark</ent>," et als., were not -- and were not intended to be
represented as -- the real authors of those "according to" <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s.
The form of the titles to the <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Epistle</ent>s</ent> -- also later tagged to
them, -- as "The <ent type='person'>Epistle</ent> of St. <ent type='person'>Paul</ent> to the Romans," etc. makes
this clear and convincing, that no <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Apostle</ent>s</ent> wrote the "according
to" <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>-biographies of the Christ.</p>

<p>   It is obvious, too, from an attentive reading of the Four
<ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s, that they are not arranged in our present collection in
their order of composition; "<ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Matt</ent>hew</ent>" certainly is not first in
order, and is only put first because it begins with the "Book of
the Generation of <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> Christ." The <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent> "according to <ent type='person'>Mark</ent>" is
now well established as the earliest of the first three, the
"Synoptics," and "<ent type='person'>John</ent>" is clearly the latest. There has been much
dispute on this point: "The ancient lists, versions, and
ecclesiastical writings are far from being at one with regard to
the order of these (4) sacred records of Christ's words and deeds.
In early Christian literature the canonical <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s are given in no
less than eight orders, besides the one (<ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Matt</ent>hew</ent>, <ent type='person'>Mark</ent>, <ent type='person'>Luke</ent>, <ent type='person'>John</ent>)
with which we are familiar." (CE. vi, 657.)</p>

<p>   Let us pause a moment to catch the full force of these
admissions by CE. and note their consequences fatal to the pretense
of Apostolic authorship or origin of these <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s. We shall
shortly see amplest proofs that none of the Four existed until well
into the last half of the second century after so-called Christ and
<ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Apostle</ent>s</ent>; but here we have, by clearest inference, an admission
that the <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s were not written by <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Apostle</ent>s</ent> or their
contemporaries. These titles "do not go back to the respective
authors of those sacred writings; ... do not go back to the first
century; ... are not original; ... are not traceable to the
Evangelists." What an anomaly, in all literature! most especially
in apostolic "sacred records of Christ's words and deeds"!</p>

<p>   Here we have these wonderful and "only true" inspired writings
of the companions of the Christ, eye-witnesses to his mighty
career, written for the conversion and salvation of the world,
floating around loose and anonymous for a century and a half,
without the slightest indication of their divine source and
sanction! All the flood of forged and spurious gospels, epistles,
acts and revelations -- "the apocryphal and pseudo-Biblical
writings with which the East especially had been flooded" (CE. iii,
272), bore the names of the pretended writers, from the false Books
of Adam and <ent type='person'>Enoch</ent> to the forged "<ent type='person'>Gospel</ent> of <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> Christ" and the
"Apocalypse of St. <ent type='person'>Peter</ent>." But the authentic and true <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s of
the genuine <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Apostle</ent>s</ent> of Christ, are nameless and dateless scraps of
papyrus! Imagine the great <ent type='person'>Fathers</ent> and Bishops of the Churches, the
inspired and all-wise "<ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Pope</ent>s</ent>" of the Church at Rome, rising in
their pulpits before the gaping Faithful; taking up an anonymous
roll of manuscript, and announcing: "Our lesson today is from, </p>

<p>   Bank of Wisdom
    Box 926, Louisville, KY 40201
    153
.
   FORGERY IN CHRISTIANITY</p>

<p>(ahem!) one of the wonderful <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s of our Lord and Savior <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent>
Christ; but, (ahem!) I don't really know which one. It is by either
<ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Matt</ent>hew</ent>, or <ent type='person'>Mark</ent>, or <ent type='person'>Luke</ent>, or <ent type='person'>John</ent>, I'm sure; but the writer forgot
to sign or insert his name. We will, however, worship God by
reading it anonymously in faith. No, here is one with a name to it;
we will now read from the inspired '<ent type='person'>Gospel</ent> of <ent type='person'>Barnabas</ent>,' or the
sacred 'Shepherd of Hermas.' Let us sing that grand and reassuring
old Hymn, 'How firm a foundation, ye Saints of the Lord, Is laid
for your faith in His wonderful Word!' Let us pray for more faith;
and remember to believe what I have told you. Ite, missa est --
It's all over, beat it!"</p>

<p>   Books, evidently, do not go the rounds of readers nor of
inspired Churches for over a century without a title or name. The
first mention of the names or titles, as of the "<ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s" to which
they were "supplied" was, as we shall see, not until about 185
A.D., when the "<ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s according to" the Four first appear in
ecclesiastical literature, and thereupon began their career in the
current use of the Churches, and therefore, evidently, then first
came into existence. The Four <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s thus, self-evidently, did not
-- could not for more than a century exist anonymous, without the
Apostolic titles certifying their origin and authenticity. To
pretend otherwise is sheer deceit and false pretense.</p>

<p>  THE "CANONICITY" OF THE FOUR GOSPELS</p>

<p>   The only possible pretext whereby generations of men should be
persuaded or cozened or compelled to accept and believe the <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s
(as well as the other N.T. books), even under the genial threat "he
that believeth not shall be damned," is that these books were
written by immediate companions and apostles of the Christ,
faithful eye-witnesses to his work and word, commanded and inspired
by Christ, God, or the Holy Ghost (which one is not explicit), to
write and publish these wonderful biographies of the Christ. This
is explicitly the teaching and dogma of the Church: no real
Apostolic author, no true <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>.</p>

<p>   Through pious Christian fraud and forgery, there were
fraudulently in vogue some couple of hundred "books current under
an <ent type='person'>Apostle</ent>'s name in the Early Church, such as the <ent type='person'>Epistle</ent> of
<ent type='person'>Barnabas</ent> and the Apocalypse of St. <ent type='person'>Peter</ent>," as CE. (iii, 274) admits
of these fraudulent "sacred writings" -- with Apostolic titles. Our
Ecclesiastical authority then states the "certain indubitable
marks" whereby true Apostolic authenticity, essential to validity
and credence, must be known: "For the primitive Church, evangelical
character was the test of Scriptural sacredness. But to guarantee
this character it was necessary that a book should be known as
composed by the official witnesses and organs of the Evangel; hence
to certify the Apostolic authorship, or at least sanction, of a
work purporting to contain the <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent> of Christ." (CE. iii, 274.)
All purported "<ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s" as to which Apostolic authorship or
sanction could not be guaranteed and certified were, of course,
spurious, as is natural and proper. Yet, for centuries, false and
forged "<ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s," etc., as the two just named, bore the Apostolic
certificates of authenticity -- now confessed to be false.</p>

<p>   Bank of Wisdom
    Box 926, Louisville, KY 40201
    154
.
   FORGERY IN CHRISTIANITY</p>

<p>  THE "MARK" FABLE BELIES "CANONICITY"</p>

<p>   The impossibility of the pretense that the precious Four
<ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s circulated nondescript and anonymous in the Churches for a
century and a half, is patently belied by the specific instance of
the "<ent type='person'>Gospel</ent> according to <ent type='person'>Mark</ent>," of which <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent> we have the precise
"history" recorded three centuries after the alleged notorious
event. Bishop <ent type='person'>Eusebius</ent> is our witness, in his celebrated Church
History. He relates that <ent type='person'>Peter</ent> preached orally in Rome, <ent type='person'>Mark</ent> being
his "disciple" and companion. The people wanted a written record of
<ent type='person'>Peter</ent>'s preachments, and (probably because <ent type='person'>Peter</ent> couldn't write),
they importuned <ent type='person'>Mark</ent> to write down "that history which is called
the <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent> according to <ent type='person'>Mark</ent>." <ent type='person'>Mark</ent> having done so, "the <ent type='person'>Apostle</ent>
(<ent type='person'>Peter</ent>) having ascertained what was done by revelation of the
Spirit, was delighted ... and that history obtained his authority
for the purpose of being read in the Churches." (HE. Bk. II, ch.
15.) Thus <ent type='person'>Peter</ent> was dead at the time, but his ghost got the news
and somehow communicated its delight and approval for the document
to be a "<ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>" for the Churches. But in a later section the
Bishop gives another version: the people who heard <ent type='person'>Peter</ent> "requested
<ent type='person'>Mark</ent>, who remembered well what he [<ent type='person'>Peter</ent>] had said, to reduce these
things to writing. ... Which, when <ent type='person'>Peter</ent> understood, he directly
neither hindered nor encouraged it." (HE. Bk. VI, ch. 14.) <ent type='person'>Peter</ent>,
thus, was alive, but wholly indifferent about his alleged <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>.</p>

<p>   The impossibilities of these contradictory fables need not
detain us now. But both join in declaring that the "<ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>
according to <ent type='person'>Mark</ent>" was publicly given to the Churches, at Rome,
just before or after the death of <ent type='person'>Peter</ent>, 64-67 A.D. The moment,
then, that this famous manuscript fell from the inspired pen --
(but it was not inspired: <ent type='person'>Mark</ent> only "remembered well"), -- the
Great Seal of the Holy Ghost was upon it, and it bore before the
world the notorious crown of Canonicity, -- And this fact was of
course known to all the Roman Church. And so, of course, of the
other three; every papyrus containing these precious productions of
Divine Inspiration must ipso facto be "canonized" and notoriously
sacred and of Divine sanction from the very day they were written.
Every Church, Father, Bishop, and <ent type='person'>Pope</ent> must certainly have known
the fact, and have glorified in their precious possession.</p>

<p>   But so it was -- not. <ent type='person'>Pope</ent> <ent type='person'>Peter</ent> evidently did not and could
not know it; he was "martyred in Rome" 64-67, the Church tells us; 
and the earliest date clerically claimed for "<ent type='person'>Mark</ent>" is some years
after the fall of Jerusalem in 70 A.D. The great <ent type='person'>Pope</ent> <ent type='person'>Clement</ent> I
(died 97 A.D.?), first-to-fourth "successor" to <ent type='person'>Pope</ent> <ent type='person'>Peter</ent>, knew
nothing of his great Predecessor's "<ent type='person'>Gospel</ent> according to <ent type='person'>Mark</ent>"; for,
admits the CE.: "The New Testament he never quotes verbally.
Sayings of Christ are now and then given, but not in the words of
the <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s. It cannot be proved, therefore, that he used any one
of the Synoptic <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s." (CE. iv, 14.) Of course, he did not,
could not; they were not then written. And no other <ent type='person'>Pope</ent>, Bishop or
Father (except <ent type='person'>Papias</ent> and until <ent type='person'>Irenaeus</ent>), for nearly a century
after "<ent type='person'>Pope</ent> <ent type='person'>Clement</ent>," ever mentions or quotes a <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>, or names
<ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Matt</ent>hew</ent>, <ent type='person'>Mark</ent>, <ent type='person'>Luke</ent> or <ent type='person'>John</ent>. So for a century and a half -- until
the books bobbed up in the hands of Bishop St. <ent type='person'>Irenaeus</ent> and were
tagged as "<ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s according to" this or that <ent type='person'>Apostle</ent>, there exists
not a word of them in all the tiresome tomes of the <ent type='person'>Fathers</ent>. It is </p>

<p>   Bank of Wisdom
    Box 926, Louisville, KY 40201
    155
.
   FORGERY IN CHRISTIANITY</p>

<p>humanly and divinely impossible that the "Apostolic authorship" and
hence "canonicity" or divine inspiration of these Sacred Four
should have remained, for a century and a half, unknown and
unsuspected by every Church, Father, <ent type='person'>Pope</ent> and Bishop of Christendom
-- if existent. Even had they been somewhat earlier in existence,
never an inspired hint or human suspicion was there, that they were
"Divine" or "Apostolic," or any different from the scores of
"apocryphal or pseudo-Biblical writings with which the East
especially had been flooded," -- that they were indeed "Holy
<ent type='person'>Scripture</ent>." Hear this notable admission: "It was not until about
the middle of the second century that under the rubric of <ent type='person'>Scripture</ent>
the New Testament writings were assimilated to the Old"! (CE. iii,
275), -- that is, became regarded as apostolic, sacred, inspired
and canonical, -- or "<ent type='person'>Scripture</ent>s."</p>

<p>   To argue and prove that the Four were regarded as "Apostolic"
and hence "canonical" after the middle of the second century,
argues and proves that until that late date they were not so
regarded, -- which we have seen is impossible if they had been
written by <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Apostle</ent>s</ent> a hundred years and more previously and
authorized by them "for the purpose of being read in the Churches,"
as the very ground and pillar of their foundation and faith.</p>

<p>   Follow the proofs and argument of the Church to its own
undoing: "From the testimony of St. <ent type='person'>Irenaeus</ent> (A.D. 185) alone there
can be no reasonable doubt that the Canon of the <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent> was
inalterably fixed in the Catholic Church by the last quarter of the
second century ... to the exclusion of any pretended Evangels.
[Sundry writings mentioned] presuppose the authority enjoyed by the
Fourfold <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent> towards the middle of the second century. ... Even
Rationalistic scholars like <ent type='person'>Harnack</ent> admit the canonicity of the
quadriform <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent> between the years 140-175." (CE. iii, 275.) Even
CE. does not prove or claim that it was any earlier; so here the
Church and the Rationalists are in accord on this fatal fact!
Certainly <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Pope</ent>s</ent> <ent type='person'>Peter</ent> and <ent type='person'>Clement</ent> I, not to review the silent
others, would have "inalterably fixed" the Divine Canonicity of the
Four a century before, if they had known about these precious
productions of the <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Apostle</ent>s</ent>; -- if, in fact, they had existed, the
known works of Holy <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Apostle</ent>s</ent> and apostolic men! But until "towards
the middle of the second century" there was no "canon" or notion of
divinely inspired Apostolic <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s -- simply for the reason that
until just about that period they were not in existence.</p>

<p>   The sudden appearance at a certain late date, of a previously
unknown document, which is then attributed to an earlier age and
long since dead writers, is one of the surest earmarks of forgery.
Thus CE. speaking of another monumental Church forgery -- (the
"False Decretals" of <ent type='person'>Isidore</ent>, hereafter noticed) -- urges this very
fact as one of the most cogent grounds of the detection of that
forgery: "These documents appeared suddenly in the ninth century
and are nowhere mentioned before that time. ... Then again there
are endless anachronisms," -- just as in the <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s and <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Epistle</ent>s</ent>.
(CE. vi, 773.) More ample and compelling proofs of this destroying
fact will soon be made.</p>

<p>   Bank of Wisdom
    Box 926, Louisville, KY 40201
    156
.
   FORGERY IN CHRISTIANITY</p>

<p>    THE GOSPELS "ACCORDING TO" GREEK PRIESTS</p>

<p>   According to the names "supplied" to the Four <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s, as to
the other New Testament books, the "Apostolic" authors were all of
them Jews; the same is supposedly true of most of the now confessed
apocrypha. All these were forgeries in the names of Jewish pseudo-
apostles. But all of the <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s, the other New Testament Books,
and the forged apocrypha, were written in Greek. Self-evidently,
these "ignorant and unlearned" peasant <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Apostle</ent>s</ent>, speaking a vulgar
Aramaic-Jewish dialect, could neither speak nor write Greek, -- if
they could write at all. The Old Testament books were written
mostly in Hebrew, which was a "dead language," which only the
priests could read; thus in the synagogues of Palestine the rolls
were read in Hebrew, and then "expounded" to the hearers in their
Aramaic dialect. But these Hebrew "<ent type='person'>Scripture</ent>s" had been translated
into Greek, in the famous Septuagint version which we have admired.
Here is another significant admission by CE.: it speaks of "the
supposed wholesale adoption and approval, by the <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Apostle</ent>s</ent>, of the
Greek, and therefore larger Old Testament," that is, the Greek
version containing the Jewish apocrypha; and then admits the fact:
"The New Testament undoubtedly shows a preference for the
Septuagint; out of about 350 texts from the Old Testament [in the
New], 300 favor the Greek version rather than the Hebrew." (CE.
iii, 271.) It was also the Greek Septuagint and Greek forged
Oracles, that were exclusively used by the Greek <ent type='person'>Fathers</ent> and
priests in all the <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>-propaganda work of the first three
centuries. Obviously, the <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s and other New Testament booklets,
written in Greek and quoting 300 times the Greek Septuagint, and
several Greek <ent type='person'>Pagan</ent> authors, as Aratus, and Cleanthes, were
written, not by illiterate Jewish peasants, but by Greek-speaking
ex-<ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Pagan</ent> <ent type='person'>Fathers</ent></ent> and priests far from the Holy Land of the Jews.</p>

<p>   There is another proof that the <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s were not written by
Jews. Traditionally, <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> and all the "<ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Apostle</ent>s</ent>" were Jews; all
their associates and the people of their country with whom they
came into contact, were Jews. But throughout the <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s, scores of
times, "the Jews" are spoken of, always as a distinct and alien
people from the writers, and mostly with a sense of racial hatred
and contempt. A few instances only need be given; they all betray
that the writers were not Jews speaking of their fellow Jews. The
Greek writer of "<ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Matt</ent>hew</ent>" says: "this saying is commonly reported
among the Jews until this day" (Mt. xxviii, 15), -- showing, too,
that it was written long afterwards; a Jew must have said "among
our people," or some such. It is recorded by "<ent type='person'>Mark</ent>": "For the
Pharisees, and all the Jews, except they wash their hands of it,
eat not, holding to the tradition of the elders" (Mk. vii, 3); no
Jew writing for his fellow-Jews would explain or need to explain
this Jewish custom, known to and practiced by "all the Jews." <ent type='person'>Luke</ent>
names a Jew and locates geographically his place of residence:
"<ent type='person'>Joseph</ent>, of <ent type='person'>Arimathea</ent>, a city of the Jews"; an American writer,
speaking of Hoboken, could not say "a city of the Americans" nor
did Jews need to be told by a Jew that <ent type='person'>Arimathea</ent> was a "city of the
Jews." The Greek priest who wrote "<ent type='person'>John</ent>" is the most prolific in
telling his <ent type='person'>Pagan</ent> readers about Jewish customs and personalities;
absurd in a Jew writing for Jews: "After the manner of the
purifying of the Jews" (ii, 6); "And the Jews' passover was at
hand" (ii, 13) "Then answered the Jews, and said unto <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent>" (iii, </p>

<p>   Bank of Wisdom
    Box 926, Louisville, KY 40201
    157
.
   FORGERY IN CHRISTIANITY</p>

<p>1); "Then there arose a question between some of <ent type='person'>John</ent>'s disciples
-- [all Jews] -- and the Jews about purifying" (iii, 25); "And
therefore did the Jews persecute <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent>" (v, 16); "Therefore the
Jews sought the more to kill him" (v, 18). More: "And the passover,
a feast of the Jews, was nigh" vi, 4); no American would say "the
Fourth of July, a holiday of the Americans," though a French writer
might properly so explain. "After these things <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> would not walk
in Jewry, because the Jews sought to kill him" (vii, 1); "for they
feared the Jews: for the Jews had agreed already" (ix, 22); "His
disciples said unto him, Master, the Jews of late sought to stone
thee with stones" (xi, 8); "As the manner of the Jews is to bury"
(xix, 40), which need be explained to no Jew. These and many like
passages prove that no Jews wrote the <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s; that they were
written by foreigners for foreigners; these foreigners were Greek-
speaking aliens unfamiliar with Jewish customs; the writers were
therefore ex-<ent type='person'>Pagan</ent> Greek priests who were zealously "selling" the
"glad tidings of great joy" to the ignorant and superstitious <ent type='person'>Pagan</ent>
populace.</p>

<p>    THE FOUR GOSPELS -- "CHOSEN"</p>

<p>   The Four <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s are thus demonstrated as: not written by
Jews; not written by any of the "Twelve <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Apostle</ent>s</ent>"; not written nor
in existence for over a century after the supposed <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Apostle</ent>s</ent>. When
finally the <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent> "according to" <ent type='person'>Luke</ent> came to be written, already,
as "<ent type='person'>Luke</ent>" affirms, there were "many" other like pseudo-Apostolic
<ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>-biographies of the Christ afloat (<ent type='person'>Luke</ent>, i, 1); he added just
another. In his Commentary on <ent type='person'>Luke</ent>, Father Origen confirms this
fact as well known: "And not four <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s, but very many, out of
which these we have chosen and delivered to the churches, we may
perceive." (Origen, In Proem. Luc., Hom. 1, vol. 2, p. 210.) How,
and why, out of half a hundred of other lying forgeries of <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s,
were these sacred Four finally "chosen" as truly "Apostolic,"
inspired, and canonical? Nobody knows, as CE. confesses.</p>

<p>   It is a very strange and fatal confession, in view of the
insistent false pretense of the Church for centuries of the patent
Divinity of the Four <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s, and of its own infallible inspiration
and Divine guidance against all doubt and error; but it confesses:</p>

<p>  "It is indeed impossible, at the present day, to describe
   the precise manner in which out of the numerous works ascribed
   to some <ent type='person'>Apostle</ent>, or simply bearing the name of gospel, only
   four, two of which are not ascribed to <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Apostle</ent>s</ent>, came to be
   considered as sacred and canonical. It remains true, however,
   that all the early testimony which has a distinct bearing on
   the number of the canonical <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s recognizes four such
   <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s and none besides. Thus, <ent type='person'>Eusebius</ent> (d. 340) ... <ent type='person'>Clement</ent>
   of Alexandria (d. about 220), ... and Tertullian (d. 220),
   were familiar with our four <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s, frequently quoting and
   commenting on them." (CE. vi, 657.)</p>

<p>   The statement as to "all the early testimony" in favor of
these Four only, is not only untrue, but it is contradicted by a
true statement on the same page as the last above; it is, too, a
further humiliating confession of blind and groping uncertainty
with respect to the very foundation stones on which the Infallible </p>

<p>   Bank of Wisdom
    Box 926, Louisville, KY 40201
    158
.
   FORGERY IN CHRISTIANITY</p>

<p>Church is built, and makes a bit less confident the forged
assurance that the Gates of Hell -- to say nothing of human Reason
-- shall not yet prevail against the ill-founded structure. Here is
the destructive admission:</p>

<p>  "In the writings of the Apostolic <ent type='person'>Fathers</ent> one does not,
   indeed, meet with unquestionable evidence in favor of only
   four canonical gospels. ... The canonical <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s were
   regarded as of Apostolic authority, two of them being ascribed
   to the <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Apostle</ent>s</ent> St. <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Matt</ent>hew</ent> and St. <ent type='person'>John</ent>, respectively, and
   two to St. <ent type='person'>Mark</ent> and St. <ent type='person'>Luke</ent>, the respective companions of St.
   <ent type='person'>Peter</ent> and St. <ent type='person'>Paul</ent>. Many other gospels indeed claimed
   Apostolic authority, but to none of them was this claim
   universally allowed in the early Church. The only apocryphal
   work which was at all generally received, and relied upon, in
   addition to our four canonical <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s, is the '<ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>
   according to the Hebrews.' It is a well-known fact that St.
   <ent type='person'>Jerome</ent> regards it as the Hebrew original of our Greek
   Canonical <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent> according to St. <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Matt</ent>hew</ent>." (CE. vi, 657.)</p>

<p>   Thus, admittedly, "numerous works" of pretended and false
"gospels," some fifty, were forged and falsely "ascribed to some
apostle" by devout Christians; after a century and a half only four
"came to be considered" and were finally "chosen" -- selected -- as
of divine utterance and sanction. Why? one may well wonder.</p>

<p>    WHY FOUR GOSPELS?</p>

<p>   Why Four <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s, then, -- when only one would have been
aplenty and much safer, as fewer contradictions -- out of the fifty
ascribed by pious forging hands to the Holy Twelve? The pious
<ent type='person'>Fathers</ent> are ready here, as ever, with fantastic reasons to explain
things whereof they are ignorant or are not willing to give honest
reasons for. "The saintly Bishop of <ent type='person'>Lyons</ent>," says CE. with
characteristic clerical solemnity when anyone else would laugh,
"<ent type='person'>Irenaeus</ent> (died about 202), who had known <ent type='person'>Polycarp</ent> in Asia Minor,
not only admits and quotes our four <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s, [he is the very first
to mention them!] -- but argues that there must be just four, no
more and no less. He says: 'It is not possible that the <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s be
either more or fewer than they are. For since there are four zones
of the world in which we live, and four principal winds, while the
Church is scattered throughout the world. ... and the pillar and
ground of the Church is the <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>. ... it is fitting that we
should have four pillars, breathing out immortality on every side
and vivifying our flesh. ... The living creatures are quadriform,
and the <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent> is quadriform, as is also the course followed by our
Lord"! (CE. vi, 659.) Thus far CE. quoting the good Bishop; but we
may follow the Bishop a few lines further in his very innocent
ratiocinations from ancient Hebrew mythology, in proof of the
divine Four:</p>

<p>  "For this reason were four principal covenants given to
   the human race: One prior to the deluge, under Adam; the
   second, that after the deluge, under <ent type='person'>Noah</ent>; the third, the
   giving of the law, under <ent type='person'>Moses</ent>; the fourth, that which
   renovates man, and sums up all things by means of the <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>,
   raising and bearing men upon its wings into the heavenly </p>

<p>   Bank of Wisdom
    Box 926, Louisville, KY 40201
    159
.
   FORGERY IN CHRISTIANITY</p>

<p>   Kingdom. ... But that these <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s alone are true and
   reliable, and admit neither an increase nor diminution of the
   aforesaid number, I have proved by so many and such arguments.
   For, since God made all things in due proportion and
   adaptation, it was fit also that the outward aspect of the
   <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent> should be well arranged and harmonized. The opinion of
   those men, therefore, who handed the <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent> down to us, having
   been investigated, from their very fountainheads, let us
   proceed also [to the remaining apostles), and inquire into
   their doctrine with regard to God." (Iren. Adv. Haer. III, xi,
   8, 9; ANF. i, 428-29.)</p>

<p>   The true reason, however, for four finally "chosen" and
accepted <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s, is that stated by Reinach, after quoting <ent type='person'>Irenaeus</ent>
and other authorities: "The real reason was to satisfy each of the
four principal Churches each of which possessed its <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>: <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Matt</ent>hew</ent>
at Jerusalem, <ent type='person'>Mark</ent> at Rome, or Alexandria, <ent type='person'>Luke</ent> at Antioch, and
<ent type='person'>John</ent> at Ephesus." (Reinach, Orpheus, p. 217.) This reason for the
use of a different <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent> by each of the principal and independent
Churches, -- for the special uses of each of which the respective
<ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s were no doubt worked up by forging <ent type='person'>Fathers</ent> in each Fold, --
is confirmed by Bishop <ent type='person'>Irenaeus</ent> himself in this same argument. Each
of the four principal sects of heretics, he says, makes use in
their Churches of one or the other of these Four for its own uses,
for instance: <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Matt</ent>hew</ent> by the Ebionites; <ent type='person'>Mark</ent> by "those who separate
<ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> from Christ"; <ent type='person'>Luke</ent> by the Marcionites; and <ent type='person'>John</ent> by the
Valentinians; and this heretical use of the Four, argues the
Bishop, confirms their like acceptance and use by the True
Churches: "So firm is the ground upon which these <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s rest,
that the very heretics bear witness to them, and starting from
these documents, each of them endeavors to establish his own
peculiar doctrine [citing the use by each sect of a different
<ent type='person'>Gospel</ent> as above named]. Since, then, our opponents do bear
testimony to us, and make use of these documents, our proof derived
from them is firm and true." (Iren., op. cit. sec. 7.) The
"canonical Four," verily, as CE. confesses, were manufactured
precisely for the purpose of meeting and confuting the heretics, as
were the gradually developed and defined sacred dogmas of the
Orthodox Church, even that of the Trinity. The fabrication of the
Four can be seen working out under our very eyes, in the light of
the foregoing statement of <ent type='person'>Irenaeus</ent>, and of that of CE. to be
quoted.</p>

<p>   In the next section we shall see proven, that no written,
<ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s existed until shortly before 185 A.D., when <ent type='person'>Irenmus</ent> wrote;
they are first mentioned in chapter xxii of his Book II; the above
quotation is from Book III, when use of them became constant.
Evident we see it to be, from what <ent type='person'>Irenaeus</ent> has just said, that the
sects of heretics named were making use, each of them of one of the
just-published Four as well as of other "spurious gospels"; the
Orthodox claimed the Four as their own, and finally established the
claim. The "gospel" up to about this time, a century and a half
after <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> Christ, was entirely oral and "traditional"; the
Gnostics and other heretics evidently were first to reduce some
"gospels" to writing; the Orthodox quickly followed suit, in order
to combat the heretics by "apostolic" writings. This is clear from
the following, that "the spurious gospels of the Gnostics prepared </p>

<p>   Bank of Wisdom
    Box 926, Louisville, KY 40201
    160
.
   FORGERY IN CHRISTIANITY</p>

<p>the way for the canon of <ent type='person'>Scripture</ent>," -- meaning, for the now
"canonical <ent type='person'>Scripture</ent>"; for, as the "canon" was not dogmatically
established until 1546, the Four were not "canonized" when <ent type='person'>Irenaeus</ent>
wrote in 185, -- when the "way was prepared" for them by the
earlier heretical "spurious gospels." Thus CE. writes:</p>

<p>  "The endless controversies with heretics have been
   indirectly the cause of most important doctrinal developments
   and definitions formulated by councils to the edification of
   the body of Christ. Thus the spurious gospels of the Gnostics
   prepared the way for the canon of <ent type='person'>Scripture</ent>: the Patri-
   passian, Sabellian, Arian, and Macedonian heresies drew out a
   clearer concept of the Trinity; the Nestorian and <ent type='person'>Eutychian</ent>
   errors led to definite dogmas on the nature and Person of
   Christ. And so on down to Modernism, which has called forth a
   solemn assertion of the claims of the supernatural in
   history." (CE. vii, 261.)</p>

<p>   Heresy means "Choice"; heretics are those who choose what they
will believe, or whether they will believe at all. It was to
foreclose all choice on the part of believers, that the divinely-
inspired, apostolic fictions of the Four <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s were drawn up for
the first time to combat the "spurious gospels" of the free
choosers. Heresy could not exist in the time of <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> Christ, for
he laid down nothing for belief, except "He that believeth on me
shall be saved" against his immediate "second coming" and end of
the world. The gospels are thus anti-heretical documents of the
second century, after Gnosticism first appeared.</p>

<p>   In this connection it may be mentioned, as complained by
<ent type='person'>Augustine</ent>, that there were some 93 sects of heretics during the
first three centuries of the Christian Faith; all these were
Christian sects, believing in the tales of <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> Christ and him
crucified, but each of them as rivals struggling for the profits
and power of religion and warring to suppress all others, and make
itself master in <ent type='person'>pelf</ent> and power. Hence the <ent type='person'>Fathers</ent> thundered
against the heretics. The inspired Four <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s, contradictory at
every point, were impossible to believe in all points; they left
every one free to disbelieve all, or to believe such as he could.</p>

<p>   So incredible, even on their face, were one and all of these
canonical Four <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s, that the fanatic Father Tertullian thus
stated the grounds of his holy faith in them: "Credo quia
incredibilis est -- I believe because it is unbelievable"; and St.
<ent type='person'>Augustine</ent>, greatest of the <ent type='person'>Fathers</ent>, declared himself in these
terms: "Ego vero Evangelio non crederem, nisi me Catholicae
Ecclesiae conmoveret Auctoritas. ... Ego me ad eos teneam, quibus
praecipientibus <ent type='person'>Evangelio credidi</ent> -- I would not believe the <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>
true, unless the authority of the Catholic Church constrained me.
... I hold myself bound to those, through whose teachings I have
believed the <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>." (<ent type='person'>Augustine</ent>, On the Foundation, sec. 5, <ent type='person'>Ed</ent>.
Vives, vol. xxv, p. 435; Orpheus, p. 223.)</p>

<p>   In the work often cited, Bishop <ent type='person'>Irenaeus</ent> either falsely quotes
the <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent> of <ent type='person'>Mark</ent>, or the sacred text has been seriously altered
in our present copies; he says: "<ent type='person'>Mark</ent> commences with a reference to
the prophetical spirit, saying, 'The beginning of the <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent> of </p>

<p>   Bank of Wisdom
    Box 926, Louisville, KY 40201
    161
.
   FORGERY IN CHRISTIANITY</p>

<p><ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> Christ, as it is written in <ent type='person'>Esaias</ent> the prophet"' (sec. 8, p.
428), as if <ent type='person'>Isaiah</ent> testified to the <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>. The Bishop also quotes
two long passages, one a written letter of the <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Apostle</ent>s</ent> "unto those
brethren from among the Gentiles who are in Antioch, and Syria, and
Silicia, greeting," -- which are not in the Acts of the <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Apostle</ent>s</ent> or
any other New Testament book as we now have them. (Iren., Adv.
Maer. III, xi, 14; p. 436.) The good Bishop seems either to have
fabricated this alleged <ent type='person'>Epistle</ent> and passage, or other pious hands
falsified the sacred <ent type='person'>Scripture</ent>s by forging them out of its pages.
So it is evident that these inspired booklets, as we now know them,
at least differ in very many material respects from the
"traditional <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>" and from the form in which the Four <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s
were first reduced to writing. Many other instances exist, of which
some of the most notorious will be shown in the course of the
chapter.</p>

<p>   INSPIRATION AND PLAGIARISM</p>

<p>   In this connection a few words may be said as to the
chronological order and manner of composition of the first three or
Synoptic <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s. "Historically <ent type='person'>Mark</ent> is the earliest, and its study
the foundation of critical enquiry. But the ordinary Christian is
not a historical critic." (New Commentary, Pt. III, p. 126; ef. pp.
33, 45.) With the latter statement all will agree; with the first
CE. is in agreement with the leading critics, though holding to the
exploded "tradition" that one <ent type='person'>Mark</ent> wrote "<ent type='person'>Mark</ent>," or, in its words:
"If, then, a consistent and widespread early tradition is to count
for anything, St. <ent type='person'>Mark</ent> wrote a work based upon St. <ent type='person'>Peter</ent>'s
Preaching." (CE. ix, 676.) The later writers of "<ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Matt</ent>hew</ent>" and
"<ent type='person'>Luke</ent>" copied bodily from "<ent type='person'>Mark</ent>," with the utmost literality in
many places, but with the greatest freedom of changes, additions
and suppressions at others, to suit their own purposes. But one
comparison, that between "<ent type='person'>Mark</ent>" and "<ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Matt</ent>hew</ent>," can here be given;
the method extends quite as notably to "<ent type='person'>Luke</ent>." Thus CE. discloses
the process: "<ent type='person'>Mark</ent> is found complete in <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Matt</ent>hew</ent>, with the exception
of numerous slight omissions and the following periscopes. ... In
all, 31 verses are omitted"; and so with respect to the "analogies"
with the other two. "Parts peculiar to <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Matt</ent>hew</ent> are numerous, as
<ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Matt</ent>hew</ent> has 330 verses that are distinctly his own." (CE,. x, 60,
61; cf. for thorough examination, New Comm. Pt. III, pp. 33, seq.)
"These '<ent type='person'>Matt</ent>hean additions,' as they are called. ... seem to be
authentic when they relate our Lord's words; but, when they relate
incidents, they are extremely questionable." (New Comm. Pt. III, p.
127-128.)</p>

<p>   We have just seen the same authority admit the want of
authenticity of one set of words imputed by <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Matt</ent>hew</ent> to his Lord;
our next section will demonstrate another famous "<ent type='person'>Matt</ent>hean
addition" to be a gross and bungling forgery. This bodily copying
from <ent type='person'>Mark</ent>, with so many "additions and suppressions," implies, as
we have seen, "a very free treatment of the text of <ent type='person'>Mark</ent> in <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Matt</ent>hew</ent>
and <ent type='person'>Luke</ent> (a freedom which reaches a climax in the treatment of Mk.
x, 17f. in Mt. xix, 16f.). ... Just as the latter (<ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Matt</ent>hew</ent>)
tampered more with the <ent type='person'>Mark</ent>an order than St. <ent type='person'>Luke</ent> did." (New Comm.
Pt. III, 36, 40.) But this textual tampering is well explained, for
clerical apologists: "Nor need such freedom surprise us. <ent type='person'>Mark</ent>, at
the time when the others used it, had not attained anything like </p>

<p>   Bank of Wisdom
    Box 926, Louisville, KY 40201
    162
.
   FORGERY IN CHRISTIANITY</p>

<p>the status of <ent type='person'>Scripture</ent>, and an evangelist using it would feel
free, or might indeed feel bound, to bring its contents into line
with the traditions of the particular Church in which he lived and
worked"! (Ib. p. 36.)</p>

<p>   This perfectly confirms the position taken in the section "Why
Four <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s?" that these <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s were framed up each in a
different Church, to meet its own uses and special purposes, and in
answer to the "gospels" of the Heretics. "<ent type='person'>Mark</ent>," being first in
order, was probably in the hands of several Churches, some of whose
"traditions" did not accord with the "gospel" narratives therein
retailed; the local gospel-mongers, therefore, taking "<ent type='person'>Mark</ent>" as
good "copy" for a start, took their blue-pencil styluses in hand
and "edited" its text by profuse "tampering" until they produced,
severally, the "gospels according to" <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Matt</ent>hew</ent> and <ent type='person'>Luke</ent>, for use in
more "orthodox" and approved form according to the local
traditions. The "<ent type='person'>John</ent>" gospel-fabrication alone of the Four quite
disregarded the "<ent type='person'>Mark</ent>" document, and is in the most complete
contradiction with it, and with all the first three. The "Big Four"
gradually won their way against and were "chosen" from all the
other fifty or more in circulation, which then became "apocrypha,"
or admitted forgeries.</p>

<p>   GOSPELS LATE FORGERIES</p>

<p>We have seen the admissions of CE. that the earliest notice of the
Four <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>'s now known to us was towards the close of the second
century, quoting as the earliest witnesses the African Bishops,
<ent type='person'>Clement</ent> of Alexandria and Tertullian, both of whom died about 220
A.D. It presents, however, one earlier witness to <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s going in
the name of the Four: "Irenrus, in his work Against Heresies (A.D.
182-188), testified to the existence of a Tetramorph or Quadriform
<ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>, given by the Word and unified by one Spirit," (CE. iii,
275), -- of which we have just had occasion to admire his quaint
and cogent proofs. This first mention, by <ent type='person'>Irenaeus</ent>, of Four
<ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s, with the names of their supposed writers, we shall in a
moment quote; first we will get the record in honest and correct
form by citing an even earlier partial naming of something like
<ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s, and their reputed writers.</p>

<p>   1. <ent type='person'>Bishop <ent type='person'>Papias</ent></ent>, about 145 A.D., is the very first name of
something like written "<ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s" and writers; and this is what he
says, quoting his anonymous gossipy old friends, the presbyters:</p>

<p>  "And the presbyter said this. MARK having become the
   interpreter of <ent type='person'>PETER</ent>, wrote down accurately whatsoever he
   remembered. It was not, however, in exact order that he
   related the sayings or deeds of Christ. For he neither heard
   the Lord, nor accompanied him. ... For one thing he took
   especial care, not to omit anything he had heard, and not to
   put anything fictitious into the statements. MATTHEW put the
   Oracles (of the Lord) in the Hebrew language, and each one
   interpreted them as best he could." (<ent type='person'>Papias</ent>, quoted by
   <ent type='person'>Eusebius</ent>, Hist. Eccles. iii, 39; ANF. i, 154-5.)</p>

<p>   Bank of Wisdom
    Box 926, Louisville, KY 40201
    163
.
   FORGERY IN CHRISTIANITY</p>

<p>   Here, then, over one hundred years after Christ, we have the
first mention of written gospels and of <ent type='person'>Mark</ent>, and the recital, by 
hearsay on hearsay, that he wrote down "whatsoever he remembered"
that <ent type='person'>Peter</ent> had said the Lord had said and done. This is rather a
far cry from divine inspiration of inerrant truth in this first
hearsay by memory recital of the supposed <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>-writers. Thus
"<ent type='person'>Mark</ent>" is admittedly not "inspired," but is hearsay, haphazard
"traditions," pieced together a generation and more afterwards by
some unknown priestly scribe. But note well, even if <ent type='person'>Mark</ent> may have
written some things, alleged as retailed by <ent type='person'>Peter</ent>, yet this is not,
and is not an intimation even remotely, that this by-memory record
of <ent type='person'>Mark</ent> is the "<ent type='person'>Gospel</ent> according to <ent type='person'>Mark</ent>" which half a century
after <ent type='person'>Papias</ent> came to be known. Indeed, such an idea is expressly
excluded; <ent type='person'>Mark</ent>'s notes were "not in exact order," but here and
there, as remembered; while the "<ent type='person'>Gospel</ent> according to <ent type='person'>Mark</ent>" is, or
purports to be, very orderly, proceeding from "The beginning of the
gospel of <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> Christ" orderly and consecutively through to his
death, resurrection and ascension. It includes the scathing rebuke
administered by the Christ to <ent type='person'>Peter</ent>: "Get thee behind me, <ent type='person'>Satan</ent>:
for thou savourest not the things that be of God" (Mk. viii, 33) ;
one may be sure that <ent type='person'>Peter</ent> never related these eminently deserved
"sayings of Christ" to <ent type='person'>Mark</ent> or to anyone.</p>

<p>   Moreover, the present "<ent type='person'>Gospel</ent> according to <ent type='person'>Mark</ent>" relates the
crucifixion of <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> at about thirty years of age, after one year's
ministry; which is wholly false, as <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> died at home in bed of
old age, in effect says <ent type='person'>Bishop <ent type='person'>Papias</ent></ent>, on the "tradition" of these
same presbyters. So, every other consideration here aside, <ent type='person'>Papias</ent>
is not a witness to "The <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent> according to <ent type='person'>Mark</ent>." As for <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Matt</ent>hew</ent>,
<ent type='person'>Papias</ent> simply reports the elders as saying that <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Matt</ent>hew</ent> wrote down
the "ORACLES" or words of the Lord, and in Hebrew; the "<ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>
according to <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Matt</ent>hew</ent>" is much more than mere "words of the Lord";
it is the longest and most palpably fictitious of the "Lives" of
the Christ; it was written in Greek, and very obviously by a Greek
priest or Father, many years after the reputed time of <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent>
Christ. And <ent type='person'>Bishop <ent type='person'>Papias</ent></ent>, more than a century after Christ, did
not have in his important church, and had never seen, these alleged
apostolic writings, and only knew of some such by the gossip of the
elders at second or third hand. So we must count <ent type='person'>Papias</ent> out as a
witness for these two of our written <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s. None of the present
Four <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s was thus in existence in about A.D. 145. And it is
obvious that, even by "tradition," the <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s in the names of <ent type='person'>Luke</ent>
and <ent type='person'>John</ent> did not exist in the time of <ent type='person'>Papias</ent>.</p>

<p>   2. Justin Martyr (145-149) quotes sundry "sayings" of <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent>
which we find here and there in the present Four, -- just as like
alleged "sayings" identically are to be found in almost any of the
confessedly forged or apocryphal gospels; but he names no names nor
<ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s, but only says "memoirs of the apostles," or simply "it is
said." (See all instances cited, in EB. ii, 1819.) So Justin is no
witness to our present Four <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s, which evidently did not exist
in his time about 150 years after <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> Christ, -- though he
assiduously quotes the <ent type='person'>Sibyl</ent> and the heathen gods as proofs of
<ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> Christ, as we have seen.</p>

<p>   Bank of Wisdom
    Box 926, Louisville, KY 40201
    164
.
   FORGERY IN CHRISTIANITY</p>

<p>   3. <ent type='person'>Irenaeus</ent> (182-188) makes the very first mention of Four
<ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s and names the reputed authors. These are textually the 
interesting, and as we shall see, at least in part, spurious words
of Bishop <ent type='person'>Irenaeus</ent>:</p>

<p>  "<ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Matt</ent>hew</ent> also issued a <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent> -- [see it grow -- <ent type='person'>Papias</ent>
   said only "oracles of the Lord"] among the Hebrews in their
   own dialect, while <ent type='person'>Peter</ent> and <ent type='person'>Paul</ent> were preaching at Rome, and
   laying the foundations of the Church. After their departure,
   <ent type='person'>Mark</ent>, the disciple and interpreter of <ent type='person'>Peter</ent>, did also hand
   down to us in writing what had been preached by <ent type='person'>Peter</ent>. <ent type='person'>Luke</ent>
   also, the companion of <ent type='person'>Paul</ent>, recorded in a book the <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>
   preached by him. Afterwards, <ent type='person'>John</ent>, the disciple of the Lord,
   who also had leaned upon his breast, did himself publish a
   <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent> during his residence at Ephesus in Asia." (Iren. Adv.
   Haer. Bk. III, Ch. 1, i; ANF. i, 414.)</p>

<p>   <ent type='person'>Irenaeus</ent>, therefore, about the year 185 of our Lord, to use a
medium date, or some one hundred and fifty years after his death,
is the first of all the zealous Christ-bearers to record the fact
that, at the time he wrote, there were in existence four wonderful
biographies or histories of the Lord and Savior <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> Christ, two
under the names of holy <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Apostle</ent>s</ent>, and, he "implies that the <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s
of <ent type='person'>Mark</ent> and <ent type='person'>Luke</ent> were, in effect, apostolic, as being written by
companions of <ent type='person'>Peter</ent> and <ent type='person'>Paul</ent>." (EB. i, 1830.) If any such apostolic
and authentic works had been in existence before the years, we will
say, 150-180 A.D., it is beyond comprehension and possibility that
the zealous <ent type='person'>Fathers</ent>, who so eagerly quoted, and misquoted, the Old
Testament and its apocrypha, the forged New Testament apocrypha,
and the heathen Oracles, in proof of their Christ, should have been
silent as clams about the apostolic <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent>-histories "according to"
<ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Matt</ent>hew</ent>, <ent type='person'>Mark</ent>, <ent type='person'>Luke</ent> and <ent type='person'>John</ent>. Even all the later <ent type='person'>Fathers</ent>, and
ecclesiastical writers, and the CE., admittedly are unable to trace
their genealogy further back into "the age of apocryphal
literature" than about 150 A.D. or later. It is impossible,
therefore, to believe or to pretend, that these Four <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s were
written by apostles and their personal disciples, some hundred
years and more before they were ever heard of by the zealous and
myth-mongering <ent type='person'>Fathers</ent>. A confused medley of alleged words and
wonderful deeds of the Christ, handed down by ancient tradition or
new-invented for any occasion, existed in oral "tradition," and
were worn threadbare by rote repetition; but never a written word
of the Four for a century and a half after the apostles had their
say, and had handed down that wonderful and inexhaustible "Deposit
of Faith," which, oral and unedited, is yet drawn upon until this
day by the inspired Successors of <ent type='person'>Peter</ent> for their every new Dogma.</p>

<p>   One may turn the thousands of pages of the Ante-Niacin <ent type='person'>Fathers</ent>
before <ent type='person'>Irenaeus</ent> in vain to find a direct word of quotation from 
written <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s, nor (except as above, recorded) even bare mention
of the names of <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Matt</ent>hew</ent>, <ent type='person'>Mark</ent>, <ent type='person'>Luke</ent> or <ent type='person'>John</ent>, as writers of <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s.
The above words of <ent type='person'>Irenaeus</ent> are registered in his Book III, chapter
i; in the first two Books, while, like Justin, he quotes "sayings"
which are to be found in our present texts, as in the apocryphas,
he does not mention "<ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>" or any of the four reputed
evangelists, until chapter xxii of Book II, where he mentions the
word "<ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s" and those of <ent type='person'>John</ent> and <ent type='person'>Luke</ent>, and assails their record</p>

<p>   Bank of Wisdom
    Box 926, Louisville, KY 40201
    165
.
   FORGERY IN CHRISTIANITY</p>

<p>of the early death of <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> as "heresy." But beginning with chapter
x of Book III, he bristles with the names of and direct quotations
from all Four; and so with all the following <ent type='person'>Fathers</ent>. It seems,
therefore, a fair inference that <ent type='person'>Irenaeus</ent> had just heard of these
Four <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s at the time the last chapters of the second of the two
Books were composed; and that they came into existence, or to his
knowledge, just before the time be began to compose Book III. And
certainly these Four <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s could not have been in existence and
circulation very long before they would come to the eager hands of
the active and prolific Bishop of <ent type='person'>Lyons</ent>, who had recently come from
the tutelage of his friend <ent type='person'>Polycarp</ent>, -- "disciple of the <ent type='person'>Apostle</ent>
<ent type='person'>John</ent>" -- venerable Bishop of Smyrna, who sent him to <ent type='person'>Lyons</ent>, and
who, for his part, shows not a suspicion of knowledge of them. And
these <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s, just now come into existence, were immediately and
fiercely attacked by Bishop <ent type='person'>Irenaeus</ent> as false and "heresy" in the
vital points of the crucifixion and early death of <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent>, who, says
the Bishop, lived to very old age, even maybe till the times of
Trajan, 98-117, as vouched for by the <ent type='person'>Apostle</ent> <ent type='person'>John</ent> and other
apostles and by the [oral] "<ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>." This, too, casts discredit on
these <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s as containing authentic record of the apostolic
"traditions," condemned in this vital particular by the only two
Bishops, <ent type='person'>Papias</ent> and <ent type='person'>Irenaeus</ent>, who -- for a century and a half --
mention any <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>-writings at all.</p>

<p>   "LURE" DISCREDITS APOSTOLICITY</p>

<p>   Moreover, at the time that the <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent> bearing the name of <ent type='person'>Luke</ent>
was published, already many <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s or purported histories and
sayings of <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> Christ were in active circulation: "<ent type='person'>Forasmuch</ent> as
many have taken in hand to set forth in order a declaration of
those things which are most surely believed among us, Even as they
delivered them unto us, which from the beginning were eye-witnesses
and ministers of the word; it has seemed to me good also, having
had a perfect understanding of all things from the very first, to
write unto thee, in order, most excellent <ent type='person'>Theophilus</ent>, that thou
mightest know the certainty of those things, wherein thou hast been
instructed." (<ent type='person'>Luke</ent>, i, 1-4). Now, these "many" <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s were clearly
not by any of the apostles, else <ent type='person'>Luke</ent> would certainly have so
stated; they were not "inspired" writings, but they were by sundry
anonymous "eye-witnesses and ministers of the word"; they are
either totally lost to posterity, or are among the fifty admittedly
forged and apocryphal <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s which we have previously noticed.
Thus we see two of the "Four," i.e., "<ent type='person'>Mark</ent>," and "<ent type='person'>Luke</ent>" are, on
their face, uninspired, hear-say, and long ex post facto.</p>

<p>   That neither apostle nor contemporary of <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> wrote a line of
"gospel" is thus perfectly evidenced by <ent type='person'>Luke</ent>: "According to the
prologue of <ent type='person'>Luke</ent>, no eye-witness of the life of <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> took pen in
hand -- none at least appear to have produced any writings which
<ent type='person'>Luke</ent> would have called a 'narrative.'" (EB. ii, 1892.) These
conclusions are confirmed by the learned clerical translators and
editors of the ANF, respectively, as follows:</p>

<p>  "Though a few of the Apocryphal <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s are of
   comparatively early origin, there is no evidence that any
   <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s purporting to be what our Four <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s are, existed in
   the first century, or that any other than fragmentary </p>

<p>   Bank of Wisdom
    Box 926, Louisville, KY 40201
    166
.
   FORGERY IN CHRISTIANITY</p>

<p>   literature of this character existed even in the second
   century." (<ent type='person'>Ed</ent>. note to Apocrypha of the New Testament, ANF.
   viii, 349.) -- "There is abundant evidence of the existence of
   many of these traditions in the second century, though it
   cannot be made out that any of the books were then in
   existence in their present form." (Translator's Introductory
   Notice to Apocryphal <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s. ANF. viii, 351.)</p>

<p>   Such apocryphal gospels would naturally contain -- as they do
-- many of the same reputed words and deeds of the Christ as those
now reported by <ent type='person'>Luke</ent> and the others; many are indeed in large
sections in the very same words. <ent type='person'>Luke</ent> does not say or imply that
these "many" were false, but, on the contrary, being by alleged
"eye-witnesses" they were necessarily more or less the same things
which <ent type='person'>Luke</ent> undertook, not to belie or correct, but simply to repeat
in good order for the edification of his friend <ent type='person'>Theophilus</ent>. It is
very significant, for the date of the authorship of "<ent type='person'>Luke</ent>," to note
the fact that the only <ent type='person'>Theophilus</ent> known to early Church history is
a certain ex-<ent type='person'>Pagan</ent> by that name, who, after becoming Christian, and
very probably before being instructed in the certainty of the faith
by "<ent type='person'>Luke</ent>," himself turned Christian instructor and Father, and
wrote the Tract, in three Books, under the title <ent type='person'>Epistle</ent> to
<ent type='person'>Antolychus</ent>, preserved in the Collection of Ante-Niacin <ent type='person'>Fathers</ent>,
vol. ii, pp. 89-121. This <ent type='person'>Theophilus</ent> became Bishop of Antioch about
169-177 A.D. (CE. xiv, 625); and thus illuminates the date of
"<ent type='person'>Luke</ent>."</p>

<p>   That these Four <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s, then, are forgeries, falsely ascribed
to <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Apostle</ent>s</ent> and their companions, a century and a half after Christ
and the apostles, and were compounded of very conflicting
"traditions" and out of the existing 50 or more forgeries
circulating in apostolic names -- is proven as positively as
negative proofs permit, and "beyond a reasonable doubt" -- which is
proof ample for conviction of capital crime.</p>

<p>   Most people, says <ent type='person'>Bishop <ent type='person'>Papias</ent></ent>, took pleasure in "voluminous
falsehoods" in reporting or writing of <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> Christ and his life
and deeds, for which reason, says the Bishop, he was driven to "the
living voice of tradition" for his own accounts, -- samples of
which we have seen. These fanciful and distorted oral traditions,
finally reduced into some fifty fantastic written records of
"voluminous falsehoods," were later, about the time of Book III of
Bishop <ent type='person'>Irenaeus</ent>, crystallized into four documents, one each of
which was held by one of the principal churches as its
authoritative biography of the Christ, or "gospel"; to which, the
titles "According to" <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Matt</ent>hew</ent>, <ent type='person'>Mark</ent>, <ent type='person'>Luke</ent>, <ent type='person'>John</ent>, were tacked for
pretended apostolic sanction.</p>

<p>   The truth of the late second century origin of the <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s and
<ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Epistle</ent>s</ent> may be garnered from the guarded words of a standard
theological textbook on Christian Evidences: "The Christian
literature which has survived from the latter part of the first
century and the beginning of the second is scanty and fragmentary
-- [which could not be true if the <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s and <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Epistle</ent>s</ent> had then
existed]. But when we come into the light of the last quarter of
the second century, we find the <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s of the canon in undisputed
possession of the field.". (The Grounds of Theistic and Christian 
<ent type='person'>Bel</ent>ief, by <ent type='person'>George Parker Fisher</ent>, D.D., LL.D.; 1902.)</p>

<p>   Bank of Wisdom
    Box 926, Louisville, KY 40201
    167
.
   FORGERY IN CHRISTIANITY</p>

<p>   Summarizing the results of critical study of the four <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s,
upon all the evidences, internal and external, which are there
fully reviewed, the conclusions of modern Biblical scholarship are
thus recorded by the Encyclopedia Biblica:</p>

<p>  As to <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Matt</ent>hew</ent>: "The employment of various sources, the
   characteristic difference of the quotations from the LXX
   (Septuagint) and the original (Hebrew), the indefiniteness of
   the determinations of time and place, the incredibleness of
   the contents, the introduction of later conditions, as also
   the artificial arrangement, and so forth, have long since led
   to the conclusion that for the authorship of the first <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>
   the apostle <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Matt</ent>hew</ent> must be given up." (EB. ii, 1891.)</p>

<p>  As to <ent type='person'>Mark</ent>: "According to <ent type='person'>Papias</ent>, the second gospel was
   written by <ent type='person'>Mark</ent>. ... In what <ent type='person'>Papias</ent> says the important point
   is not so much the statement that <ent type='person'>Mark</ent> wrote the gospel as the
   further statement that <ent type='person'>Peter</ent> supplied the contents orally. ...
   The supposition that the gospel is essentially a repetition of
   oral communications by <ent type='person'>Peter</ent>, will at once fall to the ground.
   ... Should <ent type='person'>Mark</ent> have written in Aramaic then he cannot be held
   to have been the author of canonical <ent type='person'>Mark</ent>, which is certainly
   not a translation, nor yet, in view of the LXX quotations
   which have passed over into all three gospels, can he be held
   to have been the author of the original <ent type='person'>Mark</ent>." (EB. ii, 1891.)</p>

<p>  As to <ent type='person'>Luke</ent>: "This tradition [that <ent type='person'>Luke</ent> was the author of
   the third gospel and of Acts] cannot be traced farther back
   than towards the end of the second century (<ent type='person'>Irenaeus</ent>,
   Tertullian, <ent type='person'>Clement</ent> of Alexandria, and the Muratorian
   fragment). ... It has been shown that it is impossible to
   regard <ent type='person'>Luke</ent> with any certainty as the writer even of the 'we'
   sections of Acts, not to speak of the whole book of Acts, or
   of the Third <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>. ... If <ent type='person'>Luke</ent> cannot have been the author
   of Acts, neither can he have been the author of the Third
   <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>." (EB. ii, 1893, 2831.)</p>

<p>  As to <ent type='person'>John</ent>: "No mention of the Fourth <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent> which we can
   recognize as such carries us further than to 140 A.D. As late
   as 152, Justin, who nevertheless lays so great value upon the
   'Memorabilia of the <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Apostle</ent>s</ent>, regards <ent type='person'>John</ent> -- if indeed he
   knows it at all -- with distrust, and appropriates from it a
   very few sayings. ... If on independent grounds some period
   shortly before 140 A.D. can be set down as the approximate
   date of the production of the gospel [a certain statement in
   it is explained]. ... The Apostolic authorship of the gospel
   remains impossible, and that not merely from the consideration
   that it cannot be the son of <ent type='person'>Zebedee</ent> who has introduced
   himself as writer in so remarkable a fashion, but also from
   the consideration that it cannot be an eye-witness of the
   facts of the life of <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> who has presented, as against the
   synoptists, an account so much less credible, nor an original
   apostle who has shown himself so readily accessible to
   <ent type='person'>Alexandrian</ent> and Gnostic ideas, nor a contemporary of <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> who
   survived so late into the second century and yet was capable
   of composing so profound a work." (EB. ii, 2550, 2553.)</p>

<p>   Bank of Wisdom
    Box 926, Louisville, KY 40201
    168
.
   FORGERY IN CHRISTIANITY</p>

<p>   None of these Four <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s, then, being of apostolic
authorship or even of the apostolic age, but anonymous productions
of over a century after the apostles, all are exactly of like
origin and composition as all the other fifty apocryphal <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent>-
writings: the Four "do not, in point of fact, rest upon any real
difference in the character or origin of the writings concerned,"
from all the other fifty admittedly apocryphal and forged gospels
dating about the middle of the second century, at the height of the
Christian age of apocryphal literature. They are therefore late
Christian forgeries of the Catholic Church.</p>

<p>   FORGERIES IN THE FORGED GOSPELS</p>

<p>   That the Four <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s, as we have them, are very late
productions, issued in the names of apostles a century and more
dead, and are therefore forgeries, is now proven beyond
peradventure. That they are not, even in the form that Bishop
<ent type='person'>Irenaeus</ent> first knew them, each the work of one inspired mind and
pen, is as readily and conclusively provable. They are, each and
all Four, clumsy compilations framed by different persons and at
very different times, as is patent on their face; they are thus
concatenations of forgeries within forgeries. This we shall now
demonstrate.</p>

<p>   The Church claims these Four <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s to be apostolic and
divine works, and together with all the other books of the Trentine
Bible, to be throughout divinely inspired, having God himself for
their Author. This 1546 Dogma of the Infallible Church has been
thus reaffirmed by the Sacred Vatican Council (A.D. 1870):</p>

<p>  "These books are sacred and canonical because they
   contain revelation without error, and because, written by the
   inspiration of the Holy Ghost, they have God for their
   Author." (CE. fi, 543.)</p>

<p>   More recently, <ent type='person'>Pope</ent> <ent type='person'>Leo XIII</ent>, in his Encyclical Prov. Deus.
(1893), thus reaffirms the plenary inspiration and inerrancy of
Holy Writ:</p>

<p>  "It will never be lawful to restrict inspiration merely
   to certain portions of the Holy <ent type='person'>Scripture</ent>s, or to grant that
   the sacred writers could have made a mistake. ... They render
   in exact language, with infallible truth, all that God
   commanded, and nothing else"! (Ib.)</p>

<p>   For the Protestant sects the notion of divine inspiration and
inerrant truth of <ent type='person'>Scripture</ent> -- excepting always the dozen and more
of Old Testament "apocryphap' Books and parts, as <ent type='person'>Tobias</ent> and the
history of the Assyrian great god <ent type='person'>Bel</ent> and the Dragon, -- a typical
profession is that of the first Article of the Baptist Declaration
of Faith: "The Holy Bible was written by men divinely inspired, and
is a perfect treasure of heavenly instruction. ... It has God for
its Author, and truth without any admixture of error for its
matter."</p>

<p>   Bank of Wisdom
    Box 926, Louisville, KY 40201
    169
.
   FORGERY IN CHRISTIANITY</p>

<p>   All this priestly "confidence stuff" must remind one of what
<ent type='person'>Cicero</ent> said of the Roman augurs. Even CE., valiant but often 
perplexed defender of the orthodox Faith, can not give full credit
to that inspired canard, which even the infallible authors of it
could not have themselves believed. Timorously "reasoning in
chains" and minimizing the truth, the orthodox apologist, forced by
scholarly criticism, confesses -- utterly belying Council and
Holiness:</p>

<p>  "In all the Bible, where the same event is several times
   narrated by the same writer, or narrated by several writers,
   there is some slight [sic] divergency, as it is natural there
   should be with those who spoke or wrote from memory. Divine
   inspiration covers the substance of the narration." (CE. i,
   122.)</p>

<p>   Those sacred writers, putting on papyrus rolls from errant and
therefore necessarily uninspired "memory," their intimate
familiarities with the thoughts and desires, purposes and
providence of God, make not "some slight divergences" from accurate
recording of the promptings of the Spirit to them; they committed
incessant contradictions of so gross a nature as to impeach and
destroy the possibility of truth and credibility of Virtually every
word they said or wrote "in all the Bible," Old and New Testaments
alike. I have so fully exposed some thousands of these glaring and
self-destroying contradictions in my previous work, that here I
simply notice only those most vital ones which are pertinent and
incidental to our present subject of apostolic forgeries.</p>

<p>   In a work accompanying the Revised Version of the Bible, in
which the <ent type='person'>Revisers</ent> pointed out some 30000 (now over 150000)
variant readings in the New Testament, the reverend author makes
this naive explanation: "In regard to the New Testament, no miracle
has been wrought to preserve the text as it came from the pens of
the inspired writers. That would have been a thing altogether out
of harmony with God's method of governing the world"! (Dr. Alex.
Roberts, Companion to the Revised Version, p. 4.) One may wonder at
the writer's intimacy with God's governmental methods, as well as
at God's indifference to the preservation of his miraculously-
revealed Holy Word, so awfully necessary to save us from eternal
damnation; when, as we shall see, by special miraculous
intervention and providence he has, the Church vouches, preserved
wholly "incorrupt" through the Ages of Faith countless whole
cadavers and ghastly scraps and miraculous relics galore of the
unwashed Saints of Holy Church.</p>

<p>    CONTRADICTIONS AND TRUTH</p>

<p>   No more compelling proofs of forgery in a document can well be
than the glaring contradictions between two parts of the text.
Remember that in the "age of apocryphal literature" there were no
printed books, thus fixing the text, and no "copyright" existed.
All books, sacred and profane, were manuscripts, tediously written
by hand on rolls of papyrus or sheets of parchment-skin; like the
manuscripts of the <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s, <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Epistle</ent>s</ent>, etc., they were usually
unsigned and undated, and frequently gave no clue to the anonymous
writers. When one man came into possession of a manuscript which he</p>

<p>   Bank of Wisdom
    Box 926, Louisville, KY 40201
    170
.
   FORGERY IN CHRISTIANITY</p>

<p>desired, he sat down and copied it by hand, or employed slaves or
professional copyists to do the labor. There was absolutely no
check against errors of copying, or intentional omissions,
alterations or insertions into the text, to suit the taste or
purpose of the copyist. Religious books were written, and copied,
by priests, monks or <ent type='person'>Fathers</ent>; religious notions and doctrines were
very diversely held, and developed or were modified incessantly.
Traditions of what was said or done by <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> Christ and the
apostles were, as we have seen, very variant and conflicting. Very
often, as we shall see, conflicting traditions or accounts are
found in the same book. As no honest writer of intelligence and
care would put into one short work which he is writing, two totally
contradictory statements regarding the same fact, the only way in
which such contradictions can occur in what purports to be an
original or genuine manuscript, is by the intentional insertion by
a later copyist of the new and contradictory material, euphoniously
called "interpolations" (CE. iv, 498, post), -- without the
critical sense to perceive the contradiction, and omit the original
statement with which his addition conflicts.</p>

<p>   Father Tertullian, in his work Against Heresies, denying that
'Christians do such things -- do not need to, he says, because the
<ent type='person'>Scripture</ent>s are favorable to the Orthodox -- accuses the Heretics of
such practices, and naively explains how such interpolations or
forgeries of text are done, and why they needs must be:</p>

<p>   "All interpolation must be believed to be a later process. ...
One man perverts the <ent type='person'>Scripture</ent>s with his hand, another their
meaning by his exposition. ... Unquestionably, the Divine
<ent type='person'>Scripture</ent>s are more fruitful in resources of all kinds for this
sort of facility [of introducing interpolations]. Nor do I risk
contradiction in saying that the very <ent type='person'>Scripture</ent>s were even arranged
by the will of God in such a manner as to furnish materials for
heretics, inasmuch as I read that 'there must be heresies' (I Cor.
xi, 19), which there cannot be without <ent type='person'>Scripture</ent>s"! (Praes.
xxxviii-xxxix; ANF. iii, 262.) Speaking of instances related to the
birth of <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> Christ, EB. makes a remark, which it extends to
others, and is generally applicable to the conflicting <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>
narratives:</p>

<p>  "From the nature of the case both canonical narratives
   were accepted by faith and incorporated with each other. The
   gospels themselves supply ample justification of a criticism
   of the gospel narratives. In spite of all the revisions which
   the gospels received before they became canonically fixed,
   they still not infrequently preserve references to conditions
   which are irreconcilable with the later additions." (EB. iii,
   3343, 3344.)</p>

<p>   "For Christian orthodoxy," says the same authority,
"reconcilability of the two canonical accounts was always a
necessary dogma"; and on this point, the orthodox CE. makes a
quaint but typically clerical argument, in effect that the
confessed contradictions of Holy Writ make it all the more
credible: "As can readily be seen, variations are naturally to be
expected in four distinct, and in many ways independent, accounts
of Christ's words and deeds, so that their presence, instead of </p>

<p>   Bank of Wisdom
    Box 926, Louisville, KY 40201
    171
.
   FORGERY IN CHRISTIANITY</p>

<p>going against, rather makes for the substantial value of the
evangelical narratives"! (CE. vi, 659.) Fanciful and disingenuous
as this is, and derogatory of the Papal theory that it is not
possible that "the sacred writers could have made a mistake," the
argument loses even its rhetorical force when we find the most
monumental contradictions in the inspired words of the same writer
in the same inspired little book. We will notice some of the most
obvious and fatal forgeries by "interpolations" into the <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>
Christ-tales.</p>

<p>    <ent type='person'>JESUS</ent> -- MAN OR <ent type='person'>GOD</ent>?</p>

<p>   The Jews, in their "canonical," more definitely in their
apocryphal or admittedly forged <ent type='person'>Scripture</ent>s, expected a "Messiah,"
or anointed King of the race and lineage of <ent type='person'>David</ent>, who should
deliver them from the rule of their enemies, -- at the time of the
<ent type='person'>Gospel</ent> tales, the Romans; previously, the Assyrians, Persians, and
Greeks, successively. This King, says <ent type='person'>Isaiah</ent>, shall sit and reign
"upon the throne of <ent type='person'>David</ent>, and upon his kingdom, to establish it"
(Isa. ix, 7); and that this prophecy was in order of fulfillment,
<ent type='person'>Gabriel</ent> the Angel announced to <ent type='person'>Mary</ent> the Ever-Virgin Mother of eight
sons and daughters: "Thou shalt bring forth a son, and shalt call
his name <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent>; and the Lord God shall give unto him the throne of
his father <ent type='person'>David</ent>: And he shall reign over the house of Jacob
forever." (Lk. i, 32, 33.) There is not a word of "prophecy"
anywhere that this King should be divine, a <ent type='person'>Son</ent> of the God of
Israel; he was to be a human king of the house of Jacob, of <ent type='person'>David</ent>.
There were many false pretenders to the still vacant Messiahship,
and even <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> was not the last to proclaim himself the Messiah or
Christ: "For many shall come in my name, saying, I am Christ; and
shall deceive many." (Mt. xxiv, 4, 23, 24; Mk. xiii, 6, 21, 22.)</p>

<p>   That this Messiah <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> who was come was mere man, but
instinct with the spirit of God, is positively avowed by both <ent type='person'>Peter</ent>
and <ent type='person'>Paul</ent>. Says <ent type='person'>Peter</ent> in his first sermon at Pentecost: "Ye men of
Israel, hear these words: <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> of Nazareth, a man approved of God
among you [etc.]. The patriarch <ent type='person'>David</ent> ... therefore being a
prophet, and knowing that God had sworn with an oath to him, that
of the fruit of his loam according to the flesh, he would raise up
Christ to sit upon his throne." (Acts, ii, 22, 29, 30.) And <ent type='person'>Paul</ent>:
"There is one God, and one mediator between God and men, the man
Christ <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent>" (1 Tim. ii, 5); and again: "<ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> Christ of the seed
of <ent type='person'>David</ent>" (2 Tim. ii, 8); Therefore, in the times when the two
cited sacred books were, by whomever, written, <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> was at that
time regarded simply as a man, a "son" or descendant of <ent type='person'>David</ent>. So,
when, many years later, the <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s "according to" <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Matt</ent>hew</ent> and <ent type='person'>Luke</ent>
came to be by whomever written, in their original form <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> Christ
was mere man.</p>

<p>   <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Matt</ent>hew</ent>'s first chapter begins very humanly and explicitly:
"The book of the generation of <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> Christ, the son of <ent type='person'>David</ent>, the
son of <ent type='person'>Abraham</ent>"; and <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Matt</ent>hew</ent> gives an unbroken line of human
begettings, father of son, until "And <ent type='person'>Jacob begat <ent type='person'>Joseph</ent></ent> the
husband of <ent type='person'>Mary</ent>, of whom was born <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent>, who is called Christ"!
(<ent type='person'>Matt</ent>. i, 1-16.) And <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Matt</ent>hew</ent> names and catalogues twenty-eight
generations between <ent type='person'>David</ent> and <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent>, to-wit: <ent type='person'>David</ent>, Solomon ...
Jacob, <ent type='person'>Joseph</ent>, -- <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent>, -- a purely human ancestry. Also <ent type='person'>Luke</ent> </p>

<p>   Bank of Wisdom
    Box 926, Louisville, KY 40201
    172
.
   FORGERY IN CHRISTIANITY</p>

<p>still reflected the belief, held at the time he wrote, that <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent>
was of human ancestry; he gives his human genealogy all the way
back to Adam, and through many mythical patriarchs who assuredly
never existed. This human genealogy by <ent type='person'>Luke</ent> vastly differs,
however, from that of <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Matt</ent>hew</ent>; instead of twenty-eight generations
from <ent type='person'>David</ent>, through Solomon ... Jacob and <ent type='person'>Joseph</ent>, our <ent type='person'>Luke</ent>
genealogist makes out in detail forty-two generations, to wit:
<ent type='person'>David</ent>, Nathan. ... Heli, <ent type='person'>Joseph</ent>, <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent>; and only three of the
intermediate names are the same in the two lists. So one or the
other of the two inspired genealogies is fictitious, false and
forged, necessarily: both are, of course, if <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> was not the son
of <ent type='person'>David</ent>, but the immediate "<ent type='person'>Son</ent> of God." The truth is thus stated:
"The genealogy could not have been drawn up after <ent type='person'>Joseph</ent> ceased to
be regarded as the real father of <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent>." (EB. iii, 2960.)</p>

<p>   And CE. thus 'Scraps the inspired genealogy of <ent type='person'>Luke</ent>: "The
artificial character of <ent type='person'>Luke</ent>'s genealogy may be seen in the
following table [copying <ent type='person'>Luke</ent>'s list] ... The artificial character"
is shown by details cited. (CE. vi, 411.) It also explodes the
seventeenth century clerical pretense, -- heard often today -- in
attempted explanation of these glaring contradictions, that one or
the other of these sacred genealogies, preferably that of <ent type='person'>Luke</ent>, was
the genealogy, not of <ent type='person'>Joseph</ent>, but of <ent type='person'>Mary</ent>: "It may be safely said
that patristic tradition does not regard St. <ent type='person'>Luke</ent>'s list as
representing the genealogy of the Blessed Virgin." (CE. vi, 411.)
And, as CE. itself points out, <ent type='person'>Mary</ent> is not mentioned as in the line
of descent from <ent type='person'>David</ent> in either list. To bring her into the
genealogy, in one list or the other, it must have been written:
"And Jacob begat <ent type='person'>Mary</ent> the wife of <ent type='person'>Joseph</ent>," instead of "And, Jacob
begat <ent type='person'>Joseph</ent> the husband of <ent type='person'>Mary</ent>": or "And <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> ... being the son
of <ent type='person'>Mary</ent>, which was the daughter of Heli," instead of the recorded
"the son of <ent type='person'>Joseph</ent> (as was supposed), which was the son of Heli"
(<ent type='person'>Luke</ent> iii, 22-31). Both the genealogies are false and forged lists
of mostly fictitious names, in the original <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>-forgeries,
fabricated to prove <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> a direct son or descendant of <ent type='person'>David</ent>, and
thus to fulfill the terms of the pretended prophecies that the
human Messiah should be of the race and lineage of <ent type='person'>David</ent> the king.</p>

<p>   Moreover, <ent type='person'>Joseph</ent> and <ent type='person'>Mary</ent> both knew nothing of the Holy-
Ghostly paternity of their child <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent>. The celebrated Angelic
"Annunciation" of this Fable to the "prolific yet ever-virgin
Mother of God," recorded by Dr. <ent type='person'>Luke</ent> (i, 28), is itself a forgery,
admits CE.: "The words: 'Blessed art thou among women' (v. 28) are
spurious and taken from verse 42, the account of the Visitation ...
[Adding] The opinion that <ent type='person'>Joseph</ent> at the time of the Annunciation
was an aged widower and <ent type='person'>Mary</ent> 12 or 15 years of age, is founded only
upon apocryphal documents" -- like all the rest of these Fables of
Christ. (CE. i, 542.) <ent type='person'>Simon</ent> came into the temple when <ent type='person'>Joseph</ent> and
<ent type='person'>Mary</ent> had brought the child there "to do for him after the custom of
the law," and indulged in some ecstasies which would have been
quite intelligible if <ent type='person'>Gabriel</ent> had made the revelations attributed
to him; but, hearing them, "<ent type='person'>Joseph</ent> and his mother marvelled at
those things which were spoken of him" (Lk. ii, 33). It is false,
the original says: "His father and his mother marvelled." etc. Here
is another holy forgery stuck into <ent type='person'>Luke</ent> ii, as is the later verse,
"and <ent type='person'>Joseph</ent> and his mother knew not of it" (v. 43). The true
original reads "and his parents knew not of it," -- just as in </p>

<p>   Bank of Wisdom
    Box 926, Louisville, KY 40201
    173
.
   FORGERY IN CHRISTIANITY</p>

<p>verse 41; "Now his parents went to Jerusalem every year at the
feast of the passover"; and as in verse 48, "thy father and I have
sought thee sorrowing." In "<ent type='person'>John</ent>," <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> is twice: expressly called
the son of <ent type='person'>Joseph</ent>; Philip say's to <ent type='person'>Nathaniel</ent>, "We have found him of
whom <ent type='person'>Moses</ent> in the law, and the prophets, did write, <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> of
Nazareth, the son of <ent type='person'>Joseph</ent>" (i, 45); and again: "Is not this
<ent type='person'>Jesus</ent>, the son of <ent type='person'>Joseph</ent>, whose father and mother we know'?" (vi,
42) all which "convincingly proves that in the mind of the narrator
<ent type='person'>Joseph</ent> and <ent type='person'>Mary</ent> were and knew themselves to be, in the natural
sense of the words, the parents of <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent>." (EB. iii, 3344.) The
same authority thus sums up the whole of the New Testament evidence
prior to the "interpolations" of miraculous birth: "The remark has
long ago and often been made that, like <ent type='person'>Paul</ent>, even the <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s
themselves know nothing of the miraculous birth of our Savior. On
the contrary, their knowledge of his natural filial relationship to
<ent type='person'>Joseph</ent> the carpenter, and to <ent type='person'>Mary</ent>, his wife, is still explicit."
(<ent type='person'>Ibid</ent>.) And if <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> had been a God he could hardly have been
crazy; yet his own family thought him so and sent to arrest him as
a madman, as above noticed. It is therefore self-evident, that the
original <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> "tradition," down as late as <ent type='person'>Papias</ent> and <ent type='person'>Irenaeus</ent>,
regarded <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> simply as a man, and as a very old man when he died
a peaceful and natural death. But the zeal to Combat and win the
<ent type='person'>Pagan</ent>s, when, after the failure with the Jews, the <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent> "turned
to the Gentiles," and to exalt the man <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> into a God, as was
<ent type='person'>Perseus</ent> or Apollo, grew with the <ent type='person'>Fathers</ent>; by the same token <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent>
was now made to be the son of the Hebrew God Yahveh: we have heard
the <ent type='person'>Fathers</ent> so argue. So later pious tampering grafted the "Virgin-
birth" and "son of God" <ent type='person'>Pagan</ent> myths onto the simple original
"traditions" of merely human origin as the "son of <ent type='person'>David</ent>,"
carelessly letting the primitively forged <ent type='person'>David</ent>ic genealogies
remain to contradict and refute them. These "interpolations" are
self-apparent forgeries for Christ's sake, in two of the <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s.</p>

<p>   But if Tertullian spoke truly (if the passage is genuine with
him), the other <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s have been yet further tampered with; for
Tertullian explicitly says: "Of the apostles, <ent type='person'>John</ent> and <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Matt</ent>hew</ent>, and
apostolic men, <ent type='person'>Luke</ent> and <ent type='person'>Mark</ent>, these all start with the same
principles of the faith ... how that He was born of the Virgin, and
came to fulfill the law and the prophets." (Adv. Marcion, IV, ii;
ANF. iii, 347.) As these <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s now stand, <ent type='person'>Mark</ent> and <ent type='person'>John</ent> say not
a word of the Virgin-birth, but throughout assume <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> to have
been of human birth, and only "son of God" in a popular religious
sense; for "son of God" was in current usage to mean any person
near and dear to God. Indeed, the Greek text of the <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s makes
this plain, that no supernatural progeneration and actual God-
sonship was intended. In most instances the Greek texts read simply
"son of God -- huios Theou," not "the <ent type='person'>Son</ent> -- o huious": the
definite article is a clerical falsification.</p>

<p>   "UPON THIS ROCK I WILL BUILD MY CHURCH"</p>

<p>   Of transcendent importance as the sole basis of the Church's
most presumptuous False Pretense -- its Divine founding by <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent>
Christ -- this <ent type='person'>Peter</ent>-Rock imposture, the most notorious, and in its
evil consequences the most far-reaching and fatal of them all, will
now be exposed to its deserved infamy and destruction.</p>

<p>   Bank of Wisdom
    Box 926, Louisville, KY 40201
    174
.
   FORGERY IN CHRISTIANITY</p>

<p>   Upon a forged, and forced, Greek <ent type='person'>Pun</ent> put into the mouth of the
Jewish Aramaic-speaking <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent>, speaking to Aramaic peasants, the
Church of Christ is falsely founded. "The proof that Christ
constituted St. <ent type='person'>Peter</ent> the head of His Church is found in the two
famous Petrine texts, <ent type='person'>Matt</ent>. xvi, 17-19, and <ent type='person'>John</ent> xxi, 15-19." (CE.
xii, 261.) The text in <ent type='person'>John</ent> is that about "Feed my Lambs"; but this
forgery is not of present interest. The more notorious "proof" is
<ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Matt</ent>hew</ent>'s forged punning passage: "Thou art <ent type='person'>Peter</ent>, and upon this
rock I will build my church," etc.</p>

<p>   It may first be noticed, that "<ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Matt</ent>hew</ent>" is the only one of the
three "Synoptic" gospelers to record this "famous Petrine text."
And he records this pun as made in Greek, by <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> -- just before
his crucifixion, under very exceptional circumstances, and upon the
inspiration of a "special divine revelation" then and there first
made by God to <ent type='person'>Peter</ent>, as below to be noted. But in this, "<ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Matt</ent>hew</ent>"
is flatly contradicted by "<ent type='person'>John</ent>," who ascribes this as an Aramaic
pun by <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> in the very first remark that he made to <ent type='person'>Peter</ent>, upon
his being introduced by his brother <ent type='person'>Andrew</ent>, on the self-same day of
the baptism of <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent>; when "<ent type='person'>Andrew</ent> first findeth his brother <ent type='person'>Simon</ent>
... and brought him to <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent>"; whereupon, "when <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> beheld him,
he said, Thou art <ent type='person'>Simon</ent> son of Jona: thou shalt be called <ent type='person'>Cephas</ent>,
which is by interpretation, A stone." (<ent type='person'>John</ent> i, 42.) Thus was <ent type='person'>Simon</ent>
Barjona nick-named "<ent type='person'>Cephas</ent> -- Rock" by <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> on the very first day
of the public appearance and mission both of <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> and of <ent type='person'>Peter</ent>,
and not a year or more later, towards the close of the career of
<ent type='person'>Jesus</ent>! So the famous <ent type='person'>Petrine <ent type='person'>Pun</ent></ent>, if ever made by <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> -- as it
was not -- was made in the Aramaic speech spoken by these Galilean
peasants; the Greek Father who forged the "<ent type='person'>Gospel</ent> according to
<ent type='person'>John</ent>" had to attach the translation into Greek of the Aramaic
"<ent type='person'>Cephas</ent>," into "Petros, a stone," for the benefit of his Greek
readers.</p>

<p>   After this first explosion of the famous Greek "Rock" pun on
which the Church is founded, and as the matter is of highest
consequence, let us expose the "<ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Matt</ent>hew</ent>" forgery of the whole
"Petrine text" by arraying the three Synoptics in sequence in the
order of their composition and evolution from simple to complex
fabrication:</p>

<p>   <ent type='person'>Mark</ent> (viii, 27-38).</p>

<p>  "And <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> went out, and his disciples, into the towns of
   Caesarea <ent type='person'>Philippi</ent>: and by the way he asked his disciples,
   saying unto them, Whom do men say that I am?</p>

<p>  "And they answered, <ent type='person'>John</ent> the Baptist: but some say,
   <ent type='person'>Elias</ent>; and others, One of the prophets.
  "And he saith unto them, But whom say ye that I am? And
   <ent type='person'>Peter</ent> answereth and saith unto him, Thou art the Christ.
  "And he charged them that they should tell no man of him.
  "And he began to teach them, that the <ent type='person'>Son</ent> of man must
   suffer many things, and be rejected of the elders, and of the
   chief priests, and scribes, and be killed, and after three
   days rise again.
  "And he spak that saying openly. And <ent type='person'>Peter</ent> took him, and
   began to rebuke him.</p>

<p>   Bank of Wisdom
    Box 926, Louisville, KY 40201
    175
.
   FORGERY IN CHRISTIANITY</p>

<p>  "But when he had turned about and looked on his
   disciples, he rebuked <ent type='person'>Peter</ent>, saying, Get thee behind me,
   <ent type='person'>Satan</ent>: for thou savourest not the things that be of God, but
   the things that be of men."</p>

<p>    <ent type='person'>Luke</ent> (ix, 18-22).</p>

<p>  "And it came to pass, as he was alone praying, his
   disciples were with him; and he asked them, saying, Whom say
   the people that I am?
  "They answering said, <ent type='person'>John</ent> the Baptist; but some say,
   <ent type='person'>Elias</ent>; and others say, that one of the old prophets is risen
   again.
  "He said unto them, But whom say ye that I am? <ent type='person'>Peter</ent>
   answering said, The Christ of God.
  "And he straitly charged them, and commanded them to tell
   no man that thing.
  "Saying, The <ent type='person'>Son</ent> of man must suffer many things, and be
   rejected of the elders and chief priests and scribes, and be
   slain, and be raised the third day."</p>

<p>    <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Matt</ent>hew</ent> (xvi, 13-22).</p>

<p>  "When <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> came into the coasts of Caesarea <ent type='person'>Philippi</ent>, he
   asked his disciples, saying, Whom do men say that I the <ent type='person'>Son</ent> of
   man am?
  "And they said, Some say that thou art <ent type='person'>John</ent> the Baptist:
   some, <ent type='person'>Elias</ent>; and others, <ent type='person'>Jeremias</ent>, or one of the prophets.
  "He saith unto them, But whom say ye that I am? And <ent type='person'>Simon</ent>
   <ent type='person'>Peter</ent> answered and said, Thou are the Christ, the <ent type='person'>Son</ent> of the
   living God.
  "And <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> answered and said unto him, Blessed art thou,
   <ent type='person'>Simon</ent> Barjona: for flesh and blood hath not revealed it unto
   thee, but my Father which is in heaven.
  "And I say unto thee, That thou art <ent type='person'>Peter</ent>, and upon this
   rock I will build my church; and the gates of hell shall not
   prevail against it. [Here about the <ent type='person'>Keys</ent>, and "binding and
   loosing"].
  "Then charged he his disciples that they should tell no
   man that he was <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> the Christ.
  "From that time forth began <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> to <ent type='person'>shew</ent> unto his
   disciples, how that he must go unto Jerusalem, and suffer many
   things of the elders and chief priests and scribes, and be
   killed, and be raised again the third day.
  "Then <ent type='person'>Peter</ent> took him, and began to rebuke him, saying, Be
   it far from thee, Lord: this shall not be unto thee.
  "But he turned and said unto <ent type='person'>Peter</ent>, Get thee behind me.
   <ent type='person'>Satan</ent>: thou art an offence unto me: for thou savourest not the
   things that be of God, but those that be of men."</p>

<p>   Let it be noted, in passing, that all three of the Synoptists
expressly aver in the above narration, as elsewhere in their texts,
that <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> positively declared and predicted, that he should be put
to death, and after three days rise again: distinctly, his
Resurrection from the dead. All three on this important point are
liars, if <ent type='person'>John</ent> be believed; for after the crucifixion and burial of
<ent type='person'>Jesus</ent>, and the discovery on the third day of his empty grave by the</p>

<p>   Bank of Wisdom
    Box 926, Louisville, KY 40201
    176
.
   FORGERY IN CHRISTIANITY</p>

<p>Magdalene, which she immediately reported to <ent type='person'>Peter</ent> and <ent type='person'>John</ent>, they
ran doubting to the grave, looked in, and "saw, and believed"; and
<ent type='person'>John</ent> positively avers: "For as yet they knew not the scripture,
that he must rise again from the dead." (<ent type='person'>John</ent> xx, 9.) But this
inspired assertion contains a grave anachronism: for "as yet" there
was, of course, no "scripture" about the death and resurrection at
all, nor for well over a century afterwards, as in this chapter is
proven.</p>

<p>   Let us examine for a moment into the context of this "famous
Petrine text" and into its antecedents, in order to get the "stage
setting of this dramatic climacteric <ent type='person'>Pun</ent> of such vast and serious
consequences unto this day.</p>

<p>   The original simple narrative is told in the earlier writer,
"<ent type='person'>Mark</ent>," and copied almost verbatim into "<ent type='person'>Luke</ent>." There <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> is
reported to have put a sort of conundrum to the Twelve, "saying
unto them, Whom do men say that I am?" The answer showed a very
superstitious belief in reincarnations or "second comings" of dead
persons to earth; for "they answered, <ent type='person'>John</ent> the Baptist: but some
say, <ent type='person'>Elias</ent>; and others, One of the prophets, or <ent type='person'>Jeremias</ent>," to fuse
the somewhat disparate replies. <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> himself shared this
reincarnation superstition, for he had positively asserted that
<ent type='person'>John</ent> the Baptist was <ent type='person'>Elijah redivivus</ent>: "This is <ent type='person'>Elias</ent>, which was
for to come," (<ent type='person'>Matt</ent>. xi, 14; xvii, 11-13); though <ent type='person'>John</ent>, being
questioned about it, "Art thou <ent type='person'>Elias</ent>?" contradicted the Christ,
"and he saith, I am not." (<ent type='person'>John</ent> i, 20, 21.)</p>

<p>   After hearing the disciples report what others said about him,
who he was, <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> then "saith unto them, But whom say ye that I am?
And <ent type='person'>Peter</ent> answereth and saith unto him, Thou art the Christ. And he
charged them that they should tell no man of him" (Mk. viii, 27-30;
Lk. ix, 18-22). There was certainly nothing novel or unexpected in
this alleged reply of <ent type='person'>Peter</ent>; it was exactly the proclaimed mission
of <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> as the "promised Messiah," as the precedent texts of
"<ent type='person'>Mark</ent>" verify. On the day of his baptism by <ent type='person'>John</ent>, before all the
people, "the heavens opened ... And there came a voice from heaven,
saying, Thou art my beloved <ent type='person'>Son</ent>" (i, 2); what the devils cried out
in the synagogue, "I know thee who thou art, the Holy one of God"
(i, 24) just what all the devils unanimously proclaimed before the
disciples and all hearers, "And unclean spirits, when they saw him.
... cried, saying, Thou art the son of God" (iii, 2); just what the
possessed man with the legion of devils cried out before all the
disciples, "What have I to do with thee, <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent>, thou <ent type='person'>Son</ent> of the
most high God" (v, 7); -- all as recorded by "<ent type='person'>Mark</ent>" prior to the
above reply by <ent type='person'>Peter</ent>. So, naturally, <ent type='person'>Peter</ent>'s "confession" caused no
surprise; it was the expected thing: so <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> made no remark on
hearing it, except the peculiar injunction that "they should tell
no man" -- what all men and devils already knew by much-repeated
hearsay. So <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> at once proceeded to speak of his coming
persecution, death, and resurrection; "And <ent type='person'>Peter</ent> took him, and
began to rebuke him. But when he had turned about and looked on his
disciples, he rebuked <ent type='person'>Peter</ent>, saying, Get thee behind me, <ent type='person'>Satan</ent>: for
thou savourest not the things that be of God, but the things that
be of men" (Mk. viii, 31-33). The identical story in its same
simple form, minus the <ent type='person'>Satan</ent> colloquy, is told also in <ent type='person'>Luke</ent> (ix,
18-22). This is the round, unvarnished tale of the first Greek </p>

<p>   Bank of Wisdom
    Box 926, Louisville, KY 40201
    177
.
   FORGERY IN CHRISTIANITY</p>

<p>Father "gospel" writers, a century after the reputed conversation,
and long before the "primacy of <ent type='person'>Peter</ent>" idea dawned as a "good
thing" upon the <ent type='person'>Fathers</ent> of the Church. There is not a word about
"church" in the passage, nor in the entire "gospel according to
<ent type='person'>Mark</ent>," nor in <ent type='person'>Luke</ent>, nor in even the much later "<ent type='person'>John</ent>."</p>

<p>   The later Church Father who wrote up the original of the
"gospel according to <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Matt</ent>hew</ent>," copied <ent type='person'>Mark</ent>'s story substantially
verbatim, <ent type='person'>Mark</ent>'s verses 27-33, being nearly word for word
reproduced in <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Matt</ent>hew</ent>'s 13-16, 20-24 of chapter xvi; the only
material verbal difference being in <ent type='person'>Peter</ent>'s answer, in verse 16,
where <ent type='person'>Peter</ent>'s words are expanded: "Thou art the Christ, the <ent type='person'>Son</ent> of
the Living God," -- obviously padded in by the "interpolator" of
verses 17-19, which we now examine.</p>

<p>   As the years since "<ent type='person'>Mark</ent>" rolled by, the zeal of the <ent type='person'>Fathers</ent>
to exalt <ent type='person'>Peter</ent> increased; we have seen many admitted forgeries of
documents having that purpose in view. So it was, obviously, a new
forging Father who took a manuscript of "<ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Matt</ent>hew</ent>," and turning to
the above verses copied from "<ent type='person'>Mark</ent>," added in, or made a new
manuscript copy containing, the notable forgery of verses 17-19.
There, onto the commonplace and unnoticed reply of <ent type='person'>Peter</ent>, "Thou art
the Christ," the pious interpolator tacked on:</p>

<p>  "the <ent type='person'>Son</ent> of the living God. And <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> answered and said
   unto him, Blessed art thou, <ent type='person'>Simon</ent> Barjona: for flesh and blood
   hath not revealed it unto thee, but my Father which is in
   heaven. And I say also unto thee, that thou art <ent type='person'>Peter</ent>, and
   upon this rock I will build my church; and the gates of hell
   shall not prevail against it. And I will give unto thee the
   keys of the Kingdom of heaven: and whatsoever thou shalt bind
   on earth shall be bound in heaven and whatsoever thou shalt
   loose on earth shall be loosed in heaven." (<ent type='person'>Matt</ent>. xvi,
   16b-19.)</p>

<p>   It is impossible that the original writer of "<ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Matt</ent>hew</ent>" should
have written those remarkable and preposterous verses, in which
<ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> is made to take <ent type='person'>Peter</ent>'s commonplace announcement, "Thou art
the Christ," as a "special revelation from heaven" to <ent type='person'>Peter</ent> and a
great secret mystery here first "revealed"; -- this matter of
common notoriety and even devil-gossip throughout Israel, as we
have seen from "<ent type='person'>Mark</ent>'s" numerous Christ-texts; the same is true in
<ent type='person'>Luke</ent>. These avowals that <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> was the Christ are even more
numerous and explicit in "<ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Matt</ent>hew</ent>" up to the interpolation. That
<ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> was "Christ" is the identical disclosure and announcement,
which had been declared by <ent type='person'>Gabriel</ent> to <ent type='person'>Mary</ent>; by a dream to the
suspicious <ent type='person'>Joseph</ent>; by wicked <ent type='person'>Herod</ent>, who "demanded of them where
Christ should be born" (ii, 4); by the voice from heaven
proclaiming to the world, "This is my beloved <ent type='person'>Son</ent>" (iii, 17); that
was declared by the Devil in the wilderness, "If thou be the <ent type='person'>Son</ent> of
God" (iv, 6); that the Legion of Devils cried aloud, "What have we
to do with thee, <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent>, thou son of God" (viii, 29); that <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent>
himself avowed of himself time and again, "All things are delivered
unto me by my Father, Lord of heaven and earth" (xi, 25-27) that
all the crew of <ent type='person'>Peter</ent>'s fishing-boat acclaimed when they
"worshipped him, saying, Of a truth thou art the <ent type='person'>Son</ent> of God" (xiv,
33). 'Just two chapters earlier in <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Matt</ent>hew</ent>, is the fable of <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> </p>

<p>   Bank of Wisdom
    Box 926, Louisville, KY 40201
    178
.
   FORGERY IN CHRISTIANITY</p>

<p>and <ent type='person'>Peter</ent> "walking on the water," as "foretold" by the <ent type='person'>Sibyl</ent>s; when
<ent type='person'>Peter</ent> began to sink, he was rescued and dragged aboard the little
fishing boat by <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent>; -- "and they that were in the ship came and
worshipped him, saying, Of a truth thou art the son of God." (Mt.
xiv, 29-33.) So that <ent type='person'>Peter</ent>'s wonderful information was no novelty
and special divine revelation, to himself, but was the common
credulity and gossip of the whole crew of fishermen, devils and
Palestinian peasantry. And long before, on the very next day after
his baptism by <ent type='person'>John</ent>, and before <ent type='person'>Peter</ent> was "called" or even found,
and when his brother <ent type='person'>Andrew</ent> went and found him to bring him to
<ent type='person'>Jesus</ent>, <ent type='person'>Andrew</ent> declared to <ent type='person'>Peter</ent>. "We have found the Messiah, which
is, being interpreted, the Christ"! (<ent type='person'>John</ent> i, 41.) And, on the next
day <ent type='person'>Nathaniel</ent> said to <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent>: "Rabbi, thou art the <ent type='person'>Son</ent> of God; thou
art the King of Israel"! (<ent type='person'>John</ent> i, 49.) <ent type='person'>Peter</ent>'s wonderful "special
revelation" and confession thus lose an originality and are without
merit of the great "reward" which CE. (xii, 261) says <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent>
bestowed upon him for this pretended original and inspired
discovery, as we shall in due order notice.</p>

<p>   That <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> Christ never spoke the words of those forged
verses, that they are a late Church forgery, is beyond any
intelligent or honest denial. The first mention of them in
"patristic literature," and that only a reference to the "keys," is
this scant line of Father Tertullian, in a little tract called
<ent type='person'>Scorpiace</ent> or "The Scorpion's Sting," written about 211 A.D., in
which he says: "For, though you think heaven is still shut,
remember that the Lord left to <ent type='person'>Peter</ent> and through him to the Church,
the keys of it." (<ent type='person'>Scorpiace</ent>, x; ANF. iii, 643.) That <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> did not
use the words of those verses, interpolated into a paragraph of
<ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Matt</ent>hew</ent> copied bodily and verbatim by the original "<ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Matt</ent>hew</ent>" writer
from "<ent type='person'>Mark</ent>," and repeated in their original form by "<ent type='person'>Luke</ent>,"' is
thus conclusive from "internal" evidences; the later and
embroidered form is a visible interpolation and forgery. That this
is true, is demonstrated, moreover, by the inherent impossibility
of the thing itself.</p>

<p>   THE "CHURCH" FOUNDED ON THE "ROCK"</p>

<p>   First of all, in proof that <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> Christ never made this <ent type='person'>Pun</ent>,
did not establish any Christian Church -- nor even a Jewish
reformed synagoguel, -- are his own alleged positive statements to
be quoted in refutation of the other forged "missionary" passage in
<ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Matt</ent>hew</ent>: "Go ye into all the world, and teach all nations." The
avowed mission of <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent>, as we have seen from his reputed words,
was exclusively to his fellow Jews: "I am not sent but to the lost
sheep of the house of Israel"; and he expressly commanded his
disciples not to preach to the Gentiles, nor even to the near-
Jewish Samaritans. He proclaimed the immediate end of the world,
and his quick second coming to establish the exclusively Jewish
Kingdom of Heaven, even before all the Jews of little Palestine
could be warned of the event -- that "the Kingdom of Heaven is at
hand." It is impossible, therefore, that <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> could have so
flagrantly contradicted the basic principles of his exclusive
mission as the Jewish promised Messiah, and could have commanded
the institution of a permanent and perpetual religious organization
an ecclesia" or "Church," to preach his exclusively Jewish </p>

<p>   Bank of Wisdom
    Box 926, Louisville, KY 40201
    179
.
   FORGERY IN CHRISTIANITY</p>

<p>Messianic doctrines to all nations of the earth, which was to
perish within that generation. This is a conclusive proof of the 
later "interpolation" or forgery of this punning passage.</p>

<p>   On this point says EB.:</p>

<p>  "It would be a great mistake to suppose that <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent>
   himself founded a new religious community" (c. 3103). -- "A
   further consideration which tells against the genuineness of
   Mt. xvi, 18b, is the occurrence in it of the word ecclesia. It
   has been seen to be impossible to maintain that <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> founded
   any distinct religious community. ...</p>

<p>  "As for the word itself, it occurs elsewhere in the
   <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s only in Mt. xviii, 17. There, however, it denotes
   simply the Jewish local community to which every one belongs;
   for what is said relates not to the future but to the present,
   in which a Christian ecclesia cannot, of course, be thought
   of." (c. 3105) ... "It is impossible to regard as historical
   the employment of the word ecclesia by <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> as the
   designation of the Christian community." (EB. iii, 3103, 3105,
   3117.)</p>

<p>   Indeed, as said by a contemporary wit, the truth is that
"<ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> Christ did not found the Church -- he is its Foundling. His
parent, the Jewish church, abandoned the child; the Roman church
took it in, adopted it, and gave his mother a certificate of good
character." (The Truth Seeker, 10/23/26.)</p>

<p>   <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> spoke Aramaic, a dialect of the ancient and "dead"
Hebrew. The true name of the fisherman "Prince of the <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Apostle</ent>s</ent>,"
just repudiated by <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> as "<ent type='person'>Satan</ent>," was Shimeon, or in its Greek
form, <ent type='person'>Simon</ent>, who was later "surnamed <ent type='person'>Peter</ent>." He attained somehow
the Aramaic nickname Kepha, or in its Greek form, <ent type='person'>Cephas</ent>, meaning
a rock; this evidently furnished to the Greek punster the cue for
his play on words: "Thou art Petro, [Greek, petros, a rock; cf.
Eng. petrify, petroleum, etc.), and upon this petros [rock] I will
build my ecclesia [church]." <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> could not have made this Greek
play on words; neither <ent type='person'>Peter</ent> nor any of the other "ignorant and
unlearned" Jewish peasant disciples could have understood it. Much
less could <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> have said, or the apostles have understood, this
other Greek word "ecclesia," even had it been possible for <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent>,
facing the immediate end of the world -- proclaimed by himself --
to have dreamed of founding any permanent religious sect. There was
nothing like ecclesia known to the Jews; it was a technical Greek
term designating the free political assemblies of the Greek
republics. This is illustrated by one sentence from the Greek
Father Origen, about 245 A.D., when the Church had taken over the
Greek political term ecclesia to denote its own religious
organization. Says Origen, using the word in both its old meaning
and in its new Christian adaptation: "For the Church [ecclesia] of
God, e.q., which is at Athens; ... Whereas the assembly [ecclesia]
of the Athenians," etc. (Origen, Contra Celsum, iii, 20; ANF. iv,
476.) The Greek <ent type='person'>Fathers</ent> who, a century later, founded the Church
among the <ent type='person'>Pagan</ent> Greek-speaking Gentiles, adopted the Greek word
ecclesia for their organizations because the word was familiar for
popular assemblies, and because the translators of the Septuagint </p>

<p>   Bank of Wisdom
    Box 926, Louisville, KY 40201
    180
.
   FORGERY IN CHRISTIANITY</p>

<p>had used ecclesia as the nearest Greek term for the translation of
the two Hebrew words qahal and edah used in the Old Testament for
the "congregation" or "assembly" of all Israel at the tent of
meeting.</p>

<p>   These Hebrew words (qahal, edah) had also a more general use,
as signifying any sort of gathering or crowd, religious or secular.
Thus "sinners shall not stand in the congregation [Heb. edah] of
the righteous" (Ps. i, 5); or of a mob of wicked ones: "I have
hated the congregation [Heb. qahal] of evil doers" (Ps. xxvi, 5);
and even of the great assemblage of the dead: "The man that --
[etc.], shall remain in the congregation [Heb. qahal] of the dead"
(Prov. xxi, 16); all these various senses being rendered "ecclesia"
in the Greek Septuagint translation.</p>

<p>   Thus no established and permanent organization of disciples of
the Christ is implied by the term ecclesia, even if <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> could
have used the Aramaic equivalent of that Greek term; at most it
would have only meant the small group of Jews which might adopt the
"Kingdom of Heaven" watchword and watchfully wait until the speedy
end of the world and the expected quick consummation of the
proclaimed Kingdom, -- not yet come to be, these 2000 years.</p>

<p>   This only possible meaning is made indisputable by the one
other instance of the use of the Greek word ecclesia attributed to
<ent type='person'>Jesus</ent>, -- and that also by the myth-mongering "<ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Matt</ent>hew</ent>." Here <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent>
is made to lay down some rules for settling the incessant discords
among his peasant believers in the Kingdom: "Moreover, if thy
brother shall trespass against thee ... tell it to the church
[ecclesia] but if he neglect to hear the ecclesial let him be unto
thee as an heathen man and a publican" (<ent type='person'>Matt</ent>. xviii, 15-17); --
that is, kick him like a dog out of your holy company and exclude
him from share in the coming Kingdom. There was, of course, no
organized Christian "Church" in the lifetime of <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent>; he could
only have meant -- (if he said it), that disputes were to be
referred to the others of the little band of Kingdom-watchers, who
should drop the "trespasser" out of their holy group if he proved
recalcitrant and insisted upon the right of his opinion or action.
But <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> never said even this; it is a forged later companion-
piece to the "Rock and <ent type='person'>Keys</ent>" forgery, as is proven by the following
verse 18 -- (a repetition of xvi, 19) -- regarding the "binding and
loosing" powers given to itself by the later forging Church when it
assumed this preposterous prerogative of domination.</p>

<p>   The "On this Rock" forgery of <ent type='person'>Matt</ent>. xvi, says Reinach, "is
obviously an interpolation, made at a period when a church,
separated from the synagogue, already existed. In the parallel
passages in <ent type='person'>Mark</ent> (vii, 27, 32) and in <ent type='person'>Luke</ent> (ix, 18-22), there is
not a word of the primacy of <ent type='person'>Peter</ent>, a detail which <ent type='person'>Mark</ent>, the
disciple of <ent type='person'>Peter</ent>, could hardly have omitted if he had known of it.
The interpolation is posterior to the compilation of <ent type='person'>Luke</ent>'s
gospel." (Orpheus, pp. 224-225.)</p>

<p>   As aptly said by Dr. McCabe; "It [the word ecclesia] had no
meaning whatever as a religious institution until decades after the
death of <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> Christ. In the year 30 A.D. no one on earth would
have known what <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> meant if he had said that he was going to </p>

<p>   Bank of Wisdom
    Box 926, Louisville, KY 40201
    181
.
   FORGERY IN CHRISTIANITY</p>

<p>'found' an ecclesia or church, and that the powers of darkness
would not prevail against it, and so on. It would sound like the
talk of the Mad Hatter in Alice in Wonderland." (The Story of
Religious Controversy, p. 294.) Indeed, it may be remarked, it is
the "powers of darkness" of mind which have so far prevailed to
perpetuate this fraud; the powers of the light of reason are
hastening to its final overthrow.</p>

<p>   <ent type='person'>PETER</ent>-ROCK-CHURCH" DENIED AB SILIENCIO</p>

<p>   "<ent type='person'>Luke</ent>" was not present when this monumental pronouncement of
the "Rock and <ent type='person'>Keys</ent>" was allegedly made; <ent type='person'>Peter</ent> may have forgotten to
tell him of it, or "<ent type='person'>Luke</ent>" may have forgotten that <ent type='person'>Peter</ent> told him.
And <ent type='person'>Peter</ent> may have forgotten to tell of it and of his peerless
"primacy" to his own "companion" and "interpreter" <ent type='person'>Mark</ent>, or <ent type='person'>Mark</ent>
may have forgotten that <ent type='person'>Peter</ent> told him, and thus have failed to
record so momentous an event. But <ent type='person'>John</ent>, the "<ent type='person'>Bel</ent>oved Disciple" was
right there, with <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Matt</ent>hew</ent>, himself, one of the speakers and hearers
in the historic colloquy, -- and <ent type='person'>John</ent> totally ignores it. The
silence of all three discredits and repudiates it. Moreover, and
most significantly, <ent type='person'>Peter</ent> himself, in his two alleged <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Epistle</ent>s</ent>, has
not a word of his tremendous dignity and importance conferred on
him by his Master; never once does he describe himself in the pride
of priestly humility, "<ent type='person'>Peter</ent>, Servant of the servants of God," or
"Prince of <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Apostle</ent>s</ent>: or even "Bishop of the Church which sojourns
at Rome," or any such to distinguish himself from the common herd
of peasant apostles. <ent type='person'>Peter</ent> must have been very modest, even more so
than his "Successors."</p>

<p>   Furthermore, the official "Acts of the <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Apostle</ent>s</ent>" never once
notes this divinely commissioned "primacy" of <ent type='person'>Peter</ent>; and every
other book of the New Testament utterly ignores it. <ent type='person'>Paul</ent> is said to
have written a sententious "<ent type='person'>Epistle</ent> to the Romans," and to have
written two or three <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Epistle</ent>s</ent> from Rome, where <ent type='person'>Peter</ent> is supposed to
have been, enthroned as divine Vicar of God and Head of the Church
Universal; and yet never a word of this tremendous fact; <ent type='person'>Paul</ent> did
not know it, or ignores it. The "<ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Epistle</ent>s</ent> of <ent type='person'>Paul</ent>," fourteen of
them, and the "Acts," are replete with defiances of <ent type='person'>Paul</ent> to <ent type='person'>Peter</ent>,
-- "I withstood him to his face"; and in all the disputes between
them, over matters of the faith and the fortunes of the new
"Church," not a single one of the <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Apostle</ent>s</ent> rises in his place and
suggests that <ent type='person'>Peter</ent> is Prince and Primate, and that <ent type='person'>Peter</ent>'s view of
the matters was ex-cathedra the voice of God, and he, having
spoken, the matter was settled. <ent type='person'>Paul</ent>, in all his <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Epistle</ent>s</ent>, never
gives a suspicion that he had ever heard, even from <ent type='person'>Peter</ent>, of the
latter's superior authority.</p>

<p>   Thus the admitted principal, if not only "proof" which the
Church urges for its Divine and "Petrine" foundation is found to be
-- like every other Church muniment and credential, a clerical
forgery, a priestly imposture. We shall glance at some other like
examples of the Christian art of "<ent type='person'>Scripture</ent>" falsification.</p>

<p>   Bank of Wisdom
    Box 926, Louisville, KY 40201
    182
.
   FORGERY IN CHRISTIANITY</p>

<p>   "GO, TEACH ALL NATIONS" FORGERY</p>

<p>   Applying Tertullian's test of authenticity, that contradictory
passages betray a later "interpolation," the closing verses, 16-20,
of the last chapter of <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Matt</ent>hew</ent> -- as of <ent type='person'>Mark</ent> 9-20, -- are
themselves late interpolations or forged passages.</p>

<p>   <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Matt</ent>hew</ent> previously quotes <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> as declaring: "I am not sent
but unto the lost sheep of the house of Israel" (xv, 24; x, 6); and
his command to the Twelve: "Go not into the way of the Gentiles.
... but go rather to the lost sheep of the house of Israel" (x, 5,
6). Also <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Matt</ent>hew</ent> (as <ent type='person'>Mark</ent>) has reiterated the assurance of the
immediacy of the end of the world and the "second coming" in glory:
"Ye shall not have gone over the cities of Israel, till the <ent type='person'>Son</ent> of
Man be come." (Mt. x, 23; cf. x, 7; xxvi, 28, 34, passim.) So that
neither in reason nor in truthful statement could it be possible
for <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> to have met the Eleven a few days after his resurrection,
in Galilee, and commanded them in this wonderful language: "Go ye
therefore, and teach all nations, baptizing them in the name of the
Father, and of the <ent type='person'>Son</ent>, and of the Holy Ghost: ... and, lo, I am
with you always, even unto the end of the world" -- which he had
just, and repeatedly, averred should happen in the life-time of his
hearers and before they could preach even to the Jews of little
Palestine. (Mt. xxviii, 18, 20; cf. Mk. xvi, 15-16.) This "command"
could only have been "interpolated" into the forged ending of
<ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Matt</ent>hew</ent> and <ent type='person'>Mark</ent> long after the original form of the tradition of
<ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> had been first written, and when the "second coming" in the
"Kingdom of God" and the immediate "end of the world" had become
impossible of further credit by lapse of long years of time and
disappointed expectation. It could also only have been written
after the gospel of the "Kingdom" for the Jews had failed, and the
apostles had "turned to the Gentiles," which was not, even on the
face of <ent type='person'>Scripture</ent>, until after the so-called "Council of
Jerusalem," when the Jewish apostles, after bitter quarrel with the
interloper <ent type='person'>Paul</ent>, had recognized <ent type='person'>Paul</ent>'s pretended "revelation" of
mission to the Gentiles and had parcelled out the propaganda work,
<ent type='person'>Paul</ent> to the uncircumcised Gentiles, all the others, <ent type='person'>Peter</ent> included,
to "the circumcision" only; though the entire story of the Council
is itself a contradictory fabrication, as demonstrated by EB. (i,
916, et seq.)</p>

<p>   ACTS BELIES THE "GO, TEACH ALL NATIONS" FORGERY</p>

<p>   Culminating proof that <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> Christ never uttered this
command, to "Go, teach all nations," of <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Matt</ent>hew</ent> and <ent type='person'>Mark</ent>, and that
it is a forgery long after interpolated into the original forged
texts, is found in the positive "history" of the inspiredly forged
Acts of the <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Apostle</ent>s</ent>, in Holy Writ itself. If <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> Christ, just
arisen from the dead, had given that ringing and positive command
to <ent type='person'>Peter</ent> and the Eleven, utterly impossible would it have been for
the remarkable "history" recorded in Acts to have occurred. Acts,
too, disproves the assertion of <ent type='person'>Mark</ent> that, straightway, after the
command was given to the Eleven, "they went forth, and preached
everywhere" (Mk. xvi, 20), -- that is, to all nations thereabouts,
the <ent type='person'>Pagan</ent> Gentiles. A further contradiction may he noted: <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Matt</ent>hew</ent>
says that the command was given to the Eleven in Galilee, on "a
mountain where <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> had appointed them" (Mt. xxviii, 16-19), -- </p>

<p>   Bank of Wisdom
    Box 926, Louisville, KY 40201
    183
.
   FORGERY IN CHRISTIANITY</p>

<p>and some days after the resurrection; whereas <ent type='person'>Mark</ent> records that the
command was given to the Eleven "as they sat at meat," evidently in
a house in Jerusalem, through the roof of which <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> immediately
afterwards ascended into heaven (Mk. xvi, 14-19); after which they
immediately "went forth, and preached everywhere" (verse 20). But
they did not, as the silence of the other two <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s, and the
positive evidence of Acts and several of the <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Epistle</ent>s</ent>, proves;
together with the promised disproof of the "Go, teach all nations"
command, for preaching the Kingdom to the Gentile <ent type='person'>Pagan</ent>s, now to be
produced.</p>

<p>   <ent type='person'>Cornelius</ent>, the leader of the Italian Band at Coesarea, a Roman
Gentile <ent type='person'>Pagan</ent>, had a "revelation" that he should go to <ent type='person'>Joppa</ent> to
find <ent type='person'>Peter</ent>, evidently with a view to "conversion" and admission
into the new all-Jewish sect. A companion vision in a trance was
awarded to <ent type='person'>Peter</ent>, seemingly to prepare him for the novel notion of
community with Gentiles; though "<ent type='person'>Peter</ent> doubted in himself what this
vision which he had seen should mean"; but at this juncture the
messengers came from <ent type='person'>Cornelius</ent>, and related to <ent type='person'>Peter</ent> the vision of
<ent type='person'>Cornelius</ent>, and his request that <ent type='person'>Peter</ent> come to see him. Evidently,
<ent type='person'>Peter</ent> had never heard of the Master's command alleged to have been
given by <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> to <ent type='person'>Peter</ent> himself, and the others: "Go, teach all
nations" of the uncircumcised, for he said to the messengers: "Ye
know how it is an unlawful thing for a man that is a Jew to keep
company, or come unto one of another nation"; but recalling the
vision from which he had just awaked, be added: "but God hath
showed me" that it was permissible now to deal with "one of another
nation." So, <ent type='person'>Peter</ent> went along to <ent type='person'>Cornelius</ent>, and he asked "For what
intent ye have sent for me?" <ent type='person'>Cornelius</ent> repeated the vision, and
said, "Now we are all here present before God, to hear all things
that are commanded thee by God." At this, <ent type='person'>Peter</ent> was evidently
greatly surprised, and "opened his mouth, and replied; Of a truth
I perceive that God is no respecter of persons: But that in every
nation he that feareth him, and worketh righteousness, is accepted
with him." Thus clearly <ent type='person'>Peter</ent> had never heard his <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> command:
"Go, teach all nations"; it required this new "revelation" -- some
years later -- for him to tardily and finally "perceive" that God
accepted even "one of another nation." Clearer yet is this, that up
to this time salvation is of the Jews" only, by <ent type='person'>Peter</ent>'s next words:
"The word which God sent unto the children of Israel ... which was
published throughout Judaea -- [not to "all nations"], and began in
Galilee, after the baptism which <ent type='person'>John</ent> preached -- [not baptism "in
the name" of the Trinity]. ... And be [<ent type='person'>Jesus</ent>] commanded us to
preach unto all the people" -- of the children of Israel. And now
for proof positive: <ent type='person'>Peter</ent> was now "showed" the new dispensation: a
visitation of the Holy Ghost came upon the <ent type='person'>Pagan</ent>s present, who
thereupon all "spake with tongues," to the great amazement of <ent type='person'>Peter</ent>
and his Jewish companions: "They of the circumcision which believed
were astonished, as many as came with <ent type='person'>Peter</ent>, because that on the
Gentiles was also poured out the gift of the Holy Ghost," which had
been promised only to all believing Jews. Ignorant thus of the
Christ's preascension command to him and the Eleven, to teach all
men, but now convinced that "one of another nation" was acceptable
with God, and should be baptized, <ent type='person'>Peter</ent> yielded, and argued for his
companions to consent: "Then answered <ent type='person'>Peter</ent>, Can any man forbid
water, that these should not be baptized, which have received the
Holy Ghost as well as we? And he commanded them to be baptized in </p>

<p>   Bank of Wisdom
    Box 926, Louisville, KY 40201
    184
.
   FORGERY IN CHRISTIANITY</p>

<p>the name of the Lord" (Acts x), -- not in the name of the Trinity,
as <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Matt</ent>hew</ent> alleges that <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> himself had commanded <ent type='person'>Peter</ent> himself
to do. So this bit of <ent type='person'>Scripture</ent> "history" is positive refutation of
the "Go, teach all nations, baptizing them in the name of the
Father, and of the <ent type='person'>Son</ent>, and of the Holy Ghost" forgery.</p>

<p>   And none of the others of the Twelve had ever heard the
command. For immediately that they learned of this flagrant
"heresy" of <ent type='person'>Peter</ent>, "that the Gentiles have also received the word
of God," they were piously outraged and furious against <ent type='person'>Peter</ent>: "And
when <ent type='person'>Peter</ent> had come up to Jerusalem, they that were of the
circumcision contended with him, Saying, Thou wentest in to men
uncircumcised, and didst eat with them." <ent type='person'>Peter</ent> put up a long
argument in defense, urging the "revelation" to <ent type='person'>Cornelius</ent> and his
own trance vision, quoted the gospels of <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Matt</ent>hew</ent> and <ent type='person'>John</ent> -- (not
yet in existence!), -- and wound up: "<ent type='person'>Forasmuch</ent> then as God gave
them the like gift as he did unto us, ... what am I, that I could
withstand God?" This line of argument pacified the other apostles;
"When they heard these things, they held their peace, and glorified
God, saying, Then hath God also to the Gentiles granted repentance
unto life." (Acts xi.) Perfect proof is this, that the alleged "Go,
teach all nations" command of the Christ to <ent type='person'>Peter</ent> and the other
apostles, is a falsification, a late forgery into <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Matt</ent>hew</ent> and <ent type='person'>Mark</ent>:
for if <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> had so commanded these same apostles, the special
revelations would not have been necessary; <ent type='person'>Peter</ent>'s doubt and
hesitation, and the row of the others with <ent type='person'>Peter</ent> for baptizing
<ent type='person'>Cornelius</ent> and his Band could not have occurred, would have been
impossible and absurd; as would have been the apostolic rows of the
"Council of Jerusalem," recorded in Acts xv and belied by <ent type='person'>Paul</ent> in
Galatians ii, as is made evident in EB. (i, 916.)</p>

<p>   This incontrovertible fact, that <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> Christ never uttered
that command, "Go, teach all nations," and that the texts so
reciting are later forgeries to serve the Gentilic propaganda of
the Faith after the Jews had rejected it, -- is confessed by CE. in
these destructive words: "The Kingdom of God had special reference
to Jewish beliefs. ... A still further expansion resulted from the
revelation directing St. <ent type='person'>Peter</ent> to admit to baptism <ent type='person'>Cornelius</ent>, a
devout Gentile." (CE. iii, 747.) If <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> Christ, preaching the
exclusive Jewish Kingdom, had revised and reversed his God-ordained
program, and had commanded "Go, teach all nations, baptizing them,"
the "expansion" would have resulted then and there from the command
itself, -- not from the "revelation" and apostolic row some years
later, which would have been unnecessary and supererogatory -- as
it was unseemly. Thus another pious lie and forgery is exposed and
confessed.</p>

<p>   Even more plain and comprehensive are the words of this same
divine forged command of the Christ, as recorded by <ent type='person'>Mark</ent>: "Go ye
into all the world, and preach the gospel to every creature. And he
that believeth and is baptized shall be saved; but he that
believeth not shall be damned." (Mk. xvi, 15-16.) It should be a
relief to many pious Hell-fearing Christians to know that their
Christ did not utter these damning words, and that they may
disbelieve with entire impunity; that they are priestly forgeries
to frighten credulous persons into belief and submission to
priestcraft. The proofs of this from the Bible itself we see 
confirmed by clerical admissions under compulsion from exposure of
the fraud.
   Bank of Wisdom
    Box 926, Louisville, KY 40201
    185
.
   FORGERY IN CHRISTIANITY</p>

<p>   Thus this whole section, says Reinach, is a "late addition" to
<ent type='person'>Mark</ent>, ."and is not found in the best manuscripts." (Orpheus, p.
221.) We have seen that CE. includes this section among those
rejected as spurious up to the time that the Holy Ghost belatedly
vouched for it at the Council of Trent in 1546, putting the seal of
divine truth upon this lie. Both these parallel but exceedingly
contradictory closing sections of <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Matt</ent>hew</ent> and <ent type='person'>Mark</ent>, are spurious
additions made after the "end of the world" and "second coming"
predictions had notoriously failed, in order to give pretended
divine sanction to the "turning to the Gentiles," after the Jews,
to whom alone the Christ was sent and had expressly and repeatedly
limited his mission, had rejected his claim to be Messiah.</p>

<p>   The Gentile Church of Christ has therefore no divine sanction;
was never contemplated nor created by <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> Christ. The Christian
Church is thus founded on a forgery of pretended words of the
pretended Christ. This proposition is of such immense significance
and importance, that I array here the admissions of the forgery, in
addition to the demonstration of its falsity above given. The
virtual admissions of CE. totally destroy the authenticity of the
entire spurious section, <ent type='person'>Mark</ent> xvi, 9-20, together with the
correlated passages of the equally spurious "<ent type='person'>Matt</ent>hean addition,"
copied from <ent type='person'>Mark</ent>, with embellishments into <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Matt</ent>hew</ent>.</p>

<p>    THE FORGED GOSPEL ENDINGS</p>

<p>   "The conclusion of <ent type='person'>Mark</ent> (xvi, 9-20) is admittedly not genuine.
Still less can the shorter conclusion lay claim to genuineness. ...
Almost the entire section is a compilation, partly even from the
fourth gospel and Acts." (EB. ii, 1880; 1767, n. 3; 1781, and n. 1,
on "the evidence of its spuriousness.") "The longer form ... has
against it the testimony of the two oldest Uncial MSS. (Siniatic
and Vatican) and one of the two earliest of the Syriac Versions
(Siniatic Syriac), all of which close the chapter at verse 8. In
addition to this, is the very significant silence of Patristic
literature as to anything following verse 8." (New Standard Bible
Dictionary, p. 551.) The acute and careful critical reasonings and
evidences upon which the foregoing conclusions are based, I have
omitted from these extracts, to present them in full in the
following ample review from CE., which, "reasoning in chains"
fettered upon it by the Trentine Decree, yet fully establishes the
impeaching facts and substantially confesses the forgery into
"<ent type='person'>Mark</ent>," while "saving its face" for the "inspiration" of the
forgery by clerical assumption of "some other inspired pen" as the
source of the text, which makes it "just as good" as any other,
when invested with the sanctity of the sanction of the Council of
Trent. Says CE.:</p>

<p>  "But the great textual problem of the <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent> (<ent type='person'>Mark</ent>)
   concerns the genuineness of the last twelve verses. Three
   conclusions of the <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent> are known: the long: conclusion, as
   in our Bibles, containing verses 9-20, the short one ending
   with verse 8, and an intermediate form [described]. ... Now
   this third form way be dismissed at once -- [as an admitted
   Bible forgery]. No scholar regards this intermediate
   conclusion as having any title to acceptance.</p>

<p>   Bank of Wisdom
    Box 926, Louisville, KY 40201
    186
.
   FORGERY IN CHRISTIANITY</p>

<p>  "We may pass on, then, to consider how the case stands
   between the long conclusion and the short, i.e. between
   accepting xvi, 9-20, as a genuine portion of the original
   <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>, or making the original end with xvi, 8. <ent type='person'>Eusebius</ent> ...
   pointing out that the passage in <ent type='person'>Mark</ent> beginning with verse 9
   is not contained in all the MSS. of the <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>. The historian
   then goes on himself to say that in nearly all the MSS. of
   <ent type='person'>Mark</ent>, at least in the accurate ones, the <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent> ends with xvi,
   8. ... St. <ent type='person'>Jerome</ent> also says in one place that the passage was
   wanting in nearly all Greek MSS. ... As we know, he
   incorporated it in the <ent type='person'>Vulgate</ent>. ... If we add to this that the
   <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent> ends with xvi, 8, in the two oldest Greek MSS. -- [
   Siniatic and Vatican] -- [also in the Siniatic Syriac, some
   Ethiopic, Armenian, and other MSS.] indicate doubt as to
   whether the true ending is at verse 8 or verse 20. (p. 678.)
   . . .</p>

<p>  "Much has been made of the silence of some of the third
   and fourth century <ent type='person'>Fathers</ent>, their silence being interpreted to
   mean that they either did not know the passage or rejected it.
   Thus Tertullian, SS. Cyprian, Athanasius, Basil the Great,
   Gregory of <ent type='person'>Nazianzus</ent>, and <ent type='person'>Cyril of Alexandria</ent>.</p>

<p>  "When we turn to the internal evidence, the number, and
   still more the character, of the peculiarities is certainly
   striking [citing many instances from the Greek text]. ... But,
   even when this is said, the cumulative force of the evidence
   against the Marcan origin of the passage is considerable. (p.
   678.) ... The combination of so many peculiar features, not
   only of vocabulary, but of matter and construction, leaves
   room for doubt as to the Marcan authorship of the verses. (p.
   679.) ...</p>

<p>   "Whatever the fact be, it is not at all certain that <ent type='person'>Mark</ent> did
not write the disputed verses. It may be that he did not; that they
are from the pen of some other inspired writer [!], and were
appended to the <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent> in the first century or the beginning of the
second. ... Catholics are not bound to hold that the verses were
written by St. <ent type='person'>Mark</ent>. But they are canonical <ent type='person'>Scripture</ent>, for the
Council of Trent (Sess. IV), in defining that all parts of the
Sacred Books are to be received as sacred and canonical, had
especially in view the disputed parts of the <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s, of which this
conclusion of <ent type='person'>Mark</ent> is one. Hence, whoever wrote the verses, they
are inspired, and must be received as such by every Catholic." (CE.
ix, 677, 678, 679.)</p>

<p>   The New Commentary on the Holy <ent type='person'>Scripture</ent> has a special section
entitled "The Ending of St. <ent type='person'>Mark</ent>'s <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>," in which it reviews the
evidences in much the same manner as CE., with additional new and
able criticism; it thus concludes, -- not being fettered by the
dogmatic decision of the Council of Trent, which CE. so clerically
yields to in the letter but evades in the spirit:</p>

<p>  "It is practically certain that neither <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Matt</ent>hew</ent> nor <ent type='person'>Luke</ent>
   found it in their copies of <ent type='person'>Mark</ent> [from which they copied in
   making up the gospels under those names: see pp. 33, 45). ...
   The Last Twelve Verses are constructed as an independent </p>

<p>   Bank of Wisdom
    Box 926, Louisville, KY 40201
    187
.
   FORGERY IN CHRISTIANITY</p>

<p>   summary with total neglect of the contents of xvi, 1-8. ... It
   is as certain as anything can be in the domain of criticism
   that the Longer Ending did not come from the pen of the
   evangelist <ent type='person'>Mark</ent>. ... We conclude that it is certain that the
   Longer Ending is no part of the <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>." (New Commentary, Pt.
   III, pp. 122, 123.)</p>

<p>   More shaming proofs and confessions of forgery of pretended
words of the Christ there could not be, than of this falsified
command to preach a forged <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent> to the credulous dupes of
<ent type='person'>Pagan</ent>ism. Gentile Christianity collapses upon its forged
foundations.</p>

<p>    THE BAPTISMAL FORGERY</p>

<p>   The contradictory "baptismal formulas," the simple "in the
name of the Lord" of <ent type='person'>Peter</ent> in Acts, and the elaborated forgery of
<ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Matt</ent>hew</ent>, "in the name of the Father, and of the <ent type='person'>Son</ent>, and of the
Holy Ghost," are sufficiently branded with falsity in the preceding
paragraphs, and may be dismissed without further notice. This
"Trinitarian Formula" is most palpably a late forgery, never
uttered by <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> Christ; for the Holy "Trinity" was not itself
officially invented until the Council of Constantinople, in 381
A.D. Admittedly, "of all revealed truths this is the most
impenetrable to reason"; it is therefore called a "mystery." (CE.
xv, 52.) Of this Baptism-formula of <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Matt</ent>hew</ent>, the ex-priest scholar,
McCabe, says: "It was fraudulently added to the gospel when the
priesthood was created." (LBB. 1121, p. 4.) Bishop <ent type='person'>Gore</ent>'s English
Divines thus cautiously confess the fraud: "<ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Matt</ent>hew</ent>'s witness to
the teaching of the risen Lord in these verses is widely rejected
on two grounds. The witness of Acts makes it almost certain that
baptism at first was into the name of <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> Christ, and not
formally into the name of the Blessed Trinity. ... It is quite
likely that <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Matt</ent>hew</ent> here expresses our Lord's teaching in language
which the Lord Himself did not actually use." (New Comm., Pt. III,
p. 204; ef. EB. i, 474.) Another blasting priestly fraud of
"<ent type='person'>Scripture</ent>" forgery is thus exposed and confessed!</p>

<p>    A <ent type='person'>MEDLEY</ent> OF FORGERIES</p>

<p>   After the foregoing colossal forgeries within the originally
forged <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>s of <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> Christ, there yet remain many other
viciously dishonest falsifications of text. A little trinity of
them only will be noted.</p>

<p>   THE "WOMAN IN ADULTERY" FORGERY</p>

<p>   The CE. has admitted that the so-called pericope adulterae,
was regarded as spurious until the Council of Trent, in 1546,
declared it divine truth; but Reinach says: "The episode of <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent>
and the woman taken in adultery, which was inserted in <ent type='person'>John</ent>'s
gospel in the fourth century, was originally in the [apocryphal]
'<ent type='person'>Gospel</ent> according to the Hebrews.'" (Orpheus, p. 235.)</p>

<p>   Bank of Wisdom
    Box 926, Louisville, KY 40201
    188
.
   FORGERY IN CHRISTIANITY</p>

<p>    THE <ent type='person'>JOHN XXI</ent> FORGERY</p>

<p>   The entire chapter xxi of <ent type='person'>John</ent> is likewise a surcharge of 
forgery in that gospel; it may be disposed of with this terse
comment of EB.: "As xx, 30-31 constitutes a formal and solemn
conclusion, xxi is beyond question a later appendix. We may go on
to add that it does not come from the same author with the rest of
the book." (EB. ii, 2543.)</p>

<p>   THE "LORD'S PRAYER" FORGERY</p>

<p>   As may be seen by mere comparison, the "Doxology" at the end
of the Lord's Prayer in <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Matt</ent>hew</ent> (vi, 13): "For thine is the
kingdom, and the power, and the glory, forever. Amen," is an
interpolation into the original text, and is omitted as spurious by
the Revised Version; it is not in the Catholic "True" Version. But,
it may be remarked, the whole of the so-called Lord's Prayer is not
the Lord's at all; it is a late patch-work of pieces out of the Old
Testament, as readily shown by the marginal cross-references, --
just as we have seen that the "<ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Apostle</ent>s</ent> <ent type='person'>Creed</ent>" was said to have
been patched up by inspired lines from each apostle. The Sermon on
the Mount, in which its most used form is found, is a concatenation
of supposed logia or "sayings" of <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent>, drawn out through three
chapters of "<ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Matt</ent>hew</ent>"; it was delivered before "the multitudes"
which surrounded the Master and his disciples, and in the middle of
the fictitious discourse. This is not true, according to "<ent type='person'>Luke</ent>,"
who makes it out a private talk in reply to a question by one of
the Twelve: "And it came to pass, that, as (<ent type='person'>Jesus</ent>) was praying in
a certain place, when he ceased one of his disciples said to him,
Lord, teach us to pray, as <ent type='person'>John</ent> also taught his disciples. And be
said unto them, When ye pray, say, Our Father," etc. (<ent type='person'>Luke</ent> xi, 1-
228 2.) Indeed, the entire "Lord's Prayer" in <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Matt</ent>hew</ent>, copied from
<ent type='person'>Luke</ent> and expanded with considerable new material, is as to such new
matter a forgery, confesses CE.: "Thus it is that the shorter form
of the Lord's Prayer in <ent type='person'>Luke</ent>, xi, 2-4, is in almost all Greek
manuscripts lengthened out in accordance with <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Matt</ent>hew</ent>, vi, 9-13.
Most errors of this kind proceed," etc. (CE. iv, 498.) I shall
quote now the whole of CE.'s paragraph, admitting this and other
"deliberate corruptions" of the New Testament texts, with clerical
apologetic reasons therefor:</p>

<p>  "(b) Errors Wholly or Partly Intentional. -- Deliberate
   corruption of the Sacred Text has always been rather rare,
   Marcion's case being exceptional. Hort (Introduction (1896),
   p. 282) is of the opinion that 'even among the unquestionably
   spurious readings of the New Testament there are no signs of
   deliberate falsification of the text for dogmatic purposes.'
   Nevertheless it is true that the scribe often selects from
   various readings that which favors either his own individual
   opinion or the doctrine that is just then more generally
   accepted. It also happens that, in perfectly good faith, he
   changes passages which seem to him corrupt because he fails to
   understand them, that he adds a word which he deems necessary
   for the elucidation of the meaning, that he substitutes a more
   correct grammatical expression, and that he harmonizes
   parallel passages. Thus it is that the shorter form of the
   Lord's Prayer in <ent type='person'>Luke</ent>, xi, 2-4, is in almost all Greek </p>

<p>   Bank of Wisdom
    Box 926, Louisville, KY 40201
    189
.
   FORGERY IN CHRISTIANITY</p>

<p>   manuscripts lengthened out in accordance with <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Matt</ent>hew</ent>, vi,
   9-13. Most errors of this kind proceed from inserting in the
   text marginal notes which, in the copy to be transcribed, were
   but variants, explanations, parallel passages, simple remarks,
   or perhaps the conjectures of some studious reader. All
   readers have observed the predilection of copyists for the
   most verbose texts and their tendency to complete citations
   that are too brief; hence it is that an interpolation stands
   a far better chance of being perpetuated than an omission."
   (CE. iv, 498.)</p>

<p>   Thus, as to the "Lord's Prayer" in <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Matt</ent>hew</ent>, its "variants"
from <ent type='person'>Luke</ent> are confessed forgeries; every circumstance of the two
origins is in contradiction. Like the whole "Sermon on the Mount,"
the Prayer is a composite of ancient sayings of the <ent type='person'>Scripture</ent>
strung together to form it, as the marginal cross-references show
throughout.</p>

<p>    THE "UNKNOWN <ent type='person'>GOD</ent>" FORGERY</p>

<p>   At this point I may call attention to a notable instance in
Acts of a fraudulent perversion of text; <ent type='person'>Paul</ent>'s use of the
pretended inscription on the statue on Mars' Hill, "To the Unknown
God," on which is based his famous harangue to the Athenians: "Whom
therefore ye ignorantly worship, him declare I unto you." This
omits the truth, for the whole inscription would have been fatal to
his cause. The actual words of the inscription, together with some
uncomplimentary comment on "<ent type='person'>Paul</ent>'s" manipulation of the truth, are
presented by the famous Catholic "Humanist" Erasmus. First he
states the chronic clerical propensity to warp even <ent type='person'>Scripture</ent> to
their deceptive schemes: "In general it is the public charter of
all divines, to mould and bend the sacred oracles till they comply
with their own fancy, spreading them (as Heaven by its Creator)
like a curtain, closing together, or drawing them back as they
please." Then he discloses the dishonest dodge of the great <ent type='person'>Apostle</ent>
of Persecution: "Indeed, St. <ent type='person'>Paul</ent> minces and mangles some citations
which he makes use of, and seems to wrest them to a different sense
from that for which they were first intended, as is confessed by
the great linguist St. <ent type='person'>Jerome</ent>. Thus when that apostle saw at Athens
the inscription of an altar, he draws from it an argument for the
proof of the Christian religion; but leaving out a great part of
the sentence, which perhaps if fully recited might have prejudiced
his cause, he mentions only the last two words, viz., 'To the
Unknown God'; and this, too, not without alteration, for the whole
inscription runs thus: 'TO THE <ent type='person'>GOD</ent>S OF ASIA, EUROPE, AND AFRICA, TO
ALL FOREIGN AND UNKNOWN <ent type='person'>GOD</ent>S'"! (Erasmus, The Praise of Folly, p.
292.) That the original Greek text of Acts used the plural "gods"
is shown by the marginal note to Acts xvii, 23, in the King <ent type='person'>James</ent>
Version. From this dreary, exposure of "<ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>" forgeries we pass
to the forged "<ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Epistle</ent>s</ent> of the <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Apostle</ent>s</ent>."</p>

<p>    THE FORGED EPISTLES, ETC.</p>

<p>   There are 21 so-called <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Epistle</ent>s</ent> or Letters found in the New
Testament under the names of five different "apostles" of <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent>
Christ. Making a significant reservation which seems to question
the plenary inspiration of the Council of Trent, "There are," says </p>

<p>   Bank of Wisdom
    Box 926, Louisville, KY 40201
    190
.
   FORGERY IN CHRISTIANITY</p>

<p>CE., "thirteen <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Epistle</ent>s</ent> of St. <ent type='person'>Paul</ent>, and perhaps fourteen, if, with
the Council of Trent, we consider him the author of the <ent type='person'>Epistle</ent> to
the Hebrews." (CE. xiv, 530.) If <ent type='person'>Paul</ent>, the "apostle of the
Gentiles," didn't write the Letter to the Hebrews, some Church
Father must have forged it in his name. This was admitted by the
early <ent type='person'>Fathers</ent>: "Tertullian ascribed it to <ent type='person'>Barnabas</ent>, and Origen
confessed that the author was not known." (Reinach, Orpheus, p.
235; CE. xiv, 525; New Comm. Pt. III, p. 596.) "The <ent type='person'>Epistle</ent> to the
Hebrews," says EB., "had already been excluded from the group [of
then supposed <ent type='person'>Paul</ent>ine <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Epistle</ent>s</ent>] by Carlstadt (1520), and among
those who followed him in this were Luther, Calvin, Grotius, etc."
(EB. iii, 3605.) So CE.'s cautious clerical reservation is
justified, and the forgery of Hebrews in the name of <ent type='person'>Paul</ent> may be
taken as established, the inspired Council of Trent to the contrary
notwithstanding.</p>

<p>   But the entire "<ent type='person'>Paul</ent>ine group" is in the same forged class
with Hebrews, says EB. after exhaustive consideration of the
proofs, internal and external:</p>

<p>  "With respect to the canonical <ent type='person'>Paul</ent>ine <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Epistle</ent>s</ent>, ...
   there are none of them by <ent type='person'>Paul</ent>; neither fourteen, nor
   thirteen, nor nine or eight, nor yet even the four so long
   'universally' regarded as unassailable. They are all, without
   distinction, pseudographia [false-writings, forgeries]; -- [it
   adds, with a typical clerical striving after saving something
   from the wreckage] this, of course, not implying the least
   depreciation of their contents. ... The group ... bears
   obvious marks of a certain unity -- of having originated in
   one circle, at one time, in one environment; but not of unity
   of authorship." (EB. iii, 3625, 3626.) They are thus all
   uninspired anonymous church forgeries for Christ's sweet sake!</p>

<p>   Besides the so-called <ent type='person'>Paul</ent>ine <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Epistle</ent>s</ent>, another group, i.e.
those attributed to <ent type='person'>Peter</ent>, <ent type='person'>John</ent>, Jude and <ent type='person'>James</ent>, is known as
"Catholic <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Epistle</ent>s</ent>," so called because addressed to the Church at
large; "not one of them is authentic." (Reinach, Orpheus, p. 239;
cf. EB., under the various titles.) A third small group, Titus and
2 <ent type='person'>Timothy</ent>, are called Pastoral <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Epistle</ent>s</ent>" because they are addressed
to pastors of churches. These, with Acts and the Book of
<ent type='person'>Revelation</ent>, complete the tale of the Old-Christian Literature
finally approved, in 1546, by the Council of Trent as divinely
inspired, along with the inspired nonsense of <ent type='person'>Tobias</ent>, Judith, <ent type='person'>Bel</ent>
and the Dragon, and like late Hebrew pious forgeries. With respect
to the Apocalypse <ent type='person'>Revelation</ent>, attributed to the <ent type='person'>Apostle</ent> <ent type='person'>John</ent>, this
has long been held to be impossible; nor is <ent type='person'>Revelation</ent> by the same
writer as the Fourth <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent> falsely attributed to <ent type='person'>John</ent>, as we have
seen. The results of ancient patristic denials and of modern
critical scholarship are thus summed up: "<ent type='person'>John</ent> ... is not the
author of the Fourth <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>; so, in like manner, in the Apocalypse
we may have here and there a passage that may be traced to him, but
the book as a whole is not from his pen. <ent type='person'>Gospel</ent>, <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Epistle</ent>s</ent>, and
Apocalypse all come from the same school." (EB. i, 199.) "The
author of <ent type='person'>Revelation</ent> calls himself <ent type='person'>John</ent> the <ent type='person'>Apostle</ent>. As he was not
<ent type='person'>John</ent> the <ent type='person'>Apostle</ent>, who died perhaps in Palestine about 66, he was a
forger." (Orpheus p. 240.) The same can truly be said as to all the
others.</p>

<p>   Bank of Wisdom
    Box 926, Louisville, KY 40201
    191
.
   FORGERY IN CHRISTIANITY</p>

<p>   It is impossible here to review the criticism of the twenty-
three booklets individually. The comment of EB. on the <ent type='person'>Epistle</ent> to
the <ent type='person'>Philippi</ent>ans, as not written by <ent type='person'>Paul</ent>, is, fairly applicable to
them all: "What finally puts an end to all doubt is the presence of
unmistakable traces of the conditions of a later period. ... More
particularly, everything that points to a considerably advanced
stage in the development of doctrine." (EB. iii, 3709.) This
principle of criticism will be admitted by anyone; we have read it
from CE. as "universally admitted" to wit: "A fundamental one is
that a literary work always betrays the imprint of the age and
environment in which it was produced." (CE. iv, 492.) <ent type='person'>Paul</ent> and
<ent type='person'>Peter</ent> are reputed to have died together in Rome under <ent type='person'>Nero</ent>, in 64
(67) A.D. We have shown the impossibility of the existence of "New
Testament" writings, and of a "church" during the first several
generations which daily expected the end of the world and the
sudden second coming of the Christ to set up the supernatural
Kingdom of God, among, of, and for Jews only. More especially
impassible is it, that a Catholic or "universal" Church among the
far-scattered cities and nations of the Gentiles should have
existed even in embryo within the scant, say 35 years between the
reputed death of <ent type='person'>Jesus</ent> about 30 A.D. and the deaths of <ent type='person'>Paul</ent> and
<ent type='person'>Peter</ent> in 64 (67) A.D. Most impossible would it have been for such
Gentile Church then to have had the intricate hierarchical
organization of Bishops, presbyters, deacons, priests, and
"damnable heresies," portrayed as actually existing and in active
function, by these apocryphal <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Epistle</ent>s</ent>. They are self-evidently the
product of an elaborately organized church, -- just as they are
more elaborately laid out and their several jurisdictions and
functions defined in the admittedly forged Apostolic Constitutions
and Canons, forged in the names of the apostles in the following
centuries. Nothing from ancient times can be or is more positively
proven false and forged than every book and text of the New
Testament, attributed to apostles. Who can now deny this?</p>

<p>    THE "EPISTLE OF <ent type='person'>PETER</ent>" FORGERIES</p>

<p>   Owing to the peculiar importance attributed to them by the
Church, as among the most unquestionable of its "proofs" of
authentic divine foundation and sanction, the so-called <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Epistle</ent>s</ent> I
and II of <ent type='person'>Peter</ent> call for a few words of special refutation. These
two <ent type='person'>Peter</ent> books were, in truth, questioned and denied from the
early days. Bishop <ent type='person'>Eusebius</ent>, the first Church Historian, (HE. III,
iii, 25), says of II <ent type='person'>Peter</ent> that it was "controverted and not
admitted into the canon"; and, says EB., "The tardy recognition of
II <ent type='person'>Peter</ent> in the early church supports the judgment of the critical
school as to its un-apostolic origin." (EB. iii, 3684.)</p>

<p>   The critical considerations which lead to the rejection of
both <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Epistle</ent>s</ent> as "not Petrine" and "not of the apostolic age," may
be very briefly summarized: That I <ent type='person'>Peter</ent> is addressed to the
"Sojourners of the Dispersion" in Asia Minor, which was <ent type='person'>Paul</ent>'s
reserved territory. "There is no trace of the questions mooted in
the apostolic age. ... The historical conditions and circumstances
implied in the <ent type='person'>Epistle</ent> indicate, moreover, a time far beyond the
probable duration of <ent type='person'>Peter</ent>'s life. ... The history of the spread of
Christianity imperatively demands for I <ent type='person'>Peter</ent> a later date than 64
A.D.," the alleged date of <ent type='person'>Peter</ent>'s death. The second <ent type='person'>Epistle</ent>, II </p>

<p>   Bank of Wisdom
    Box 926, Louisville, KY 40201
    192
.
   FORGERY IN CHRISTIANITY</p>

<p><ent type='person'>Peter</ent>, is vaguely addressed to Christians in general (i, 1), yet in
iii, 1, the writer inconsistently assumes that the First <ent type='person'>Epistle</ent>
was addressed to the same readers; and he tells them (i, 6 and iii,
15) that they had already received instructions from him
(ostensibly <ent type='person'>Peter</ent>), and also letters from <ent type='person'>Paul</ent>. "The relation of II
<ent type='person'>Peter</ent> to I <ent type='person'>Peter</ent> renders a common authorship extremely doubtful.
The name and title of the author are different. ... The style of
the two epistles is different. ... It is late and un-apostolic."
(EB. <ent type='person'>Peter</ent>, <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Epistle</ent>s</ent> of, iii, 3678-3685; cf. New Comm. Pt. III, pp.
639, 653, 654.) "The genuineness of I <ent type='person'>Peter</ent> cannot be maintained.
Most probably it was not written before 112 A.D." (EB. 2940.) The
two letters of <ent type='person'>Peter</ent> are Graeco-Egyptian forgeries." (Reinach,
Orpheus, p. 240.) The Church pretense that I <ent type='person'>Peter</ent> was written at
Rome ("Babylon") will be judged in its more appropriate place. In
the early list of supposedly apostolic Books drawn up by Tertullian
as accepted and read in the several Churches, while he "cites the
Book of <ent type='person'>Enoch</ent> as inspired, ... also recognizes IV Esdras, and the
<ent type='person'>Sibyl</ent>, ... he does not know <ent type='person'>James</ent> and II <ent type='person'>Peter</ent>. ... He attributes
Hebrews to St. <ent type='person'>Barnabas</ent>." (CE. xiv, 525.) Bishop <ent type='person'>Dionysius</ent>
complains that his own writings "had been falsified by the apostles
of the devil; no wonder, he adds, 'that the <ent type='person'>Scripture</ent>s were
falsified by such persons.'" (CE. v, 10.) The "<ent type='person'>Peter</ent>" Books are
other instances.</p>

<p>   THE "<ent type='person'>GOD</ent> MANIFEST" FORGERY</p>

<p>   In the King <ent type='person'>James</ent> or "Authorized" Version we read: "Great is
the mystery of Godliness: God was manifest in the flesh," etc. (1
Tim. iii, 16.) In the "Revised Version" this "God manifest" forged
interpolation is shamed out of the text, which there honestly
reads: "He who was manifested in the flesh," etc. Thus the great
"mystery of godliness," premised in the text, is no longer a
mystery; and the fraudulent insertion into the text by some over-
zealous Christian forger, seeking to bolster up an "apostolic"
pedigree for the later "tradition" of the divinity of the Christ,
is confessed. This pious "interpolation" was probably made at the
time and by the same holy hands which forged the "Virgin-birth"
interpolations into "<ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Matt</ent>hew</ent>" and "<ent type='person'>Luke</ent>." This passage is but one
of a whole series of "Spurious Passages in the New Testament,"
catalogued by <ent type='person'>Taylor</ent>, in the appendix to his <ent type='person'>Diegesis</ent>, (p. 421).
This pious fraud was first detected and exposed by Sir Isaac
Newton.</p>

<p>   THE "THREE HEAVENLY WITNESSES" FORGERY</p>

<p>   Bishop <ent type='person'>Clement</ent> of Alexandria, writing around 200 A.D., thus
quotes a comparatively trivial and innocuous passage from the
forged First <ent type='person'>Epistle</ent> of St. <ent type='person'>John</ent> (v, 7), -- which, through
fraudulent tampering later became one of the "chief stones of the
corner" of the Holy Church that the <ent type='person'>Fathers</ent> built: "<ent type='person'>John</ent> says: 'For
there are three that bear witness, the spirit, and the water, and
the blood: and these three are one.'" (Clem. Alex., Fragment from
Cassiodorus, ch. iii; ANF. iii, 576.) This is self-evidently the
original text of this now famous, or infamous, passage. Turning now
to the Word of God as found in the "Authorized" Protestant and in
the Chaloner-Douay Version of the Catholic <ent type='person'>Vulgate</ent>, we read with
wonder:</p>

<p>   Bank of Wisdom
    Box 926, Louisville, KY 40201
    193
.
   FORGERY IN CHRISTIANITY</p>

<p>  "7. For there are three that bear record in heaven, the
   Father, the Word, and the Holy Ghost: and these three are one.
  "8. And there are three that bear witness in earth, the
   spirit, and the water, and the blood: and these three agree in
   one." (I <ent type='person'>John</ent>, v, 7, 8.)</p>

<p>   Let us now turn to the same text, or what is left of it, in
the Revised Version. Here we read, with more wonder (if we do not
know the story of pious fraud behind it), what seems to be a
garbled text:</p>

<p>  "8. For there are three who bear witness, the Spirit, and
   the water, and the blood: and the three agree in one."</p>

<p>   Erasmus first detected the fraud and omitted the forged verse
in his edition of the Greek Testament in 1516. (New Comm. Pt. III,
p. 718-19.) This verse 7, bluntly speaking, is a forgery: "It had
been wilfully and wickedly interpolated, to sustain the Trinitarian
doctrine; it has been entirely omitted by the <ent type='person'>Revisers</ent> of the New
Testament." (Roberts, Companion to the Revised Versions p. 72.)
"This memorable text," says <ent type='person'>Gibbon</ent>, "is condemned by the silence of
the <ent type='person'>Fathers</ent>, ancient versions, and authentic manuscripts, of all
the manuscripts now extant, above four score in number, some of
which are more than 1200 years old." (Ch. xxvii, p. 598.) Speaking
of this and another, Reinach says: "One of these forgeries (I <ent type='person'>John</ent>
v, 7) was subjected to interpolation of a later date. ... If these
two verses were Authentic, they would be an affirmation of the
doctrine of the Trinity, at a time when the gospels, and Acts and
St. <ent type='person'>Paul</ent> ignore it. It was first pointed out in 1516 that these
verses were an interpolation, for they do not appear in the best
manuscripts down to the fifteenth century. The Roman Church refused
to bow to the evidence. ... The Congregation of the Index, on
January 13, 1897, with the approbation of <ent type='person'>Leo XIII</ent>, forbade any
question of the authenticity of the text relating to the 'Three
Heavenly Witnesses.' It showed in this instance a wilful ignorance
to which St. Gregory's rebuke is specially applicable: "God does
not need our lies."' (Orpheus, p. 239.) But His Church does; for
without them it would not be; and without the forged "Three
Heavenly Witnesses," and the forged "Baptism Formula" of <ent type='person'><ent type='person'>Matt</ent>hew</ent>
(xxviii, 19), there would be not a word in the entire New Testament
hinting the existence of the Three-in-One God of Christianity. The
Holy Trinity is an unholy Forgery!</p>

<p>   Lest it be thought by some pious but uninformed persons that
the foregoing imputation may be either false or malicious, we shall
let CE. make the confession of shame, with the usual clerical
evasions to "save the face" of Holy Church confronted with this
proven forgery and fraud. From a lengthy and detailed review, under
separate headings, of all the ancient MSS., Greek, Syriac,
Ethiopia, Armenian, Old Latin, and of the <ent type='person'>Fathers</ent>, the following is
condensed, but in the exact words of the text:</p>

<p>  "The famous passage of the Three Witnesses [quoting I
   <ent type='person'>John</ent>, v, 7]. Throughout the past three hundred years, effort
   has been made to expunge from our <ent type='person'>Clement</ent>ine <ent type='person'>Vulgate</ent> edition
   of the canonical <ent type='person'>Scripture</ent>s the words that are bracketed. Let
   us examine the facts of the case. [Here follows the thorough </p>

<p>   Bank of Wisdom
    Box 926, Louisville, KY 40201
    194
.
   FORGERY IN CHRISTIANITY</p>

<p>   review of the MSS, closed in each instance by such words as:
   "The disputed part is found in none"; "no trace"; "no
   knowledge until the twelfth century," etc. etc.] The silence
   of the great and voluminous St. <ent type='person'>Augustine</ent>, [etc.] are admitted
   facts that militate against the canonicity of the Three
   Witnesses. St. <ent type='person'>Jerome</ent> does not seem to know the text, --
   [<ent type='person'>Jerome</ent> made the <ent type='person'>Vulgate</ent> Official Version].</p>

<p>  "Trent's is the first certain ecumenical decree, whereby
   the Church established the Canon of <ent type='person'>Scripture</ent>. We cannot say
   that the Decree of Trent necessarily included the Three
   Witnesses" -- [for reasons elaborately stated, and upon two
   conditions discussed, saying): "Neither condition has yet been
   verified with certainty; quite the contrary, textual criticism
   seems to indicate that the Comma Johanninum was not at all
   times and everywhere wont to be read in the Catholic Church,
   and it is not contained in the Old Latin <ent type='person'>Vulgate</ent>. However, the
   Catholic theologian must take into account more than textual
   criticism"! (CE. viii, 436.)</p>

<p>   A confessed forgery of Holy Writ consciously kept in the
"canonical" text as a fraudulent voucher for a false Trinity --
such is "The Three Heavenly Witnesses" -- to the shame and ignominy
of the Holy Church of Christ, which "has never deceived any one,"
and which "has never made an error, and never shall err to all
eternity"! This is not an error, however; it is but one more
deliberate clerical "lie to the glory of God."</p>

<div>    ****   ****</div>

<p>   Abbreviations for most often used sources:</p>

<p>   The libraries of the Union Theological Seminary and of
Columbia University, in New York City, were the places of the finds
here recorded. Cited so often, space will be saved for more
valuable uses by citing by their initials, -- which will become
very familiar -- my chief ecclesiastical authorities, towit:</p>

<p>   The Ante-Nicene <ent type='person'>Fathers</ent>, cited as ANF.; A Collection of the
extant Writings of all the Founders of Christianity down to the
Council of Nicaea, or Nice, in 325 A.D. American Reprint, eight
volumes. The Christian Literature Publishing Co., Buffalo, N.Y.,
1885. [xxx]</p>

<p>   The Nicene and Post-Nicene <ent type='person'>Fathers</ent>, cited as N&amp;PNF.; First and
Second Series; many volumes; same publishers.</p>

<p>   The Catholic Encyclopedia, cited as CE.; fifteen volumes and
index, published under the <ent type='person'>Imprimatur</ent> of Archbishop Farley; New
York, Robert Appleton Co., 1907-9.</p>

<p>   The Encyclopedia Biblica, cited as EB., four volumes; Adam &amp;
Charles Black, London, 1899; American Reprint, The Macmillan Co.,
New York, 1914.</p>

<div>    ****   ****</div>

<p>  Reproducible Electronic Publishing can defeat censorship.</p>

<p>   Bank of Wisdom
    Box 926, Louisville, KY 40201
    195
 </p></xml>