<xml><p>
<ent type='ORG'>WHO</ent> Murdered <ent type='LOC'>Africa</ent>
The Greatest Murder Mystery of all Time </p>
<p> There is no question mark after the title of this article because
the title is not a question. It's a declarative statement. <ent type='ORG'>WHO</ent>, the
World Health Organization, murdered <ent type='LOC'>Africa</ent> with the AIDS virus. Thats
a provocative statement, isn't it? </p>
<p> The answers to this little mystery, Murder on the <ent type='ORG'>WHO</ent> Express will
be quite clear to you by the end of this report. You will also
understand why the other suspects, the homosexuals, the green monkey
and the <ent type='NORP'>Haitians</ent>, were only pawns in this virocidal attack on the
non-<ent type='NORP'>Communist</ent> world. </p>
<p> If you believe the government propaganda that AIDS is hard to catch
then you are going to die even sooner than the rest of us. The common
cold is a virus. Have you ever had a cold? How did you catch it?
You don't really know, do you? If the cold virus was fatal, How many
people would be left in the world? </p>
<p> Yellow fever is a virus. You catch it from mosquito bites. Malaria
is a parasite also carried by mosquitoes. It is many times larger than
the AIDS virus ( like comparing a pinhead to a moose head ) yet the
mosquito easily carries this large organism to man. </p>
<p> The tuberculosis germ, also larger than that AIDS virus, can be
transmitted by formites ( inanimate objects such as towels ). The
AIDS virus can live for as long as 10 days on a dry plate. You can't
understand this murder mystery unless you learn a little virology. </p>
<p> Many viruses grow in animals and many grow in humans, but most of
the viruses that affect animals don't affect humans. There are exceptions,
of course, such as yellow fever and small pox. </p>
<p> There are some viruses in animals that can cause very lethal cancer
in those animals, but do not affect man or other animals. The Bovine
Leukemia Virus ( BLV ), for example, is lethal to cows but not humans.
There is also another virus that occurs in sheep called Sheep Visna Virus
which is also non-reactive in man. These Deadly viruses are " Retro -
Viruses ", meaning that they can change the genetic composition of the
cells that they enter. </p>
<p> <ent type='ORG'>The World Health Organization</ent>, in published articles, called for
scientists to work these deadly agents and attempt to make a hybrid
virus that would be deadly to humans. " An attempt should be made to
see if viruses can in fact exert selective effects on immune function.
The possibility should be looked into that the immune response to the
virus itself maybe impaired if the infecting virus damages, more or
less selectively, the cell responding to the virus." </p>
<p> Thats AIDS. What the <ent type='ORG'>WHO</ent> is saying in plain english is " Let's cook
up a virus that selectively destroys the T-Cell system of man, an
acquired immune deficiency. Why would anyone want to do this? If you
destroy the T-Cell system of man then you destroy man. Is it even
remotely possible that the <ent type='ORG'>WHO</ent> would want to develop a virus that would
wipe out the human race? </p>
<p> If there new creation worked, the <ent type='ORG'>WHO</ent> stated, then many terrible
and fatal infectious viruses could be made even more terrible and more
malignant. Does this strike you as being a peculiar goal for a health
organization? </p>
<p> Sometimes <ent type='NORP'>Americans</ent> believe in conspiracies and sometimes the don't.
Was there a conspiracy to kill President <ent type='PERSON'>Kennedy</ent>? Twenty five years later
the debate still continues, and people keep changing there minds. One day
it's yes and the next it's no - depending upon what was served for lunch,
or how the stock market did the day before. </p>
<p> But it doesn't take a bad lunch to see an amazing concatenation of
events involving <ent type='NORP'>Russian</ent> and <ent type='NORP'>Chinesse</ent> <ent type='NORP'>communist</ent> nationals, The <ent type='ORG'>WHO</ent>, The
National Cancer Institute, and the AIDS epidemic. </p>
<p> But what about the green monkey? Some of the best virologist in the
world and many of those directly involved in AIDS research, such as
Robert Gallo and Luc <ent type='PERSON'>Montagnier</ent>, have said that the green monkey may be
the culprit. You know the story: A green monkey bit a native on the ass
and, bam - AIDS all over central <ent type='LOC'>Africa</ent>. </p>
<p> There is a fatal flaw here. It is very strange. Because Gallo,
<ent type='PERSON'>Montagnier</ent> and these other virologist know that the AIDS virus doesn't
occur naturally in monkeys. In fact it doesn't occur naturally in any
animal. </p>
<p> AIDS started practically simultaneously in <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States, <ent type='GPE'>Haiti</ent>,
<ent type='GPE'>Brazil</ent>, and Central <ent type='LOC'>Africa</ent>. ( Was the green monkey a jet pilot? )
Examination for the gene structure of the green monkey cells prove that
it is not genetically possible to transfer the AIDS virus from monkeys
to man by natural means. </p>
<p> Because of the artificial nature of the AIDS virus it will not easily
transfer from man to man unless it has become very concentrated in the
body fluids through repeated injections from person to person, such as
drug addicts, and through high multiple partner sexual activity such as
takes place in <ent type='LOC'>Africa</ent> and among homosexuals. After repeated transfer it
can become a " natural " infection for man, which it has. </p>
<p> Dr. <ent type='PERSON'>Theodore Strecker</ent>'s research of the literature indicates that
<ent type='ORG'>the National</ent> Cancer Institute ( <ent type='ORG'>NCI</ent> ) in collaboration with the <ent type='ORG'>WHO</ent>,
made the AIDS virus in there laboratories at Fort <ent type='ORG'>Detrick</ent> ( now <ent type='ORG'>NCI</ent> ).
They combined the deadly retro-viruses Bovine-Leukemia Virus and Sheep
Visna Virus, and injected them into human tissue cultures. The result
was the AIDS virus, the first human retro-virus known to man and now
believed to be 100% fatal to those infected. </p>
<p> The momentous plague that we now face was anticipated by <ent type='ORG'>the National</ent>
Academy of Sciences (<ent type='ORG'>NAS</ent>) in 1974 when they recommended that "Scientists
throughout the world join with the members of this committee in voluntarily
deferring experiments linking animal viruses". What the <ent type='ORG'>NAS</ent> is saying in
carefully guarded english is: "For God's sake. Stop this madness!" The
green monkey is off the hook. How about the <ent type='NORP'>Communist</ent>s? </p>
<p> <ent type='NORP'>Communist</ent> are in the process of conducting germ warfare from Fort
<ent type='ORG'>Detrick</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Maryland</ent> against the free world, expecially <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States,
even using foreign <ent type='NORP'>communist</ent> agents within the US Army's germ warfare
unit euphamistically called <ent type='ORG'>the Army Infectious Disease Unit</ent>. </p>
<p> You don't believe it? <ent type='PERSON'>Carlton Gajdusek</ent>, an <ent type='ORG'>NIH</ent> bigshot at <ent type='ORG'>Detrick</ent>
admits it. " IN THE FACILITY I HAVE A BUILDING WHERE MORE GOOD AND
LOYAL COMMUNIST SCIENTISTS FROM THE <ent type='GPE'>USSR</ent> AND MAINLAND CHINA WORK, WITH
FULL PASSKEYS TO ALL THE LABORATORIES, THAN THERE ARE AMERICAN. EVEN THE
ARMY'S INFECTIOUS DISEASE UNIT IS LOADED WITH FOREIGN WORKERS NOT ALWAYS
FRIENDLY NATIONALS." </p>
<p> Can you imagine that? A UN-<ent type='ORG'>WHO</ent> <ent type='NORP'>communist</ent> trojan horse in our
biological warfare center with the full blessing of the US government? </p>
<p> The creation of the AIDS virus by the <ent type='ORG'>WHO</ent> was not just a diabolical
scientific exercise that got out of hand. It was a cold-blooded
successful attempt to create a killer virus which was then used in a
successful experiment in <ent type='LOC'>Africa</ent>. So successful in fact that most of
Central <ent type='LOC'>Africa</ent> may be wiped out, 75000000 dead within 3-5 years. </p>
<p> It was not an accident, it was deliberate. In the Federation
Proceedings of <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States in 1972, <ent type='ORG'>WHO</ent> said : " In relation
to the immune response a number of useful experimental approaches can
be visualized ". They suggested a neat way to do this would be to put
their new killer virus ( AIDS ) into a vaccination program, sit back and
observe the results. " This would be particularly informative in
sibships," they said. That is, give AIDS to brothers and sisters and
see if they die, who dies first, and of what, just like rats in a
laboratory. </p>
<p> They used the smallpox vaccine for their vehicle and the geographical
sites chosen in 1972 were <ent type='GPE'>Ugunda</ent> and other <ent type='LOC'>Africa</ent>n sites, <ent type='GPE'>Haiti</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Brazil</ent>
and <ent type='GPE'>Japan</ent>. The present and recent past of AIDS epidemiology coincides
with these geographical areas. </p>
<p> Dr. <ent type='PERSON'>Strecker</ent> points out that even if the <ent type='LOC'>Africa</ent>n green monkey could
transmit AIDS to humans, the present known amount of infection in <ent type='LOC'>Africa</ent>
makes it statistically impossible for a single episode, such as a monkey
biting someone, to have brought this epidemic to this point. The doubling
time of the number of people infected, about every 14 months, when
correlated with the first known cases, and the present known number of
cases, prove beyond a doubt that a large number of people had to be
infected at the same time. Starting in 1972 with the first case from our
mythical monkey, and doubling the number of infected from that single
source every 14 months you get only a few thousand cases. From 1972 to
1987 is 15 years or 180 months. If it takes 14 months to double the number
of cases then there would have been 13 doublings. 1 then 2 then 4 then 8..
etc...In 15 years, from a single source of infection there would be about
8000 cases in <ent type='LOC'>Africa</ent>, not 75 million. We are approaching <ent type='EVENT'>World War</ent> II
mortality statistics here - without a shot being fired. </p>
<p> Dr. Theodore A. <ent type='PERSON'>Strecker</ent> is the courageous doctor who has unraveled
this conundrum, the greatest murder mystery of all time. He should get
the Nobel Prize but he'll be lucky not to get "suicided." ( "Prominent
<ent type='GPE'>California</ent> doctor ties his hands behind his back, hangs himself, and
jumps from 20th floor. There was no evidence of foul play." ) </p>
<p> <ent type='PERSON'>Strecker</ent> was employed as a consultant to work on a health proposal
for <ent type='ORG'>Security Pacific Bank</ent>. He was to estimate the cost of their health
care for the future. Should they form an <ent type='ORG'>HMO</ent> was the major issue. After
investigating the current medical market he advised against the <ent type='ORG'>HMO</ent> because
he found that the AIDS epidemic in all probability bankrupt the nation's
medical system. </p>
<p> He became fascinated with all the scientific anomalies concerning AIDS
that kept cropping up. Why did the " experts " keep talking about
green monkeys and homosexuals being the culprits when it was obvious that
the AIDS virus was a man-made virus? Why did they say it was a homosexual
and drug-user disease when in <ent type='LOC'>Africa</ent> it was obviously a heterosexual
disease? If the green monkey did it then why did AIDS explode practically
simultaneously in <ent type='LOC'>Africa</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Haiti</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Brazil</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Japan</ent>, and <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States? </p>
<p> Why, when it was proposed to <ent type='ORG'>the National</ent> Institute of Health that the
AIDS virus was a combination of two bovine or sheep viruses cultured in
human cells in a laboratory, did they say it was " bad science " when
thats exactly what occurred? </p>
<p> As early as 1970 the <ent type='ORG'>WHO</ent> was growing these deadly animal viruses in
human tissue cultures. <ent type='PERSON'>Cedric Mims</ent>, in 1981, said in a published article
that there was a bovive virus contaminating the culture media of th <ent type='ORG'>WHO</ent>.
Was this an accident or a "non-accident"? If it was an accident then why
did the <ent type='ORG'>WHO</ent> continue to use the vaccine? </p>
<p> This viral and genetic death bomb, AIDS, was finally produced in 1974.
It was given to monkeys and they died of pneumocystis carni which is
typical of AIDS. </p>
<p> Dr. R. J. <ent type='PERSON'>Biggar</ent> said in <ent type='ORG'>Lancet</ent> ( a <ent type='ORG'>Brittish</ent> journal ) that the AIDS
agent could not have developed de novo. That means in plain english that
it didn't come out of thin air. AIDS was engineered in a laboratory by
virologists. It couldn't engineer itself. As Dr. <ent type='PERSON'>Stricker</ent> so colorfully
puts it: " If a person has no arms or legs and shows up at a party in a
tuxedo, how did he get dressed? Somebody dressed him. " </p>
<p> There are 9000 to the 4th power possible AIDS viruses. ( There are
9000 base pairs on the geneome. ) So the fun has just begun. Some will
cause brain rot similar to the sheep virus, some leukemia-like diseases
from the cow viruses, and some that won't do anything. So the virus will
be constantly changing and trying out new esoteric disease on hapless
man. We're only the beginning </p>
<p> Because of the trillions of possible genetic combinations there will
never be a vaccine. Even if they could develop a vaccine they would
undoubtfully give us something equally as bad as they did with the Polio
vaccine ( cancer of the brain ), the Swine Flu vaccine ( a Polio-like
disease ), the Smallpox vaccine (AIDS), and the Hepatitis vaccine (AIDS). </p>
<p> There are precedents. This is not the first time the virologists have
brought us disaster. SV-40 virus from monkey cell cultures contaminated
Polio cultures. Most people in there 40's are now carrying the virus
through contaminated Polio innoculations given in the early 60's. It is
known to cause brain cancer which explains the increase in this disease
that we have seen in the past 10 years. </p>
<p> This is the origin of the green monkey theory. The Polio vaccine was
grown on green monkey kidney cells. 64 million <ent type='NORP'>Americans</ent> were vaccinated
with SV-40 contaminated vaccine in the 60's. An increase in cancer of the
brain, possibly Multiple Sclerosis, and God only knows what else is the
tragic result. The delay between vaccination and the onset of cancer
with this virus is as long as 20-30 years. 1965 + 20 = 1985. Get the
picture? </p>
<p> The final piece of the puzzle is how AIDS devastated the homosexual
population in <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States. It wasn't from Smalpox vaccination as
in <ent type='LOC'>Africa</ent> because we don't do that any more. There is no Smallpox in the
United States and so vaccination was discontinued. Although some AIDS has
been brought to <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States from <ent type='GPE'>Haiti</ent> by homosexuals, It would not
be enough to explain the explosion of AIDS that occurred simultaneously
with the <ent type='LOC'>Africa</ent>n and <ent type='GPE'>Haiti</ent>an epidemics. </p>
<p> The AIDS virus didn't exist in <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States before 1978. You can
check back in any hospital and no stored blood samples can be found
anywhere that exhibit the AIDS virus before that date. What happened in
1978 and beyond to cause AIDS to burst upon the scene and devastate the
homosexual section of our population? It was the introduction of the
Hepatitis B vaccine which exhibits the exact same epidemiology of AIDS. </p>
<p> A Doctor W. <ent type='PERSON'>Schmunger</ent>, born in <ent type='GPE'>Poland</ent> and educated in <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>, came
to this country in 1969. Schmunger's immigration to the U.S. was
probably the most fatefull immigration in our history. He, by unexplained
process, became the head of one of the <ent type='GPE'>New York City</ent> blood bank. ( How
does a <ent type='NORP'>Russian</ent> trained doctor become the head of one of the largest blood
banks in the world? Doesn't that strike you as peculiar? ) </p>
<p> He set up the rules for the Hepatitis vaccine studies. Only males
between the ages of 20 and 40 , who were not monogamous, were allowed to
participate in this study. Can you think of any reason for insisting that
all expermentees be promiscuous? Maybe you don't believe in the <ent type='NORP'>Communist</ent>
conspiracy theory but give me some other logical explanation. <ent type='PERSON'>Schmunger</ent>
is now dead and his diabolical secret went with him. </p>
<p> <ent type='ORG'>The Centers for Disease Control</ent> reported in 1981 that 4% of those
receiving the Hepatitis vaccine were AIDS infected. In 1984 they admitted
to 60%. Now they refuse to give out the figures at all because they don't
want to admit that 100% of the Hepatitis vaccine receivers are AIDS
infected. Where is the data on the Hepatitis vaccine studied? <ent type='ORG'>FDA</ent>? <ent type='ORG'>CDC</ent>?
No, the U.S. Department of Justice has buried it where you will never see
it. </p>
<p> What has the government told us about AIDS? </p>
<p> * It's a homosexual disease-----------------------WRONG
* It's related to anal intercourse only-----------WRONG
* Only a small % of those testing positive
for AIDS would get the disease------------------WRONG
* It came from the <ent type='LOC'>Africa</ent>n green monkey-----------WRONG
* It came from cytomegalovirus--------------------WRONG
* It was due to popping amyl nitrate with sex-----WRONG
* It was started 400 years ago by the <ent type='NORP'>Portugese</ent>---WRONG
* You cant get it from insects--------------------WRONG
* The virus can't live outside the body-----------WRONG </p>
<p> The head of <ent type='ORG'>the Human Leukemia Research Group</ent> at <ent type='ORG'>Harvard</ent> is a
veterinarian. Dr. O. W. <ent type='ORG'>Judd</ent>, International Agency for Research on Cancer,
the agency that requested the production of the virus in the first place,
is also a veterinarian. The Leukemia research he is conducting is being
done under the auspices of a school of veterinary medicine. Now, there is
nothing wrong with being a vet but, as we have pointed out, the AIDS virus
is a human virus. You can't test these viruses in animals and you can't
test leukemias in them either. It doesn't work. So why would your
government give <ent type='ORG'>Judd</ent>, a veterinarian, 8.5 million dollars to study
leukemia in a veterinary college? As long as we are being used as
experimental animals maybe it is appropriate. </p>
<p> <ent type='ORG'>The London</ent> Times should be congratulated for uncovering the smallpox-AIDS connection. But there expose was very misleading. The article states
that the <ent type='LOC'>Africa</ent>n AIDS epidemic was caused by the smallpox vaccine
"triggering" the AIDS in those vaccinated. Dr. Robert Gallo, who has been
mixed up in some very strange scientific snafus, supports this theory.
Whether the infection of 75 million Africians was deliberate or
accidental can be debated, but there is no room for debate whether the
smallpox shots "awakened the unsuspecting virus infection." There is
absolutely no scientific evidence that this laboratory-engineered virus
was present in <ent type='LOC'>Africa</ent> before the <ent type='ORG'>WHO</ent> descended upon these hapless people
in 1967 with their deadly AIDS-laced vaccine. The AIDS virus didn't come
from <ent type='LOC'>Africa</ent>, it came from Fort <ent type='ORG'>Detrick</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Maryland</ent>, U.S.A. </p>
<p> The situation is extremely desperate and the medical profession is
too frightened and cowed (as usual) to take any action. Dr. <ent type='PERSON'>Strecker</ent>
attempted to mobilize the doctors through some of the most respected
medical journals in the world. The prestigious <ent type='ORG'>Annals</ent> of Internal Medicine
said that his material "appears to be entirely concerned with maters of
virology" and so try some other publication. </p>
<p> In his letter to The <ent type='ORG'>Annals</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Strecker</ent> said, "If correct human
experimental procedures had been followed we would not find half of the
world stumbling off on the wrong path to the cure for AIDS with the other
half of the world covering up the origination of the dammed disease. It
appears to me that your <ent type='ORG'>Annals</ent> of Internal Medicine is participating in
the greatest fraud ever perpetrated." </p>
<p> I guess they didn't like that so <ent type='PERSON'>Stricker</ent> submitted his sensational
and mind-boggling letter with all of the proper documentation to the
<ent type='NORP'>British</ent> journal, <ent type='ORG'>Lancet</ent>. Their reply : " Thank you for that interesting </p>
<p> letter on AIDS. I am sorry to have to report that we will not be able to
publish it. We have no criticism" but their letter section was " over
crowded with submissions ". </p>
<p> They're too crowded to announce the end of western civilization and
possibly all mandkind? Doesn't seem reasonable. What can we do? The first
thing that should be done is to close down all laboratories in this
country that are dealing with these deadly retro-viruses. Then we must
sort out the insane, irresponsible and traitorous scientists involved
in these experiments and try them for murder. Then maybe, just ,maybe, we
can repopulate and re-civilize the world. </p>
<p> <ent type='PERSON'>William Campbell Douglass</ent>, M.D.
P.O. Box 38 <ent type='GPE'>Lakemont</ent>, GA 30552 </p>
<p> </p></xml>