<xml><p>
Taken from KeelyNet BBS (214) 324-3501
Sponsored by <ent type='ORG'>Vangard Sciences</ent>
PO BOX 1031
<ent type='GPE'>Mesquite</ent>, TX 75150</p>

<p> August 16, 1990
AIDSPLOT.ASC</p>

<p> AIDS as a Weapon of War</p>

<p> by Dr. <ent type='PERSON'>William Campbell Douglas</ent>, M.D.</p>

<p> Introduction &amp; Comments by Jim Shults</p>

<p> INTRODUCTION AND COMMENTS</p>

<p> I must admit I am just a little gun shy of doing this
particular article. The reason is pretty obvious. Who in hell is
going to plead guilty to inventing the AIDS virus. Do I think it
was invented? Absolutely and without a doubt.</p>

<p> Firstly, where in hell has it been during the last 5000 years?
Why haven't we had exposure to it sooner, like in the last 50 years?</p>

<p> All of a sudden certain countries and entire continents are
coming down with the AIDS virus and no organization, body, group, or
whatever you care to call it has even a clue to the real source, and
it sure as hell isn't some monkey in <ent type='LOC'>Africa</ent>, that's for sure.</p>

<p> Over the last twenty years the genetic scientists have been
having a filed day inventing all kinds of new "life." Some have
even been granted patents for their creatures, which are usually
various types of bacteria, etc.</p>

<p> One patent was granted for the invention, or more accurately
put, creation, of a type of bacteria that eats oil, handy for oil
spills I guess. Now do you think for even a second that a virus
like the AIDS virus couldn't be created with all the genetic
engineering that is going on around the world?</p>

<p> There are certain types of bacteria that are living in test
tubes in labs around the world that if released would cause the end
of mankind in less than a year.</p>

<p> The real question is why we allow these bozos to play in labs,
making all kinds of new and artificial life in the first place. It
is going to backfire, in fact the author already feels it has,
through the deliberate release of the HIV (human immunodeficiency
virus); that's what AIDS is really called.</p>

<p> Something extraordinary happened last June (88'), in fact it
was so extraordinary that nothing like it has ever happened before.</p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>The Surgeon General</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States had mailed to every
mail box and address in <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States a brochure attempting to
explain AIDS, its danger, myths and means of transmission. The</p>

<p> Page 1</p>

<p> absolutely amazing thing about this was that it was done at
all.
Think of this for a minute: the U.S. Government mailed this
information to every address in <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>. That in itself should tell
all of us something that the media has somehow missed -- that this
is a population-destroying virus.</p>

<p> That really means that we all are in shit city, race fans, and
the Government know it. It is significant that they did the
mailing, and that should be very significant to anyone who knows
how our government works and what kind of very real panic those
who really know are experiencing.</p>

<p> When something like this brochure is made available as it was,
you can be very sure that the boys at the top, including the
scientific folks, are up against something they may not beat before
it has a very real chance of destroying at least half of mankind!</p>

<p> In fact, the fastest time even guessed at, for some kind of
beginning cure for some types of AIDS is at least five years and
that's thought to be impossible by medical people.</p>

<p> The author comes up with a very plausible scenario for how
rapidly AIDS has been distributed. (We are not blaming the
World Health Organization. In the author's scenario he simply
indicates that the <ent type='ORG'>WHO</ent> was used by others.)</p>

<p> Let's face it, we are in very real trouble. There are several
types of new AIDS viruses and more to be discovered, and who is to
say how the new ones, not yet mutated, will spread -- a sneeze
perhaps?</p>

<p> Our government and others around the world are not telling us
the truth about this stuff in order to protect our poor little dumb
minds. I suspect that if we know the truth, an enormous citizen
effort could be martialed worldwide which would probably shut down
the arms race for the time being.</p>

<p> Again, at the bottom line, we are in big trouble and "they"
know it....Many scientists predict we will lose half the world's
population (including U.S.) by the year 2000.</p>

<p> -- Jim Shults</p>

<p> Page 2</p>

<p> ABOUT THE AUTHOR</p>

<p> <ent type='PERSON'>William Campbell Douglas</ent>s, M.D.</p>

<p> Age: 62</p>

<p> Education: BS, University of Rochester, <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent>;
MD, University of Miami School of
Medicine; Graduate, U.S. <ent type='ORG'>Navy</ent> School of
Aviation and Space Medicine</p>

<p> Career: U.S. <ent type='ORG'>Navy</ent>, 7 years -- Flight Surgeon.
In practice for over 25 years. Former
state president, <ent type='GPE'>Florida</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n
College of Emergency Physicians.
Former Editor of <ent type='ORG'>the Journal</ent> of the
Sarasota County Medical Society.
Consulting Editor, <ent type='ORG'>Health Freedom</ent> News.
On Board of Governors of the National
Health Federation. Regular speaker at
<ent type='ORG'>the National Health Federation</ent> meetings
around <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States. Appears
regularly on radio and television
programs on health.
Doctor of the
Year: National Health Federation, 1985.</p>

<p> Dr. <ent type='PERSON'>Douglass</ent> has studied in <ent type='GPE'>England</ent> with Dr. <ent type='PERSON'>Katharina Dalton</ent>,
discoverer of the premenstrual syndrome. He was one of the
first doctors in <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States to diagnose and treat <ent type='ORG'>PMS</ent>.
He opened his <ent type='ORG'>PMS</ent> Clinic in 1981.</p>

<p> Page 3</p>

<p> AIDS as a Weapon of War</p>

<p> <ent type='PERSON'>William Campbell Douglas</ent>s, M.D.</p>

<p> The great powers renounced chemical and biological warfare 20
years ago -- but kept right on experimenting. The germ warfare
experiments on Seventh Day Adventist soldiers,</p>

<p> 1) the <ent type='ORG'>Tuskeegee</ent> syphilis experiments on prisoners,
2) the <ent type='LOC'>San Francisco Bay</ent> attack by the U.S. <ent type='ORG'>Army</ent> using
serratia marcescens bacteria,
3) the <ent type='GPE'>New York City</ent> subway germ attack
4 and many other experiments on humans, largely unknown to
the victims, continue in the free world.</p>

<p> In Novosybirsk, at <ent type='ORG'>the Ivanofsky Institute</ent> and other <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent>
centers of biological warfare, you can be sure that similar
diabolical experiments on humans continue at a frantic pace.</p>

<p> The <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> press, always masters of the half truth, accused
the U.S. <ent type='ORG'>Army</ent> of having engineered the AIDS virus in the biological
warfare laboratories at Fort Detrick, <ent type='GPE'>Maryland</ent>.</p>

<p> This was a clever psy-war ploy which, for a while anyway,
neutralized those of us who were saying essentially the same thing,
that the AIDS virus was probably created through recombinant genetic
engineering (the rearranging of genes between two or more species of
plants or animal) and/or serial passage: the growing of a virus in
a series of generations of tissue culture cells or live animals,
thus adapting the virus to a new species, using human tissue culture
cells in the top security labs at Fort Detrick.</p>

<p> People started accusing us of spreading the <ent type='NORP'>communist</ent> line, not
a comfortable position for a dedicated anti-<ent type='NORP'>communist</ent> like myself.</p>

<p> What the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> propagandists didn't say was that their agents
had been working in our top security biological warfare laboratories
for over 20 years.</p>

<p> In a burst of brotherly love they were invited in by President
<ent type='PERSON'>Nixon</ent>. The astounded <ent type='NORP'>communist</ent> scientists from <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>, the Eastern
Bloc and <ent type='NORP'>Communist</ent> <ent type='GPE'>china</ent>, who had been trying to penetrate this
vital security area for 40 years, quickly accepted.</p>

<p> They have been snickering in their beakers ever since, while
they prepare for our demise.</p>

<p> "It's no secret that they are there," Dr. <ent type='PERSON'>Carlton Gajdusek</ent>,
Nobel Prize winner, a top official at <ent type='ORG'>the Fort Detrick Army</ent>
laboratory in <ent type='GPE'>Maryland</ent>, said in <ent type='ORG'>Onmi Magazine</ent> (March 1986): "In
the facility I have a building where more good and loyal <ent type='NORP'>communist</ent>
scientists from the <ent type='GPE'>USSR</ent> and mainland <ent type='GPE'>China</ent> work, with full passkeys
to all the laboratories, than there are <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n. Even the Army's
infectious disease unit is loaded with foreign workers who are not
always friendly nationals."</p>

<p> This answer to an interview question refers to the high number
of <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> bloc scientists in this U.S. facility who act as</p>

<p> Page 4</p>

<p> inspectors to ensure that we are not producing bacteriological
weapons in violation of treaties with the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent>s.</p>

<p> You can't put it more plainly than that. Even the <ent type='NORP'>Trojans</ent>
weren't that stupid: at least they didn't KNOW the Trojan horse
was full of soldiers.</p>

<p> When it became obvious to the <ent type='NORP'>Communist</ent> press that we were
getting the truth out about who was running things at Fort Detrick,
they completely reversed themselves and said it was all a mistake.
Everything was just fine at Fort Detrick.</p>

<p> To understand the enormity of our betrayal you must know about
the origin of the AIDS virus. The virologists of the world, the
sorcerers who brought us this ghastly plague, have a united front in
denying that the virus was laboratory-made from known, lethal animal
viruses.</p>

<p> The scientific party line is that a monkey in <ent type='LOC'>Africa</ent> with AIDS
bit a native on the butt. The native then went to town and gave it
to a prostitute who gave it to the local banker who gave it to his
wife and three girlfriends and what!</p>

<p> 50 to 75 million people became infected with AIDS in <ent type='LOC'>Africa</ent> and
throughout the world. This is an entirely preposterous story, and
it is preposterous because:</p>

<p> 1. The green velvet monkey of <ent type='LOC'>Africa</ent> doesn't get human AIDS. You
can't reproduce the disease in monkeys even by injecting AIDS
virus directly into them.</p>

<p> 2. After injecting the virus into monkeys, you can't transmit it
to other monkeys, much less to humans.</p>

<p> 3. Genetically, AIDS (HIV-1) is not even close to the monkey form
of immunodeficiency virus.
[Ed. Note: For references on the three items above,
see: Seale, Dr. John J.,
<ent type='ORG'>Royal Society</ent> of Medicine, Sept. 1987,
Seale, Dr. John J.,
The Origin of AIDS -- International
Conference on AIDS, <ent type='GPE'>Cairo</ent>, March 1988.]</p>

<p> 4. AIDS started not in the villages but in the cities of <ent type='LOC'>Africa</ent>,
where there are no wild monkeys.</p>

<p> 5. The doubling time of AIDS infection being about 12 months, one
monkey biting one native and then spreading the disease would
have taken 20 years to reach a million cases. Seventy-five million <ent type='LOC'>Africa</ent>ns became infected practically simultaneously.
At the same time, the disease became rampant in the U.S.,
<ent type='GPE'>Haiti</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Brazil</ent>.</p>

<p> It is obvious that one monkey couldn't have done that (or one
homosexual, either). There had to be some sort of simultaneous
seeding process.</p>

<p> The only worldwide simultaneous seeding going on at the same
time was the smallpox vaccine program of the World Health
Organization (the <ent type='ORG'>WHO</ent>).
Page 5</p>

<p> The early epidemiology of the AIDS pandemic fits the smallpox
vaccination project of the <ent type='ORG'>WHO</ent> -- AND NOTHING ELSE -- with the
exception of the U.S., which we will examine subsequently.)</p>

<p> The AIDS virus was created in a laboratory by combining lethal
animal "retroviruses" in human cancer (HeLA) cell cultures. These
viruses have never before caused infection in man.</p>

<p> The "species barrier" has always been nature's way of keeping a
deadly virus from wiping out the entire animal kingdom, including
man. The myxoma virus of rabbits, for example, wiped out the rabbit
population of Europe, but man and other animals were not affected.</p>

<p> The sheep visna virus completely decimated the flocks of
<ent type='GPE'>Iceland</ent>, but no other animal was affected.</p>

<p> The virologists deny that the AIDS virus, HIV-1, is of animal
origin. I am sure that you see the paradox here. Aren't monkeys
animals?</p>

<p> They are also united in saying that it's not possible for the
virus to have been engineered in a laboratory. If it didn't come
from other animals and it didn't come from a laboratory, and they
now admit privately that the monkey couldn't have done it, then it
must have come out of thin air. That's a theological position and
hence beyond argument. It's certainly not scientific.</p>

<p> These scientists who have created this monstrous problem in
their sorcerer's retrovirology laboratories are constantly caught in
their own lies.</p>

<p> The line goes: "The AIDS virus could not have been engineered
in a laboratory because the technology wasn't available until
recently."</p>

<p> <ent type='GPE'>Iceland</ent>ic scientists combined the sheep visna virus with human
tissue cells over 20 years ago. The technology has been refined in
recent years, but the basic process has been actively used in labs
all over the world for long before the AIDS virus made its dramatic
appearance.</p>

<p> But the scientists hold fast in their denial of culpability.
Professor <ent type='PERSON'>William Jarrett</ent> said, when asked about the possibility of
AIDS arising from animal retroviruses, "That is like someone saying
babies come out of cabbages."5</p>

<p> Dr. Robert Gallo said that people who claim AIDS was
manufactured artificially are "either insane or <ent type='NORP'>communist</ent>s."6</p>

<p> Dr. Luis <ent type='PERSON'>Montagnier</ent>, the discoverer of the AIDS virus, said,
"In 1970 there was not enough knowledge in genetic engineering to
make such a virus starting from already existing viruses."7 (See
<ent type='GPE'>Iceland</ent>ic experiments mentioned above.)</p>

<p> This tower of lies must eventually fall of its own weight.
Then what? Where do we look for a solution? Certainly not from
the people who caused the disaster.</p>

<p> But where? -- the <ent type='ORG'>Pentagon</ent>? The <ent type='ORG'>Pentagon</ent> is supporting</p>

<p> Page 6</p>

<p> research on biological warfare in over 100 federal and private
laboratories, including those at many prominent universities.8 Yet,
<ent type='PERSON'>Neil Levitt</ent>, who worked for 17 years at the <ent type='ORG'>Army</ent> Infectious Disease
Institute, says, "It's a joke...there's no defense against these
kinds of organisms. And if you can't defend against something, then
why are we pouring more and more money in it? There's something
else going on that we don't know about."9</p>

<p> Some joke.</p>

<p> A short virology lesson will help you understand that AIDS is
indeed an animal virus and that it was laboratory-made as a weapon
of biological warfare against the free world.</p>

<p> A basic rule of virology is that if two viruses have the same
shape, design and size, then they are almost certainly the same
virus (a very simple and easy to understand rule).10</p>

<p> For example, this virus:</p>

<div> -----------
|==| |||
-----------</div>

<p> ... a virus of bacteria (bugs have diseases, too), doesn't look
anything like this virus:</p>

<p> ___________
/ \
/ ~~~~~~~ \
\ /
\___________/</p>

<p> ... a virus of ticks that's transmitted to pigs, or this virus:</p>

<p> __________
____/ ~~~~ \
/ ______/
\________/</p>

<p> ... which is found in horses.</p>

<p> The AIDS virus, which "couldn't have come from animal
viruses" is almost certainly a recombinant virus from fusing a
cattle virus, bovine leukemia virus:</p>

<div> =
*
=* *=</div>

<div> =* ++++ *=</div>

<div> =* *=
*
=</div>

<p> Page 7</p>

<p> ...with sheep visna virus:</p>

<div> *
* *</div>

<div> * ==== *</div>

<div> * *
*</div>

<p> You combine the two in human tissue culture cells and you get bovine
visna virus:</p>

<div> =
*
=* *=</div>

<div> =* ==== *=</div>

<div> =* *=
*
=</div>

<p> ... A VIRUS THAT HERETOFORE DID NOT EXIST -- a product of man,
engineered in a laboratory.</p>

<p> Now, if you isolate the AIDS virus from an infected human, it
looks like this:</p>

<div> =
*
=* *=</div>

<div> =* ==== *=</div>

<div> =* *=
*
=</div>

<p> It doesn't look like this (the tick virus):</p>

<p> __________
____/ ~~~~ \
/ ______/
\________/</p>

<p> ... or this (the cattle virus):</p>

<div> =
*
=* *=</div>

<div> =* ++++ *=</div>

<div> =* *=
*
=</div>

<p> Page 8</p>

<p> It looks like THIS:</p>

<div> =
*
=* *=</div>

<div> =* ==== *=</div>

<div> =* *=
*
=</div>

<p> ... the recombinant virus from cattle and sheep AND ITS CALLED
AIDS. You don't have to be a genius to understand this. Any
properly instructed 10-year-old can understand it ....</p>

<p> But, some alert reader will say, we don't give smallpox
vaccinations in the U.S., so how do you explain the simultaneous
outbreak of AIDS in <ent type='LOC'>Africa</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Brazil</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Haiti</ent>, where they did indeed
give the vaccine, and in the U.S., where they didn't give the
vaccine?</p>

<p> Simple. The homosexual community was used as a large group of
experimental animals through the hepatitis-B program. It didn't
take many infected homosexuals among the I.V. drug users to quickly
spread the disease among a large percentage of the addicts due to
the near certainly of infection through direct intravenous insertion
of the virus.</p>

<p> To understand the seeding of AIDS among homosexuals (and
eventually to the rest of us through bisexuals unless drastic action
is taken), you must know about a character with the strange name of
<ent type='PERSON'><ent type='PERSON'>Wolf</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Szmuness</ent></ent>. His life story will seem bizarre to you unless, like
me, you have a conspiratorial turn of mind.</p>

<p> Dr. <ent type='PERSON'>Szmuness</ent> was a <ent type='NORP'>Polish</ent> Jew who supposedly ended up in a
<ent type='NORP'>Siberian</ent> labor camp during <ent type='EVENT'>World War</ent> II. But after the war he
somehow became a privileged person, was sent to medical school in
<ent type='GPE'>Tomsk</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>, and married a <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>n woman. Hardly typical
treatment of an enemy of the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> state [under Stalin.</p>

<p> <ent type='PERSON'>Szmuness</ent>' biographer said that <ent type='PERSON'>Wolf</ent> was always reluctant to
discuss "those dark years in <ent type='LOC'>Siberia</ent>." Maybe he wasn't in <ent type='LOC'>Siberia</ent>.
If he [actually] was, he certainly wasn't shoveling salt.</p>

<p> In 1959 the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> government "allowed" him to practice in
<ent type='GPE'>Poland</ent> in a public health capacity. Standard policy in all
<ent type='NORP'>Communist</ent> countries is never to allow all members of a family to
travel out of the country to the <ent type='LOC'>West</ent> at the same time.</p>

<p> This eliminates 98 percent of all defection attempts. I have
physician friends in Hungary, for example. He can go to a meeting
anywhere in the world if she stays home. She can go if he stays
home. They can both go if the children are left at home. But in
1969, the entire <ent type='PERSON'>Szmuness</ent> family was allowed by <ent type='NORP'>communist</ent> <ent type='GPE'>Poland</ent> to
go to a medical meeting in <ent type='GPE'>Italy</ent>. At that time they "defected" and
moved to <ent type='GPE'>New York City</ent>.</p>

<p> WITH NO AMERICAN CREDENTIALS <ent type='ORG'>WHATSOEVER</ent>, he immediately got a</p>

<p> Page 9</p>

<p> job as a "lab technician" at the <ent type='GPE'>New York City</ent> Blood Center. Within
a very few years this <ent type='NORP'>Polish</ent> immigrant was GIVEN HIS OWN LAB, a
separate department of epidemiology was created for him at the blood
bank and he, like the chrysalis turning into a butterfly, changed
into a FULL PROFESSOR OF <ent type='ORG'>EPIDEMIOLOGY</ent> AT THE COLUMBIA MEDICAL
SCHOOL!</p>

<p> In six years this "lab tech" became a full professor AND THEN
WENT BACK TO <ent type='ORG'>MOSCOW</ent> for a scientific presentation and was received
as a dignitary, not a defector.</p>

<p> We tell you this amazing story because in retrospect it is
obvious that <ent type='PERSON'><ent type='PERSON'>Wolf</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Szmuness</ent></ent> was a carefully groomed ... agent,
planted here after years of preparation, to instigate biological
warfare against the <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n people.</p>

<p> <ent type='PERSON'>Szmuness</ent>, with the full cooperation and financial support of
the U.S. Center for Disease Control and <ent type='ORG'>the National Institutes</ent> of
Health,11 masterminded the hepatitis-B vaccine experimental program
used on homosexual men.</p>

<p> He insisted that only young, promiscuous homosexuals be allowed
to participate in the experiment. The experiment started in New
York at the blood bank in November 1978.</p>

<p> THE EXPERIMENTAL VACCINE WAS PRODUCED in a government
supervised laboratory.12 The study was completed in October 1979.
Within 10 years, most of these young men would be dead or dying from
AIDS.</p>

<p> In 1980 the program was expanded to major cities all across the
U.S. In the fall of 1980 the first AIDS case was reported in San
Francisco. Eight years later most of the homosexuals in San
Francisco are infected, dead or dying.</p>

<p> <ent type='PERSON'>Szmuness</ent> did not live to see the fruition of this larger
experiment. He died of cancer in 1982.</p>

<p> In 1986 Dr. <ent type='PERSON'>Cladd Stevens</ent>, one of Szmuness's collaborators,
penned an astonishing report that did not make your local newspaper.</p>

<p> She reported that the majority of the homosexuals in the
experimental program were infected with the AIDS virus.13 The AIDS-laced vaccine, through the bridge of bisexual men, now infects as
many as three million <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>ns. Mission accomplished.</p>

<p> AIDS was not the first germ warfare attack against <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>ns.</p>

<p> In the early '60s, millions of unsuspecting <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>ns took
either <ent type='PERSON'>Salk</ent> injected polio vaccine or the live <ent type='PERSON'>Sabin</ent> polio vaccine,
which was taken by mouth.</p>

<p> BOTH WERE LACED WITH S.V.-40, A CANCER-CAUSING MONKEY VIRUS.14</p>

<p> With an incubation period of 20 years, we are only now seeing
the grim results of this bio-attack against <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>ns, largely in
the form of brain tumors and leukemia.</p>

<p> Page 10</p>

<p> <ent type='PERSON'>Salk</ent> didn't like the <ent type='PERSON'>Sabin</ent> vaccine and <ent type='PERSON'>Sabin</ent> didn't like the
<ent type='PERSON'>Salk</ent> vaccine. I think they are both right. It is interesting to
note that polio was rapidly disappearing WITHOUT a vaccine (J. Trop.
Pediat, env. Child. Health 21, 11) ....</p>

<p> Our <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> enemies not only instigated the AIDS epidemic
through clandestine agents within our government, but they now
control, through <ent type='ORG'>the World Health Organization</ent>, the AIDS policies of
the free world.</p>

<p> You are probably not aware that the international AIDS
prevention program of <ent type='ORG'>the World Health Organization</ent> (<ent type='ORG'>WHO</ent>) is run by
the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent>s.</p>

<p> You don't believe it? Call <ent type='ORG'>WHO</ent> and ask them who is in charge
in Europe. If you want to save your nickel I'll tell you. He's a
<ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>n named <ent type='PERSON'>Bysencho</ent> and he operates out of <ent type='GPE'>Copenhagen</ent>....</p>

<p> The <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent>s control the response to AIDS of the entire free
world at many levels, including the top. Dr. <ent type='PERSON'>Sergei Litvinov</ent>,
the coordinator of all task forces on AIDS at the <ent type='ORG'>WHO</ent>, is a high
official in the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> Ministry of Health. Allegedly <ent type='PERSON'>Litvinov</ent>
gave out the order to our scientists and medical organizations in
the western world not to discuss the real cause of the epidemic.</p>

<p> At a secret meeting (information supplied the author from a
confidential source) between the editors of <ent type='ORG'>Lancet</ent>, the highly
respected <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> medical publication, and a group of the leading
<ent type='ORG'>retrovirologists</ent> of the world, it was decided not to publish any
academic discussion about the possible artificial creation of the
AIDS virus in a laboratory.</p>

<p> They particularly agreed not to make any mention of world-renowned biologist <ent type='PERSON'>Isaac Farlane Bernet</ent>'s published remarks that
molecular biology may get out of hand like atomic physics and be
used for evil purposes and "practical applications of molecular
biology to cancer research might be sinister."</p>

<p> Other medical journals such as <ent type='ORG'>Science</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>JAMA</ent> have
lockstepped with <ent type='ORG'>Lancet</ent> and put all references to the man-made
origins of AIDS down the memory hole.</p>

<p> Did Comrade <ent type='PERSON'>Litvinov</ent> have a little talk with the
<ent type='ORG'>retrovirologists</ent>? They, of course, wouldn't need any encouragement
from the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> [<ent type='ORG'>WHO</ent>] bosses to attempt a little coverup of their
own heinous crime, but <ent type='ORG'>Lancet</ent>, the <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> Medical Journal, and the
New <ent type='GPE'>England</ent> Journal of Medicine are another matter.</p>

<p> It took some powerful and sinister forces indeed to get these
respected publications to cover up the crime of the millennium.</p>

<p> The notable exception to this appalling censorship of mass
murder is Professor Harding Rains, Editor of <ent type='ORG'>the Journal</ent> of the
<ent type='ORG'>Royal Society</ent> of Medicine. Rains refers to "a conspiracy of
silence" covering the allegation that AIDS was man-made. I hope
Dr. Rains is watching his backside.</p>

<p> Dr. <ent type='PERSON'>Zhores Medvedev</ent>, unlike <ent type='PERSON'>Bysencho</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Litvinov</ent>, supposedly
is a <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>n exile. <ent type='PERSON'>Medvedev</ent> operates out of <ent type='GPE'>London</ent> at the National</p>

<p> Page 11</p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>Institute for</ent> Medical Research. He's a senior research scientist
who continues to communicate freely with his supposed enemies in the
<ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> biowarfare laboratories, but we lack the space to catalog all
the details [here].</p>

<p> <ent type='PERSON'>Medvedev</ent> is spreading the disinformation that AIDS is rampant
in <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent> due to the escape of the virus from a laboratory, a sort
of biological <ent type='GPE'>Chernobyl</ent>.</p>

<p> This tends to divert suspicion away from <ent type='PERSON'>Litvinov</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Szmuness</ent> and
the other reds that President <ent type='PERSON'>Nixon</ent> allowed to penetrate our
biological warfare laboratories at Fort Detrick, <ent type='GPE'>Maryland</ent>.</p>

<p> Having the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent>s "control" the spread of AIDS in the <ent type='LOC'>West</ent> has
let to some interesting paradoxes. Our masters in the U.S. tell us
that there shall be absolutely no restrictions on travel between
various parts of the non-<ent type='NORP'>Communist</ent> world by persons who test
positive for AIDS.</p>

<p> Surgeon General C.E. <ent type='ORG'>Koop</ent> supports this <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> policy of
biological suicide. (Are those the instructions he received when he
made his trip to <ent type='GPE'>Moscow</ent>, where the <ent type='ORG'>WHO</ent> has set up its main AIDS
research center?)</p>

<p> But, our <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> masters in the <ent type='ORG'>WHO</ent> tell us, this open policy of
international travel does not apply to the <ent type='NORP'>communist</ent> bloc of
nations. If you or I were to visit <ent type='GPE'>Moscow</ent> and tested positive for
the AIDS virus, POW! -- out on the next plane!</p>

<p> If they stay clean through their immigration policies and we
die because of the immigration policies imposed on us through the
U.N.-controlled World "Health" Organization, who needs atomic bombs
for world conquest?</p>

<p> <ent type='GPE'>Cuba</ent>, Dr. <ent type='PERSON'>John Seale</ent> informs me, has a strict asylum system for
the AIDS-infected. When their troops come back from "liberating"
<ent type='LOC'>Africa</ent>ns, they are tested as they get off the boat.</p>

<p> If tested positive the soldier goes directly to hell --
euphemistically called a sanitarium. He can visit his family
occasionally, but only in the presence of a commissar called a
"health official (no hanky-panky).</p>

<p> Unless the <ent type='LOC'>West</ent> gets its act together and closes down the U.N.
genocide division called the <ent type='ORG'>WHO</ent>, freedom and decency will disappear
from planet <ent type='LOC'>Earth</ent> for a thousand years. But the problem goes much
deeper.</p>

<p> How do you close down the U.S. government laboratories such as
<ent type='ORG'>the Centers for Disease Control</ent> (<ent type='ORG'>CDC</ent>), <ent type='ORG'>the National Institute</ent> of
Health (<ent type='ORG'>NIH</ent>) and the Fort Detrick bio-warfare lab when the
perpetrators of the crime are in control at all levels?</p>

<p> I don't know the answer. *****</p>

<p> _________________________</p>

<p> Page 12</p>

<p> 1 Project Whitecoat, to be published in <ent type='ORG'>Health Freedom</ent> News,
P.O. Box 688, <ent type='GPE'>Monrovia</ent> CA 91016/Subscription $20.00 per year.</p>

<p> 2 Bad Blood, J.H. Jones, MacMillan, NY, 1982.</p>

<p> 3 Common Cause Magazine, Jan./Feb. 1988.</p>

<p> 4 First aids Report, March/April 1988.</p>

<p> 5 Private communication, <ent type='PERSON'>John Seale</ent>, M.D., 1988</p>

<p> 6 Ibid.</p>

<p> 7 First International Conference on the Global Impact of aids,
<ent type='GPE'>London</ent>, March 8-10, 1988.</p>

<p> 8 <ent type='ORG'>New Scientist</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>London</ent>, 5/19/88.</p>

<p> 9 <ent type='ORG'>Science</ent> News, 133:100, 2/13/88.</p>

<p> 10 Joklik, Virology, 2nd edition, pp. 36 ff.</p>

<p> 11 AIDS and the Doctors of Death, Cantwell, Aries Rising Press,
Los Angeles,p.76.</p>

<p> 12 Ibid.</p>

<p> 13 Ibid.
14 <ent type='PERSON'>Salk</ent>/<ent type='PERSON'>Sabin</ent> s.v.-40 Proc. Nat'l Acad. Sci., vol. 77, #8,
p. 4861, and <ent type='ORG'>Atlantic Monthly</ent>, 2/76.</p>

<div> --------------------------------------------------------------------</div>

<p> If you have comments or other information relating to such topics as
this paper covers, please upload to KeelyNet or send to the Vangard
<ent type='ORG'>Science</ent>s address as listed on the first page. Thank you for your
consideration, interest and support.</p>

<p> <ent type='PERSON'>Jerry</ent> W. Decker...<ent type='PERSON'>Ron Barker</ent>.....Chuck <ent type='GPE'>Henderson</ent>
<ent type='ORG'>Vangard Sciences</ent>/KeelyNet
--------------------------------------------------------------------
If we can be of service, you may contact
<ent type='PERSON'>Jerry</ent> at (214) 324-8741 or <ent type='PERSON'>Ron</ent> at (214) 484-3189
--------------------------------------------------------------------

</p></xml>