<xml><p>
Anti-<ent type='ORG'><ent type='NORP'>American</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> League</ent>
---------------------------</p>

<p>From: <ent type='ORG'>San Francisco Chronicle</ent>, Wed. Dec. 12, 1990 (Briefing Section)
----</p>

<p>The <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Zionists</ent> were led by <ent type='PERSON'>Chaim Weizmann</ent>, a brilliant chemist who
contributed to the war effort by discovering a new process for manufacturing
acetone, a substance vital for TNT that was until then only produced in
<ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent>. Weizmann saw a historic opening for <ent type='NORP'>Zionism</ent> and began to lobby
influential <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> politicians.</p>

<p>Early in their talks with <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> politicians, it became clear to them that
only a <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> <ent type='GPE'>Palestine</ent> would be a reliable buffer for the Suez Canal.
Weizmann therefore assured <ent type='GPE'>Britain</ent> that in exchange for its support,
<ent type='NORP'>Zionists</ent> would work for the establishment of a <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> protectorate there.
This suited <ent type='GPE'>Britain</ent> better than the agreement it had already made with
<ent type='GPE'>France</ent> for an international administration for <ent type='GPE'>Palestine</ent>.</p>

<p>So on November 2, 1917, Foreign Secretary <ent type='PERSON'>Arthur Balfour</ent> made his famous
and deeply ambiguous declaration that <ent type='GPE'>Britain</ent> would "view with favor the
establishment in <ent type='GPE'>Palestine</ent> of a national home for the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> people..."
How did the pledge to the <ent type='NORP'>Zionists</ent> square with what had already been
promised to the <ent type='NORP'>Arabs</ent> in return for their support in the war against the
<ent type='NORP'>Turks</ent>? The <ent type='NORP'>Arabs</ent> realized that they had been outmaneuvered.</p>

<p>Note - As you can see, the main reason our troops are in <ent type='LOC'>the Persian Gulf</ent>
is because of the <ent type='NORP'>Zionist</ent> hunger for a national home in <ent type='GPE'>Palestine</ent>.
<ent type='GPE'>Palestine</ent> was an independent land before 1917. But after the
totally unfair <ent type='PERSON'>Balfour Declaration</ent>, written by <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Zionists</ent>,
<ent type='NORP'>Zionists</ent> (<ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>) were given permission by Great <ent type='GPE'>Britain</ent> to take
over <ent type='GPE'>Palestine</ent> and keep lands which do not belong to them. And
the US has not done anything about it. Why? Because of the
better known media, which are all <ent type='NORP'>Zionists</ent>. (ie. <ent type='PERSON'>Ted Koppell</ent>,
<ent type='PERSON'>Larry King</ent>, etc etc etc) Many large corporations are also run
by <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, including many of the large corporations which make
stuff for our military. </p>

<p>Note - The <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> Anti-<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> League in no way supports the naked
aggression committed by <ent type='PERSON'>Saddam Hussein</ent> against <ent type='GPE'>Kuwait</ent>. He
must leave <ent type='GPE'>Kuwait</ent>, even though <ent type='GPE'>Kuwait</ent>, contrary to popular
opinion, once WAS a <ent type='GPE'>PROVINCE</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>Iraq</ent>. There is no doubt about
this: just go to your public library and get a good book on
<ent type='GPE'>Iraq</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Kuwait</ent>, or <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> Foreign Policy in the <ent type='LOC'>Middle East</ent>.
Once again, it was the <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> (and <ent type='NORP'>French</ent>) who set up the
current boundaries which exist today. However, what <ent type='PERSON'>Saddam</ent>
has done must be overruled, exactly as what the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> have
done to <ent type='GPE'>Palestine</ent> must be stopped. Do you know how much of
our <ent type='ORG'>TAXES</ent> go to <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent> every year? Do you know how much
trouble we've gone through to protect <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent>? Do you know
that there are more <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> in the <ent type='GPE'>USA</ent> than in any other country
in the world? Do you know most <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> (especially the conservative and highly orthodox ones) are strong anti-<ent type='NORP'>Americans</ent>?
Why then, are we supporting them? Because many of our
highest government positions are run by <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>. They are
practically running the US. And what about the <ent type='NORP'>British</ent>?
It is not <ent type='GPE'>Japan</ent> that owns more of the US than other countries.
It is Great <ent type='GPE'>Britain</ent>. They own more US land, corporations,
stocks, interests, etc. in the US than the <ent type='GPE'>Japan</ent>ese and 5
other countries put together. If you don't believe any of
this, just print it out, and go to your local public library
or ask an unbiased History professor. This is all true.
Please spread the word around, and upload this and other
files to as many BBS's as you can. We must begin to stop
this low-profile takeover of our country, or else it will
be too late to control it. Thank you for your time.</p>

<p> <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> Anti-<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> League
---------------------------</p>

<p>Have you ever wondered why so many people hate or dislike <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>? From their
very first existence, they have been hated by people around them and people
who knew them. Why? All through these ages, anti-semitism is still strong.
Why? It is true that some of this hatred is not founded for truly, such as
in the case of the <ent type='NORP'>Germans</ent>. Hitler was looking for a people to accuse of
Germany's downfall, so he picked the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>. Although this is not the main
reason for Germany's weakness at that time, there is still something to it.
<ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> were contributing, but very minutely, and in low-profile, to Germany's
problems. Anyway, back to the main point. Now it is the <ent type='NORP'>Arabs</ent> who are after
the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, even though if you go back to <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> today, the majority of
<ent type='NORP'>Germans</ent> (although they will not admit it right away) are still anti-<ent type='NORP'>semitic</ent>.
Wouldn't you still be? Just look at ALL these movies made and shown on
TV and at cinemas in which the world is pitted against the <ent type='NORP'>Germans</ent>, and
the <ent type='NORP'>Germans</ent> always lose. These movies are still shown every day on TV and
cable. Just turn on <ent type='ORG'>TBS</ent>, TNT, etc. Anyway, now it is the <ent type='NORP'>Arabs</ent>. And
now we have and soon will have more movies which bring down the <ent type='NORP'>Arabs</ent>.
(ie. the new <ent type='PERSON'>Sally Field</ent> movie, which is grossly exaggerated) Don't
forget who runs most of the TV networks and movie studios. So why do
so many people hate <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> (also known as <ent type='NORP'>Zionists</ent>, <ent type='NORP'>semitic</ent> people (not very
correctly though), <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent>ites, <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent>is) The answer to this question
is very simple. <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> believe that they are God's chosen people (they
honestly believe this, even though they will not admit it anymore directly) and that because they are so, then they are superior to all
other people. All others must work for <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, because no one else is
as gifted as they are. It is true that most <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> have above-average
intelligence, and that they are very handy and dexterous, and work hard
(but only for themselves) We are not denying this. What we detest is
their attitude that they are superior to us, and therefore we must
be their slaves. And they can do almost anything they want, because
they are the "chosen" ones. Because of this belief of theirs, <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>
along with their other attributes have been slowly and quietly taking
over the most important world systems. They cheat a lot; this is one
of their most distinguished characteristics. What we mean by cheat
is not just cheating, but taking advantage of the right opportunities
to gain their objectives. They are extremely well-known for their
"money habits". They take advantage of less qualified peoples, using
them knowingly. They help mostly only themselves, and have very close
ties with each other. (they even have their owns BBs's, just look inside Computer Currents) Because of this connections, they can get
things done easily. If a <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent> needs job, no problem. There are other
<ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> in all the top job areas, who will right away hire him/her first
over others. They have extremely high-level propaganda machinery;
many TV and radio commentators are <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, many reporters, book writers,
and magazines are <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent>. AND very importantly, the many publications
companies are run by <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>. If you have any doubts, just do some
research. It might take you a while, but you will find out that, yes,
it is true. And these people are ALL over the world: <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>USA</ent>,
England, <ent type='GPE'>Canada</ent>, spread over in S. <ent type='NORP'>American</ent>, all over Europe, <ent type='GPE'>USSR</ent>,
etc etc. They are practically in the highest-level positions all over
the world. And they use their clear advantage to continually gain
more and more power. The <ent type='LOC'>Middle East</ent> is the last bastion of true
anti-<ent type='NORP'>Zionism</ent>. God only knows what would happen if they were to take
over the <ent type='LOC'>Middle East</ent> and its oil too. They already have the biggest
banks, corporations, communications systems, etc in the world. All
they need now is oil. And all throughout the ages, they have been
doing the same thing, and when successful, suppressing all opposing
views. Now they have finally succeeded in turning the whole world
against <ent type='GPE'>Iraq</ent>, the 2nd biggest anti-<ent type='NORP'>Zionist</ent> country in the world. This
of course, has been done in an indirect manner, and has taken them a
lot of time. But it has worked. Once <ent type='PERSON'>Saddam</ent> is ousted, thanks to
our soldiers and money, they will then begin to slowly get control of
the region. There is still <ent type='GPE'>Iran</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Syria</ent>, and other countries, but they
can be taken care of too. It will not be easy for them, because the
<ent type='NORP'>Arabs</ent> are tremendous anti-semites, and they are willing to do anything
to stop the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>. But, with the US, <ent type='GPE'>Britain</ent>, and other countries
helping them, the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> will have all the support they need to accomplish their goals. And all because these countries are practically
run by <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>. So please, become more informed on this subject. Read
more books, newspapers, etc. about these people, making DEAD sure
that they are not written by <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> authors, or published by <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent>
publication companies, or third-party <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent>-influenced writers.
We must stop these people from controlling the world. We don't want
to kill them or hurt them, we want to let them know that they are
not superior to us, they are not God's chosen people, and that they
cannot do whatever they want. Please, help us out. Spread these
files around, call your senators and representatives, read more
about this stuff, etc. <ent type='NORP'>JEWS</ent> MUST BE STOPPED... NOW!</p>

<p> <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> Anti-<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> League
--------------------------- </p>

<p>How would you like it if another peoples, with greater military capability
and more money came to <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States and started to control it. If
they began to put strict restrictions on everything you did, and started
to take away your rights. If they set curfews, so that you couldn't
come outside at times, and refused to let you go wherever you wanted.
If they refused to allow you to celebrate certain holidays. If they put
down all opposition brutally, killing anyone who disobeyed their rules.
And to top if off, they were supported by the biggest military in the
world. You could do nothing about it. Nothing. All tries have been
put down by force. Anything you have done has ended in your people
being killed or injured. How would you feel? Be honest now. Well,
this is exactly what is happening in <ent type='GPE'>Palestine</ent> now. It's even worse
than this. There is no way to describe it. The only way to do so is
to sit down for a few minutes and imagine people coming into your
town and suddenly taking control of it. You have to do everything
they tell you to. If you go out and protest, they will injure you. If
you get violent, they will kill you, saying that you have been wanted
for other offenses as well, and that you had done such and such.
And there is absolutely nothing that you can do. Many people outside
are talking about this, but no one is really doing anything about it.
It feels terrible, doesn't it? You are beginning to get really angry
now, that no one is listening to your cries. You try more violent
methods - nothing. So you decide the only way to make it known to
others is to use terrorist methods. You hijack a plane. Now the
whole world is against you. More <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> propaganda. You are called
a barbarian, uncivilized. Just throw a nuke on you, many say. So
what do you do? This is exactly what is happening to the <ent type='NORP'>Palestinian</ent>
people. Please, do something about it. Or at least, next time you
hear <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> propaganda, or some other <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> views, question
them, embarass them. Don't believe everything they say. Become
more informed. STOP THEM BEFORE IT'S TOO LATE!</p>

<p> <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> Anti-<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> League
---------------------------</p>

<p> Disclaimer - Any use of this info for illegal purposes is forbidden
and against the law. All of the info in this file is
only for your personal knowledge. If you use any of
this info in the process, the consequences are yours
and yours alone.</p>

<div> </div>

<p> Useful Addresses and Phone Numbers
----------------------------------</p>

<p>1. Consulate General of <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent>
220 <ent type='GPE'>Bush</ent>
<ent type='GPE'>San Francisco</ent>, CA.</p>

<p> (415) 398-8885</p>

<p> Open M-F 10am to 1pm</p>

<p>2. Adath <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent>
Rabbi <ent type='PERSON'>Jacob Traub</ent>
1851 <ent type='PERSON'>Noriega</ent></p>

<p> (415) 564-5665</p>

<p>3. Ahavat Shalom
150 Eureka</p>

<p> (415) 621-1020</p>

<p>4. <ent type='ORG'>Congregation</ent> Anshey Sfard
1500 Clement

(415) 752-4979</p>

<p>5. <ent type='ORG'>Congregation</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Beth</ent> <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent>-<ent type='NORP'>Judea</ent>
Rabbi <ent type='PERSON'>Herbert Morris</ent>
625 Brotherhood Way</p>

<p> (415) 586-8833</p>

<p>6. <ent type='ORG'>Congregation</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Beth</ent> Sholom
Rabbi <ent type='PERSON'>Alexander Graubart</ent>
14th Ave &amp; Clement</p>

<p> (415) 221-8736</p>

<p>7. <ent type='ORG'>Congregation</ent> B'Nai B'Rit Ha Mashiach
(415) 992-2079</p>

<p>8. <ent type='ORG'>Congregation</ent> B'<ent type='PERSON'>Nai Emunah</ent> (<ent type='NORP'>Conservative</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> - Give 'em HELL!)
Rabbi <ent type='PERSON'>Theodore</ent> R. Alexander
3595 Taraval</p>

<p> (415) 664-7373</p>

<p>9. <ent type='ORG'>Congregation</ent> B'Nai <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent> (also conservative)
Rabbi <ent type='PERSON'>Malcolm Cohen</ent>
1575 <ent type='PERSON'>Annie</ent></p>

<p> (415) 756-5430</p>

<p>10. <ent type='ORG'>Congregation</ent> Chevra Thilim
751 25th Ave

(415) 386-9570 </p>

<p>11. <ent type='ORG'>Congregation</ent> Emanu-El
199 Arguello Bl.

(415) 751-2535</p>

<p>12. <ent type='ORG'>Congregation</ent> Keneseth <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent>
1255 Post Suite 427

(415) 771-3420</p>

<p>13. <ent type='ORG'>Congregation</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Magain David</ent> Sephardim
351 4th Ave

(415) 752-9095</p>

<p>14. <ent type='ORG'>Congregation</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Ner Tamid</ent>
1250 Quintara</p>

<p> (415) 661-3383</p>

<p>15. <ent type='ORG'>Congregation</ent> Sherith <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent>
2266 <ent type='GPE'>California</ent></p>

<p> (415) 346-1720</p>

<p>16. Hillel Foundation
33 <ent type='GPE'>Banbury</ent> Dr.</p>

<p> (415) 333-4922</p>

<p>17. <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> Educational Center of SF
538 29th Ave</p>

<p> (415) 221-7045</p>

<p>18. <ent type='GPE'>United Synagogue</ent> of America
425 Divisadero
(415) 864-1051</p>

<p>Note - Some 42% of the problems of the US are a direct result of <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>. This
is not some hypothetical figure, it is thouroughly researched fact.
One of the main reasons our troops are in the <ent type='LOC'>gulf</ent> is <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent>. Why?
They run practically all the biggest TV networks, newspapers, radio
stations, higher posts, etc. in the <ent type='GPE'>USA</ent>. </p>

<p> <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> Anti-<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> League
---------------------------</p>

<p> UPDATE</p>

<p>So, now that <ent type='PERSON'>Saddam Hussein</ent> has fired Scud missiles into <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent>, and the
<ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> have shown restraint, they immediately expect something from us. Today
they asked for 13 billion more dollars (billion, not million). In addition
to this, they have asked for another $10 billion from other countries.
Why the hell do we have to send our tax dollars to them? Why? They have
everything they already need. They have a huge air force, many nuclear
weapons, an army, navy, and money. Why should we send them anything? If
we are going to send money to someone, there are many other needier nations
on this planet who have none of the above. Instead, we send this money to
a country which from its very beginning has caused trouble. Possibly, no
other country has ever caused so many problems for humankind in history.
These <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> pigs are now taking advantage of the circumstances to get many
of their ideas across, and thanks to <ent type='PERSON'>Saddam</ent>, they are being very successful. All the TV networks (most of which are run by <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> (many of the news
directors are <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent>, plus anchormen as well, such as <ent type='PERSON'>Ted Coppel</ent>, Larry
King, etc etc)) are interviewing <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> state figures, and asking them
favorable questions. <ent type='ORG'>CNN</ent> itself constantly interviews many <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> heads
of state. But very few <ent type='NORP'>Arab</ent> leaders/figures are interviews, and if done
so, not very rational figures are chosen so that people get the wrong
impression. (ie. those two <ent type='NORP'>Jordanian</ent> engineers on Nightline who do not
reflect the majority opinion of <ent type='NORP'>Arabs</ent>) All the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> pigs interviewed
have been saying: "Now the world knows what we have had to put up with
all these years", when in fact, it is exactly the opposite! It is what
the <ent type='NORP'>Arab</ent> people have had to put up with, especially the <ent type='NORP'>Palestinian</ent>s,
who unfortunately supported Saddam's aggression. This is truly sad,
because it has given the <ent type='NORP'>Palestinian</ent>s a very bad image, especially in
the <ent type='GPE'>USA</ent>. Many of you are probably saying, "Oh, those poor <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent>is,
look what they have to put up with. If <ent type='GPE'>San Francisco</ent> was bombed, I
would do the same too." And this is somewhat true; <ent type='PERSON'>Saddam</ent> is a brutal
dictator, and the only thing he has done is help the <ent type='NORP'>Zionist</ent> pigs.
So here we go again; we've given them <ent type='ORG'>Patriot</ent> missile systems (each
<ent type='ORG'>Patriot</ent> missile costs $1 million - this is your TAX money!) Now we're
about to give those pigs, who don't really need this money, another
$13 billion. Of course the <ent type='NORP'>Arab</ent> countries will see us with an evil
eye. Not only have we ignored them, but now we are putting the icing
on the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> cake. This is enfuriating them. The <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> are (they say
this, and it is true, but they also take advantage of inferior peoples.
Just trace <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> history) smart people, they are literate, have schools,
money, etc. Why can't they just get their own money? They practically
run a third of our country. Now, for restraining against immediate
attack (they will attack later though), they ask us for $13 billion.
This is an outrage! An absolute outrage! Our economy is going down,
we are cutting from health care, and from education, there are many
programs here that need money, and what do we do? We give those <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent>
pigs, who need the money less than we do, millions of dollars every
year. So that they can in return take advantage of our resources.
I plead with you that you do something about this. We have to stop
this. Many of the people who run the <ent type='GPE'>USA</ent> our <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>. Get them out
of their posts. Please, we must do something about this NOW, before
it's too late to even start something. Write letters. Ask people.
Inform yourselves. Read books (that are not biased - many of the
biggest publications companies are run by <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>) Spread this file
around as many bulletin boards as possible. Thank you for your
time.

</p></xml>