<xml><p>
Wrong Number BBS FILE NAME: <ent type='ORG'>BUSHBOMB</ent>.TXT </p>

<p> [Reproduced with permission from _The Spotlight_, June 22, 1992 </p>

<p> The Spotlight
300 Independence Avenue, SE
<ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, DC 20003 </p>

<p> Free use of this material is permitted provided that _The Spotlight_
is credited, including publisher's address] </p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>BUSH</ent> LINKED TO TERROR BOMBING; </p>

<p> WILL U.N. ASK FOR EXTRADITION?: </p>

<p> Shocking Evidence Revealed </p>

<p> The evidence pointing to President Bush's role in the terrorist bombing of
a <ent type='NORP'>Cuban</ent> airliner grows stronger with new revelations. Will the UN Security
Council demand his extradition to <ent type='GPE'>Cuba</ent> or the <ent type='ORG'>World Court</ent>, as <ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent> and the
UN have done in the case of <ent type='NORP'>Libyan</ent> suspects in a similar crime? </p>

<p> By Warren Hough
Exclusive to The Spotlight </p>

<p> <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, DC, 6/12/92 -- Long-suppressed records have turned up
"shattering" new evidence of the role played by President George <ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent> in
the <ent type='ORG'>midair</ent> bombing of a <ent type='NORP'>Cuban</ent> airliner and in its subsequent cover-up,
<ent type='NORP'>Latin American</ent> officials conducting a "preliminary review" of the tragic
incident have told the UN Security Council.
The secret files reportedly confirm that in mid-1976, while serving as
<ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> chief, <ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent> was in "overall command" of a botched sabotage operation
that ended in the crash of a <ent type='NORP'>Cuban</ent> passenger jet, killing all 73 aboard,
The SPOTLIGHT has learned from diplomatic sources close to the
investigation.
A <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> agent identified as <ent type='PERSON'>Luis Posada</ent> was arrested by <ent type='NORP'>Venezuelan</ent>
authorities shortly after the <ent type='NORP'>Cuban</ent> plane exploded in <ent type='ORG'>midair</ent> during its
takeoff from a <ent type='LOC'>Caribbean</ent> stopover, these sources say. <ent type='PERSON'>Posada</ent>, a member of
a sizable <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> contingent conducting covert operations from <ent type='NORP'>Venezuelan</ent> bases
at the time, was charged with having smuggled an explosive device aboard
the flight, and held for trial.
<ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent>, anxious to disclaim all responsibility for such an atrocious
terrorist outrage, ordered a "no-holds-barred" cover-up of the crime, the
record suggests.
"In order to take the heat off <ent type='PERSON'>Posada</ent>, the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> targeted another
suspect, Dr. <ent type='ORG'>Orlando Bosch</ent>, a militant <ent type='NORP'>Cuban</ent> exile activist who advocated
'armed action' against the <ent type='PERSON'>Castro</ent> dictatorship," recounted <ent type='PERSON'>Felipe Rivero</ent>,
the popular <ent type='GPE'>Miami</ent> broadcaster who is The SPOTLIGHT's correspondent in the
region."
Venezuela's secret police, known after its <ent type='NORP'>Spanish</ent> initials as DISIP,
maintained close relations with the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> and followed its lead. <ent type='ORG'>Bosch</ent> was
imprisoned and charged with complicity in the bombing in <ent type='GPE'>Venezuela</ent>. </p>

<p> <ent type='PERSON'>BUSH</ent> ORCHESTRATION </p>

<p> The next move in the cover-up reportedly orchestrated by <ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent> was to
"recover" <ent type='PERSON'>Posada</ent>, these sources day. In a well-organized and lavishly
financed jailbreak, the alleged aerial bomber was spirited from <ent type='GPE'>Venezuela</ent>
to <ent type='GPE'>Panama</ent>, where the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> issued him a new set of identity documents under
the name of Ramon Medina, a <ent type='NORP'>Guatemalan</ent> businessman.
In the concluding move of the cover-up, <ent type='PERSON'>Posada</ent>, now known as "Medina,"
was handed over to <ent type='PERSON'>Felix Rodriguez</ent>, a senior <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> field agent with whom <ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent>
had a personal working relationship, the record shows. <ent type='PERSON'>Rodriguez</ent> gave
<ent type='PERSON'>Posada</ent> a series of covert jobs with <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> teams stationed in <ent type='LOC'>Central America</ent>,
largely in order to protect him and "keep him happy," these sources
related.
"I, for my part, spent 11 years in various maximum security <ent type='NORP'>Venezuelan</ent>
prisons," <ent type='ORG'>Bosch</ent> told a SPOTLIGHT reporter during a recent telephone
interview. "During those years, I was put on trial four times for that
airplane bombing. My case was heard by military, civilian and appellate
courts. I was found innocent each time. But after each acquittal, the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>
came up with new 'suggestions' about my guilt." </p>

<p> PALE AND FRAIL </p>

<p> Finally the <ent type='NORP'>Venezuelan</ent> government told <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent> it could no longer
hold <ent type='ORG'>Bosch</ent>. Pale and in frail health, the falsely accused "terrorist" was
flown back to <ent type='GPE'>Miami</ent>. "Here I could hope for no acquittal," recounted
<ent type='ORG'>Bosch</ent>. "At the airport, immigration officials threw me into chains. I was
held in solitary confinement for 29 months."
Finally granted a provisional release after leading <ent type='NORP'>Cuban</ent>-<ent type='NORP'>American</ent>
<ent type='NORP'>Republicans</ent> pressed his cause without letup, <ent type='ORG'>Bosch</ent> now lives in seclusion
near <ent type='GPE'>Miami</ent>. "My status is that of a 'deportable' alien," he told The
SPOTLIGHT. "If I engage in any political activity, or even if I talk too
much, I can be tossed back into jail. I am in no position to comment on
controversial questions -- not even in my own cause."
Living under the assumed name and a small <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> paycheck in Central
America also proved difficult for <ent type='PERSON'>Posada</ent>, SPOTLIGHT correspondent <ent type='PERSON'>Rivero</ent>
reports. "A couple of years ago, two men walked up to <ent type='PERSON'>Posada</ent> in a
<ent type='NORP'>Guatemalan</ent> restaurant and shot him five times," <ent type='PERSON'>Rivero</ent> related. "He
survived the shooting by a sheer miracle. Badly injured -- he lives
largely on liquefied food and walks with a crutch, I hear -- he has
vanished into the 'protective custody' of the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>."
The reason for Posada's attempted assassination is known, however. He
"drank a bit and began to talk too much," U.N. sources said. "The <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>
needed an airtight cover-up of that airline bombing. When <ent type='PERSON'>Posada</ent> turned
talkative, his usefulness to <ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent> was at an end -- and, but for an iron
physique and that miraculous survival, he would have been, too."
Now the U.N. Security Council, having assumed jurisdiction over such
international terrorist crimes when it clamped harsh sanctions on <ent type='GPE'>Libya</ent>
last April, faces a tougher challenge: How to deal with a case of aerial
mass murder in which the principal suspect happens to be THE INCUMBENT
PRESIDENT OF <ent type='GPE'>THE UNITED STATES</ent>. </p>

</xml>