<xml><p>
*** The "Liberation of the Camps": FACTS vs. LIES ***</p>

<p> By <ent type='PERSON'>Theodore</ent> J. O'Keefe
_______________________________________________________________________________</p>

<p> Nothing has been more effective in establishing the authenticity of the <ent type='EVENT'>Holocaust</ent> in the minds of <ent type='NORP'>Americans</ent> than the terrible scenes U.S. GI's discovered when they entered the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> concentration camps at the close of <ent type='EVENT'>World War</ent> II.</p>

<p> At <ent type='LOC'>Dachau</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Buchenwald</ent>, Dora, Mauthausen, and other work and detention camps, horrified <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> infantrymen encountered heaps of dead and dying inmates, emaciated and diseased. Survivors told them hair-raising stories of torture and slaughter, and backed up their claims by showing the GI's crematory ovens, alleged gas chambers, supposed implements of torture, even shrunken heads and lampshades, gloves, and handbags purportedly made from skin flayed from dead inmates.</p>

<p> U.S. government authorities, mindful that most <ent type='NORP'>Americans</ent>, who remembered the atrocity stories fed them during <ent type='EVENT'>World War</ent> I, still doubted the <ent type='ORG'>Allied</ent> propaganda directed against the <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> regime, resolved to "document" what the GI's had found in the camps. Prominent newsmen and politicians were flown in to see the harrowing evidence, while the U.S. <ent type='ORG'>Army</ent> Signal Corps filmed and photographed the scenes for posterity. The famous journalist <ent type='PERSON'>Edward</ent> R. <ent type='PERSON'>Murrow</ent> reported, in tones of horror, but no longer of disbelief, what he had been told and shown, and <ent type='LOC'>Dachau</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Buchenwald</ent> were branded on the hearts and minds of the <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> populace as names of infamy unmatched in the sad and bloody history of this planet.</p>

<p> For <ent type='NORP'>Americans</ent>, what was "discovered" at the camps - the dead and the diseased, the terrible stories of the inmates, all the props of torture and terror - became the basis not simply of a transitory propaganda campaign but of the conviction that yes, it was true: the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>s DID exterminate six million <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, most of them in lethal gas chambers. What the GI's found was used, by way of films which were mandatory viewing for the vanquished populace of <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y, to "re-educate" the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> people b
destroying their national pride and their will to a united, independant national state, imposing in their place overwhelming feelings of collective guilt and political impotence. And when the testimony, and the verdict, at <ent type='GPE'>Nuremberg</ent> incorporated mos, if not all, of the horror stories <ent type='NORP'>Americans</ent> were told about <ent type='LOC'>Dachau</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Buchenwald</ent>, and other places captured by the U.S. <ent type='ORG'>Army</ent>, the <ent type='EVENT'>Holocaust</ent> could pass for one of the most documented, one of the most authenticated, one of the most proven historical episodes in the human record.</p>

<p> A Different Reality</p>

<p>* But it is known today that, very soon after the liberation of the *
* camps, <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> authorities were aware that the real story of the camps *
* was quite different from the one in which they were coaching military *
* public information officers, government spokesmen, politicians, *
* journalists, and other mouthpieces. *</p>

<p> When <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> and <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> forces overran western and central <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y in the spring of 1945, they were followed by troops charged with discovering and securing any evidence of <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> war crimes. Among them was Dr. <ent type='PERSON'>Charles Larson</ent>, one of America's
leading forensic pathologists, who was assigned to the Judge Advocate General's Department. Dr. <ent type='ORG'>Larson</ent> performed autopsies at <ent type='LOC'>Dachau</ent> and some twenty other <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> camps, examining on some days more than 100 corpses. After his grim work at <ent type='LOC'>Dachau</ent>, he was questioned for three days by U.S. <ent type='ORG'>Army</ent> prosecutors.^1</p>

<p> Dr. Larson's findings? According to an interview he gave to an <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> journalist in 1980, "What we've heard is that six million <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> were exterminated. Part of that is a hoax."^2 And what part was the hoax? Dr. <ent type='ORG'>Larson</ent>, who told his biographer that to his knowledge he "was the only forensic pathologist on duty in the entire European Theater,"^3 informed "<ent type='ORG'>Wichita Eagle</ent>" reporter <ent type='PERSON'>Jan Floerchinger</ent> that "never was a case of poison gas uncovered."^4 Neither Dr. <ent type='ORG'>Larson</ent> nor any other forensic specialist has ever been cited by any <ent type='EVENT'>Holocaust</ent> historian to substantiate a single case of death by poison gas, whether <ent type='ORG'>Zyklon</ent>-B or any other variety.</p>

<p> <ent type='PERSON'>Typhus</ent>, Not Poison Gas</p>

<p> If not by gassing, how did the unfortunate victims at <ent type='LOC'>Dachau</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Buchenwald</ent>, and Bergen-<ent type='PERSON'>Belsen</ent> perish? Were they tortured to death? Deliberately starved? The answers to these questions are known as well. As Dr. <ent type='ORG'>Larson</ent> and other <ent type='ORG'>Allied</ent> medical men discovered, the chief cause of death at <ent type='LOC'>Dachau</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Belsen</ent>, and the other camps was disease, above all typhus, an old and terrible scourge of mankind which until recently flourished in places where populations were crowded together in circumstances where public health measures were unknown or had broken down. Such was the case in the overcrowded internment camps in <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y at war's end, where, despite such measures as systematic delousing, quarantine of the sick, and cremation of the dead, the virtual collapse of <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y's food, transport, and public health systems led to catastrophe.</p>

<p> Perhaps the most authoritative statement of the facts as to typhus and mortality in the camps has been made by Dr. <ent type='PERSON'>John</ent> E. <ent type='PERSON'>Gordon</ent>, M.D., Ph.D., a professor of preventive medicine and epidemiology at <ent type='ORG'>the Harvard University School</ent> of Public Health
who was with U.S. forces in <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y in 1945. Dr. <ent type='PERSON'>Gordon</ent> reported in 1948 that "The outbreaks in concentration camps and prisons made up the great bulk of typhus infection encountered in <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y." Dr. <ent type='PERSON'>Gordon</ent> summarized the causes for the outbreaks as
follows:</p>

<div> * * *</div>

<p> <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y was in chaos. The destruction of whole cities and the path left by advancing armies produced a disruption of living conditions contributing to the spread of the disease. <ent type='ORG'>Sanitation</ent> was low grade, public utilities were seriously disrupted
food supply and food distribution was poor, housing was inadequate and order and discipline were everywhere lacking. Still more important, a shifting of populations was occurring such as few countries and few times have experienced.^5</p>

<div> * * *</div>

<p> Dr. Gordon's findings are corroborated by Dr. <ent type='PERSON'>Russel Barton</ent>, today a psychiatrist of international repute, who entered Bergen-<ent type='PERSON'>Belsen</ent> with <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> forces as a young medical student in 1945. <ent type='PERSON'>Barton</ent>, who volunteered to care for the diseased survivors, testified under sworn oath in a <ent type='GPE'>Toronto</ent> courtroom in 1985 that "Thousands of prisoners who died at the Bergen-<ent type='PERSON'>Belsen</ent> concentration camp during <ent type='EVENT'>World War</ent> II weren't deliberately starved to death but died from a rash of diseases."^6 Dr. <ent type='PERSON'>Barton</ent> further testified that on entering the camp he had credited stories of deliberate starvations but had decided such stories were untrue after inspecting the well-equipped kitchens and the meticulously maintained ledgers, dating back to 1942, of food cooked and dispensed each day. Despite noisily publicized claims and widespread popular notions to the contrary, no researcher has been able to document a <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> policy of extermination through starvation in the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> camps.</p>

<p> No Lampshades, No Handbags, Etc.</p>

<p> What of the ghoulish stories of concentration camp inmates skinned for their tattoos, flayed to make lampshades and handbags, or other artifacts? What of the innumerable "torture racks," "meathooks," whipping posts, gallows, and other tools of torment and death that are reported to have abounded at every <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> camp? These allegations, and even more grotesque ones profferred by <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> prosecutors, found their way into the record at <ent type='GPE'>Nuremberg</ent>.</p>

<p> The lampshade and tattooed-skin charges were made against <ent type='PERSON'>Ilse Koch</ent>, dubbed by journalists the "Bitch of <ent type='GPE'>Buchenwald</ent>," who was reported to have furnished her house with objects manufactured from the tanned hides of luckless inmates. But General <ent type='PERSON'>Lucius Clay</ent>, military governor of the U.S. zone of occupied <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y, who reviewed her case in 1948, told his superiors in <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>: "There is no convincing evidence that she [<ent type='PERSON'>Ilse Koch</ent>] selected inmates for extermination in order to secure tattooed sins or that she possessed any articles made of human skin."^7 In an interview General <ent type='PERSON'>Clay</ent> gave years later, he stated about the material for the infamous lampshades: "Well, it turned out actually that it was goat flesh. But at the trial it was still
human flesh. It was almost impossible for her to have gotten a fair trial."^8 <ent type='PERSON'>Ilse Koch</ent> hanged herself in a West <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> jail in 1967.</p>

<p> It would be tedius to itemize and refute the thousands of bizarre claims as to <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> atrocities. That there were instances of <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> cruelty, however, is clear from the testimony of Dr. <ent type='PERSON'>Konrad Morgen</ent>, a legal investigator attached to <ent type='ORG'>the Reich Criminal Police</ent>, whose statements on the witness stand at <ent type='GPE'>Nuremberg</ent> have never been challenged by believers in the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> <ent type='EVENT'>Holocaust</ent>. Dr. <ent type='PERSON'>Morgen</ent> informed the court that he had been given full authority by <ent type='PERSON'>Heinrich Himmler</ent>, commander of Hitler's SS and th
dread <ent type='ORG'>Gestapo</ent>, to enter any <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> concentration camp and investigate instances of cruelty and corruption on the part of the camp staffs. According to Dr. Morgen's sworn testimony at <ent type='GPE'>Nuremberg</ent>, he investigated 800 such cases, in which over 200 convictions resulted.^9 Punishments included the death penalty for the worst offenders, including <ent type='PERSON'>Hermann Karl Koch</ent>, Ilse's husband, commandant of <ent type='GPE'>Buchenwald</ent>.</p>

<p> In reality, while camp commandants in certain cases did inflict physical punishment, such acts had to be approved by authorities in <ent type='GPE'>Berlin</ent>, and it was required that a camp physician first certify the good health of the prisoner to be disciplined
and then be on hand at the actual beating.^10 After all, the camps were throughout most of the war important centers of industrial activity. The good health and morale of the prisoners was critical to the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> war effort, as is evidenced by a 1942
order issued by SS-Brigadefuhrer <ent type='PERSON'>Richard Glucks</ent>, chief of the office which controlled the concentration camps, which held camp commanders "personally responsible for exhausting every possibility to preserve the physical strength of the detainees."^11</p>

<p> Concentration Camp Survivors - Merely Victims?</p>

<p> U.S. <ent type='ORG'>Army</ent> investigators, working at <ent type='GPE'>Buchenwald</ent> and other camps, quickly ascertained what was common knowledge among veteran inmates: that the worst offenders, the cruelest denizens of the camps were not the guards but the prisoners themselves. Common criminals of the same stripe as those who populate U.S. prisons today committed many <ent type='GPE'>villainies</ent>, particularly when they held positions of authority, and fanatical <ent type='NORP'>Communists</ent>, highly organized to combat their many political enemies among the inmates, eliminated their foes with <ent type='NORP'>Stalinist</ent> ruthlessness.</p>

<p> Two U.S. <ent type='ORG'>Army</ent> investigators at <ent type='GPE'>Buchenwald</ent>, Egon W. <ent type='PERSON'>Fleck</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Edward</ent> A. <ent type='ORG'>Tenenbaum</ent>, carefully investigated circumstances in the camp before its liberation. In a detailed report submitted to their superiors, they revealed, in the words of <ent type='PERSON'>Alfred Tombs</ent>, their commander, who wrote a preface to the report, "how the prisoners themselves organized a deadly terror within the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> terror."^12</p>

<p> <ent type='PERSON'>Fleck</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>Tenenbaum</ent> described the power exercised by criminals and <ent type='NORP'>Communists</ent> as follows:
* * *</p>

<p>. . . The <ent type='ORG'>trusties</ent>, who in time became almost exclusively <ent type='NORP'>Communist</ent> <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>s, had the power of life and death over all other inmates. They could sentence a man or a group to almost certain death . . . The <ent type='NORP'>Communist</ent> <ent type='ORG'>trusties</ent> were directly responsible for a large part of the brutalities at <ent type='GPE'>Buchenwald</ent>.</p>

<div> * * *</div>

<p> Colonel <ent type='PERSON'>Donald</ent> B. <ent type='PERSON'>Robinson</ent>, chief historian of the <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> military government in <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y, summarized the <ent type='PERSON'>Fleck</ent>-<ent type='ORG'>Tenenbaum</ent> report in an article which appeared in "The <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Mercury</ent>" shortly after the war. Colonel <ent type='PERSON'>Robinson</ent> wrote succinctly of
the <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> investigators' findings: "It appeared that the prisoners who agreed with the <ent type='NORP'>Communists</ent> ate; those who didn't starved to death."^13</p>

<p> Additional corroboration of inmate brutality has been provided by <ent type='PERSON'>Ellis</ent> E. Spackman, who, as Chief of Counter-Intelligence Arrests and Detentions for the Seventh U.S. <ent type='ORG'>Army</ent>, was involved in the liberation of <ent type='LOC'>Dachau</ent>. Spackman, later a professor of
history at San Bernardino Valley College in <ent type='GPE'>California</ent>, wrote in 1966 that at <ent type='LOC'>Dachau</ent> "the prisoners were the actual instruments that inflicted the barbarities on their fellow prisoners."^14</p>

<p> "Gas Chambers"</p>

<p> On December 9, 1944 Col. <ent type='PERSON'>Paul Kirk</ent> and Lt. Col. <ent type='PERSON'>Edward</ent> J. <ent type='PERSON'>Gully</ent> inspected the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> concentration camp at <ent type='PERSON'>Natzweiler</ent> in <ent type='GPE'>Alsace</ent>. They reported their findings to their superiors at the headquarters of the U.S. 6th <ent type='ORG'>Army</ent> Group, which subsequently forwarded <ent type='PERSON'>Kirk</ent> and Gully's report to <ent type='ORG'>the War Crimes Division</ent>. While, significantly, the full text of their report has never been published, it has been revealed, by an author supportive of <ent type='EVENT'>Holocaust</ent> claims, that the two investigators were careful to characterize equipment exhibited to them by <ent type='NORP'>French</ent> informants as a "SO-CALLED lethal gas chamber," and claim it was "<ent type='ORG'>ALLEGEDLY</ent> used as a lethal gas chamber"^15 [emphasis added].</p>

<p> Both the careful phraseology of the <ent type='PERSON'>Natzweiler</ent> report, and its effective suppression, stand in stark contrast to the credulity, the confusion, and the blaring publicity which accompanied official reports of alleged gas chambers at <ent type='LOC'>Dachau</ent>. At first, a U.S. <ent type='ORG'>Army</ent> photo depicting a GI gazing mournfully at a steel door marked with a skull and crossbones and the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> words for: "Caution! Gas! Mortal danger! Don't open!" was identified as showing the murder weapon. Later, however, it was evidently
decided that the apparatus in question was merely a standard delousing chamber for clothing, and another alleged gas chamber, this one cunningly disguised as a shower room, was exhibited to <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> congressmen and journalists as the site where thousands breathed their last. While there exist numerous reports in the press as to the operation of this second "gas chamber," no official report by trained <ent type='ORG'>Army</ent> investigators has yet surfaced to reconcile such problems as the function of the shower heads: Were they "dummies," or did lethal cyanide gas stream through them? (Each theory has appreciable support in journalistic and historiographical literature.)</p>

<p> As with <ent type='LOC'>Dachau</ent>, so with <ent type='GPE'>Buchenwald</ent>, Bergen-<ent type='PERSON'>Belsen</ent>, and the other camps captured by the <ent type='ORG'>Allies</ent>. There was no end of propaganda about "gas chambers," "gas ovens," and the like, but so far not a single detailed description of the murder weapon and its function, not a single report of the kind that is mandatory for the successful prosecution of any assault or murder case in <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> at the time and today, has come to light.</p>

<p> Furthermore, a number of <ent type='EVENT'>Holocaust</ent> authorities have now publicly decreed that there were no gassings, no extermination camps in <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y after all! All these things, we are told, were located in what is now <ent type='GPE'>Poland</ent>, in areas captured by the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent>
Red <ent type='ORG'>Army</ent> and off-limits to <ent type='NORP'>Western</ent> investigators. In 1960 Dr. <ent type='PERSON'>Martin Broszat</ent>, who is now director of the <ent type='GPE'>Munich</ent>-based <ent type='ORG'>Institute for Contemporary History</ent>, which is funded by the West <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> government to SUPPORT the <ent type='EVENT'>Holocaust</ent> story, wrote a letter to
he <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> weekly "Die <ent type='ORG'>Zeit</ent>" in which he stated categorically: "Neither in <ent type='LOC'>Dachau</ent> nor in Bergen-<ent type='PERSON'>Belsen</ent> nor in <ent type='GPE'>Buchenwald</ent> were <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> or other prisoners gassed."^16 Professional <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>-hunter <ent type='PERSON'>Simon Wiesenthal</ent> wrote in 1975 that "there were no extermination
camps on <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> soil."^17 And <ent type='LOC'>Dachau</ent> "gas chamber" No. 2, which was once presented to a stunned and grieving world as a weapon which claimed hundreds of thousands of lives, is now described in the brochure issued to tourists at the modern <ent type='LOC'>Dachau</ent> "memorial site" in these words: "This gas chamber, camouflaged as a shower room, was not used."^18</p>

<p> The Propaganda Intensifies</p>

<p> More than forty years after <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> troops entered <ent type='LOC'>Dachau</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Buchenwald</ent>, and the other <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> camps, and trained <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> investigators established the facts as to what had gone on in them, the government in <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, the entertainment media in
<ent type='GPE'>Hollywood</ent>, and the print media in <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent> continue to churn out millions of words and images annually on the horrors of the camps and the infamy of the <ent type='EVENT'>Holocaust</ent>. Despite the fact that, with the exception of the defeated Confederacy, no enemy of <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> has ever so suffered so complete and devestating defeat as did <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y in 1945, the mass media and the politicians and bureaucrats behave as if <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent>, his troops, and his concentration camps continue to exist in an eternal present, and our opinion makers continue to distort, through ignorance or malice, the facts about the camps.</p>

<p> Time for the Truth</p>

<p> It is time that the government and the professional historians revealed the facts about <ent type='LOC'>Dachau</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Buchenwald</ent>, and the other camps. It is time that they let the <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> public know how the inmates died, and how they didn't die. It is time that the
claims as to mass murder by gassing were clarified and investigated in the same manner as any other claims of murder are dealt with. It is time that the free ride certain groups have enjoyed as the result of unchallenged <ent type='EVENT'>Holocaust</ent> claims be terminate, just as it is time that other groups, including <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>s, eastern Europeans, the <ent type='NORP'>Roman Catholic</ent> hierarchy, and the wartime leadership of <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Britain</ent> stop being scapegoated, either for their alleged role in the <ent type='EVENT'>Holocaust</ent> or their supposed failure to stop it.</p>

<p> Above all, it is time that the citizens of this great democratic Republic have the facts about the camps, facts which they possess a right to know, a right that is fundamental to the exercise of their authority and their will in the governance o
their country. As citizens and as taxpayers, <ent type='NORP'>Americans</ent> of all ethnic backgrounds, of all faiths, have a basic right and an overriding interest in determining the facts of incidents which are deemed by those in positions of power to be determinative in America's foreign policy, in its educational policy, in its selection of past events to be memorialized in our civic life. The alleged facts of the <ent type='EVENT'>Holocaust</ent> are today at issue all over the civilized world: in <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y, in <ent type='GPE'>France</ent>, in <ent type='GPE'>Italy</ent>, in <ent type='GPE'>Britain</ent>, in the Low Countries and Scandinavia, in <ent type='GPE'>Japan</ent>, across our border in <ent type='GPE'>Canada</ent> and in <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States of <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> itself. The truth will be decided only by recourse to the facts, in the public forum: not by concealing the facts, denying the truth, stonewalling reality. The truth will out, and it is time the government of this country, and governments and international bodies throughout the world, made public and patent the evidence of what actually transpired in the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> concentration camps in
the years 1933-1945, so that we may put paid to the lies, without fear or favor, and carry out the work of reconciliation and renewal that is and must be the granite foundation of mutual tolerance between peoples and of a peace based on justice, rather than on guns, barbed wire, prisons, and lies.</p>

<p> NOTES</p>

<p> 1. _Crime Doctor_, a biography of <ent type='ORG'>Larson</ent> by <ent type='PERSON'>John</ent> D. McCallum, <ent type='GPE'>Mercer</ent>,
<ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent> &amp; <ent type='GPE'>Vancouver</ent>, <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> <ent type='GPE'>Columbia</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Canada</ent>, 1979, p. 69.</p>

<p> 2. _<ent type='ORG'>Wichita Eagle</ent>_, April 1, 1980, p. 4C.</p>

<p> 3. _Crime Doctor_, p. 46.</p>

<p> 4. _<ent type='ORG'>Wichita Eagle</ent>_, April 1, 1980, p. 4C.</p>

<p> 5. <ent type='PERSON'>John</ent> E. <ent type='PERSON'>Gordon</ent>, "Louse-Borne <ent type='PERSON'>Typhus</ent> Fever in the European Theater of
Operations, U.S. <ent type='ORG'>Army</ent>, 1945," in <ent type='ORG'>Forest</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Ray Moulton</ent>, Ed., _Rickettsial
Diseases of Man_, Am. Acad. for <ent type='ORG'>the Advancement</ent> of Science, <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent> D.C.
1948.</p>

<p> 6. _<ent type='GPE'>Toronto</ent> Star_, February 8, 1985, p. A2.</p>

<p> 7. _<ent type='GPE'>New York</ent> Times_, 24 September 1948, p. 3.</p>

<p> 8. Interview with <ent type='PERSON'>Lucius Clay</ent>, _Official Proceeding of the George C. Marshall
Research Foundation,_ cited in "<ent type='GPE'>Buchenwald</ent>: Legend and Reality," Mark
Weber, _<ent type='ORG'>The Journal</ent> of Historical Review_, Vol. 7, no. 4.</p>

<p> 9. International Military Tribunal, Vol. XVII, p. 556; IMT, Vol. XX, pp. 489,
438.</p>

<p>10. Cited in _The Theory and Practice of Hell_, <ent type='PERSON'>Eugen Kogon</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Berkley Books</ent>, New
York, pp. 108-109.</p>

<p>11. <ent type='GPE'>Nuremberg</ent> document NO-1523.</p>

<p>12. _<ent type='GPE'>Buchenwald</ent>: A Preliminary Report_, Egon W. <ent type='PERSON'>Fleck</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Edward</ent> A. <ent type='ORG'>Tenenbaum</ent>,
U.S. <ent type='ORG'>Army</ent>, 12th <ent type='ORG'>Army</ent> Group, 24 April 1945. <ent type='ORG'>National Archives</ent>, Record Group
331, <ent type='ORG'>SHAEF</ent>, G-5, 17.11, Jacket 10, Box 151 (8929/163-8929/180).</p>

<p>13. "<ent type='NORP'>Communist</ent> Atrocities at <ent type='GPE'>Buchenwald</ent>," <ent type='PERSON'>Donald</ent> B. <ent type='PERSON'>Robinson</ent>, in _<ent type='NORP'>American</ent>
<ent type='ORG'>Mercury</ent>_, October 1946.</p>

<p>14. _San Bernardino <ent type='LOC'>Sun</ent>-Telegram_, March 13, 1966 (cited in _The Man Who
Invented "Genocide"_, James J. Martin, Institute for Historical Review,
IHR, 1984, pp. 110-111.</p>

<p>15. _Concentration Camp at <ent type='GPE'>Natzwiller</ent> [sic]_, RG 331, Records of <ent type='ORG'>Allied</ent>
Operations and Occupation, <ent type='ORG'>Army</ent> Headquarters WW2, <ent type='ORG'>SHAEF</ent>/G-5/2717, Modern
Military, <ent type='ORG'>National Archives</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, D.C., cited in Robert H. Abzug,
_Inside the Vicious Heart_, <ent type='ORG'>Oxford University Press</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent>, 1985, p. 10,
p. 181.</p>

<p>16. _Die <ent type='ORG'>Zeit</ent>_, <ent type='GPE'>Hamburg</ent>, <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y, August 26, 1960.</p>

<p>17. _Books &amp; Bookmen_, April 1975, Vol. 7, p. 5.</p>

<p>18. Leaflet, _Memorial Site Concentration Camp <ent type='LOC'>Dachau</ent>_, <ent type='ORG'>The International</ent>
<ent type='LOC'>Dachau</ent>-Committee, <ent type='LOC'>Dachau</ent>, <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y, n.d.
_______________________________________________________________________________</p>

<p> <ent type='PERSON'>Theodore</ent> J. O'Keefe is the editor of "<ent type='ORG'>The Journal</ent> of Historical Review." Educated at <ent type='ORG'>Harvard</ent>, he has studied history and literature on three continents, and has published many articles on historical and political subjects.
_____________________________________________________________________________
The conclusions of the early U.S. <ent type='ORG'>Army</ent> investigations as to the
truth about the wartime <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> concentration camps have since been
corroborated by all subsequent investigators and can be summarized:
1. The harrowing scenes of dead and dying inmates were not the result of
a <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> policy of "extermination," but rather the result of epidemics of
typhus and other disease brought about largely by the effects of <ent type='ORG'>Allied</ent>
aerial attacks.
2. Stories of <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> supercriminals and sadists who turned <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> and others
into handbags and lampshades for their private profit or amusement were
sick lies or diseased fantasies; indeed, the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> authorities
consistently punished corruption AND cruelty on the part of camp
commanders and guards.
3. On the other hand, the representations of the newly liberated inmates
to have been saints and martyrs of <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent>ism were quite often very far
from the truth; indeed, most of the brutalities inflicted on camp
detainees were the work of their fellow prisoners, in contravention of
<ent type='NORP'>German</ent> policy and <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> orders.
4. The alleged homicidal showers and gas chambers had been used either
for bathing camp inmates or delousing their clothes; the claim that they
had been used to murder <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> or other human beings is a contemptible
fabrication. Orthodox, Establishment historians and professional "<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>-hunters" have quietly dropped claims that inmates were gassed at <ent type='LOC'>Dachau</ent>,
<ent type='GPE'>Buchenwald</ent>, and other camps in <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y. They continue, however, to keep
silent regarding the lies about <ent type='LOC'>Dachau</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Buchenwald</ent>, as well as to
evade an open discussion of the evidence for homicidal gassing at
Auschwitz and the other camps captured by the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent>s.
|_____________________________________________________________________________|</p>

<p> Send $2 for a packet of literature and a full listing of books, audio cassettes and videotapes. Or, order more copies of this leaflet, postpaid, at the following prices:
10 copies: $2
50 copies: $5
100 copies or more: 8 cents each
</p>
<p>
THE INSTITUTE FOR HISTORICAL REVIEW
1822 1/2 Newport Blvd., Suite 191
<ent type='GPE'>Costa Mesa</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>California</ent> 92627
</p></xml>