<xml><p>
Article: 569 of sgi.talk.ratical
From: dave@ratmandu.esd.sgi.com (dave "who can do? ratmandu!" ratcliffe)
Subject: Top Secret: How To Kill--"The CIA's <ent type='ORG'>Secret Weapons Systems</ent>"
Keywords: our culture has lost its moral, ethical, and spiritual foundations
Organization: Silicon Graphics, Inc.
Date: Wed, 8 Apr 1992 15:56:51 GMT
Lines: 321</p>

<p> unless we know MUCH MORE about the atrocities committed "in the interests
and name of 'national security,'" how can we possibly become sufficiently
motivated and driven to dedicate our energies towards changing this form
of "government" by lies, dissembling, expediency, profit-as-god, and
murder? we have no idea what is "done in our name." if we did, we would
no longer be able to participate in its commoditized seductiveness because
we would not be able to look ourselves in the mirror or sleep at night.
--ratitor</p>

<p> the following is taken from the June, 1978 issue of "Gallery" magazine:
__________________________________________________________________________
THE CIA'S SECRET WEAPONS SYSTEMS
by <ent type='PERSON'>Andrew Stark</ent></p>

<p> Exploding wine bottles, guns constructed out of pipes,
bullets made of teeth, aspirin explosives: they sound like
props from a second-rate spy story. <ent type='ORG'>Horrifyingly</ent> enough,
they are real. The <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> has spent a great deal of its time--
and your money--developing countless bizarre weapons for
assassination, sabotage, and mass destruction. If that's
news to you, it's because the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> doesn't want these
products, some of which are quite easy to put together, to
fall into the "wrong hands." As for whether they are in the
right hands now--judge for yourself.</p>

<p> The <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> has developed many exotic and sophisticated devices
intended for use in interrogation, sabotage, and assassination.
These weapons are necessary--if you grant that what the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> itself
does is necessary. If the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> wants to eliminate a key <ent type='ORG'>KGB</ent> agent
operating in Hungary, it faces certain problems. It would be
virtually impossible to slip a deadly weapon, such as a gun or
bomb, past Hungarian customs officials. Thus, the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> assassin
must assemble his weapon from commonly obtainable materials after
he crosses the border.
The <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> agent might decide to construct a urea nitrate
explosive, commonly known as a urine bomb. This weapon is quite
deadly, easily exploded, and consists primarily of nitric acid and
urine. The urine bomb is one of literally hundreds of murderous
weapons in the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> arsenal.
"<ent type='ORG'>The New York</ent> Times" of September 26, 1975 revealed the
existence of guns that shoot cobra-venom darts. Then there was the
shoe polish compound intended to make <ent type='PERSON'>Fidel Castro</ent>'s beard fall
out, so that he would lose his "charisma." And <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> laboratories in
<ent type='GPE'>Fort Monmouth</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>New Jersey</ent> developed the famous rifle that shoots
around corners.
Some <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> weapons are designed to kill many people--deadly germs
can be released in subways; others are intended to kill a single,
specific individual--the <ent type='PERSON'>Borgia</ent> ring contains deadly poison to be
slipped into a victim's drink; and still others are standard
weapons supplied for such missions as overthrowing the <ent type='PERSON'>Allende</ent>
government in <ent type='GPE'>Chile</ent> in 1973.
The information about <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> weapons that you will read in this
article generally has not been made public before. It was not
intended to be. But your tax dollars pay for these devices; it is
your right to know about them.
There is a booklet, written in 1977 and distributed to a select
group of U.S. mercenaries, titled "<ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> Improvised Sabotage
Devices." This instructional guidebook, part of "the Combat
Bookshelf," was published by <ent type='ORG'>Desert Publications</ent>, P.O. Box 22005,
<ent type='GPE'>Phoenix</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Arizona</ent> 85028. If you want to know how the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> turns a
cigar box into an explosive that can destroy a 10000-gallon
capacity storage tank, then "<ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Improvised Sabotage Devices</ent>" is
what you should read. You will need it if you want to build the
"Water-Drip Electric Delay," a bomb that requires little more than
wood scrap, a tin can, and a battery. The "<ent type='ORG'>Pocket Watch Electric</ent>
Delay" requires little more than a watch, a screw, and a battery.
The "Mousetrap Electric Release" is another bomb, this one
requiring a mousetrap, a trip wire, a battery, and little else. It
is described as "an excellent device to use with bazooka rockets
against trucks, tanks, or locomotives." The "Chemical
Instantaneous Initiator" is made from a sugar-chlorate mix and is
effective in sabotaging trains. The "<ent type='PERSON'>Martini Glass</ent> Shaped Charge"
is a bomb that also can be made out of a beer can. You might want
to try to construct the "<ent type='ORG'>Vehicle Booby Trap</ent>." The "Potassium
Chlorate and Sugar Igniter" and the "Sawdust, Moth Flakes, and Oil
Incendiary" can be made with only what you see in their titles.
For these and more than fifty other <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> devices, step-by-step
instructions on how to make them and illustrations of what they
should look like when completed are given. Turn a wine bottle into
a bomb. Build a land-mine rocket. Manufacture napalm in your
basement. Even the simple how-tos of causing a dust explosion can
be found in "<ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Improvised Sabotage Devices</ent>."
Why is the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> so deeply involved in sabotage techniques? The
<ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> might think it is in this country's interest to delay
scientific work being done by another nation. Or, the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> might
want to disrupt a nation's economy in the hope that the resulting
chaos will lead to civil unrest and the overthrow of the existing
government (some of this actually happened in <ent type='GPE'>Chile</ent>). The original
John <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> used such tactics against his competitors. He
simply had their refineries blown up.
Another pamphlet the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> would not like you to see is titled
"How to Kill," written by <ent type='PERSON'>John Minnery</ent>, edited by <ent type='PERSON'>Robert Brown</ent> and
<ent type='PERSON'>Peder Lund</ent>, and published by Paladin Press, Box 1307, <ent type='GPE'>Boulder</ent>,
<ent type='GPE'>Colorado</ent> 80306. The reason the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> would prefer that you not see
this eighty-eight-page pamphlet, which is unavailable at bookstores
and newsstands, is because it contains a number of "ingenious"
methods of doing what the title says. Also, Paladin Press, which
published a book called "<ent type='ORG'>OSS Sabotage and Demolition</ent> Manual," is
widely regarded by journalists as an organization with close ties
to mercenary groups and the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>. Paladin Press doesn't want you to
know that, but how else could they have published the "<ent type='ORG'>OSS</ent> Sabotage
and Demolition Manual?" <ent type='ORG'>The Office</ent> of Strategic Services was the
precursor of today's <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>.
This writer's call to <ent type='GPE'>Colorado</ent> yielded the following
conversation:</p>

<p> "How could you publish the "<ent type='ORG'>OSS Sabotage and Demolition</ent> Manual,"
I asked <ent type='PERSON'>Peter Lund</ent>, editor and publisher of Paladin Press, "if your
organization, at the least, was not dealing with former <ent type='ORG'>OSS</ent> agents?
And what about "How to Kill?"
"I don't talk to journalists," <ent type='PERSON'>Lund</ent> said.
"You're called the Paladin Press. You must publish books. Can
I order them?"
"No."
"Why not? You're a publisher, aren't you?"
"We're afraid our publications might fall into the wrong hands."
"What are the right hands?" I asked.
"I don't talk to journalists."
"Have you ever heard of <ent type='ORG'>Desert Publications</ent>?" I asked.
"A fine outfit," <ent type='PERSON'>Lund</ent> said. "If they recommend you, I'll send
you our material."
"That's my problem," I said. "They don't seem to have a phone
number."
"Well, they're a good group."
"Listen," I said, "wasn't your group, and <ent type='ORG'>Desert Publications</ent>
besides, involved in <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> mercenary activity in <ent type='LOC'>Africa</ent>?"
"I don't know anything about that."
"Were you in the Special Forces?"
"July 1967 to July 1968 in <ent type='GPE'>Vietnam</ent>."
"Were you <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>?"
"I was MACV [Military Armed Forces Command <ent type='GPE'>Vietnam</ent>]."
"You weren't affiliated with <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>?"
"I didn't say that."
"What do you say?"
"We did joint operations with <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> on the <ent type='GPE'>Phoenix</ent> Program."
"Wasn't that a murder operation?"
"No. It was snatching people."</p>

<p> The <ent type='GPE'>Phoenix</ent> Program was designed for a job that the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>
euphemistically described as "eliminating the <ent type='GPE'>Viet Cong</ent>
infrastructure." In reality, it was a rampant reign of terror run
out of <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> headquarters at <ent type='GPE'>Langley</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Virginia</ent>. Former <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> director
<ent type='PERSON'>William Colby</ent> later termed the program "effective." The <ent type='GPE'>Phoenix</ent>
Program was a naked murder campaign, as proved by every realistic
report, ranging from <ent type='ORG'>the Bertrand Russell Tribunal</ent> to the Dellums
Committee to admissions by <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> agents themselves. The program
killed--and *none* of these killings occurred in combat--18000
people, mostly women and children.
But what about <ent type='PERSON'>Peder Lund</ent>, editor and publisher of Paladin
Press? The book he edited and published, "How to Kill," outlined a
surfeit of murder methods, horrific techniques of causing people to
die. For example:
"Without getting too deeply into the realm of the bizarre,"
wrote <ent type='PERSON'>John Minnery</ent>, the author of "How to Kill" as he proceeded to
just that, "a specially loaded bullet made from a human tooth
(bicuspid) could be fired under the jaw or through the mouth into
the head. The tooth is a very hard bone, and its enamel shell
would allow it to penetrate into the brain. The intention here is
also to hide the cause of death because the examiner in his search
for a projectile will disregard bone fragments."
One last example from "How to Kill" should give you the flavor
of the book:</p>

<p> Lesson Nine: Hot Wire</p>

<p> "Essentially, the weapon is an electrified grid in the urinal
basin. This can take the form of a screen cover for the drain
or a metal grill. If the urinal is completely porcelain, the
screen must be added by the assassin. The drain cover is
connected to the electrical system of the washroom by means of
an insulated cord that is hidden behind the plumbing.
"What happens when the subject uses the urinal should be
obvious now. The subject's urine, which is a salty liquid and
a perfect conductor of electricity, makes contact with the
charged grid, and the shock will kill him."</p>

<p> This reporter's investigation revealed that the "Hot Wire" was
child's play compared to certain other <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> weapons devices. For
instance, I was able to obtain Volumes One and Two of the "<ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>
Black Book" on improvised munitions, volumes that are stamped "for
official use only" on almost every page. It is obvious why the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>
would like these books to remain secret. With elaborate
instructions, they describe how to make high explosives from
aspirin, how to construct a nail grenade, and how to turn a Coke
bottle into a bomb.
Described in detail in the "Black Book" is the previously
mentioned urea nitrate explosive, or, as it is known to the pros,
"the piss bomb." Instructions for the preparation of this weapon
assure the maker that animal urine will do as well as human; the
important thing is to have ten cups of it, boil it down to one cup,
and mix it with the nitric acid.
Also described in the "Black Book" is how to construct a pipe
pistol, which, as the name indicates, is a gun constructed out of a
pipe. Other weapons include a cooking syringe filled with poison
that can be stabbed into "the subject's" stomach; a cyanide gas
pistol; a throat cutter gauntlet knife (razor sharp and only an
inch or so in length); and a mixture of fertilizer and aluminum
powder that can be made into a powerful bomb.
Why build murder weapons out of such weird material? Is the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>
insane?
No. In its own way, the whole thing is perfectly logical.
The pamphlet "How to Kill" explained it all: "As most of these
devices are homemade, this precludes the possibility of their being
traced. They are, in effect, 'sanitized' and perfect for
assassinations, where weapons are prohibited, or where customs in
the hostile country are stringent, so these can be made from local
materials."
Being a contract killer for the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> is not all roses. You
cannot kill in just any way. A number of attempts have been made
on <ent type='PERSON'>Fidel Castro</ent>'s life--some with the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> and the <ent type='ORG'>Mafia</ent>
cooperating--and some of them may have failed because of
restrictions imposed on the potential assassins. It would be
unacceptable for Castro's murder to be laid at the door of the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>.
This would make <ent type='PERSON'>Castro</ent> a martyr in the eyes of his countrymen.
Thus, a method that would suggest death by natural causes must be
found.
Abundant speculation and considerable evidence suggest that the
<ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> or some other government agency arranged for the "natural"
deaths of <ent type='PERSON'>David Ferrie</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Jack Ruby</ent>, George De Mohrenschildt, and
other potential witnesses into the assassination of <ent type='PERSON'>John Kennedy</ent>.
Some methods of killing, like the injection of an air bubble into
the bloodstream, will often go unnoticed by medical examiners.
Another hard-to-trace method of killing is to mail a snake to
the victim. This is known as killing by long distance. A
disadvantage to this method is that the snake might bite an
innocent third party who just happens to open the package. The
advantage is that once the snake has struck, the evidence can
simply slither away.
Sometimes, as the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> knows, killing has to be done at close
range. For this purpose, a valuable weapon is the ice pick with a
blood arrester attached. The blood arrester is a cloth wrapped
near the tip of the ice pick. When the pick is shoved into the
victim, the spurting blood is absorbed by the blood arrester.
People who see the victim fall will probably think he has had a
heart attack. While the onlookers try to help the victim, the
assassin uses this valuable ten or fifteen seconds to escape
unnoticed.
Often it is advisable to use what is called in the trade a
"quiet weapon." Silenced weapons can include pistols, rifles, and
even machine guns.
Poison is a quiet killer. Here is a partial list of the poisons
the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> has become expert at administering: oil of bitter almonds;
ant paste; cadmium, used in vapor form, and death is delayed four
hours; radiator cleaner, also causing a delayed death;
Cantharides (<ent type='NORP'>Spanish</ent> Fly); ethyl mercury; and freon, heated by a
flame. These poisons and many others are listed in "How to Kill."
The author then cautions the reader:
"Unless otherwise stated, these poisons are either to be
injected into the subject, or taken orally by him by adding it to
his food. Use common sense in the application of these potions
and, if possible, double the O.D. necessary."
W.H. <ent type='PERSON'>Bowart</ent>, in his book, "Operation Mind Control" described the
CIA's use of drugs: "In 1953, the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> made plans to purchase ten
kilograms of LSD for use in 'drug experiments with animals and
human beings.' Since there are more than 10000 doses in a gram,
that meant the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> wanted 100 million doses. The <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> obviously
intended to 'corner the market' on LSD so that other countries
would not be ahead of the U.S. in their potential for 'LSD
warfare.'"
Dr. <ent type='PERSON'>Albert Hoffman</ent>, an early researcher into the uses of LSD,
was horrified by what the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> was doing: "I had perfected LSD for
medical use, not as a weapon. It can make you insane or even kill
you if it is not properly used under medical supervision. In any
case, the research should be done by medical people and not by
soldiers or intelligence agencies."
Perhaps the most frightening weapon of all is the one that can
be used to alter weather and climate. It was used with
considerable success in <ent type='GPE'>Vietnam</ent>. It slowed troop movements with
heavy rains, and it destroyed the rice crop, as well. The danger
is that these climatological changes may become permanent,
affecting not only enemies of <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States, but also the
entire planet.
Finally, considerable evidence exists that <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States,
through the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>, employed germ warfare during <ent type='EVENT'>the Korean War</ent>. A
number of captured pilots testified that germ warfare was used, but
their testimony was dismissed as brainwashing. A <ent type='ORG'>Marine Corps</ent>
colonel named <ent type='PERSON'>Frank</ent> H. <ent type='PERSON'>Schwable</ent> signed a germ warfare confession
and, according to W.H. <ent type='PERSON'>Bowart</ent>, "named names, cited missions,
described meetings and strategy conferences."
<ent type='PERSON'>Schwable</ent> later repudiated his confession. But the charges of
germ warfare were taken up in front of <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> Nations, and a
number of countries believed them.
<ent type='GPE'>The United</ent> States, incidentally, was later charged with using
nerve gas in <ent type='GPE'>Vietnam</ent>.
What you have read on these pages is pretty revolting stuff.
Yet, if the world ought to be saved from Communism, who can say it
is not necessary? One danger, of course, is that these terrible
weapons have been introduced into our body politic and have
produced strange and terrible fruits on our own native soil. When
assassination becomes government policy, when men are trained to
kill in every conceivable way, when morality is set aside for a
"higher good," can even the President of <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States consider
himself safe?</p>

<p> <ent type='PERSON'>Andrew Stark</ent> is a pseudonym for a specialist on weaponry.</p>

<p>--
daveus rattus </p>

<p> yer friendly neighborhood ratman</p>

<p> KOYAANISQATSI</p>

<p> ko.yan.nis.qatsi (from <ent type='EVENT'>the Hopi Language</ent>) n. 1. crazy life. 2. life
in turmoil. 3. life out of balance. 4. life disintegrating.
5. a state of life that calls for another way of living.</p></xml>