<xml><p>The following pamphlet was written in 1989 by a minister (now
deceased) who had the courage and inspiration to explain in
very simple and uncluttered language -- how it is that we
are presently being ENSLAVED and IMPOVERISHED by the current
"debt-usury banking system" that we have.</p>

<p>It was written for a predominately <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> audience (which may
or may not be your cup of tea), and some of the information
may be a little dated (the figures for the debt, for example,
have increased ast<ent type='PERSON'>ron</ent>omically since it was penned) but regardless
of that -- it is a clear and URGENT message that needs to be
listened to by the <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> people.</p>

<p>Keep in mind, also, that according to <ent type='PERSON'>William Cooper</ent> ("Behold
a Pale Horse" p. 80-81) -- in the year 1952, an alliance was
formed between all the various groups that are working for total
financial enslavement of the worlds' peoples: The <ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent>,
<ent type='ORG'>Knights</ent> of Malta, <ent type='NORP'>Freemasons</ent>, European and <ent type='ORG'>Continental Banking</ent>
Families, etc.. Thus, it is NOT any one group or subgroup of
this alliance (referred to as the "<ent type='ORG'>Bankers</ent>" in the text) that
is doing it to us. </p>

<p>There is no copyright to this information. Print out a copy and
share it with your friends!</p>

<p>-- JS</p>

<p>__________________________________________________________________________</p>

<p> BILLIONS FOR <ent type='ORG'>THE BANKER</ent>S AND <ent type='ORG'>DEBTS</ent> FOR THE <ent type='ORG'>PEOPLE</ent></p>
<p>A Study by Pastor <ent type='PERSON'>Sheldon Emry</ent></p>

<p> "For the love of money is the root of all evil..."
1 <ent type='PERSON'>Timothy</ent> 6:10
</p>

<p> Produced and Distributed by:</p>

<p> AMERICA'S PROMISE MINISTRIES
P.O. BOX 157
SANDPOINT, <ent type='ORG'>IDAHO</ent> 83864
</p>

<p> [There is NO COPYRIGHT on this information. Please re-post it freely
and widely. It needs to be in the hands of every <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> citizen!]

______________________________________________________________________
</p>
<p>

TABLE OF CONTENTS</p>

<p> INTRODUCTION

Love of Money...................i
Thomas Jefferson Quote...............ii
Three Types of Conquest.............iii</p>

<p> BILLIONS FOR <ent type='ORG'>THE BANKER</ent>S.................1

Money is Man's Only Creation................2
Money Creating Profitable.............3
Adequate Money Supply Needed................3
The <ent type='ORG'>Bankers</ent>' Depression of the 1930's.............3
Money For Peace or War?...............5</p>

<p> POWER TO COIN AND REGULATE MONEY...............6</p>

<p> HOW <ent type='ORG'>PEOPLE</ent> LOST CONTROL OF <ent type='ORG'>THE FEDERAL RESERVE</ent>.......6</p>

<p> More Disastrous Than <ent type='PERSON'>Pearl Harbor</ent>...........7
They Print It -- We Borrow It...............7
And There is More...............9
And There is Still More...............9</p>

<p> THE INTEREST AMOUNT IS NEVER CREATED..........10</p>

<p> Borrow $60000 and Pay Back $255931.............11
Small Loans....................11
<ent type='ORG'>Bankers</ent> Always Prosper...............12
The Cost to You................13
For the Gamblers...............14</p>

<p> YES, IT'S POLITICAL TOO!................15

<ent type='ORG'>Mounting Debts</ent> and Wars..............16
And There is More....................17</p>

<p> THE CONSTITUTIONAL WAY..................19

No <ent type='ORG'>Bankers</ent>' Plunder..................21
Stable Money...................22
Citizen Control................23
A Debt-Free <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>..................24</p>

<p> WHY HAVEN'T WE KNOWN....................25</p>

<p> Controlled News................25</p>

<p> TELL THE <ent type='ORG'>PEOPLE</ent>...................27</p>

<p> AUDIT <ent type='ORG'>THE FEDERAL RESERVE</ent>...............29</p>

<p> NOTABLE QUOTES ON MONEY.................33</p>

<p> THEY HAVE NOT TOLD YOU..................35</p>

<p> GOD KNOWS OUR PLIGHT....................37</p>

<p> WHAT YOU CAN DO...................38</p>

<p>----------------------------------------------------------------------------

p. i
</p>

<p> INTRODUCTION</p>

<p> "The love of money is the root of all evil": (1 <ent type='PERSON'>Timothy</ent> 6:10)</p>

<p> "If thou lend money to any of my people that is poor by thee, thou
shalt not be to him an usurer, neither shalt thou lay upon him
usury." Exodus 22:25</p>

<p> "Take no usury of him, or increase ... thou shalt not give him thy
money upon usury." Leviticus 25:36-37</p>

<p> "Unto thy brother thou shalt not lend upon usury: That the Lord
they God bless thee." Deute<ent type='PERSON'>ron</ent>omy 23:20</p>

<p> In the early <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>, any interest on debt was considered usury.
Read below to see what interest (usury) on debts, a violation of
God's Law, is doing to <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>.</p>

<div> ----------------------------------------------------------------


</div>

<p> THE NEWS
-------------------------------------------------------------
A-8 <ent type='GPE'>Lynchburg</ent>, Va., Sat., March 26, 1977</p>

<p> -------------------------------------------------------------

THE <ent type='ORG'>NATIONAL</ent> DEBT</p>

<p>
In 1901 the national debt of <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States was less than $1 billion.
It stayed at less than $1 billion until we got into world war I. Then it
jumped to $25 billion.</p>

<p> Between 1918 and 1941, on the eve of <ent type='EVENT'>World War</ent> II, the national debt
just about doubled -- from $25 to $49 billion.</p>

<p> Between 1942 and 1952, the debt went from $72 billion to $265 billion.
In 1962 it was $303 billion. Eight years later, in 1970, it was $383
billion.</p>

<p> Between 1971 and 1976 it rose from $409 billion to $631 billion. The
estimated debt at the end of this year [1977] is $727 billion, and
next year it is expected to top $800 billion -- having nearly doubled
in the past eight years.

If the present trend continues, and there is no evidence whatsoever
that it will not continue, we can expect the national debt to nearly
double again within the next six to eight years. By then, the INTEREST
in the debt alone should be in the $400 billion a year range.

[Transcriber's note: As of 1996, the official debt about 5 TRILLION].

Eventually, the government will own nothing, the people will own
nothing, the banks will own everything.</p>

<p>_____________________________________________________________________________

p. ii </p>

<p> BILLIONS FOR <ent type='ORG'>THE BANKER</ent>S

<ent type='ORG'>DEBTS</ent> FOR THE <ent type='ORG'>PEOPLE</ent>
--------------------</p>

<p> [Top of page: A cartoon showing two bankers sitting on top of a
private bank tower -- one banker sitting contentedly in a
chair smoking a cigar; the other banker throwing a money
windfall up in the air and saying to the first banker, "IT IS
EASY TO ROB THE <ent type='ORG'>PEOPLE</ent> AND GET RICH. WE JUST <ent type='ORG'>LEND</ent> THEM THEIR
OWN CREDIT ON PAPER AND CHARGE THEM <ent type='ORG'>USURY</ent> (INTEREST)."
Beneath the bankers is a door called "loans" showing a
$50000 paper credit "loan" going out of the bank to a
residential home. From the home are $250000 in payments
(30 year payemts) flying back to land on the "tongue" of the
voracious "open mouth" of the bank.] </p>

<div> * * *</div>

<p> "If the <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> people ever allow private banks to control the
issue of their money, first by inflation and then by deflation,
the banks and corporations that will grow up around them [around
the banks], will deprive the people of their property until their
children will wake up homeless on the continent their fathers
conquered."
-- Thomas Jefferson</p>

<p>_____________________________________________________________________________</p>

<p> p. iii</p>

<p> THREE TYPES OF CONQUEST</p>

<p>
History reveals nations can be conquered by the use of one or more of
three methods.</p>

<p> The most common is conquest by war. In time, though, this method usually
fails, because the captives hate the captors and rise up and drive them
out if they can. Much force is needed to maintain control, making it
expensive for the conquering nation.</p>

<p> A second method is by religion, where men are convinced they must give
their captors part of their earnings as "obedience to God." Such a
captivity is vulnerable to philosophical exposure or by overthrow by
armed force, since religion by its nature lacks military force to
regain control, once its captives become "disillusioned."</p>

<p> The third method can be called economic conquest. It takes place when
nations are placed under "tribute" without the use of visible force or
coercion, so that the victims do not realize they have been conquered.
"Tribute" is collected from them in the form of "legal" debts and taxes,
and they believe they are paying it for their own good, for the good of
others, or to protect all from some enemy. Their captors become their
"benefactors" and "protectors".</p>

<p> Although this is the slowest to impose, it is often quite long lasting,
as the captives do not see any military force arrayed against them, their
religion is left more or less intact, they have freedom to speak and
to travel, and they participate in "elections" for their rulers. Without
realizing it, they are conquered, and the instruments of their own society
are used to transfer their wealth to their captors and make the conquest
complete.</p>

<p> In 1900 the average <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> worker paid few taxes and had little debt.
Last year payments on debts and taxes took more than half of what he
earned. Is it possible a form of conquest has been imposed on our people?
Read the following pages and decide for yourself. And may God have mercy
on this once debt-free and great nation, in Christ,

-- The author</p>

<div>--------------------------------------------------------------------------
--------------------------------------------------------------------------</div>

<p> p. 1</p>

<p>
BILLIONS FOR <ent type='ORG'>THE BANKER</ent>S

<ent type='ORG'>DEBTS</ent> FOR THE <ent type='ORG'>PEOPLE</ent>
--------------------</p>

<p> THE REAL STORY OF THE MONEY-CONTROL OVER AMERICA</p>

<p> by

Pastor <ent type='PERSON'>Sheldon Emry</ent>


[Cartoon showing a mother standing in f<ent type='PERSON'>ron</ent>t of a judge in divorce
court, holding the hand of her small boy and girl -- with her
husband sitting in the witness chair, holding his head in gloom.
The mother says to the judge, "AND JUDGE, WE WERE ALWAYS IN DEBT!."]</p>

<div>
* * *</div>

<p>
<ent type='NORP'>American</ent>s, living in what is called the richest nation on earth, seem
always to be short of money. Wives are working in unprecedented numbers,
husbands hope for overtime hours to earn more, or take part-time jobs
evenings and weekends, children look for odd jobs for spending money,
the family debt climbs higher, and psychologists say one of the biggest
causes of family quarrels and breakups is "arguments over money." Much
of this trouble can be traced to our present "debt-money" system.</p>

<p>___________________________________________________________________________</p>

<p> p. 2</p>

<p> Too few <ent type='NORP'>American</ent>s realize why <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> Statesmen wrote into Article I
of the U.S. Constitution:</p>

<p>
"<ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent> shall have <ent type='ORG'>the Power</ent> to Coin Money and
Regulate the Value Thereof."
</p>

<p> They did this, as we will show, in prayerful hope that it would prevent
"love of money" from destroying the republic they had founded. We shall
see how subversion of Article I has brought on us the "evil" of which
God's Word had warned.
</p>

<p> MONEY IS MAN'S ONLY "CREATION"</p>

<p> Economists use the term "create" when speaking of the process by which
money comes into existence. Now, "creation" means making something which
did not exist before. <ent type='ORG'>Lumbermen</ent> make boards from trees, workers build
houses from lumber, and factories manufacture automobiles from metal,
glass and other materials. But in all these they did not "create,"
They only changed existing materials into a more usable and, therefore,
more valuable form. This is not so with money. Here, and here alone,
man actually "creates" something out of nothing.

___________________________________________________________________________</p>

<p> p. 3

A piece of paper of little value is printed so that it is worth a piece
of lumber. With different figures it can buy the automobile or even the
house. It's value has been "created" in the true meaning of the word.</p>

<p>
"CREATING" MONEY IS VERY PROFITABLE!</p>

<p> As is seen by the above, money is very cheap to make, and whoever does
the "creating" of money in a nation can make a tremendous profit!
Builders work hard to make a profit of 5% above their cost to build a
house.</p>

<p> Auto makers sell their cars for 1% to 2% above the cost of manufacture
and it is considered good business. But money "manufactures" have no limit
on their profits, since a few cents will print a $1 bill or a $10000 bill.</p>

<p> That profit is part of our story, but first let consider another unique
characteristic of the thing -- money, the love of which is the "root of
all evil".</p>

<p>
ADEQUATE MONEY SUPPLY NEEDED</p>

<p> An adequate supply of money is indispensable to civilized society. We
could forego many other things but without money industry would grind to
a halt, farms would become only self-sustaining units, surplus food would
disappear, jobs requiring the work of more than one man or one family
would remain undone, shipping and large movement of goods would cease,
hungry people would plunder and kill to remain alive, and all government
except family or tribe would cease to function.</p>

<p> An overstatement, you say? Not at all. Money is the blood of civilized
society, the means of all commercial trade except simple barter. It is
the measure and the instrument by which one product is sold and another
purchased. Remove money or even reduce the supply below that which is
necessary to carry on current levels of trade, and the results are
catastrophic. For an example, we need only look at America's Depression
of the early 1930's.</p>

<p>
<ent type='ORG'>THE BANKER</ent>'S DEPRESSION OF THE 1930'S</p>

<p> In 1930 <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> did not lack industrial capacity, fertile farmland,
skilled and willing workers or industrious farm families. It had an
extensive and efficient transportation system in railroads, road networks,
and inland and ocean waterways.

____________________________________________________________________________

p. 4

Communications between regions and localities were the best in the world,
utilizing telephone, teletype, radio, and a well-operated government mail
system. No war had ravaged the cities or the countryside, no pestilence
weakened the population, nor had famine stalked the land. <ent type='GPE'>The United</ent>
States of <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> in 1930 lacked only one thing: an adequate supply of
money to carry on trade and commerce.</p>

<p> In the early 1930s, <ent type='ORG'>Bankers</ent>, the only source of new money and credit,
deliberately refused loans to industries, stores and farms. Payments on
existing loans were required however, and money rapidly disappeared from
circulation. Goods were available to be purchased, jobs waiting to be
done, but the lack of money brought the nation to a standstill.

By this simple ploy <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> was put in a "depression" and the greedy
<ent type='ORG'>Bankers</ent> took possession of hundreds of thousands of farms, homes, and
business properties. The people were told, "times are hard" and "money
is short." Not understanding the system, they were cruelly robbed of
their earnings, their savings, and their property.</p>

<p> _______________________________________________________________________</p>

<p> p. 5</p>

<p> MONEY FOR PEACE? NO!

MONEY FOR WAR? YES!</p>

<p>
<ent type='EVENT'>World War</ent> II ended the "depression." The same <ent type='ORG'>Bankers</ent> who in the
early 30's had no loans for peacetime houses, food and clothing,
suddenly had unlimited billions to lend for <ent type='ORG'>Army</ent> barracks, K-rations
and uniforms! A nation that in 1934 couldn't produce food for sale,
suddenly could produce bombs to send free to <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Japan</ent>! (More
on this riddle later).</p>

<p> With the sudden increase in money, people were hired, farms sold
their produce, factories went to two shifts, mines re-opened, and "The
Great Depression" was over! Some politicians were blamed for it and
others took credit for ending it. The truth is the lack of money (caused
by the <ent type='ORG'>Bankers</ent>) brought on the depression, and adequate money ended it.
The people were never told that simple truth and in this article we will
endeavor to show how these same <ent type='ORG'>Bankers</ent> who control our money and credit
have used their control to plunder <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> and place us in bondage.</p>

<p>_________________________________________________________</p>

<p>p. 6</p>

<p> POWER TO COIN AND REGULATE MONEY

When we can see the disastrous results of an artificially created
shortage of money, we can better understand why our Founding Fathers, who
understood both money and God's Laws, insisted on placing the power to
"create" money and the power to control it ONLY in the hands of the
<ent type='ORG'>Federal</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>. </p>

<p> They believed that ALL <ent type='ORG'>Citizens</ent> should share in the profits of its
"creation" and therefore the <ent type='ORG'>Federal</ent> government must be the ONLY creator
of money. They further believed that ALL citizens, of whatever State
or <ent type='GPE'>Territory</ent>, or station in life, would benefit by an adequate and stable
currency, and therefore, the national government must also be, by law,
the ONLY controller of the value of money.</p>

<p> Since <ent type='ORG'>the <ent type='ORG'>Federal</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent></ent> was the only legislative body subject to all
the citizens at the ballot box, it was, to their minds, the only safe
depository of so much profit and so much power. They wrote it out in the
simple, but all inclusive:

"<ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent> shall have <ent type='ORG'>the Power</ent> to Coin Money and
Regulate the Value Thereof."</p>

<p> HOW THE <ent type='ORG'>PEOPLE</ent> LOST CONTROL T0 <ent type='ORG'>THE FEDERAL RESERVE</ent></p>

<p> Instead of the Constitutional method of creating our money and putting
it into circulation, we now have and entirely unconstitutional system.
This has brought our country to the brink of disaster, as we shall see.</p>

<p> Since our money was handled both legally and illegally before 1913, we
shall consider only the years following 1913, since from that year on, ALL
of our money had been created and issued by an illegal method that will
eventually destroy <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States if it is not changed. Prior to 1913,
<ent type='GPE'>America</ent> was a prosperous, powerful, and growing nation, at peace with its
neighbors and the envy of the world. But -- in December of 1913, <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>,
with many members away for the Christmas holidays, passed what has since
been known as <ent type='ORG'>the FEDERAL RESERVE ACT</ent>. (For the full story of how this
infamous legislation was forced through our <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>, read "Conquest or
Consent", by W. D. Vennard). </p>

<p> Omitting the burdensome details, it simply authorized the establishment of
a <ent type='ORG'><ent type='ORG'>Federal Reserve</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Corporation</ent></ent>, with a Board of Directors (The <ent type='ORG'>Federal</ent>
Reserve Board) to run it, and <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States was divided into 12
<ent type='ORG'>Federal Reserve</ent> "Districts."</p>

<p>_____________________________________________________________________________</p>

<p> p. 7</p>

<p> This simple, but terrible, law completely removed from <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent> the
right to "create" money or to have any control over its "creation", and
gave that function to The <ent type='ORG'><ent type='ORG'>Federal Reserve</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Corporation</ent></ent>. This was done with
appropriate fanfare and propaganda that this would "remove money from
politics" (they didn't say "and therefore from the people's control") and
prevent "Boom and <ent type='ORG'>Bust</ent>" from hurting our citizens. </p>

<p> The people were not told then, and most still do not know today, that the
<ent type='ORG'><ent type='ORG'>Federal Reserve</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Corporation</ent></ent> is a private corporation controlled by bankers
and therefore is operated for the financial gain of the bankers over the
people rather than for the good of the people. The word "<ent type='ORG'>Federal</ent>" was used
only to deceive the people.</p>

<p>
MORE <ent type='PERSON'>DISASTROUS THAN PEARL</ent> HARBOR</p>

<p> Since that "day of infamy", more disastrous to us than <ent type='PERSON'>Pearl Harbor</ent>, the
small group of "privileged" people who lend us "our" money have accrued to
themselves all of the profits of printing our money -- and more! Since
1913 they have "created" tens of billions of dollars in money and credit,
which, as their own personal property, they then lend to our government
and our people at interest. </p>

<p> "The rich get richer and the poor get poorer" had become the secret policy
of the <ent type='ORG'>Federal</ent> government. An example of the process of "creation" and its
conversion to peoples "debt" will aid our understanding.</p>

<p> THEY PRINT IT --</p>

<p> WE BORROW IT AND PAY THEM INTEREST

We shall start with the need for money. The <ent type='ORG'><ent type='ORG'>Federal</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Government</ent></ent>, having
spent more than it has taken from its citizens in taxes, needs, for the
sake of illustration, $1000000000. Since it does not have the money,
and <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent> has given away its authority to "create" it, the <ent type='ORG'>Government</ent>
must go to the "creators" for the $1 billion. </p>

<p> But, the <ent type='ORG'>Federal Reserve</ent>, a private corporation, doesn't just give its
money away! The <ent type='ORG'>Bankers</ent> are willing to deliver $1000000000 in money
or credit to the <ent type='ORG'><ent type='ORG'>Federal</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Government</ent></ent> in exchange for the Government's
agreement to pay it back -- with interest. So <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent> authorizes the
<ent type='ORG'>Treasury</ent> Department to print $1000000000 in U.S. Bonds, which are then
delivered to the <ent type='ORG'>Federal Reserve</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Bankers</ent>.</p>

<p>_____________________________________________________________________________</p>

<p> p. 8</p>

<p> The <ent type='ORG'>Federal Reserve</ent> then pays the cost of printing the $1 billion (about
$1000) and makes the exchange. The government then uses the money to pay
its obligations. What are the results of this fantastic transaction? Well,
$1 billion in <ent type='ORG'>Government</ent> bills are paid all right, but the <ent type='ORG'>Government</ent> has
now indebted the people to the <ent type='ORG'>Bankers</ent> for $1 billion on which the people
must pay interest! </p>

<p> Tens of thousands of such transactions have taken place since 1913 so that
by the 1980s, the U.S. <ent type='ORG'>Government</ent> is indebted to the <ent type='ORG'>Bankers</ent> for over
$1000000000000 (trillion), on which the people pay over $100 billion
a year in interest alone with no hope of ever paying off the principal.
Supposedly, our children and following generations will pay forever and
forever! (Since this book was printed in 1984, the national debt has
grown to today's 1989 total of approximately 3 trillion dollars.)

[Transcriber's note: As of 1996, it is approximately 5 trillion dolllars].

_____________________________________________________________________________</p>

<p> p. 9</p>

<p> AND THERE'S MORE</p>

<p> You say, "This is terrible!" Yes, it is, but we have shown only part of
the sordid story. Under this unholy system, those <ent type='GPE'>United</ent> States Bonds have
now become "assets" of the <ent type='ORG'>Bank</ent>s in the Reserve <ent type='ORG'>System</ent>, which they then use
as "reserves" to "create" more "credit" to lend. Current "reserve"
requirements allow them to use that $1 billion in bonds to "create" as
much as $15 billion in new "credit" to lend to States, municipalities, to
individuals and businesses. </p>

<p> Added to the original $1 billion, they could have $16 billion of "created
credit" out in loans paying them interest with their only cost being
$1000 for printing the original $1 billion! Since the U.S. <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent> has
not issued Constitutional money since 1863 (over 100 years), in order
for the people to have money to carry on trade and commerce they are
forced to borrow the "created Credit" of the Monopoly bankers and pay
them usury-interest!</p>

<p>

AND THERE'S STILL MORE</p>

<p> In addition to the vast wealth drawn to them through this almost
unlimited usury, the <ent type='ORG'>Bankers</ent> who control the money at the top are able
to approve or disapprove large loans to large and successful corporations
to the extent that refusal of a loan will bring about a reduction in
the price that that Corporation's stock sells for on the market.</p>

<p> After depressing the price, the <ent type='ORG'>Bankers</ent>' agents buy large blocks of the
company's stock, after which the sometimes multi-million dollar loan is
approved, the stock rises, and is then sold for a profit. In this manner
billions of dollars are made with which to buy more stock. This practice
is so refined today that the <ent type='ORG'>Federal Reserve</ent> Board need only announce to
the newspapers an increase or decrease in their "discount rate" to send
stocks up and down as they wish.

Using this method since 1913, the <ent type='ORG'>Bankers</ent> and their agents have purchased
secret or open control of almost every large corporation in <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>. Using
that control, they then force the corporations to borrow huge sums from
their banks so that corporate earnings are siphoned off in the form of
interest to the banks. This leaves little as actual "profits" which can
be paid as dividends and explains why stock prices are so depressed,
while the banks reap billions in interest from corporate loans. In effect,
the bankers get almost all of the profits, while individual stockholders
are left holding the bag.</p>

<p> __________________________________________________________________________</p>

<p> p. 10</p>

<p> The millions of working families of <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> are now indebted to the
few thousand <ent type='ORG'>Bank</ent>ing families for twice the assessed value of the entire
<ent type='GPE'>United</ent> States. And these <ent type='ORG'>Bank</ent>ing families obtained that debt against us
for the cost of paper, ink, and bookkeeping!</p>

<p> THE INTEREST AMOUNT IS NEVER CREATED</p>

<p> The only way new money (which is not true money, but is "credit"
representing a debt), goes into circulation in <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> is when it is
borrowed from <ent type='ORG'>Bankers</ent>. When the State and people borrow large sums, we
seem to prosper. However, the bankers "create" only the amount of the
principal of each loan, never the extra amount needed to pay the
interest.</p>

<p> Therefore, the new money never equals the new debt added. The amounts
needed to pay the interest on loans is not "created," and therefore does
not exist!</p>

<p> Under this kind of a system, where new debt always exceeds the new money
no matter how much or how little is borrowed, the total debt increasingly
outstrips the amount of money available to pay the debt. The people can
never, ever get out of debt!</p>

<p> An example will show the viciousness of this usury-debt system with
its "built in" shortage of money.</p>

<p>____________________________________________________________________________</p>

<p> p. 11</p>

<p> IF $60000 IS BORROWED</p>

<p> - $255931.20 MUST BE PAID BACK</p>

<p> When a citizen goes to a banker to borrow $60000 to purchase a home or
a farm, the <ent type='ORG'>Bank</ent> clerk has the borrower agree to pay back the loan plus
interest. At 14% interest for 30 years, the borrower must agree to pay
$710.92 per month for a total of $255931.20.

The clerk then requires the citizen to assign to the banker the right of
ownership of the property if the borrower does not make the required
payments. The bank clerk then gives the borrower a $60000 check or a
$60000 deposit slip, crediting the borrower's checking account with
$60000.</p>

<p> The borrower then writes checks to the builder, subcontractors, etc.,
who in turn write checks. $60000 of new "checkbook" money is thereby
added to the "money in circulation."</p>

<p> However, and this is the fatal flaw in a usury system, the only new
money created and put into circulation is the amount of the loan, $60000.
The money to pay the interest is NOT created, and therefore was NOT added
to "money in circulation."</p>

<p> Even so, this borrower (and those who follow him in ownership of the
property) must earn and TAKE OUT OF CIRCULATION $255931, almost $200000
MORE than he put IN CIRCULATION when he borrowed the original $60000!
(By the way, it is this interest which cheats all families out of nicer
homes. It is not that they cannot afford them; it is because the <ent type='ORG'>Bankers</ent>'
usury forces them to pay for FOUR homes to get ONE!)</p>

<p> Every new loan puts the same process in operation. Each borrower adds a
small sum to the total money supply when he borrows, but the payments on
the loan (because of interest) then deduct a much LARGER sum from the
total money supply.</p>

<p> There is therefore no way all debtors can pay off the money-lenders. As
they pay the principle and interest, the money in circulation disappears.

All they can do is struggle against each other, borrowing more and more
from the money-lenders each generation. The money lenders (<ent type='ORG'>Bankers</ent>),
who produce nothing of value, slowly, then more rapidly, gain a death
grip on the land, building, and present and future earnings of the whole
working population. Proverbs 22:7 has come to pass in <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>. The
borrowers have become the servants to the lenders. No wonder God
Almighty forbids interest on loans. (See cover again).</p>

<p> __________________________________________________________________________</p>

<p> p. 12
</p>

<p> SMALL LOANS DO THE SAME THING</p>

<p> If you haven't quite grasped the impact of the above, let us consider
a small auto loan for 3 years at 18% interest. Step 1: Citizen borrows
$5000 and pays it into circulation (it goes to the dealer, factory,
miner, etc.) and signs a note agreeing to pay the <ent type='ORG'>Bankers</ent> $6500. Step 2:
Citizen pays $180 per month of his earnings to the <ent type='ORG'>Bank</ent>er. In three years,
he will take OUT of circulation $1500 more than he put IN circulation.</p>

<p> Every loan of <ent type='ORG'>Bank</ent>er "created" money (credit) causes the same thing to
happen. Since this has happened millions of times since 1913 (and
continues today), you can see why <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> has gone from a prosperous,
debt-free nation to a debt-ridden nation where practically every home,
farm and business is paying usury-tribute to some <ent type='ORG'>Bank</ent>er.

The usury-tribute to the <ent type='ORG'>Bankers</ent> on personal, local, State and <ent type='ORG'>Federal</ent>
debt totals more than the combined earnings of 25% of the working
people. Soon it will be 50% and continue upward.</p>

<p>
THIS IS WHY BANKERS PROSPER IN <ent type='ORG'>GOOD TIMES</ent> OR BAD</p>

<p> In the millions of transactions made each year like those above, little
actual currency changes hands, nor is it necessary that it do so. 95% of
all "cash" transactions in the U. S. are executed by check, so the
<ent type='ORG'>Bank</ent>er is perfectly safe in "creating" that so-called "loan" by writing
the check or deposit slip, not against actual money, but AGAINST YOUR
PROMISE TO PAY IT BACK! The cost to him is paper, ink and a few
dollars in salaries and office costs for each transaction. It is "check
kiting" on an enormous scale. The profits increase rapidly, year after
year, as shown below.</p>

<p> * * *

[Article from a newspaper:]

"Valley <ent type='ORG'>Bank</ent> Posts 49% Gain in Profits"</p>

<p> "Gains of 49 percent in net income and 51 percent in operating
income were posted last year by <ent type='ORG'>Valley National</ent> bank. Those
gains brought net income to $33959000 in the year ended Dec.
31 and operating income to $34459000. The year before those
totals were $22836000 and $22807000 respectively."</p>

<p>__________________________________________________________________________</p>

<p> p. 13</p>

<p> "Bank's Profit Rise 21%"</p>

<p> "<ent type='GPE'>Arizona</ent> bank announced on Monday it had achieved a 21.2 percent
increase in net income in 1978 over 1977. On the basis of
operating income, excluding the 1977 sale of the <ent type='GPE'>Arizona</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Bank</ent>
Building for $1336368, the bank said the increase was 43.9
percent. <ent type='ORG'>Tostenrud</ent> said loans and deposits increased in the
last year. Deposits 18.8 percent to $1353 billion and loans
21.9 percent to $951 million."</p>

<div> * * *</div>

<p> THE COST TO YOU? <ent type='EVENT'>EVENTUALLY</ent>, EVERYTHING!</p>

<p> In 1910 the U. S. <ent type='ORG'>Federal</ent> debt was only $1 billion, or $12.40 per
citizen. State and local debts were practically non-existent.</p>

<p> By 1920, after only six years of <ent type='ORG'>Federal Reserve</ent> shenanigans, the
<ent type='ORG'>Federal</ent> debt had jumped to $24 billion, or $228 per person, and State
and local debts were mushrooming.</p>

<p> By 1981 the <ent type='ORG'>Federal</ent> debt passed $1 trillion and was growing
exponentially as the <ent type='ORG'>Bankers</ent> tripled the interest rates. State and local
debts are now MORE than the <ent type='ORG'>Federal</ent>, and with businesses and personal
debts totalled over $6 trillion, three times the value of all land
and buildings in <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>.

If we signed over to the money-lenders of all of <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> we would
still owe them more two more <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>s (plus their usury, or course!).</p>

<p> However, they are too cunning to take the title to everything. They
instead leave you with some "illusion of ownership" so you and your
children will continue to work and pay the <ent type='ORG'>Bankers</ent> more of your earnings
on ever increasing debts. The "establishment" has captured our people
with their ungodly system of usury and debt as certainly as if they had
marched in with an uniformed army.</p>

<p> To understand that it really is a "conquest," go back to the f<ent type='PERSON'>ron</ent>t
and read the "Three Types of Conquest" again.

_____________________________________________________________________________</p>

<p> p. 14

The borrower must pay back MORE then he borrowed, so bankers
ALWAYS get more than they lend!</p>

<p>
FOR THE GAMBLERS AMONG MY READERS</p>

<p> To grasp the truth that periodic withdrawal or money through interest
payments will inexorably transfer all wealth in the nation to the receiver
of interest, imagine yourself in a poker or dice game where everyone must
buy the chips (the medium of exchange) from a "banker" who does not risk
chips in the game, but watches the table and every hour reaches in and
takes 10% to 15% of all the chips on the table. As the game goes on, the
amount of chips in the possession of each player will go up and down with
his luck. However, the TOTAL number of chips available to play the game
(carry on trade and business) will decrease rapidly.

The game will get low on chips, and some will run out. If they want to
continue to play, they must buy or borrow them from the "banker". The
"banker" will sell (lend) them ONLY if the player signs a "mortgage"
agreeing to give the "banker" some real property (car, home, farm,
business, etc.) if he cannot make periodic payments to pay back all
the chips plus some EXTRA ones (interest). The payments must be made on
time, whether he wins (makes a profit) or not.</p>

<p>_____________________________________________________________________________</p>

<p> p. 15</p>

<p> It is easy to see that no matter how skillfully they play, eventually
the "banker" will end up with all of his original chips back, and except
for the very best players, the rest, if they stay in long enough, will
lose to the "banker" their homes, their farms, their businesses, perhaps
even their cars, watches, rings, and the shirts off their backs!</p>

<p> Our real life situation is MUCH WORSE than any poker game. In a poker
game none is forced to go into debt, and anyone can quit at any time and
keep whatever he still has. But in real life, even if we borrow little
ourselves from the "bankers," the local, State and <ent type='ORG'>Federal</ent> governments
borrow billions in our name, squander it, then confiscate our earnings
from us and pay it back to the <ent type='ORG'>Bankers</ent> with interest. </p>

<p> We are forced to play the game, and none can leave except by death. We
pay as long as we live, and our children pay after we die. If we cannot
pay, the same government sends the police to take our property and
give it to the <ent type='ORG'>Bankers</ent>. The bankers risk nothing in the game; they just
collect their percentage and "win it all." In <ent type='GPE'>Las Vegas</ent> and at other
gambling centers, all games are "rigged" to pay the owner a percentage,
and they rake in millions...The <ent type='ORG'>Federal Reserve</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Bankers</ent>' "game" is also
rigged, and it pays off in billions!</p>

<p> In recent years, <ent type='ORG'>Bankers</ent> have added real "cards" to their game.
"Credit" cards are promoted as a convenience and a great boon to trade.
Actually, they are ingenious devices by which <ent type='ORG'>Bankers</ent> collect 2% to 5%
of every retail sale from the seller and 18% interest from buyers. A
real "stacked" deck!</p>

<p>p. 16 </p>

<p>
YES, IT'S POLITICAL, TOO!</p>

<p> <ent type='NORP'>Democrat</ent>, <ent type='NORP'>Republican</ent>, and independent voters who have wondered why
politicians always spend more tax money than they take in should now see
the reason. When they begin to study our "debt-money" system, they soon
realize that these politicians are not the agents of the people but are
the agents of the <ent type='ORG'>Bankers</ent>, for whom they plan ways to place the people
further in debt. </p>

<p> It takes only a little imagination to see that if <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent> had been
"creating," spending and issuing into circulation the necessary increase
in the money supply, THERE WOULD BE NO <ent type='ORG'>NATIONAL</ent> DEBT and the over
$4 Trillion of other debts would be practically non-existent. </p>

<p> Since there would be no <ent type='ORG'>ORIGINAL</ent> cost of money except printing, and no
continuing costs such as interest, <ent type='ORG'>Federal</ent> taxes would be almost nil.
Money, once in circulation, would remain there and go on serving its
purpose as a medium of exchange for generation after generation and
century after century, with no payments to the <ent type='ORG'>Bankers</ent> whatsoever!</p>

<p>
MOUNTING <ent type='ORG'>DEBTS</ent> AND WARS</p>

<p> But instead of peace and debt-free prosperity, we have ever-mounting
debt periodic wars. We as a people are now ruled by a system of
<ent type='ORG'>Bank</ent>er-owned <ent type='ORG'>Mammon</ent> that has usurped the mantle of government, disguised
itself as our legitimate government, and set about to pauperize and
control our people. </p>

<p> It is now a centralized, all-powerful political apparatus whose main
purposes are promoting war, confiscating the people's money, and
propagandizing to perpetuate itself in power. Our two large political
parties have become its servants, the various departments of government
its spending agencies, and <ent type='ORG'>the Internal Revenue Service</ent> is its
collection agency.</p>

<p> Unknown to the people, it operates in close cooperation with similar
apparatuses in other nations, which are also disguised as "governments."
Some, we are told, are friends. Some, we are told, are enemies. "Enemies"
are built up through international manipulations and used to frighten the
<ent type='NORP'>American</ent> people into going billions of dollars more into debt to the
bankers for "military preparedness," "foreign aid to stop communism,"
"minority rights" etc. </p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>Citizens</ent>, deliberately confused by brainwashing propaganda, watch
helplessly while our politicians give food, goods, and money to
<ent type='ORG'>Bank</ent>er-controlled alien governments under the guise of "better relations"
and "easing tensions." Our <ent type='ORG'>Bank</ent>er-controlled government takes our finest
and bravest sons and sends them into foreign wars with obsolete equipment
and inadequate training, where tens of thousands are murdered, and hundreds
of thousands are crippled. Other thousands are morally corrupted,
addicted to drugs, and infected with venereal and other diseases, which
they bring back to <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States.</p>

<p> When the "war" is over, we have gained nothing, but we are scores of
billions of dollars more in debt to the bankers, which was the reason for
the "war" in the first place!</p>

<p> __________________________________________________________________________</p>

<p> p. 17-19</p>

<p> AND THERE'S MORE</p>

<p> The profits from these massive debts have been used to erect a
complete and almost hidden economic and political colossus over our
nation. They keep telling us they are trying to do us "good," when in
truth they work to bring harm and injury to our people. These would-be
despots know it is easier to control and rob an ill, poorly-educated
and confused people than it is a healthy and intelligent population,
so they deliberately prevent real cures for diseases, they degrade our
educational systems, and they stir up social and racial unrest. For the
same reason they favor drug use, alcohol, sexual promiscuity, abortion,
pornography, and crime. Everything which debilitates the minds and
bodies of the people is secretly encouraged, as it makes the people
less able to oppose them or even to understand what is being done to
them. Family, morals, love of Country, the <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> religion, all
that is honorable is being swept away, while they try to build their
new, subservient man.</p>

<p> Our new "rulers" are trying to change our whole racial, social,
religious, and political order, but they will not change the debt-money economic system by which they <ent type='PERSON'>ron</ent> and rule. Our people have
become tenants and "debt-slaves" to the <ent type='ORG'>Bankers</ent> and their agents in
the land our fathers conquered. It is conquest through the most
gigantic fraud and swindle in the history of mankind.</p>

<p> And we need to remind you again: The key to their wealth and power
over us is their ability to create "money" out of nothing and lend it
to us at interest. If they had not been allowed to do that, they
would never would have gained secret control of our nation. How true
Solomon's words are:</p>

<p> "The rich rule over the poor, and the borrower is
servant to the lender." Proverbs 22.7</p>

<p> God Almighty warned in the Bible that one of the curses which would
come upon His People for disobeying His Laws was:</p>

<p> "The stranger that is within thee shall get up above thee
very high, and thou shalt come down very low. He shall
lend to thee, and thou shalt not lend to him; he shall be
the head, and thou shalt be the tail." Deut. 28:44-45</p>

<p> Most of the owners of the largest banks in <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> are of <ent type='NORP'>Eastern</ent>
European ancestry and connected with the <ent type='PERSON'>Rothschild</ent> European banks.
Has that warning come to fruition in <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>?</p>

<p> Let us now consider the correct method of providing the medium of
exchange (money) needed by our people.</p>

<p>
THE CONSTITUTIONAL WAY -- EVERY CITIZEN A STOCKHOLDER</p>

<p> If we would have used the Constitutional way of "creating" the money
needed in the nation, <ent type='ORG'>the <ent type='ORG'>Federal</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent></ent> would spend most of its time
and study on the issuance and control of an adequate supply of stable
money for the people.</p>

<p> If an increase of population and production required an increase in
the medium of exchange, <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent> would authorize the "coining," (i.e.,
printing) of the determined amount. Some could be used to pay current
legitimate expenses of the <ent type='ORG'><ent type='ORG'>Federal</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Government</ent></ent>, with the balance paid
directly to the citizens. <ent type='ORG'>Records</ent> for payment would be similar to
Social Security records, except a citizen would be recrded at birth,
instead of when he first goes to work.

Each person on the records as of the date of the <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>ional
authorization would receive an equal amount just as of he were a
stockholder holding one share. Just think -- a peyment of only $20 to
each citizen would put $4 billion of debt-free and interest-free money
into circulation.</p>

<p> _________________________________________________________________________</p>

<p> p. 20</p>

<p> Such a suggestion always scares the <ent type='ORG'>Bankers</ent>. Their propagandists
will immediately cry "printing press money," <ent type='ORG'>abd</ent> warn that it would
soon be "worthless" and would cause "inflation."</p>

<p> The truth is their immense <ent type='ORG'>ursury</ent> charges on their "created" credit
(our debt) is the sole cause of "inflation." All prices on all
industry, trade and labor must be reaised periodically to pay the ever
increasing usury charges. That is the ONLY cause of higher prices,
and the money-changers spend millions in propaganda to keep you from
realizing that.</p>

<p> The money-creators (<ent type='ORG'>Bankers</ent>) know that if we ever tried a
Constitutional issue of debt-free, interest-free currency, even a
limited issue, the benefits would be apparent immediately. That they
must prevent. <ent type='PERSON'>Abraham Lincoln</ent> was the last President to issue such
debt-free and interest-free currency (in 1863) and he was assassinated
shortly thereafter. [Transcriber's note: <ent type='PERSON'>JFK</ent> also made an issue of some
interest-free U.S. <ent type='ORG'>Treasury</ent> currency notes in 1963, and he quickly met
the same fate as <ent type='PERSON'>Lincoln</ent>].</p>

<p>___________________________________________________________________________

p. 21

NO BANKS PLUNDER</p>

<p> Under the Constitutional system, no private banks would exist to rob
the people. <ent type='ORG'>Government</ent> banks under the control of the people's
representatives would issue and control all money and credit. They would
issue not only actual currency, but could lend limited credit at no
interest for the purchase of capital goods, such as homes. </p>

<p> A $60000 loan would require only $60000 repayment, not $255931 as it
is now. Everyone who supplied materials and labor for the home would get
paid just as they do today, but the bankers would NOT get $195931 in
interest. AND THAT IS WHY THEY RIDCULE AND DESTROY ANYONE SUGGESTING
GOVERNMENT (<ent type='ORG'>CITIZENS</ent>') MONEY WITHOUT INTEREST AND WITHOUT DEBT.</p>

<p> History tells us of debt-free and interest-free money issued by
governments. The <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> colonies did it through colonial script in the
1700's and their wealth soon rivaled that of <ent type='GPE'>England</ent> and brought
restrictions from <ent type='ORG'>Parliament</ent>, which led to <ent type='EVENT'>the Revolutionary War</ent>.

<ent type='PERSON'>Abraham Lincoln</ent> did it in 1863 to help finance the <ent type='EVENT'>Civil War</ent>. He was
later assassinated by an agent of the <ent type='PERSON'>Rothschild</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Bank</ent>. No debt-free or
interest-free money has been issued in <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> since then.</p>

<p> Several <ent type='NORP'>Arab</ent> nations issue interest free loans to their citizens today.
[<ent type='ORG'>Transcribers</ent> note: Now you can understand what all the commotion in the
Middle East is all about, and why the banker-owned press is brainwashing
<ent type='NORP'>American</ent> citizens to think of all <ent type='NORP'>Arab</ent>s as terrorists). </p>

<p> <ent type='GPE'>The Saracen Empire</ent> forbade interest on money 1000 years ago and its
wealth outshone even Saxon Europe. Mandarin <ent type='GPE'>China</ent> issued its own money,
interest-free and debt-free and historians and collectors of art today
consider those centuries to be China's time of greatest wealth, culture,
and peace.</p>

<p> <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> issued debt-free and interest-free money from 1935 on,
accounting for its startling rise from the depression to a world power
in 5 years. <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> fiunanced its entire government and war operation
from 1935 to 1945 without gold and without debt, and it took the
whole Capitalist and <ent type='NORP'>Communist</ent> world to destroy the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> power over
Europe and bring Europe back under the heel of the bankers. Such
history of money does not even appear in the textbooks of public
(government) schools today.

Issuing money which does not have to be paid back in interest leaves
the money available to use in the exchange of goods and services and
services, and its only continuing cost is replacement as the paper wears
out. Money is the paper ticket by which transfers are made and should
always be in sufficient quantity to transfer all possible production of
the nation to the ultimate consumers.

___________________________________________________________________________</p>

<p> p. 22</p>

<p> It is as ridiculous for a nation to say to its citizens, "You must
consume less because we are short of money," as it would be for an
airline to say, "Our planes are flying, but we cannot take you because
we are short of tickets."</p>

<p>
STABLE MONEY</p>

<p> Money, issued in such a way, would derive its value in exchange from
the fact that it had come from the highest legal source in the nation
and would be declared legal to pay all public and private debts. </p>

<p> Issued by a sovereign nation, not in danger of collapse, it would need
no gold or silver or other so-called "precious" metals to back it.

As history shows, the stability and responsibility of government issuing
it is the deciding factor in the acceptance of that government's
currency -- not gold, silver, or i<ent type='PERSON'>ron</ent> buried in some hole in the ground.
Proof is America's currency today. Our gold and silver are practically
gone, but our currency is accepted. But if the government was about to
collapse our currency would be worthless. </p>

<p> Also, money issued through the people's legitimate government would not
be under the control of a privately owned corporation whose individual
owners benefit by causing the mojney amount and value to fluctuate and
the people to go into debt.</p>

<p> Under the present debt-usury system, the extra burden of usury forces
workers and businesses to demand more money for the work and goods to
pay their ever-increasing debts and taxes. This increase in prices and
wages is called "inflation." <ent type='ORG'>Bankers</ent>, politicians and "economists"
blame it on everything but the real cause, which is the usury levied on
money and debt by the <ent type='ORG'>Bankers</ent>. </p>

<p> This "inflation" benefits the money-lenders, since it wipes out savings
of one generation so they can not finance or help the next generation,
who must then borrow from the money-lenders, and pay a large part of
their life's labor to the usurer.</p>

<p> With an adequate supply of interest-free money, little borrowing would
be required and prices would be established by people and goods, not by
debts and usury.</p>

<p>__________________________________________________________________________</p>

<p> p. 23</p>

<p> CITIZEN CONTROL</p>

<p> If <ent type='ORG'>Federal</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent> failed to act, or acted w<ent type='PERSON'>ron</ent>gly, in the supply of
money, the citizens would use the ballot or recall petitions to replace
those who prevented correct action with others whom the people believe
would pursue a better money policy. Since the creation of money and its
issuance in sufficient quantity would be one of the few functions of
<ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>, the voter could decide on a candidate by his stand on money
instead of the hundreds of lesser issues which are presented to us
today.

And since money is, and would remain, a national function, local
differences or local factrions would not be able to sway the people from
the nation's (citizens') interest. All other problems, except the
nation's defense, would be taken care of in the State, County, or <ent type='GPE'>City</ent>
governments where they are best handled and most easily corrected.</p>

<p> An adequate national defense would be provided by the same citizen-controlled <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>, and there would be no <ent type='ORG'>Bankers</ent> behind the scenes,
bribing politicians to give $220 billions of <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> military
equipment to other nations, disarming us, while alien nations prepare
to attack and invade <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States of <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>.

___________________________________________________________________________ </p>

<p> p. 24</p>

<p> A DEBT-FREE AMERICA
</p>
<p>
With debt-free and interest-free money, there would be no high and
confiscatory taxation, and our homes would be mortgage-free with no
$10000-per-year payments to the <ent type='ORG'>Bankers</ent>, nor would they get $1000 to
$2500 per year from every automobile on our roads. </p>

<p> We would need no "easy payment" plans, "revolving" charge accounts,
loans to pay medical or hospital bills, loans to pay taxes, loans to pay
for burials, loans to pay loans, nor any of the thousand and one
usury-bearing loans which now suck the life-blood of <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> families. </p>

<p> There would be no unemployment, divorces caused by debt, destitute old
people, or mounting crime, and even the so-called "depraved" classes
would be deprived of neither job nor money to buy the necessities of
life.</p>

<p> Criminals could not become politicians, nor would politicians become
criminals in the pay of the Money-lenders. Our officials, at all
government levels, would be working for the people instead of devising
more money to place us further in debt to the <ent type='ORG'>Bankers</ent>.</p>

<p>____________________________________________________________________________</p>

<p> p. 25</p>

<p> We would get out of the entangling foreign alliances that have engulfed
us in four major ways and scores of minor wars since the <ent type='ORG'>Federal Reserve</ent>
Act was passed, alliances which are now used to prevent <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> from
preparing her own defense in the face of mounting danger from alien
powers.</p>

<p> A debt-free <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> would mean mothers would not have to work.
With mothers at home, juvenile deliquency would decrease rapidly. The
elimination of the usury and debt would be the equivalent of a 50%
raise in the purchasing power of every worker. With this cancellation
of all debts, the return to the people of all the property and wealth
the parasitic <ent type='ORG'>Bankers</ent> and their quasi-legal agents have stolen by usury
and fraud, and then ending of their theft of $300 Billion (or more)
every year from the people. <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> would be prosperous and powerful
beyond the wildest dreams of the citizens today. And we would be at
peace! (For a Bible example of cancellation of debts to money lenders
and restoration of property and money to the people, read
<ent type='PERSON'>Nehemiah</ent> 5:1-13.)


WHY YOU HAVEN'T KNOWN</p>

<p> We realize that this small, and necessarily incomplete, article on
money may be charged with oversimplification. Some may say that if it
is that simple the people would have known about it, and it could not
have happened. </p>

<p> But this MONEY <ent type='ORG'>LEND</ent>ERS consPIRACY is as old as <ent type='GPE'>Babylon</ent>, and even in
<ent type='GPE'>America</ent> it dates far back before the year 1913. </p>

<p> Actually, 1913 may be considered the year in which their previous plans
came to fruition, and the way opened for complete economic conquest of
our people. The consPIRACY is old enough in <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> so that to its
agents have been, for many years, in positions of influence such as
newspaper publishers, editors, columnists, church ministers, university
presidents, professors, textbook writers, labor union leaders, movie
makers, radio and TV commentators, politicians, and from school board
members to U.S. presidents, and many others.</p>

<p>
CONTROLLED NEWS AND INFORMATION</p>

<p> These agents control the information available to our people. They
manipulate public opinion, elect whom they will locally and nationally,
and never expose the crooked money system. They promote school bonds,
municipal bonds, expensive and detrimental farm programs, "urban renewal,"
foreign aid, and many other schemes which put the people more deeply
into debt to the <ent type='ORG'>Bankers</ent>.</p>

<p> __________________________________________________________________________

p. 26

Thoughtful citizens wonder why billions are spent on one program and
billions on another which may duplicate it or even nullify it, such as
paying some farmers not to raise crops, while at the same time building
dams or canals to irrigate more farm land. Crazy or stupid? </p>

<p> Neither. The goal is more debt. Thousands of government-sponsored
ways of wasting money go on continually. Most make no sense, but they
are never exposed for what they really are, builders of "billions for
the bankers and debts for the people."</p>

<p> So-called "economic experts" write syndicated columns in hundreds of
newspapers, craftily designed to prevent the people from learning the
simple truth about our money system. Commentators on radio and TV,
preachers, educators, and politicians blame the people as wasteful, lazy
or spend-thrift, and blame the workers and consumers for the increase
in debts and the inflation of prices, when they know the cause is the
debt-money system itself. </p>

<p> Our people are literally drowned in charges and counter-charges designed
to confuse them and keep them from understanding the unconstitutional and
evil money-system that is so efficiently and silently robbing the farmers,
the workers, and the businessmen of the fruits of their labor and of their
freedoms.</p>

<p>_________________________________________________________</p>

<p>p. 27</p>

<p> When some few <ent type='NORP'>Patriotic</ent> people or organizations who know the truth
begin to expose them or try to stop any of their mad schemes, they are
ridiculed and smeared as "right-wing extremists," "super-patriots,"
"ultra-rightists," "bigots," "fascists," and "anti-<ent type='NORP'>Semites</ent>." Any name
is used which will cause them to shut up or will at least stop other
people from listening to the warning they are giving. Articles and
books such as you are now reading are kept out of schools, libraries,
and book stores.</p>

<p> Some, who are especially vocal in their exposure of the treason
against our people, are harassed by government agencies such as
the <ent type='ORG'>EPA</ent>, the <ent type='ORG'>OSHA</ent>, the <ent type='ORG'>IRS</ent>, and others, causing them financial loss
and bankruptcy. Using the above methods, they have been completely
successful in preventing most <ent type='NORP'>American</ent>s from learning the truth.</p>

<p> Therefore, to prevent violence or armed resistance to their plunder of
<ent type='GPE'>America</ent>, they plan to register all firearms and eventually to disarm
all citizens. They have to eliminate most guns, except those in the
hands of their government, polics and army.</p>

<p>
TELL THE <ent type='ORG'>PEOPLE</ent></p>

<p> The "almost hidden" conspirators in politics, religion, education,
entertainment, and the news media are working for A <ent type='ORG'>Bank</ent>er-owned
<ent type='GPE'>United</ent> States, in a <ent type='ORG'>Bank</ent>er-owned world under a <ent type='ORG'>Bank</ent>er-owned World
<ent type='ORG'>Government</ent>!</p>

<p> Love of Country, compassion for your race, and concern for your
children should make you deeply interested in this, America's greatest
problem, for our generation has not suffered under the "yoke" as the
coming generations will. <ent type='ORG'>Usury</ent> and taxes will continue to take a
larger and larger part of the annual earning of the people and put
them into the pockets of the <ent type='ORG'>Bankers</ent> and their political Agents.
Increasing "government" regulations will prevent citizen protest and
opposition to their control. </p>

<p> _________________________________________________________________________</p>

<p> p. 28</p>

<p> It is possible that your grandchildren will own neither home nor car,
but will live in "government-owned" apartments and ride to work in
"government-owned" buses (both paying interest to the bankers),
AND BE ALLOWED TO KEEP JUST ENOUGH OF THEIR EARNINGS TO BUY A MINIMUM
OF FOOD AND CLOTHING while in luxury? In <ent type='LOC'>Asia</ent> and eastern Europe it is
called "communism;" in <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> it is called "Democracy" and "Capitalism."</p>

<p> <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> will not shake off her <ent type='ORG'>Bank</ent>er-controlled dictatorship as long
as the people are ignorant of the hidden controllers. <ent type='ORG'>International</ent>
financiers, who control most of the governments of the nations, and most
sources of information, seem to have us completely within their grasp.

They are afraid of only one thing: an awakened <ent type='NORP'>Patriotic</ent> Citizenry, armed
with the truth, and with a trust in Almighty God for deliverance. This
pamphlet has given you the truth about their iniquitous system. What you
do with it is in your hands, as in the hands of Divine Providence. "The
fear of man bringeth a snare: but whoso putteth his trust in the Lord
shall be safe." Proverbs 29:25</p>

<div> * * *</div>

<p> [Chart at bottom of page shows "Principal Assets of All
Commercial <ent type='ORG'>Bank</ent>s: 1950 to 1980" -- shows an exponentially
increasing upward spike. Source: Statistical Abstract of
<ent type='GPE'>United</ent> States. A note below the chart states:
"1982: Since 1950 the <ent type='ORG'>Bankers</ent> "assets" (obtained by fraud)
have risen from $160 billion to almost $2000 billion.
They are stealing <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> with their debt-usury system!]

[Note alongside the chart: "<ent type='ORG'>Bankers</ent> produce no usable product
or any "wealth," yet their usury robbery amost doubles their
net assets (wealth) every ten years! Is it possible another
generation under their "<ent type='ORG'>System</ent>" will make them "legal" owners
of the entire <ent type='GPE'>United</ent> States and 200 million citizens will be
their bond-slaves on the continent our fathers colonized and
developed?"]
____________________________________________________________________________

p. 29</p>

<p> AUDIT <ent type='ORG'>THE FEDERAL RESERVE</ent> SYSTEM?

The <ent type='ORG'>Federal Reserve</ent> has never been audited by the government since
it took over our money and credit in 1913. In 1975, a bill, H.R. 4316,
to require an audit, was introduced in <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>.</p>

<p> During the April, 1975, hearings, this author submitted a statement
favoring the audit, as did many others. It is reprinted on the next
two pages, from pages 306-308 of the 739 pages of testimony given
during those hearings before <ent type='ORG'>the Subcommittee</ent> on Domestic Monetary
Policy of <ent type='ORG'>the Committee</ent> on <ent type='ORG'>Bank</ent>ing, Currency, and Housing, House of
Representatives. Due to pressure from the money-controllers, it was
not passed. No audit has ever been made.</p>

<p>
____________________________________________________________________________</p>

<p>
p. 33 </p>

<p> NOTEABLE MONEY QUOTES</p>

<p> PRESIDENT <ent type='PERSON'>JAMES</ent> A. <ent type='ORG'>GARFIELD</ent>: "whoever controls the volume of money in
in any country is absolute master of all industry and commerce."</p>

<p> HORACE GREELRY: "While boasting of our noble deeds, we are careful to
conceal the ugly fact that by an iniquitous money system we have
nationalized a system of oppression which, though more refined, is
not less cruel than the old system of chattel slavery."</p>

<p> THOMAS A. <ent type='ORG'>EDISON</ent>: "People who will not turn a shovel full of dirt on
project (Muscle Shoals Dam) nor contribute a pound of material, will
collect more money from <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States than will the People who
supply all the material and do all the work. This is the terrible
thing about interest...But here is the point: If the <ent type='ORG'>Nation</ent> can
issue a dollar bond it can issue a dollar bill. The element that
makes the bond good makes the bill good also.

The difference between the bond and the bill is that the bond lets
the money broker collect twice the amount of the bond an an additional
20%. Whereas the currency, the honest sort provided by the
Constitution, pays nobody but those who contribute in some useful way. </p>

<p> It is absurd to say our Country can issue bonds and cannot issue
currency. Both are promises to pay, but one fattens the usurer and
the other helps the People. If the currency issued by the People
were no good, then the bonds would be no good, either. It is a
terrible situation when the <ent type='ORG'>Government</ent>, to insure the <ent type='ORG'>Nation</ent>al
Wealth, must go in debt and submit to ruinous interest charges at
the hands of men who <ent type='ORG'>cointrol</ent> the fictitious value of gold. Interest
is the invention of Satan."</p>

<p> PRESIDENT WOODROW WILSON: "A great industrial <ent type='ORG'>Nation</ent> is controlled
by its system of credit. Our system of credit is concentrated. The
growth of the <ent type='ORG'>Nation</ent> and all our activities are in the hands of a few
men. We have come to be one of the worst ruled, one of the most
completely controlled and dominated <ent type='ORG'>Government</ent>s in the world -- no
longer a <ent type='ORG'>Government</ent> of free opinion, no longer a <ent type='ORG'>Government</ent> by
conviction and vote of the majority, but a <ent type='ORG'>Government</ent> by the opinion
and duress of small groups of dominant men."

(Just before he died, <ent type='ORG'>Wilson</ent> is reported to have stated to friends
that he had been "deceived" and that "I have betrayed my Country."
He referred to the <ent type='ORG'>Federal Reserve</ent> Act, passed during his
Presidency) [&lt;--note by the author, <ent type='PERSON'>Emry</ent>.]

SIR <ent type='ORG'>JOSIAH</ent> STAMP: (President of the <ent type='ORG'>Bank</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>England</ent> in the 1920's, the
second richest man in <ent type='GPE'>Britain</ent>): "<ent type='ORG'>Bank</ent>ing was conceived in iniquity
and was born in sin. The <ent type='ORG'>Bankers</ent> own the earth. Take it away from
them, but leave them the power to create deposits, and with the flick
of the pen they create enough deposits to buy it back again. However,
take it away from them, and all the great fortunes like mine will
disappear, and they ought to disappear, for this would be a happier
and better world to live in. But, if you wish to remain the slaves
of the <ent type='ORG'>Bankers</ent> and pay the cost of your own slavery, let them
continue to create deposits."</p>

<p>___________________________________________________________________________</p>

<p> p. 34</p>

<p> MAJOR L.L.B. <ent type='ORG'>ANGAS</ent>: "The modern <ent type='ORG'>Bank</ent>ing system manufactures money out
of nothing. The process is perhaps the most astounding piece of
sleight of hand that was ever invented. <ent type='ORG'>Bank</ent>s can in fact inflate,
mint, and unmint the modern ledger-emntry currency."</p>

<p> RALPH M. HAWTREY (Former Secretary of the British <ent type='ORG'>Treasury</ent>): "<ent type='ORG'>Bank</ent>s
lend by creating credit. They create the means of payment out of
nothing."</p>

<p> ROBERT H. HEMPHILL (Credit Manager of <ent type='ORG'>Federal Reserve</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Bank</ent>, Altanta,
Ga.): "This is a staggering thought. We are completely dependent
on the the commercial <ent type='ORG'>Bank</ent>s. Someone has to borrow every dollar we
have in circulation, cash or credit. If the <ent type='ORG'>Bank</ent>s create ample
synthetic money, we are prosperous; if not, we starve. We are
absolutely without a permanent money system. When one gets a
complete grasp of the picture, the tragic absurdity of our
hopeless position is almost incredible, but there it is. It is
the most important subject intelligent persons can investigate and
reflect upon. It is so important that our present civilization may
collapse unless it becomes widely understood and the defects
remedied very soon."</p>

<p> CONGRESSMEN LOUIS T. <ent type='ORG'>MCFADDEN</ent>: The <ent type='ORG'>Federal Reserve</ent> (<ent type='ORG'>Bank</ent>s) are one
of the most corrupt institutions the world has ever seen. There is
not a man within the sound of my voice who does not know that this
<ent type='ORG'>Nation</ent> is run by the <ent type='ORG'>International</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Bankers</ent>."</p>

<p> JOHN C. CALHOUN (Speech in the Senate, May 26, 1836): "A power has
risen up in the government greater than the people themselves,
consisting of many and various powerful interests combined in one mass,
and held together by the cohesive power of the vast surplus in the
banks."</p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>LYOF</ent> N. TOLSTOY (In What Shall We Do?, 1891): "Money is a new form
of slavery, and sistinguishable from the old simply by the fact that
it is impersonal -- that there is no human relation between master
and slave."</p>

<p> THOMAS JEFFERSON (Letter to <ent type='PERSON'>Elbridge Gerry</ent>, Jan. 26, 1779): "<ent type='ORG'>Bank</ent>ing
establishments are more dangerous than standing armies."</p>

<p> <ent type='PERSON'>WILLIAM CORBETT</ent>: (In Advice to <ent type='ORG'>Yound Men</ent>, 1, 1829): "The power
which money gives is that of brute force; It is the power of
the bludgeon and the bayonet."</p>

<p> SOPHOCLES (Atigone, c. 450 B.C.): "Money lays waste cities; It sets
men to roaming from home. It seduces and corrupts honest men and
turns virtue to baseness; It teaches villany and impiety."</p>

<p> __________________________________________________________________________

p. 35</p>

<p> THEY HAVE NOT TOLD YOU!</p>

<p> Listed below are the individuals, organizations and publications
that control rather completely what you know or do not know.</p>

<p> Please read this list, and see if any of them, since 1920, have told
you any of the simple truths about our iniquitous debt-usury economic
system which you have read in this little booklet:

Presidents, Vice-Presidents, or potential candidates [except for
<ent type='PERSON'>Harry Browne</ent> -- JS]; <ent type='ORG'>Cabinet</ent> members, U.S. Judges, or other appointed
U.S. officials; Any U.S. Senator or Representative, except Robert
Lafoliete, <ent type='PERSON'>Charles Binderup</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Charles Lindberg</ent> Sr., Louis McFadden,
Wright-Patman, or <ent type='PERSON'>John Rarick</ent>? (All now gone).</p>

<p> State Governors or members of State Legislatures?</p>

<p> The <ent type='NORP'>Republican</ent> Party;</p>

<p> The <ent type='NORP'>Democrat</ent>ic Party;</p>

<p> The <ent type='NORP'>Communist</ent> Party;</p>

<p> The Socialist Worker's Party;</p>

<p> Other so-called "voter information" groups?</p>

<p> News sources such as Associated Press (AP), <ent type='GPE'>United</ent> Press <ent type='ORG'>International</ent>
(<ent type='GPE'>UPI</ent>), <ent type='ORG'>Reuters</ent>, etc;</p>

<p> Any large daily newspaper or newspaper columnist?</p>

<p> Radio or TV networks such as <ent type='ORG'>ABC</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>NBC</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>CBS</ent>, [<ent type='ORG'>CNN</ent>] and Mutual;</p>

<p> Radio or television newsmen or commentators;</p>

<p> News magazines such as <ent type='ORG'>TIME</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>NEWSWEEK</ent>, LOOK, U.S. NEWS &amp; WORLD REPORT,
<ent type='ORG'>PEOPLE</ent>, etc.</p>

<p> Any other widely circulated magazines?</p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>Books</ent> sold on the newsstands, in book stores, by Book-of-the-Month
Club or any other book clubs?</p>

<p> The moves, stage or other "entertainment" (although they often attack
politics, religion, or <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> society, they NEVER expose the money
system);</p>

<p> University to College professors;</p>

<p> Any elementary, high school or college textbooks;</p>

<p> Any other "educator" or educational organization such as the N.E.A.,
P.T.A. or similar?</p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>Labor Unions</ent> such as the A.F. of L., C.I.O., Teamsters, UMW, Farm
organizations such as <ent type='ORG'>Farmers Union</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Farm Bureau</ent>, NFO, <ent type='GPE'>United</ent> Farm
Workers, etc, (the recent <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> Agricultural Movement has exposed
the debt-usury);</p>

<p> ________________________________________________________________________

p. 36

Any farm publication?</p>

<p> Business organizations such as the <ent type='ORG'>Nation</ent>al Association of
Manufacturers, <ent type='ORG'>Better Business Bureau</ent>, Chamber of Commerce, etc.?</p>

<p> Medical, scientific or professional organizations such as the A.M.A,
A.A.U.P., etc.?</p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>Civic</ent> or Fraternal organizations such as Rotary, Elks, Lions,
Moose, Eagkles, Odd Fellows, etc.?</p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>Veterans</ent> organizations such as the <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> Legion, <ent type='ORG'>Veterans</ent> of
Foreign Wars, Disabled Vets, etc.?</p>

<p> The hundreds of "civil rights," "student," "Women's Lib." and
similar "protest" organizations or publications? They protest
"racism," atomic weapons, war, pollution, and scores of other supposed
"w<ent type='PERSON'>ron</ent>gs," but NEVER, NEVER, expose or object to the robbery of the
people by the Billionaire <ent type='ORG'>Bankers</ent>!</p>

<p> <ent type='NORP'>Masonic</ent> Orders, Lodges or publications;</p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>Knights</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>Columbus</ent>;</p>

<p> Any <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Pope</ent>, Bishop or Priest? (Father <ent type='PERSON'>Coughlin</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>Michigan</ent>
spoke on radio and wrote books in the 1930's protesting the <ent type='ORG'>Bankers</ent>'
plunder of <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>. He was silenced in a few years on direct orders
of the <ent type='PERSON'>Pope</ent>. Since then few Priests have mentioned the plunder).</p>

<p> <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> Rabbis or <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> organizations such as <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> Synagogues
of <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>, B'nai Brith, Anti-defamation League, etc;</p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>World Council</ent> of <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>es (WCC)</p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>Nation</ent>al Council of <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>es (NCC)</p>

<p> Any denominational Protestant minister or church;</p>

<p> <ent type='NORP'>Mormons</ent>, Jehovah's Witnesses, <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> Science, or similar;
"Charismatic" or "Pentacostal" ministers or churches;
"Non-denominational" or independent ministers or churches; Religious
magazines, publishing houses, or bookstores; "<ent type='NORP'>Evangelists</ent>" or
"Crusaders" on radio and television;</p>

<p>__________________________________________________________________________</p>

<p> p. 37</p>

<p> YOUR MINSTER?</p>

<p> ANYONE?</p>

<p> By the 1980's virtually no prominent indiviual or national organization
of influence in <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>, including religious organizations, opposes or
exposes the <ent type='ORG'>Bankers</ent>' plunder. Because of that silence most <ent type='NORP'>American</ent>s
live out their whole lives in this land without ever learning how they are
being robbed.</p>

<p> Small groups of patriots are opposing the <ent type='ORG'>Bankers</ent>. One is LIBERTY
LOBBY which publishes The SPOTLIGHT, a weekly newspaper ($32 per year
or $59 for two years, 300 Independence Ave., S.E., <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, D.C.
20003). Each issue exposes the anti-<ent type='NORP'>American</ent> shenanigans of the
<ent type='ORG'>Bankers</ent>, <ent type='NORP'>Communist</ent>s and other enemies of <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>. Every patriotic
<ent type='NORP'>American</ent> family should subscribe.</p>

<p> Read this short booklet over again.</p>

<p> Since the politicians, the major media and the churches will not
warn the people, that warning is up to us AND YOU! Will you pray
AND ACT?</p>

<p>

IS IT POSSIBLE GOD KNOWS ABOUT OUR PLIGHT?

"But this is a people robbed and spoiled;
they are all of them snared in holes,
and they are bid in prison houses;
they are for a prey, and none delivereth;
for a spoil, AND NONE SAVETH, RESTORE.</p>

<p> "Who among you will give ear to this?
Who will hearken, and hear for the time
to come?" (the "last days") <ent type='PERSON'>Isaiah</ent> 42:22-23</p>

<p>
___________________________________________________________________________</p>

<p> p. 38</p>

<p> WHAT YOU CAN DO</p>

<p> Pray for America's release from this wicked money control, which
is at the root of our debts and wars.</p>

<p> Send copies of this book to officials in your State government,
to school board members, principals, teachers, ministers, neighbors,
etc. Ask them for their comments.</p>

<p> Write letters to elected or appointed officials. Write "letters-to-the-editor" to newspapers. Most small towns and suburban newspapers
are not totally controlled, while most of the big city newspapers are.</p>

<p> Give or mail them out by the hundreds to awaken and educate other
<ent type='NORP'>American</ent>s to this fantastic plunder of the working people of <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>.
The cost to you is VERY LITTLE compared to the BILLIONS in money and
property being STOLEN from our people.</p>

<p> The <ent type='ORG'>Bibe</ent> has scores of passages condemning the robbery of the
workers and the poor by the wicked. For a Bible-related study of
this evil system of plunder, write to the publisher of this booklet for
a list of books, tracts, and cassette sermons on Bible Law and Prophecy.</p>

<p> [End of Part 2 of 2]</p>

<p> _________________________________________________________________________</p>

<p> PRINT OUT A COPY OF THIS MESSAGE AND SHARE IT WITH YOUR FRIENDS!</p>

<p> THERE IS NO COPYRIGHT -- PLEASE HELP ALERT THE AMERICAN <ent type='ORG'>PEOPLE</ent>!</p>

<p> *******************************************************
Interested in learning more about <ent type='NORP'>communist</ent> influence
in the <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> media, the resurging <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> empire,
the FBI's proposed domestic terrorism centre, the
<ent type='ORG'>TWA</ent>800 shootdown, the ATF's "Operation Piedmont" plans
to plant pipe bombs at <ent type='EVENT'>the Atlanta Olympics</ent> and blame
them on the militias...and much, much more that the
media will not tell you?</p>

<p> Visit the NEW WORLD ORDER INTELLIGENCE UPDATE Web page
at:</p>

<p> http://www.inforamp.net/~jwhitley</p>

<div> ********************************************************

</div></xml>