<xml><p>From alt.conspiracy
From: vincent@dreamon.com (The Bok)
Subject: The History and Significance of <ent type='EVENT'>the New World</ent> Order
Date: <ent type='LOC'>Sun</ent>, 09 Feb 1997 03:30:54 GMT
<info type="Message-ID"> 32fd2942.367248603@news.<ent type='PERSON'>gte</ent>.net</info></p>

<p>---------------------------------------------------------------
<ent type='ORG'>American Dissident Voices</ent> is a world wide radio program which
deals with topics of interest that concern people of European
descent. We hope that these weekly articles will offer the reader
an opposing viewpoint to the major news media. </p>

<p>If you would like to subscribe to this service, please e-mail
advinfo@dreamon.com.
--------------------------------------------------------------- </p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>American Dissident Voices</ent> Online Radio
http://www.natvan.com/radio/radio.html</p>

<p>The History and Significance of <ent type='EVENT'>the New World</ent> Order </p>

<p>by <ent type='PERSON'>Scott Spencer</ent> </p>

<p>The author of this series, <ent type='PERSON'>Scott Spencer</ent>, is a writer and researcher
who lives in <ent type='GPE'>Toronto</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Canada</ent>. </p>

<p>Introduction </p>

<p>The concept and the reality of <ent type='EVENT'>the New World</ent> Order are widely
misunderstood, even by most patriots; or perhaps I should
say, especially by most patriots. Some of this misunderstanding is
caused by the shortcomings of the patriots, but there is also
disinformation deliberately inserted by our enemies. We need an
accurate understanding of what -- and who -- we are
fighting to insure our victory. </p>

<p>The self-styled "patriots," the coin-sellers and quack-cure salesmen,
if given the reins of power in <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States tomorrow morning,
would either be shot dead trying to flee the country, or would be
dancing to an internationalist <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> tune by nightfall. Most of them
want only to hawk their questionable wares. Even if they know what the
<ent type='EVENT'>New World</ent> Order really is, they would rather have their bank
statements published than oppose it. </p>

<p>The Old World Order </p>

<p>The United States is, itself, a product of the fall of <ent type='EVENT'>the Old World</ent>
Order. The Old World Order, as far as government is concerned, was
comprised of the <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> monarchies which ruled by "divine right"
after the fall of the <ent type='LOC'>West</ent>ern <ent type='NORP'>Roman</ent> Empire in the sixth century. The
term "<ent type='EVENT'>New World</ent> Order" pertained to an ideal world which was allegedly
to develop on the ashes of the Old Order after no powerful monarchs
ruled in Europe. <ent type='EVENT'>The <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> <ent type='EVENT'>Revolution</ent></ent> was a relatively benign
manifestation of a revolutionary movement against that Old Order. This
movement bore its most bitter fruit in the 19th and 20th centuries.
This revolutionary movement, whatever its merits once were, has been
hijacked by the enemies of our race and nation. </p>

<p>The increase of chaos in 19th century Europe, brought about by the
undermining of monarchies, was offset by the growth of national
consciousness among the peoples of Europe. </p>

<p>The idea that the overthrow of a monarchy would always lead to
self-government of "the people" was transparently fraudulent. Powerful
<ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> were often ideally positioned when the monarch fell. The <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>
were, then as now, a people unto themselves. They had their own
interests, and these interests were often antithetical to the
interests of the peoples among whom they lived. </p>

<p>Self-government of a people leads to nationalism and a sensitivity to
alien control of government. Consequently there was a healthy,
although grossly inadequate, reaction against <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> power.
Nationalism is inherently hostile toward organized <ent type='ORG'>Jewry</ent>, and
organized <ent type='ORG'>Jewry</ent> is inherently hostile toward nationalism. </p>

<p>The <ent type='NORP'>French</ent> <ent type='EVENT'>Revolution</ent> </p>

<p>An early milestone of <ent type='EVENT'>the New World</ent> Order was the <ent type='NORP'>French</ent> <ent type='EVENT'>Revolution</ent>.
The <ent type='NORP'>French</ent> monarchy, and the causes of its downfall, have been widely
and deliberately misrepresented. The truth about the <ent type='NORP'>French</ent> monarchy
was stated by the <ent type='NORP'>Scottish</ent> philosopher <ent type='PERSON'>David Hume</ent> in 1742: </p>

<p> Though all kinds of government be improved in modern times, yet
monarchical government seems to have made the greatest advance to
perfection. It may now be affirmed of civilized monarchies, what
was formerly said of republics alone, that they are a government
of laws, not of men. They are susceptible of order, method, and
constancy, to a surprising degree. Property is there secure;
industry is encouraged; the arts flourish; and the prince lives
among his subjects like a father among his children. </p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Hume</ent> added that he saw more "sources of degeneracy" in representative
republics like that of <ent type='GPE'>England</ent> than in <ent type='GPE'>France</ent>, which he called "the
most perfect model of pure monarchy." </p>

<p>It is generally conceded that a conspiracy orchestrated the <ent type='NORP'>French</ent>
<ent type='EVENT'>Revolution</ent>. The moderate members of the conspiracy, such as <ent type='GPE'>Lafayette</ent>,
were appalled at the outcome of the process they had helped to start.
<ent type='GPE'>Lafayette</ent> and many others had merely wanted to establish a
constitutional monarchy, but as in all revolutions, the moderates did
not determine the outcome. </p>

<p>But in spite of any conspiracy, <ent type='PERSON'>Louis XVI</ent> could not have been
overthrown unless he allowed himself to be overthrown. </p>

<p>This may seem a peculiar thing to say, that <ent type='PERSON'>Louis XVI</ent> allowed himself
to be overthrown, allowed his kingdom to be ruined, and subjected
himself and many others to the whim of filthy degenerates, but <ent type='PERSON'>Louis</ent>
XVI was a liberal, much like the liberals we encounter today. He was
an enemy to his friends and a friend to his enemies. The entire <ent type='NORP'>French</ent>
<ent type='EVENT'>Revolution</ent> could have been stifled on several occasions if only the
King had allowed his bodyguards and his troops to deal with the gangs
of hired ruffians in the manner they so richly deserved. But no, <ent type='PERSON'>Louis</ent>
was a "humanitarian." In the Siege of the Tuileries the King's
own <ent type='NORP'>Swiss</ent> guards were brutally murdered simply because he had
forbidden them to raise their weapons, even in self-defense, against
those hired thugs whom the King naively regarded as "the people." </p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Louis</ent> was not a congenitally stupid man, but from childhood his head
had been filled with wrong ideas, the same kind of wrong ideas which
public schools and the mass-media impress upon us and our children
today. </p>

<p>The fate of <ent type='PERSON'>Louis XVI</ent> should be a cautionary tale about the deadliness
of wrong ideas. Some wrong ideas, the "brotherhood of man," for
example, are highly infectious because they appeal to wishful
thinking; it is soothing and pleasant to think that violence,
conflict, and death are mere vestiges of an unenlightened past, and
that all unpleasantness can be avoided simply by being nice to
everyone. This mode of thinking is a deadly form of self-indulgence. </p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Louis XVI</ent> had far more armed forces than were needed to crush the
<ent type='EVENT'>Revolution</ent>, but he chose not to crush it. Over one million <ent type='NORP'>French</ent>men,
many of whom were the best in the nation, were murdered -- as a
consequence of his "humanitarianism." </p>

<p>The <ent type='NORP'>Bolshevik</ent> <ent type='EVENT'>Revolution</ent> </p>

<p>Czarist <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent> was naturally a prime target of <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> malice and
defamation, since it was the last absolute monarchy in Europe. In
addition, the government of the Czar (Czar is the <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>n equivalent
of <ent type='ORG'>Kaiser</ent> or Caesar), more than any other government, had taken steps
to protect its people from <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> exploitation. The <ent type='NORP'>Japanese</ent> victory
over Czarist <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent> in 1905 was the first great blow to the confidence
of the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> world; it was brought about with the financial assistance
of <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> bankers. Czarist Russia's defeat in 1905 was part of a long
pattern of events, including numerous assassinations, attempted
assassinations, and bombings. In the end there was the bloody ritual
murder of Czar Nicholas II and most of his family. </p>

<p>It should be noted, however, that the Czar, like <ent type='PERSON'>Louis XVI</ent>,
essentially permitted his own rule to be replaced. At first, it was
replaced by a republic. The republic was weak and dissolute and ended
up paving the way for a reign of terror. As in <ent type='GPE'>France</ent>, the better
racial elements were murdered. </p>

<p>The preponderance of <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> influence in the <ent type='NORP'>Bolshevik</ent> <ent type='EVENT'>Revolution</ent> is
thoroughly documented. Additionally, <ent type='NORP'>Zionism</ent> played a part. <ent type='NORP'>Zionism</ent>
is, and was, an integral aspect of the largely <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> <ent type='EVENT'>New World</ent> Order.
Rabbi <ent type='PERSON'>Moses Hess</ent>, one of the primary instigators of <ent type='NORP'>Zionism</ent>, was a
mentor of <ent type='PERSON'>Karl Marx</ent>. </p>

<p>The Destruction of <ent type='GPE'>Britain</ent> </p>

<p><ent type='NORP'>Zionism</ent> contributed to the destruction of <ent type='GPE'>Britain</ent> as a world power.
<ent type='NORP'>Zionism</ent> helped to dismantle the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent>-dominated world of our
grandfathers, ushering in the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>' <ent type='EVENT'>New World</ent> Order of multiracialism,
the absolute rule of money, and cultural chaos.</p>

<p>In 1914 the greatest power in the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> world was the <ent type='GPE'>British Empire</ent>.
After <ent type='EVENT'>the First World War</ent> the alleged "victor," Great <ent type='GPE'>Britain</ent>, was a
second-rate power. After <ent type='EVENT'>the Second World War</ent>, which <ent type='GPE'>Britain</ent> also
supposedly "won," she was a third-rate power and quickly stripped of
almost all her possessions. How was this great empire destroyed? </p>

<p>As a consequence of <ent type='EVENT'>the First World War</ent>, the international <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent>
bankers raked in a huge debt. <ent type='GPE'>Britain</ent> in particular was ruinously
indebted. Britain's plight would not have been so grievous had the
<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> bankers not succeeded in prolonging the war by involving the
United States. Even <ent type='PERSON'>Winston Churchill</ent> later stated that it would have
been better if <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States had stayed out of <ent type='EVENT'>World War</ent> I. </p>

<p>However, it was the moral weakness of Britain's leaders which allowed
<ent type='GPE'>Britain</ent> to suffer usury and to participate in that fratricidal war.
One can blame the people of <ent type='GPE'>Britain</ent> for having elected such leaders,
and it is the <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> people who have suffered because of it, but it
is an inherent feature of every democratic republic that the people
can only vote on the basis of information the controlled media give
them. It is only in retrospect that a voter can know whether he has
made a mistake. <ent type='GPE'>Britain</ent> has gone to its ruin quietly and obediently,
lacking a national leadership with the will to preserve the nation. </p>

<p>The First <ent type='EVENT'>World War</ent> </p>

<p>The <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> people have likewise been saddled with treacherous
leadership. Neither of the <ent type='EVENT'>World War</ent>s, and perhaps no foreign war in
this century, has served the interests of the <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> people. </p>

<p><ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> bankers, many of whom were influential <ent type='NORP'>Zionists</ent>, extorted the
Balfour Declaration from <ent type='GPE'>Britain</ent>. Organized <ent type='ORG'>Jewry</ent> promised <ent type='GPE'>Britain</ent> to
bring <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States into the war against <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> if, after the
war, they would be given <ent type='GPE'>Palestine</ent>. How were the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> able to bring
<ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States into the war? Firstly, even at that time, they owned
many newspapers in <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States which they used for pro-war
propaganda. And secondly, through <ent type='PERSON'>Woodrow Wilson</ent>. <ent type='ORG'>Wilson</ent> was a
weak-willed and self-indulgent man. He was the first U.S. president to
be surrounded by <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> "advisors" and to be thoroughly beholden to
<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> interests. </p>

<p>The <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Kaiser</ent>, William II, had been a great friend of the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> and
had many <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> in his government. <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> gratitude manifested itself
just as it always has historically -- as a stab in the back. <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent>
was deserted by World <ent type='ORG'>Jewry</ent> the moment <ent type='GPE'>Britain</ent> offered the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> a
sweeter deal: the Balfour Declaration. </p>

<p>The "war to make the world safe for democracy," as it was called, was
the first war explicitly propagandized as a struggle for a <ent type='EVENT'>New World</ent>
Order. In November 1918, on the eve of the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> surrender, the
"<ent type='ORG'>League</ent> to Enforce Peace" published a pamphlet entitled The
Foundations of a <ent type='EVENT'>New World</ent> Order. The nominal president of the <ent type='ORG'>League</ent>
was former U.S. President <ent type='PERSON'>William Howard Taft</ent>. Evidence suggests the
"<ent type='ORG'>League</ent> to Enforce Peace" was largely a <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> creation. And its
Orwellian-sounding title carries the mark of one of their operations. </p>

<p>The <ent type='EVENT'>New World</ent> Order and Egalitarianism </p>

<p><ent type='EVENT'>World War</ent> I was the first of the many wars in which young <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> men
were required to shed their blood and end their lives, not to defend
their borders from invaders, not to gain an increase in the territory
controlled by their people, and not even to enrich their national
treasury, but for abstract and allegedly "moral" purposes crafted to
increase the suckers' enthusiasm for slaughter. Thus, we had the war
"to end war" or the war "to make the world safe for democracy." In
recent times we have had a war to "restore democracy" in <ent type='GPE'>Kuwait</ent> and
U.S. intervention to "restore democracy" to <ent type='GPE'>Haiti</ent>. The pattern was set
in 1917. </p>

<p>The <ent type='ORG'>Pyrrhic</ent> victors of <ent type='EVENT'>the First World War</ent> could not disregard the
egalitarian <ent type='EVENT'>New World</ent> Order propaganda which they had spouted. Lothrop
Stoddard, a widely read political and social commentator in the
post-war period, wrote in The Rising Tide of Color in 1920: </p>

<p> During the war years the allied statesmen had officially
proclaimed times without number that the war was being fought to
establish a new world order based on such principles as the
rights of small nations, and the liberty of all peoples. These
pronouncements had been treasured and memorized throughout the
<ent type='LOC'>East</ent>. When, therefore, the <ent type='LOC'>East</ent> saw a peace settlement based,
not upon those high professions, but upon the imperialistic
secret treaties, it was fired with a moral indignation and sense
of outraged justice never known before. </p>

<p>The European powers, while they displayed an unlimited capacity for
treachery toward defeated <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent>, whose people were certainly not
granted self-determination, did abide by their foolish feel-good
propaganda of a "<ent type='EVENT'>New World</ent> Order" when it came to the non-<ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> world.
Unrest by non-<ent type='NORP'>Whites</ent> in <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> and <ent type='NORP'>French</ent> colonies was met with
concessions, and the European empires were gradually dissolved. </p>

<p>It is ironic that <ent type='GPE'>Britain</ent> was a leading promoter of the <ent type='ORG'>League</ent> of
Nations and <ent type='EVENT'>the New World</ent> Order; it perhaps lost more than
any other nation because of it. It seems less ironic if one considers
that <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> foreign policy was under the control of <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent>
bankers, who did not give a hoot about Britain's destiny. Once the
<ent type='GPE'>Britons</ent> had developed and pacified the dark continent
sufficiently for safe operation of <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent>-owned gold, copper, and
diamond mines, they were disposable. Beyond this
trail-blazing function, all those <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> colonists were just in the
way. And the destruction of <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> political power in <ent type='LOC'>Africa</ent>
was an explicit part of <ent type='EVENT'>the New World</ent> Order agenda. </p>

<p>A collection of essays entitled "The <ent type='EVENT'>New World</ent> Order" was published by
<ent type='ORG'>Oxford University Press</ent> in 1932. In the essay entitled Race Problems
in Industry and Culture, F. S. <ent type='PERSON'>Marvin</ent> states: </p>

<p> Until South <ent type='LOC'>Africa</ent> can not only contemplate, but insist on
having, a <ent type='NORP'>Bantu</ent> as one of its delegation to <ent type='GPE'>Geneva</ent>, it has not
recognized the principle. </p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Marvin</ent> also advocated the admission of the non-<ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> hordes into <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent>
homelands. He wrote: </p>

<p> But there does exist a teeming population in <ent type='GPE'>Japan</ent>, pressing for
outlets, and hundreds of millions of Chinese . . . . India, too,
constantly increases her needy but industrious and
naturally skillful peasantry. Meanwhile the white man in
<ent type='GPE'>Australia</ent>, South <ent type='LOC'>Africa</ent>, and on <ent type='LOC'>the Pacific Coast</ent> [of <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent>
States] is maintaining in his own supposed interest the strictest
exclusion that he can arrange against the settlement of these
people in lands which he controls, and they could happily and
profitably inhabit. It is a policy untenable in the long run,
condemned alike by considerations of industry, biology, and
humanity. Let us be thankful that a <ent type='ORG'>League</ent> of Nations stands in
the breach, not yet to take active steps, for other more urgent
tasks are at hand, but to keep steadily before the
eyes of all parties the hopes and duties of cooperating mankind. </p>

<p>F.S. <ent type='PERSON'>Marvin</ent> was a professor of history and a member of the Royal
Historical Society. It is absolutely terrifying that there have been,
and are, men who hold positions of respect who speak such idiocy.
Similarly, in more recent times, the Queen of <ent type='GPE'>England</ent>, in her
Christmas address of 1994, praised the recent introduction of
"democracy" to South <ent type='LOC'>Africa</ent>. F.S. Marvin's prescription was a
toned-down version of the tirades of lunatic <ent type='NORP'>abolitionist</ent>s one hundred
years earlier. They said the same things because they suffered from
the same syndrome: sadomasochistic race-treason clothed in the
sanctimonious pretension of <ent type='NORP'>Judaic</ent> otherworldliness. </p>

<p>The conspiracy theorists who make so much noise about <ent type='PERSON'>Cecil Rhodes</ent> and
say <ent type='EVENT'>the New World</ent> Order is a <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> conspiracy are trafficking
information that is not only incomplete and misleading, but grossly
out of date. One of these groups is the <ent type='ORG'>Lyndon Larouche</ent> organization
whose leading figures appear to be mostly <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>. Similarly, it is a lie
that <ent type='EVENT'>the New World</ent> Order -- even <ent type='ORG'>Communism</ent> -- is a "<ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>n"
phenomena. The biggest lie, however, is that <ent type='EVENT'>the New World</ent> Order is
some sort of <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> or "<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>" plot. It is primarily <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> in origin.
"<ent type='ORG'>Patriots</ent>" who tell you otherwise are ill-informed or liars. </p>

<p>Hitler's New European Order </p>

<p>Perhaps the biggest lie on the God, country, and gold coin circuit is
that <ent type='ORG'>the National</ent> Socialist <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> government was a progenitor of
today's <ent type='EVENT'>New World</ent> Order. </p>

<p><ent type='NORP'>Bolshevism</ent> was viewed with great alarm by Russia's neighbor, <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent>,
which now found itself flanked on one side by <ent type='GPE'>the Soviet Union</ent>, and on
the other by <ent type='NORP'>Judeo</ent>-democratic <ent type='GPE'>France</ent>. In the economic ruin
deliberately foisted upon <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> at the end of <ent type='EVENT'>the First World War</ent>,
<ent type='NORP'>Bolshevism</ent> was a serious menace. A <ent type='NORP'>Judeo</ent>-<ent type='NORP'>Communist</ent> regime even seized
power briefly in <ent type='GPE'>Bavaria</ent> shortly after the war. </p>

<p>The liberal <ent type='NORP'>Weimar</ent> constitution imposed on <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> after the war was
written by <ent type='PERSON'>Hugo Preuss</ent>, a <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>. The dominant political party of the
<ent type='NORP'>Weimar</ent> period was the Social Democratic Party, founded by Ferdinand
Lasalle, also a <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>. </p>

<p>The economic devastation of <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> under the <ent type='NORP'>Weimar</ent> government was
extreme. The currency became worthless. Workers were paid with
wheelbarrows full of money -- twice a day, because the depreciation
was so rapid that your money would lose half its value by nightfall.
Eventually, billion-mark postage stamps were printed, and
trillion-mark bank notes, but all had the same ultimate value: zero.
<ent type='NORP'>German</ent> workers and soldiers saw their savings and their future turn
into nothingness. <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> children starved. <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> businessmen, during
the same period, bought ancient <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> estates for pocket change in
foreign currency. </p>

<p>The <ent type='NORP'>Weimar</ent> regime was a sink-pit of degeneracy, corruption, and
ugliness. Nihilistic creeds of self-destruction were made popular by
the mostly <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent>-controlled magazines and newspapers. Drug use
skyrocketed. Homosexuality suddenly became "fashionable." <ent type='ORG'>Modern</ent> "art"
replaced the beautiful images of the pre-1918 period. Pornography of
the grossest and most indecent kind was popularized. <ent type='PERSON'>Marx</ent>ism was
preached from university lecterns and even many church pulpits. Sound
familiar? </p>

<p>This was what it meant to implement <ent type='EVENT'>the New World</ent> Order in <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent>.
What followed was a powerful reaction against <ent type='EVENT'>the New World</ent> Order. But
it was not merely a reaction. Nor was it an impractical attempt to
reinstate the Old Order, although it did preserve much of what was
good in the Old Order. </p>

<p>The Old Order had been based on monarchy and <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent>ity. Even in the
anti-monarchical United States, <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> baptism was a widespread
qualification for holding public office until the middle of 19th
century. This reliance on religion alone as the official basis of
society had made the Old Order vulnerable. Belief in <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent>ity had
declined, especially among more educated Europeans. Some of the best
minds of our race were resentful of the Old Order. And the reliance on
<ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent>ity meant any racial alien could become part of the nation
simply by undergoing the ritual of baptism. For many <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, this ritual
was meaningless. It was simply submitted to as a means to achieve
power. </p>

<p>In opposition to <ent type='EVENT'>the New World</ent> Order, <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> erected his New Order of
Europe. It had some of the characteristics of the Old Order; for
example, it preserved the nation-state and traditional morality. It
also preserved many of Old Order's trappings, such as the customary
<ent type='NORP'>Roman</ent> salute. But it was different from the Old Order in that it was
primarily based, not on religion, but on race. </p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>Misinformation</ent> about National Socialist <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> </p>

<p>A tremendous amount of malicious dishonesty has been directed against
the memory of Hitler's New European Order. For example, there has been
an effort to manipulate <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent>s with the lie that Adolf <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> was
a scourge of <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent>ity. In fact, Adolf <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> received a great deal
of support from <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> clergymen, <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> and <ent type='NORP'>Lutheran</ent>. Among the
smaller sects, the Seventh Day Adventist and New Apostolic churches
were among the most ardent supporters of National Socialism, long
before the party actually came to power. </p>

<p>Another lie is that <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> was a member of <ent type='ORG'>the Thule Society</ent>. Such a
society did exist, but <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> regarded it as an embarrassment. You may
read his opinion of its freakish "occult" characters in the last
chapter of Book I of <ent type='PERSON'>Mein Kampf</ent>. </p>

<p>It is also a lie that <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> took away the guns from the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>
people. The promoters of this falsehood usually make the insinuation
by means of a verbal shell-game, in which they distort the actual
disarming of non-citizen, non-<ent type='NORP'>German</ent>, <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> deportees during the war
into a fictitious disarming of the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> people -- an event which
never took place under National Socialism. </p>

<p>The National Socialists actually relaxed the gun laws in <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent>. In
fact, private ownership of guns persisted in <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> until the New
World Order forces of the Allies rolled in and confiscated guns, and
converted <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> into a brainwashed province of <ent type='EVENT'>the New World</ent> Order. </p>

<p>This myth of <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> the gun-grabber has been promoted most
vociferously by an organization calling itself "<ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> for the
Preservation of Firearms Ownership." It should be clear that <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> in
general are a very biased source of information about
<ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent>. </p>

<p>Why Is <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> Demonized? </p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> is accused of many things he did not do, but there is one thing
he did do. He broke the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>' grip on <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> and restored <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> to
the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> people. This fact is reflected in his popularity; during
most of his administration, Adolf <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> was favorably regarded by
more than 90% of the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> people -- a popularity which no <ent type='NORP'>American</ent>
President has ever matched. </p>

<p>Because <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> put the interests of his own people first, and freed
them from <ent type='EVENT'>the New World</ent> Order, World <ent type='ORG'>Jewry</ent> declared war on <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> in
1933. They revived essentially the same propaganda they had used
against the <ent type='ORG'>Kaiser</ent>. With appropriate changes, the same kind of
propaganda is used to rouse us against whoever the current enemy of
<ent type='EVENT'>the New World</ent> Order happens to be. </p>

<p>Heaven forbid that our people should ever have a strong leader who
cares for our survival as a people, as <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> cared for
<ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent>. That would not suit <ent type='EVENT'>the New World</ent> Order at all! </p>

<p>And that is why the obsession with <ent type='ORG'>the democratic republic</ent> as a form
of government is a grievous error in the <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> patriot movement.
When <ent type='EVENT'>the New World</ent> Order was implemented in <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent>, it included the
establishment of a <ent type='NORP'>republican</ent> constitution in place of the monarchy.
Our political tradition in the U.S. and our public school education
lead us automatically to regard this as progress. Really, we ought not
to be so smug. </p>

<p>Those who make "democracy" their political ideal are, whether they
realize it or not, helping <ent type='EVENT'>the New World</ent> Order. Our main concern about
government should not be whether it is a "big government" or a
"democratic" government, but whether it is a government which serves
us -- or serves our enemies. </p>

<p>It is absurd to moralize against Adolf <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> for setting up a strong
government to preserve his people from <ent type='EVENT'>the New World</ent> Order. It is
absurd to criticize him for not acting like a typical <ent type='NORP'>American</ent>
conservative -- for not using approaches that have always failed.
<ent type='NORP'>Conservatives</ent> always compromise; they use half-measures and try to be
nice to everyone. It is to Hitler's credit that he saw clearly what
had to be done and did it, with very little compromise. Let us no
longer make virtues of irresolution and weakness; let us no longer
moralize against success. </p>

<p>The <ent type='EVENT'>New World</ent> Order Is Here Now </p>

<p>All of those so called "patriots," with their flag-waving and their
knee-jerk tendency to link everything bad to <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> -- including, most
ironically, <ent type='EVENT'>the New World</ent> Order -- have built their house on
quicksand, for it is <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States of <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> since 1933 which has
been the enforcer of <ent type='EVENT'>the New World</ent> Order, and it was <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> and her
allies in <ent type='EVENT'>World War</ent> II which defended our civilization against it. </p>

<p>It is customary for "patriotic" commentators to wail endlessly about
the threat of <ent type='EVENT'>the New World</ent> Order "taking over <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States." The
<ent type='EVENT'>New World</ent> Order is not some future threat. It rules now. </p>

<p>The <ent type='EVENT'>New World</ent> Order crowd has been at the levers of power in the
United States during most of this century. They experienced a
temporary setback in the 1920s, during the Harding and <ent type='PERSON'>Coolidge</ent>
administrations, when popular sentiment recognized that the First
<ent type='EVENT'>World War</ent> had been a grievous error. During the 1920s immigration was
drastically reduced, and a number of <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> subversives were even
deported. But since <ent type='EVENT'>the Great Depression</ent> swept <ent type='PERSON'><ent type='PERSON'>Frank</ent>lin <ent type='PERSON'>Roosevelt</ent></ent> and
his retinue of <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> and <ent type='NORP'>Communists</ent> into power, <ent type='EVENT'>the New World</ent> Order has
had uninterrupted control of <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States Government.
The <ent type='PERSON'>McCarthy</ent> era marked the last important attempt to regain control
of <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States government for the <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> people. <ent type='PERSON'>McCarthy</ent>ism
failed because the full depth and racial nature of the problem were
not recognized and faced in a forthright manner. Most of the patriotic
efforts since <ent type='PERSON'>McCarthy</ent> have been far more timid, far less inclined to
call a spade a spade and, as a consequence, have failed utterly. </p>

<p>The Scare Word "<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>" </p>

<p>For telling the truth about <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent>, <ent type='EVENT'>World War</ent> II, and <ent type='EVENT'>the New World</ent>
Order, some of the coin salesmen will no doubt call me a "<ent type='NORP'>nazi</ent>." Let
me say this: There has never been a government on planet <ent type='LOC'>Earth</ent> that
could receive unqualified endorsement from me, or probably from any
reasonable man. </p>

<p>Learning from history is important, and it is interesting to study
various regimes from as objective an outlook as possible. This
becomes very difficult when a government, its leader, or its people
have become demonized and turned into a metaphor for
"evil." </p>

<p>Another heavily-demonized regime is the <ent type='LOC'>Old America</ent>, which I would
define roughly as pre-1965 <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>, or European-<ent type='GPE'>America</ent>. Hardly a day
goes by that the networks or the lie-papers don't torment us with a
documentary "proving" the evil "racism" and "oppression" that were
omnipresent in the <ent type='LOC'>Old America</ent>. However, anyone over 40 can remember
<ent type='GPE'>America</ent> was freer, safer, more cultured, more prosperous, and more
optimistic then than now. Exempt from demonization, of course, are New
World Order change agents like the <ent type='NORP'>Marxist</ent> profligate "<ent type='PERSON'>Martin Luther</ent>"
King and the unspeakable <ent type='PERSON'><ent type='PERSON'>Frank</ent>lin <ent type='PERSON'>Roosevelt</ent></ent>, who were doing their best
to destroy the <ent type='LOC'>Old America</ent> and everything it stood for. They are not
demonized, but are regarded as heroes, if not saints! </p>

<p>The National Socialist regime in <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> between 1933 and 1945 has
been demonized even more than the <ent type='LOC'>Old America</ent>. It has become a
metaphor for "evil" used by almost all political factions in the
insane asylum that still goes by the name "<ent type='GPE'>America</ent>." </p>

<p>We have the loony left accusing militias of being dangerous "<ent type='NORP'>nazi</ent>s,"
while some right-wing "patriot" groups accuse the <ent type='ORG'>Clintonistas</ent> and
their enforcers of being "<ent type='NORP'>nazi</ent>s," "fascists," "stormtroopers," etc.
"<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>" has become a word that one attaches to any form of government
power, or rebellion against government power, that one disapproves of.
For all practical purposes, the word has ceased to have any actual
meaning. </p>

<p>Like the word "witch" in the 16th century, the word "<ent type='NORP'>nazi</ent>" still has
the power to instill fear of ostracism or punishment, so cowards of
many political stripes do all sorts of mental and verbal gymnastics to
avoid the feared appellation. </p>

<p>The really interesting thing to note is that National Socialist
<ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> is not demonized by the establishment for its possible
faults -- but rather for one of its virtues. After all, many regimes
of yesterday -- and today -- have far less personal freedom
than was allowed citizens there. They have far less press freedom, far
more regimentation, far higher taxation, far more government
regulation, far more hostility toward their own citizens, and all the
rest of it. </p>

<p>The real reason, and in fact the only reason, National Socialist
<ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> is demonized is the same reason that pre-1965
<ent type='GPE'>America</ent> is demonized: Both favored the survival of the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> race.
This is a crime that <ent type='EVENT'>the New World</ent> Order cannot forgive. </p>

<p>Resistance to <ent type='EVENT'>the New World</ent> Order </p>

<p>The modern resistance to <ent type='EVENT'>the New World</ent> Order may be regarded as having
begun early in this century, when alarm over the blood soaked
<ent type='NORP'>Bolshevik</ent> <ent type='EVENT'>Revolution</ent> -- and its adherents in this country -- began to
grow. </p>

<p>Literally hundreds of nationalist, anti-<ent type='NORP'>Communist</ent>, and patriotic
societies and organizations have arisen, prospered, and fallen
in the past 80 years. Some of them achieved national recognition and
had many thousands of members and supporters. Some names you would
recognize, such as the <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> First Committee and the John Birch
Society. Some may be familiar to you from their current shortwave and
satellite radio broadcasts. While some of these organizations have
made small fortunes, both by selling quack cures (for disease and for
subversion) and by selling overpriced precious metals; they have all
failed to halt the advance of <ent type='EVENT'>the New World</ent> Order. </p>

<p>Why Opposition Has Failed </p>

<p>This failure can be attributed to the fact that the "patriots"
themselves accept a large part of <ent type='EVENT'>New World</ent> Order doctrine.
They accept the idea of "rights" inherent in all beings arguably
human, regardless of race, creed, color, sexual preference,
etc., etc. -- until you gag. As long as such nonsense is enshrined as
"sacred truth," the failure will continue. </p>

<p>The doctrine "all men are created equal" is one such sacred cow. It
must be repudiated by patriots, for in five short words it exemplifies
<ent type='EVENT'>New World</ent> Order ideology. </p>

<p>Its origin lies in the 18th century philosophy of the <ent type='NORP'>Enlightenment</ent>,
which first enshrined the ideas of 1) basic human equality, and 2)
rights which inhere in every human being equally regardless of the
worth or attainments of that human being. </p>

<p><ent type='EVENT'>The <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> <ent type='EVENT'>Revolution</ent></ent> may have merely adopted some of the notions of
the <ent type='NORP'>Enlightenment</ent>, such as "all men are created equal," simply because
these were fashionable ideas at the time which were conducive to
revolution. </p>

<p>The Declaration of Independence incorporates the very unfortunate
statement, the only statement from that document which the public
schools and the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent>-controlled media have made sure that we know by
heart: "We hold these truths to be self-evident, that all men are
created equal . . ." Now, it is obvious to almost everyone that
individual human beings are not born equal to each other. On the face
of it, <ent type='PERSON'>Thomas Jefferson</ent>'s statement is blatantly, and even
embarrassingly, untrue. <ent type='PERSON'>Jefferson</ent> himself later advocated repatriation
of <ent type='NORP'>Blacks</ent> to <ent type='LOC'>Africa</ent>. This may give us some insight into his more
mature and considered views. Unfortunately however, he did write that
phrase. </p>

<p>During the <ent type='NORP'>Enlightenment</ent>, leading philosophers such as <ent type='PERSON'>John Locke</ent> and
<ent type='PERSON'>Jean Jacques Rousseau</ent> seriously argued that everyone was born mentally
identical. Locke's term for the condition of the mind at birth was
tabula rasa, <ent type='NORP'>Latin</ent> for "blank slate." Racial differences were thought
to be due to environmental influence over the course of just a few
generations. These fallacies, part of the intellectual universe in
which <ent type='PERSON'>Thomas Jefferson</ent> lived, were overturned in the nineteenth
century. Many scientists, including <ent type='PERSON'>Charles Darwin</ent>, began making
discoveries that showed human equality was a myth. <ent type='PERSON'>Darwin</ent> dealt a
death blow to the superstitions of the <ent type='NORP'>Enlightenment</ent> by providing
evidence that man was part of the animal kingdom in which all are
clearly not created equal. </p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Darwin</ent> wrote that men are not tabulae rasae; human motivations and
emotions are based on instincts. These are at least partially
hereditary, and differ from one race to another. More recently,
mainstream psychology has largely acknowledged that the
characteristics of the mind are largely hereditary, although the
Politically Correct adherents of the <ent type='PERSON'>Boas</ent> school still
argue the point. </p>

<p>Science should have utterly dispelled the belief that all men are
created equal, but unfortunately, because it is a piece of cant
which has been enshrined on a holy relic of <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States it has
continued to distort thinking. The Declaration of Independence was not
regarded as a holy relic until about the 1840s, when it was put on
display in <ent type='ORG'>the National</ent> Portrait Gallery, at the urging of Daniel
Webster. </p>

<p>When "<ent type='PERSON'>Martin Luther</ent>" King Jr. spoke in <ent type='PERSON'>Washington</ent>, DC, in 1963, he
used the words in the Declaration as if they were a debt instrument.
He said, 'you claim to believe this; you must act accordingly.'
(Perhaps his <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> and <ent type='NORP'>Communist</ent> associate, <ent type='PERSON'>Stanley Levison</ent>, had
something to do with it.) It is a dramatic illustration of the latent
destructive power of wrong ideas. </p>

<p>The Declaration of Independence, with enthronement of <ent type='NORP'>Judaic</ent>
egalitarian dogma, has been a millstone around the neck of
the <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> people. It has provided powerful rhetorical ammunition
for egalitarian dogmatists. Yet, since it is one of the founding
documents of <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States, the average <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> does not feel
that it would be safe to say that the words of the Declaration are
obviously not literally true -- although he may know this perfectly
well. Thus the average <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> is intimidated into endorsing the
fundamental premise of <ent type='EVENT'>the New World</ent> Order, "all men are created
equal." </p>

<p>The Constitution of <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States is on an altogether higher
level. We are indeed fortunate to have the rights which the
Constitution expresses, but that piece of paper did not create them.
These rights are part of the <ent type='NORP'>Anglo Saxon</ent> tradition and spring from the
soul of our branch of the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> race. The <ent type='NORP'>republican</ent> form of
government has hardly existed outside of the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> world (except in
name) because it presupposes a self-discipline and independence of
thought which are characteristic primarily of our race. When the
<ent type='NORP'>republican</ent> form is transplanted to <ent type='LOC'>Africa</ent> or <ent type='LOC'>Asia</ent>, it simply does not
work the same way. <ent type='ORG'>Witness Liberia</ent>. Witness the Philippines. </p>

<p>Secret Societies, etc. </p>

<p>It is not without some trepidation that I set out to discuss obscure
conspiratorial aspects of <ent type='EVENT'>the New World</ent> Order; it is a
subject on which our enemies do not mind having patriots focus. The
very obscurity of the subject makes misrepresentation
easy, and the distance of such conspiracies from everyday life
suggests that there is nothing that an ordinary person can do to
resist. Some people who call themselves patriots have become so
wrapped up in fantasies that the most obvious facts have
escaped their notice: the fact, for example, that multiracialism is
the centerpiece of <ent type='EVENT'>the New World</ent> Order. </p>

<p>Many secret societies have been heavily influenced by Cabalism -- a
system of esoteric theory and "magic" developed by rabbis from the 7th
to 13th centuries. "<ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent>on" is an important term in Cabalism,
hence the series of <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent>-led organizations calling themselves
<ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent> or <ent type='ORG'>Illuminated</ent> Ones. The <ent type='NORP'>Freemasons</ent> are one of the secret
societies which have been influenced both by <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> and by Cabalism.
With <ent type='ORG'>Illuminism</ent> and <ent type='NORP'>Freemasonry</ent>, the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> essentially resumed the
ancient <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> practice of multiplying their own power by
proselytizing <ent type='GPE'>Gentiles</ent>. </p>

<p>We may note in passing the continuing <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> involvement in <ent type='EVENT'>New Age</ent>
cults, all of which, for some reason or other, seem to have "equality"
and "brotherhood" and "One World" as central themes. The credulous
followers of these cults are thus hoodwinked, like the <ent type='ORG'>Masons</ent>, into
advancing the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> agenda in the name of a spurious humanitarianism
with a small, or large, helping of "spiritual" gobbledygook thrown in.</p>

<p>It is customary among patriot commentators, eager to stay marginally
on the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>' good side, to point to some <ent type='GPE'>Gentile</ent> stooge as an excuse
to avoid implicating the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>. The so-called <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> "patriots" can
also be counted on to do this. The fact that these essentially <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent>
organizations try to ensnare <ent type='GPE'>Gentile</ent> stooges is not at all surprising
in light of <ent type='PERSON'>Isaiah</ent> 61, which states: </p>

<p> Aliens shall stand and feed your flocks, foreigners shall be your
plowmen and vine dressers; but you shall be called the priests of
the Lord, men shall speak of you as the ministers of our God; you
shall eat the wealth of nations, and in their riches you shall
glory. </p>

<p><ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> often recruit <ent type='GPE'>Gentiles</ent> to be their "plowmen and vine dressers,"
or some equivalent thereof. </p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>Grand Orient</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Freemasonry</ent> and quasi-<ent type='NORP'>Masonic</ent> secret societies such as
<ent type='PERSON'>Adam Weishaupt</ent>'s Order of <ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent> had an important role in inciting
the <ent type='NORP'>French</ent> <ent type='EVENT'>Revolution</ent>. The <ent type='ORG'>Grand Orient</ent> Lodge of <ent type='NORP'>Freemasonry</ent>,
notorious for being <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent>-controlled, horrified Europe by ordering
that <ent type='PERSON'>Louis XVI</ent> be executed. </p>

<p><ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> writer <ent type='PERSON'>Max Dimont</ent> states in <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, God, and History that there
was an addition to Cabalism in the 16th century, which has significant
implications: </p>

<p> A new metaphysical philosophy was injected into Cabalism in the
sixteenth century by one of the great <ent type='NORP'>Cabalistic</ent> scholars, Isaac
<ent type='PERSON'>Luria</ent> (1534-1572), known as <ent type='PERSON'>Ari</ent>, 'the lion.' <ent type='PERSON'>Luria</ent> held that all
matter and thought evolved through a three stage cycle: tzimtzum,
literally 'contraction' or thesis; shevirat <ent type='PERSON'>hakeilim</ent>, literally
'breaking of the vessels' or antithesis; and <ent type='GPE'>tikkun</ent>, literally
'restoration' or synthesis. </p>

<p>That last Hebrew term, <ent type='GPE'>tikkun</ent>, you have heard before: It is the name
of Rabbi <ent type='PERSON'>Michael Lerner</ent>'s <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> magazine. It was Rabbi <ent type='PERSON'>Lerner</ent> who was
the spiritual advisor of First Lady <ent type='PERSON'>Hillary Clinton</ent>. It was Rabbi
<ent type='PERSON'>Lerner</ent> who put the words "politics of meaning" into her mouth. </p>

<p>Also notable is <ent type='PERSON'>Jacob Frank</ent>, a <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent> and the leader of the <ent type='NORP'>Frankists</ent>.
They also called themselves the "<ent type='ORG'>Illuminated</ent>." This group
was part of what is called the "<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> Reformation," which also
included Hasidic Judaism. <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> writer, Norman F. <ent type='ORG'>Cantor</ent>,
states in The Sacred Chain: the History of the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>: </p>

<p> Central to Frank's doctrine, and practiced by him and some of his
followers, was the legitimacy of sexual promiscuity based on the
assumption, from <ent type='NORP'>Cabalistic</ent> derivation, that sexual activity was
a form of cosmic healing, unifying the spiritual and material
realms. </p>

<p>The "free love" advocated and practiced by <ent type='PERSON'>Jacob Frank</ent> and his ilk was
echoed in the <ent type='NORP'>French</ent> <ent type='EVENT'>Revolution</ent>, in the <ent type='NORP'>Bolshevik</ent> <ent type='EVENT'>Revolution</ent>, in the
radical <ent type='NORP'>abolitionist</ent> movement of the <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> Civil War era, and in
the hippie movement of the 60s. </p>

<p>Abolitionism </p>

<p>Perhaps the most destructive movement in <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> history was radical
abolitionism. This movement was comprised of a tiny minority of
lunatics and degenerates, who somehow made enough noise that they
succeeded in having America's racial identity officially destroyed. </p>

<p>Few of those involved were <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> themselves, but they represent an
example of the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> "ideals" of universal human equality, which are
vended to the gullible. </p>

<p>The general character of the <ent type='NORP'>abolitionist</ent>s is suggested by a memoir of
Henry B. <ent type='PERSON'>Stanton</ent>, who attended a convention of <ent type='NORP'>abolitionist</ent>s in
<ent type='GPE'>Boston</ent>: </p>

<p> There was a representative array on the front seats, near the
platform. First was <ent type='PERSON'>Garrison</ent>, his countenance calling to mind the
pictures of the prophet <ent type='PERSON'>Isaiah</ent> in a rapt mood; next was the fine
<ent type='NORP'>Roman</ent> head of <ent type='PERSON'>Wendell Phillips</ent>; at his right was Father <ent type='PERSON'>Lampson</ent>,
so called, a crazy loon -- his hair and flowing beard as white as
the driven snow. He was the inventor of the valuable
scythe-snath, and invariably carried a snath in his hand. His
<ent type='GPE'>forte</ent> was selling his wares on secular days and disturbing
religious meetings on <ent type='LOC'>Sun</ent>day. Next to <ent type='PERSON'>Lampson</ent> sat
<ent type='PERSON'>Edmund</ent> Quincy, high born and wealthy, the son of the famous
President Quincy [of <ent type='ORG'>Harvard</ent>]. Next to Quincy was <ent type='PERSON'>Abigail Folsom</ent>,
another lunatic, with a shock of unkempt hair reaching down to her
waist. At her right was George W. <ent type='PERSON'>Mellen</ent>, clad in the military
costume of the <ent type='EVENT'>Revolution</ent>, and fancying himself to be General
<ent type='PERSON'>Washington</ent>, because he was named after him. Poor <ent type='PERSON'>Mellen</ent> died in
an asylum. </p>

<p>Another prominent figure in Radical Abolitionism was Victoria
Woodhull, who was also a feminist, an occultist, and a
<ent type='NORP'>Communist</ent>. <ent type='PERSON'>Stanton</ent> continues: </p>

<p> As if her time did not pass spectacularly enough, Victoria
Woodhull organized an <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> section of the <ent type='ORG'>International</ent>
Workingmen's Association [the First <ent type='NORP'>Communist</ent> <ent type='ORG'>International</ent>]. In
this endeavor her chief ally was William <ent type='LOC'>West</ent> . . . Their section
of the <ent type='ORG'>International</ent> advocated woman's suffrage and sexual
freedom as well as <ent type='PERSON'>Stephen Pearl Andrews</ent>' pet theories of
universal language and "pantarchical" order." </p>

<p>These flakes were an embarrassment even to the <ent type='NORP'>Marxist</ent>s. In the
interests of party orthodoxy, <ent type='PERSON'>Victoria Woodhull</ent>'s section was expelled
from the party when <ent type='PERSON'>Marx</ent> relocated the center of <ent type='ORG'>World Communism</ent> from
<ent type='GPE'>London</ent> to <ent type='GPE'>New York City</ent> in 1872. </p>

<p>In 1863 Henry C. <ent type='PERSON'>Wright</ent> published The Self-Abnegationist, which was a
reaction against the findings of <ent type='PERSON'>Charles Darwin</ent> vis a vis the
implications for man. <ent type='PERSON'>Wright</ent> defined self-abnegation in these terms:
"Suffer rather than inflict suffering; die, rather than kill." </p>

<p>He further explains: </p>

<p> Self-preservation, at the expense of others, is condemned by
universal consciousness . . . . Let any man, whatever be his
moral or intellectual development, fully understand the meaning
of self-abnegation and then enter into the sacred and silent
depths of his own soul, and he will find this to be an abiding
law of his nature, to which he will find his heaven in being
obedient. </p>

<p>Mainstream historian <ent type='PERSON'>Lewis Perry</ent> states that there was behind radical
abolitionism a religious movement called "Perfectionism," which is
"the quest for perfect holiness and the idea that such perfection
might be immediately possible." <ent type='PERSON'>Perry</ent> further states: </p>

<p> <ent type='NORP'>Perfectionist</ent> ideas permeated the major denominations and
inspired a variety of shockingly radical splinter movements. It
was possible for those who deemed their personal sanctification
to be perfect to attack the practices of institutional churches
and hold themselves to new standards of morality. Rumors of
sexual promiscuity particularly haunted the career of
perfectionism in upstate <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent>. <ent type='PERSON'>John Humphrey Noyes</ent>
proceeded from the development of perfectionist religious
theories to preach common marriage among the saints, a belief
which, as practiced by <ent type='ORG'>Noyes</ent> and his followers at the Oneida
Community, was popularly referred to as "free love." Though free
love and the disruption of churches were of course widely
condemned, it was difficult for the evangelical orthodoxy to
distinguish its basic perfectionist beliefs from those of
scandalous radicals. </p>

<p>The combination of the term "perfectionism" with the advocacy of
sexual promiscuity is a suggestive parallel to <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> Cabalism. Adam
Weishaupt's Order of the <ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent> was also known as the
<ent type='PERSON'>Perfektibilisten</ent>. We return to <ent type='PERSON'>Perry</ent>: </p>

<p> The most notorious perfectionist was <ent type='PERSON'>John Humphrey Noyes</ent>. <ent type='ORG'>Noyes</ent>
had been brought up as an orthodox New <ent type='GPE'>England</ent>er and educated in
the '<ent type='ORG'>New Divinity</ent>' at <ent type='ORG'>Yale</ent>." After a meeting with <ent type='NORP'>abolitionist</ent>
leader William Lloyd <ent type='PERSON'>Garrison</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Noyes</ent> announced that he had
retracted his allegiance to <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States government and now
championed the claim of <ent type='PERSON'>Jesus Christ</ent> to the throne of the world.
He depicted the government as a fat libertine flogging <ent type='ORG'>Negroes</ent>
and torturing <ent type='NORP'>Indians</ent>. . . . "My hope of the millennium," he
wrote, "begins where Dr. Beecher's expires -- viz, at the
overthrow of this nation." </p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>James Russell Lowell</ent>, a prominent <ent type='NORP'>abolitionist</ent>, explicitly advocated
race-mixing, on the grounds that mulatto offspring would be more
submissive -- more "<ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent>" -- than the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> race. He wrote: </p>

<p> We have never had any doubt that the <ent type='LOC'>Africa</ent>n race was intended to
introduce a new element of civilization, and that the <ent type='NORP'>Caucasian</ent>
would be benefited greatly by an infusion of its gentler and less
selfish qualities. The <ent type='NORP'>Caucasian</ent> mind, which always seeks to
govern, at whatever cost, can never come to so beautiful or
<ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> a height of civilization, as with a mixture of those
seemingly humble, but truly more noble, qualities which teach it
to obey. </p>

<p><ent type='NORP'>Abolitionist</ent> Henry C. <ent type='PERSON'>Wright</ent> stated in 1857 what would become the
actual agenda of the <ent type='ORG'>Reconstruction</ent> period: </p>

<p> A baptism of blood awaits the slave holder and his abettors. So
be it. The retribution is just. Must the slave holders become the
slaves of those whom they have enslaved? History answers "Yes."
If slavery goes down in blood, the conquered will be the bondsmen
and bondswomen of the conquerors; for the practical teaching of
<ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> and State is, that might makes the right to enslave. Bid
<ent type='NORP'>American</ent> slave holders beware! Their turn may come, will come,
must come, to be bought and sold as brutes, and to have their
wives and daughters consigned to the Negro's harem, unless they
willingly and penitently let their slaves go free. </p>

<p>It should be noted that, aside from the grotesque dream of forced
miscegenation, Wright's vision is not essentially different
from that of <ent type='PERSON'>Karl Marx</ent>; it was an axiom of <ent type='NORP'>Marxist</ent> anarchism that
workers were in fact slaves, who would one day change
places with their masters. </p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Marx</ent>ism: <ent type='ORG'>Illuminism</ent> Reincarnate </p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Karl Marx</ent>, though he disclaimed the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> religion, was the
descendent of a long line of rabbis. Both his father and mother
were <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>. His father, <ent type='PERSON'>Heinrich</ent>, a well-to-do lawyer who was a dutiful
follower of the <ent type='NORP'>Enlightenment</ent> philosophers, was faced with a choice of
being baptized or giving up his profession. He chose the former. </p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Karl Marx</ent> had no mystical pretensions whatsoever; he called his
ideology "dialectical materialism," incorporating a semblance of the
<ent type='NORP'>Hegelian</ent> philosophy which was the popular, mainstream philosophy of
that time. </p>

<p>One often hears patriotic broadcasters refer vaguely to "the <ent type='NORP'>Hegelian</ent>
dialectic," as if <ent type='NORP'>Hegelian</ent>ism itself were a tool of conspiracy. In
fact, <ent type='PERSON'>Karl Marx</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Friedrich Engels</ent> both stated repeatedly that the
<ent type='NORP'>Hegelian</ent> dialectic, as espoused by Hegel, was not and could not be an
instrument of conspiracy. I consider it important to exonerate Hegel
because it appears as part of a general knee-jerk tendency to dump on
the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>s whenever possible so as to appease the real perpetrators
of <ent type='EVENT'>the New World</ent> Order, the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>. </p>

<p>The Political Spectrum </p>

<p>In recent years, when the term <ent type='NORP'>Conservative</ent> has been redefined to mean
laissez faire -- a meaning it never had before -- it has become the
fashion among the historically myopic to redefine the terms "right"
and "left" in politics. They claim that the left stands for "more
government" and that the right stands for "less government," that
<ent type='ORG'>Communism</ent> is the extreme of the left and Anarchy the extreme of the
right. This conception of the political spectrum is a false one.
Historically, <ent type='PERSON'>Marx</ent>ism has embraced both <ent type='ORG'>Communism</ent> and Anarchism. The
<ent type='NORP'>Anarchists</ent> of 100 years ago, such as <ent type='PERSON'>Alexander Birkman</ent> and "<ent type='ORG'>Red Emma</ent>"
Goldman, were called "<ent type='ORG'>Reds</ent>," and they were indeed <ent type='NORP'>Marxist</ent>s who used
the familiar <ent type='NORP'>Marxist</ent> slogans. On the ostensible premise that society
makes men bad, the <ent type='NORP'>Marxist</ent> ideal is precisely the elimination of all
government, and of all other social barriers -- the same ideal which
<ent type='PERSON'>Adam Weishaupt</ent> espoused. The real motive behind this abhorrence of
social barriers is simply the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>' desire to recreate our society in
their own image, so that they will have a free hand to engage in
power-seeking activities without the barriers that traditional <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent>
societies imposed on them. They would like to freely engage in all the
abhorrent practices which emanate from the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> soul and are
condoned by their <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> lawbook, the <ent type='ORG'>Talmud</ent>. </p>

<p>Perhaps it is clear now why laissez faire is so widely touted by <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>
like <ent type='PERSON'>Milton Friedman</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Ayn Rand</ent>. <ent type='ORG'>Laissez</ent> faire and <ent type='PERSON'>Marx</ent>ism are not
the opposites that most of our people assume them to be. <ent type='PERSON'>Marx</ent>ism
actually goes farther than laissez faire, advocating a never-never
land in which there is no government whatsoever. </p>

<p>The Captain of the Chicago Police, Michael J. <ent type='ORG'>Schaack</ent>, stated in his
1889 book Anarchy and <ent type='NORP'>Anarchists</ent>: a History of the Red Terror and the
Social <ent type='EVENT'>Revolution</ent> in <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> and Europe: </p>

<p> It [anarchism] is founded upon the teachings of <ent type='PERSON'>Karl Marx</ent> and his
disciples, and it aims directly at the complete destruction of
all forms of government and religion. It offers no solution of
the problems which will arise when society, as we understand it,
shall disappear, but contents itself with declaring that the duty
at hand is tearing down; that the work of building up must come
later. </p>

<p>When one considers that anarchism is, in fact, laissez faire carried a
step farther, it becomes apparent that <ent type='PERSON'>Marx</ent>ism and the beloved laissez
faire doctrine of today's so-called <ent type='NORP'>Conservatives</ent> are intimately
related. The two philosophies are in fact striving toward the same
impossible goal: a world without any constraints or conflict, and with
plenty for everyone. The salient element in <ent type='PERSON'>Marx</ent>ism and laissez faire
is the drive to abolish the constraints and the order of healthy <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent>
society. The bribe which these <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> doctrines offer to their <ent type='GPE'>Gentile</ent>
adherents is a license for self-indulgence In the name of laissez
faire, our millionaires justify stabbing <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> workingmen in the
back by importing workers from the non-<ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> world. And under <ent type='NORP'>Marxist</ent>
inspiration, the so-called "civil rights" movement was organized. Now,
it is obvious that the so-called "civil rights" movement resulted in
less freedom for <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> people, but it has on the whole, by its
destruction of communities and social norms, increased the level of
anarchy, in the sense of chaos, in our society. </p>

<p>Furthermore, although it did produce an expansion of government, the
really significant thing is that the government has been perverted.
The big government we have today is distinctly anti-<ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> and is
pernicious in ways that a pro-<ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> government of equal proportions
would not be. Indeed if an equally powerful state had been organized
for the purpose of fighting off the enemies of our race, perhaps we
would not have been conquered by infiltration as we have been today. </p>

<p>Big Government </p>

<p>Any people which is at war will necessarily have a big government, and
that is true whether the enemy is internal or external. The reason why
our enemies, the enemies of our race, have built up a big government
is that they have marked us, racially conscious <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> men and women
(and really all <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> people) as enemies in our own land. Big
government has been built up to wage war against us. Should we ever
gain control of the seat of power, any scruples about using "big
government" against our enemies will be a disaster, a snatching of
defeat from the jaws of victory. The redefinition of "conservative" to
mean "laissez faire" would be crippling at the very brink of victory.
A government in the hands of <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> patriots will have to be a
powerful government if it is to correct all the damage that has been
done by the current anti-<ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> regime. </p>

<p>So the question of left and right is not a question of more or less
government. The original "rightists," were supporting the big
government (for its time) of <ent type='PERSON'>Louis XVI</ent>, and the original "leftists"
like <ent type='PERSON'>Weishaupt</ent> advocated anarchy. But anarchism is always
a transitional ideology; anarchy is a power-vacuum, and Nature abhors
a vacuum. Ultimately, the question is whether we will live in a
society ordered according to the character of our own race or
according to the demands of that vastly different Middle <ent type='LOC'>East</ent>ern race.</p>

<p>This anti-government attitude among patriots is understandable,
because in <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States our experiences with big government are
almost all bad. Really big government in the U.S. began with <ent type='PERSON'>Frank</ent>lin
<ent type='PERSON'>Roosevelt</ent>. In the U.S., more government has always meant more racially
destructive policies. This is simply because of the malevolent entity
which controls our government. A government that is truly of, by, and
for our people would not be of that nature, so the axiom that
big government is bad government would not necessarily apply. </p>

<p>The crucial question about government is whether it is run by and for
our people, or whether it is run by and for the enemies of our people.</p>

<p>Recruiting <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> as a Partner in <ent type='EVENT'>the New World</ent> Order </p>

<p>Today in <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States both political parties are universalist,
and both see man as a mainly economic entity. They share
these characteristics with <ent type='PERSON'>Marx</ent>ism. The only valid alternative, the
only true antithesis to <ent type='EVENT'>the New World</ent> Order, is a society based on
race. Only by establishing a race-based society can <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> and the
civilization of the <ent type='LOC'>West</ent> survive. Only by establishing a race-based
community can we begin to defeat <ent type='EVENT'>the New World</ent> Order. </p>

<p>The last time <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> was culturally healthy was in the 1920s.
<ent type='ORG'>International</ent>ism had been repudiated. The First <ent type='EVENT'>World War</ent> had been
recognized as a grievous mistake, and America's leaders were committed
to keeping <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> out of any such future catastrophes. Eugenics as a
national policy seemed entirely possible for <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States of the
1920s. </p>

<p>The last healthy epoch of America's existence was overturned by the
Great <ent type='EVENT'>Depression</ent>. The abrupt stock-market crash which heralded the
<ent type='EVENT'>Depression</ent> did not take the leaders of <ent type='ORG'>Jewry</ent> by surprise. Some have
argued that the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> used their control of credit through the Federal
Reserve System, which they had in place from the days of their puppet
<ent type='PERSON'>Woodrow Wilson</ent>, to engineer the stock-market crash. Regardless of
whether the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> caused the crash, manipulated it, or merely had
inside knowledge of it; evidence suggests that <ent type='PERSON'>Bernard Baruch</ent> (an
extremely wealthy <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> speculator who had been one of the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent>
string pullers behind <ent type='ORG'>Wilson</ent> and virtual economic czar during World
War I), knew exactly when the crash was coming. He abruptly pulled all
his money out of stocks only a few days before the stock market crash,
over the protests of his broker. After the crash, leading <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> were
able to buy up <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> industry for practically nothing. </p>

<p>It is an old saw that money is the mother's milk of political
campaigns. With their vastly increased share of the <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> pie,
and with a smear campaign, the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> were able to blame <ent type='PERSON'>Herbert Hoover</ent>
for the depression and replace him with their puppet <ent type='PERSON'>Roosevelt</ent>, who
had run as a <ent type='NORP'>Conservative</ent> but governed as a <ent type='NORP'>Marxist</ent> socialist and did
not let the Constitution get in his way. <ent type='PERSON'>Roosevelt</ent> was also notorious
for stocking the executive branch with large numbers of <ent type='NORP'>Communists</ent> and
<ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>; many of whom remained for decades. </p>

<p>When <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> dispossessed the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, who had robbed them on a scale far
more massive than in <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States, the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> wanted revenge. Along
the way, the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> killed several birds with one stone. In order to
discredit the eugenics movement which still had proponents in the
United States, the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> involved <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> in what amounted to a war
against eugenics. It is said that a war makes any cause sacred, and
<ent type='EVENT'>the Second World War</ent> made the cause of doing the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>'
bidding sacred in this country. This false religion remains in place
to this day. </p>

<p><ent type='EVENT'>The Cold War</ent> Era </p>

<p>At the end of <ent type='EVENT'>the Second Fratricidal War</ent> in Europe, genuine patriotic
<ent type='NORP'>American</ent>s like George S. <ent type='PERSON'>Patton</ent> urged that <ent type='NORP'>Bolshevism</ent> be finished off
by military means. Several years later, Senator <ent type='PERSON'>Joseph</ent> R. <ent type='PERSON'>McCarthy</ent>
published America's Retreat from Victory, which argued that the reason
why the opportunity to destroy <ent type='NORP'>Bolshevism</ent> had not been grasped was
that the <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> government was controlled by <ent type='NORP'>Communist</ent> sympathizers
-- an obvious fact to anyone who takes the time to investigate the
matter. The division of the world into two enemy factions helped the
<ent type='EVENT'>New World</ent> Order planners in many ways. By maintaining <ent type='ORG'>Communism</ent> and
capitalism as two ostensibly hostile brands of <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> universalism,
<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> bankers and arms merchants were able to create wars at leisure.
And by financing and selling arms to both sides in the various hot
wars and in the ongoing <ent type='EVENT'>Cold War</ent>, they were able to vastly increase
their wealth and the debt-burden of the entire world. </p>

<p>Furthermore, the <ent type='EVENT'>Cold War</ent>, with its focus on foreign aggression,
diverted attention from subversion at home. Subversion in
<ent type='GPE'>America</ent> advanced most rapidly during the <ent type='EVENT'>Cold War</ent>, especially during
<ent type='EVENT'>the Vietnam War</ent>, when patriotic <ent type='NORP'>American</ent>s were afraid to complain too
loudly lest the country appear further divided in the face of its
foreign foe. </p>

<p>At the same time, the <ent type='EVENT'>Cold War</ent>'s constant focus on a foreign menace
caused people to overlook the treason in their own government. It was
the end of the <ent type='EVENT'>Cold War</ent> that allowed America's racial consciousness to
spring back to life -- in time to survey all the damage that treason
had wrought in forty years. Not the least of this treason was the
media's gradual brainwashing of our people, many of whom had learned
to think of <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> only as the vehicle of a certain brand of
universalism -- the liberal capitalist brand. This brand of
universalism was then represented as the only alternative to
<ent type='ORG'>Communism</ent>. The liberal capitalist world view, this phony
neo-conservatism, was the rationale for <ent type='ORG'>NAFTA</ent> and for free trade
with <ent type='GPE'>China</ent>: In a purely materialistic and economic world view, whether
it be laissez faire or <ent type='ORG'>Communism</ent>, race and nation receive no
consideration. It is an encouraging sign, however, that in spite of
the brainwashing, the majority reaction was against <ent type='ORG'>NAFTA</ent>. This shows
that part of <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> still has some will to live. </p>

<p>The "<ent type='ORG'>Civil Rights</ent>" Movement </p>

<p>What damaged <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> more than anything else in recent times has been
the so-called "<ent type='ORG'>Civil Rights</ent>" movement. It is misnamed because it is
not about "rights" but about enforcing equality. This movement was
planned by the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> after <ent type='EVENT'>the Second World War</ent> and was carried out at
the tactical level by <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> agitators and fellow travelers who held
positions of influence in the media and universities. This war against
the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> race was also waged by <ent type='GPE'>Gentile</ent> stooges like Dwight David
<ent type='PERSON'>Eisenhower</ent>, who appointed <ent type='PERSON'>Earl Warren</ent> to <ent type='ORG'>the Supreme Court</ent>, then said
"Oops!" with a pretended look of surprise. Nevertheless, he did not
neglect to send paratroopers to <ent type='GPE'>Little Rock</ent> to enforce the Warren
Court's anti-<ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> agenda. <ent type='PERSON'>Eisenhower</ent>, the protege of <ent type='PERSON'>Bernard Baruch</ent>,
had also been the first "supreme commander" of the Soviet-<ent type='NORP'>American</ent>
alliance that called itself the "United Nations" even before <ent type='NORP'>Communist</ent>
agent <ent type='PERSON'>Alger Hiss</ent> chaired the nominal founding meeting of that
organization in <ent type='GPE'>San Francisco</ent> several years later. Eisenhower's mentor
<ent type='PERSON'>Baruch</ent> was also a leader of the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> community in the <ent type='LOC'>West</ent>ern
Hemisphere; at this point it is very clear how everything ties
together. </p>

<p>Immigration </p>

<p>What threatens <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> most today is immigration. The United States
government has for years been under-funding its border patrol and
refusing to take adequate measures to curb the illegal immigration of
fast-breeding mestizos. You will recall that non-<ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> immigration was
part of <ent type='EVENT'>the New World</ent> Order program described by F.S. <ent type='PERSON'>Marvin</ent> in 1932.
In <ent type='GPE'>Canada</ent> this destructive immigration is part of official government
policy. Almost one-quarter of a million largely non-<ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> immigrants
enter <ent type='GPE'>Canada</ent> legally every year, despite horrendous unemployment among
the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> population. The U.S. government pursues by subterfuge the
very same <ent type='EVENT'>New World</ent> Order policy which the Canadian government pursues
openly, and which the <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> government pursued by bringing <ent type='NORP'>Blacks</ent>
into <ent type='GPE'>Britain</ent>. </p>

<p>One would have to be brain-dead to believe that the motive for
bringing these fast-breeding non-<ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> populations into our
homelands is in any way charitable, since any relief afforded to
<ent type='GPE'>Mexico</ent> by emigration will quickly be cancelled by population
increase. The population of <ent type='GPE'>Mexico</ent> doubles every nineteen years!
Current policies will lead to the entire world being overpopulated
with brown men and women. </p>

<p>As <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> becomes increasingly non-<ent type='PERSON'>White</ent>, it will also become
increasingly unfree. A people united by common blood and common values
need few laws, few prisons, and few policemen to get along peaceably.
Multicultural empires are not known for their freedom. </p>

<p>Non-<ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>, populated by mulattos and mestizos, will be easier
for our enemies to control and exploit, and whatever <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> minority
remains, if it adheres to the representative process, will be
perennially behind the eight-ball, always outvoted by racial aliens
being manipulated by our enemies. It seems to me that those
multiracial "Constitutional" patriots, who want us all to pretend that
race doesn't matter, are leading their adherents in precisely this
direction: toward a United States in which the Constitution is a
revered artifact with even less influence than it has today. </p>

<p>We do not have to accept this fate, nor will the fight be impossible!
<ent type='PERSON'>Louis XVI</ent> and Czar Nicholas II died because they lacked the will to
resist and didn't even really try. We understand what is happening. A
highly motivated and disciplined minority can change the course of
history. It has happened before. In fact, it has seldom happened any
other way. </p>

<p>We have every reason to fight, and no incentive whatsoever to give up,
for the loss of our race means the loss of everything. The struggle
itself will make us strong! </p>

<p> Editor's Note: All five parts of the original radio broadcast are
contained in this issue of Free Speech. Due to space limitations,
and to avoid repetition, more editing than usual was required. The
audio tapes of this series contain the complete shows as
originally broadcast. These tapes are available for the special
price of $50.00 postpaid. </p>

<p> For further information write to <ent type='ORG'>National Vanguard Books</ent>, PO Box
330, <ent type='GPE'>Hillsboro</ent> WV 24946 USA. </p>

<p>National Alliance Home Page
http://www,natvan.com

</p></xml>