<xml><p> JOHN STOCKWELL</p>

<p> THE SECRET WARS OF THE <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent></p>

<p> 10 October 1987</p>

<p> A two-part speech.</p>

<p> Copyright (C) 1987 <ent type='ORG'>The Other Americas</ent> Radio
<ent type='PERSON'>John Stockwell</ent> is the highest-ranking <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> official ever to leave the
agency and go public. He ran a <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> intelligence-gathering post in
<ent type='GPE'>Vietnam</ent>, was the task-force commander of the CIA's secret war in
<ent type='GPE'>Angola</ent> in 1975 and 1976, and was awarded the Medal of Merit before he
resigned. Stockwell's book In Search of Enemies, published by W.W.
<ent type='ORG'>Norton</ent> 1978, is an international best-seller. This is a transcript of
a lecture he gave in June, 1986. </p>

<p> The policy of <ent type='ORG'>The Other Americas</ent> Radio regarding reproducing this
lecture is that while they would like to see it reproduced and passed
around as much as possible, they also need money to operate (they are
not-for-profit). Thus, please pass a copy of this transcript on, and
if you like the transcript, send a donation to them (the tape costs 13
dollars, and they have other tapes as well) at:
<ent type='ORG'>The Other Americas</ent> Radio
Programs &amp; News on <ent type='LOC'>Latin America</ent>.
KCSB-FM, Box 85
<ent type='GPE'>Santa Barbara</ent>, CA 93102
(805) 569-5381</p>

<p> For the on-line (electronic) version of this transcription, contact
toad@nl.cs.cmu.edu on the <ent type='ORG'>ARPA</ent> network, or retrieve, via FTP, the file
/usr/toad/text/talk/speech.doc or /usr/toad/text/talk/speech.<ent type='PERSON'>mss</ent> from
the NL.CS.CMU.EDU vax. Also available as a paper manuscript, or
digitally on disk. Write to P.O.Box 81795, <ent type='GPE'>Pittsburgh</ent>, PA 15217.</p>

<p> PART I</p>

<p> THE INNER WORKINGS OF <ent type='ORG'>THE NATIONAL SECURITY COUNCIL</ent> AND THE
CIA'S COVERT ACTIONS IN ANGOLA, CENTRAL AMERICA AND VIETNAM</p>

<p> "I did 13 years in the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> altogether. I sat on a subcommittee of
the <ent type='ORG'>NSC</ent>, so I was like a chief of staff, with the GS-18s (like 3-star
generals) <ent type='PERSON'>Henry Kissinger</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Bill Colby</ent> (the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> director), the GS-18s
and the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>, making the important decisions and my job was to put it
all together and make it happen and run it, an interesting place from
which to watch a covert action being done....</p>

<p> I testified for days before the <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>, giving them chapter and
verse, date and detail, proving specific lies. They were asking if we
had to do with S. <ent type='LOC'>Africa</ent>, that was fighting in the country. In fact
we were coordinating this operation so closely that our airplanes,
full of arms from the states, would meet their airplanes in <ent type='GPE'>Kinshasa</ent>
and they would take our arms into <ent type='GPE'>Angola</ent> to distribute to our forces
for us....</p>

<p> What I found with all of this study is that the subject, the
problem, if you will, for the world, for the U.S. is much, much, much
graver, astronomically graver, than just <ent type='GPE'>Angola</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Vietnam</ent>. I found
that the Senate <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> committee has reported, in their study of
covert actions, that the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> ran several thousand covert actions since
1961, and that the heyday of covert action was before 1961; that we
have run several hundred covert actions a year, and the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> has been
in business for a total of 37 years.</p>

<p> What we're going to talk about tonight is <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States national
security syndrome. We're going to talk about how and why the U.S.
manipulates the press. We're going to talk about how and why the U.S.
is pouring money into El Salvador, and preparing to invade <ent type='GPE'>Nicaragua</ent>;
how all of this concerns us so directly. I'm going to try to explain
to you the other side of terrorism; that is, the other side of what
Secretary of State <ent type='PERSON'>Shultz</ent> talks about. In doing this, we'll talk
about <ent type='EVENT'>the Korean war</ent>, the <ent type='GPE'>Vietnam</ent> war, and the <ent type='NORP'><ent type='ORG'>Central</ent> <ent type='NORP'>American</ent></ent> war.</p>

<p> Everything I'm going to talk to you about is represented, one way or
another, already in the public records. You can dig it all out for
yourselves, without coming to hear me if you so chose. Books, based
on information gotten out of the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> under the freedom of information
act, testimony before the <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>, hearings before the Senate <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>
committee, research by scholars, witness of people throughout the
world who have been to these target areas that we'll be talking about.
I want to emphasize that my own background is profoundly conservative.
We come from <ent type='GPE'>South Texas</ent>, <ent type='LOC'>East Texas</ent>....</p>

<p> I was conditioned by my training, my marine corps training, and my
background, to believe in everything they were saying about the cold
war, and I took the job with great enthusiasm (in the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>) to join the
best and the brightest of the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>, of our foreign service, to go out
into the world, to join the struggle, to project <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> values and
save the world for our brand of democracy. And I believed this. I
went out and worked hard....</p>

<p> What I really got out of these 6 years in <ent type='LOC'>Africa</ent> was a sense ...
that nothing we were doing in fact defended U.S. national security
interests very much. We didn't have many national security interests
in <ent type='GPE'>Bujumbura</ent>, Burundi, in the heart of <ent type='LOC'>Africa</ent>. I concluded that I
just couldn't see the point.</p>

<p> We were doing things it seemed because we were there, because it was
our function, we were bribing people, corrupting people, and not
protecting the U.S. in any visible way. I had a chance to go drinking
with this <ent type='PERSON'>Larry Devlin</ent>, a famous <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> case officer who had overthrown
<ent type='PERSON'>Patrice Lumumba</ent>, and had him killed in 1960, back in the <ent type='GPE'>Congo</ent>. He
was moving into the <ent type='LOC'>Africa</ent> division Chief. I talked to him in Addis
Ababa at length one night, and he was giving me an explanation - I was
telling him frankly, 'sir, you know, this stuff doesn't make any
sense, we're not saving anybody from anything, and we are corrupting
people, and everybody knows we're doing it, and that makes the U.S.
look bad'.</p>

<p> And he said I was getting too big for my britches. He said, 'you're
trying to think like the people in the <ent type='ORG'>NSC</ent> back in <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent> who have
the big picture, who know what's going on in the world, who have all
the secret information, and the experience to digest it. If they
decide we should have someone in <ent type='GPE'>Bujumbura</ent>, Burundi, and that person
should be you, then you should do your job, and wait until you have
more experience, and you work your way up to that point, then you will
understand national security, and you can make the big decisions.
Now, get to work, and stop, you know, this philosophizing.'</p>

<p> And I said, 'Aye-aye sir, sorry sir, a bit out of line sir'. It's a
very powerful argument, our presidents use it on us. President Reagan
has used it on the <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> people, saying, 'if you knew what I know
about the situation in <ent type='LOC'><ent type='ORG'>Central</ent> <ent type='GPE'>America</ent></ent>, you would understand why it's
necessary for us to intervene.'</p>

<p> I went back to <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, however, and I found that others shared
my concern. A formal study was done in the State Department and
published internally, highly classified, called the <ent type='ORG'>Macomber</ent> [sp?]
report, concluding that the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> had no business being in <ent type='LOC'>Africa</ent> for
anything it was known to be doing, that our presence there was not
justified, there were no national security interests that the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>
could address any better than the ambassador himself. We didn't need
to have bribery and corruption as a tool for doing business in <ent type='LOC'>Africa</ent>
at that time.</p>

<p> I went from ... a tour in <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent> to <ent type='GPE'>Vietnam</ent>. And there, my
career, and my life, began to get a little bit more serious. They
assigned me a country. It was during the cease-fire, '73 to '75.
There was no cease-fire. Young men were being slaughtered. I saw a
slaughter. 300 young men that the South <ent type='GPE'>Vietnam</ent>ese army ambushed.
Their bodies brought in and laid out in a lot next to my compound. I
was up-country in <ent type='GPE'>Tayninh</ent>. They were laid out next door, until the
families could come and claim them and take them away for burial.</p>

<p> I thought about this. I had to work with the sadistic police chief.
When I reported that he liked to carve people with knives in the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>
safe-house - when I reported this to my bosses, they said, '(1). The
post was too important to close down. (2). They weren't going to get
the man transferred or fired because that would make problems,
political problems, and he was very good at working with us in the
operations he worked on. (3). Therefore if I didn't have the stomach
for the job, that they could transfer me.'</p>

<p> But they hastened to point out, if I did demonstrate a lack of
'moral fiber' to handle working with the sadistic police chief, that I
wouldn't get another good job in the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>, it would be a mark against
my career.</p>

<p> So I kept the job, I closed the safe-house down, I told my staff
that I didn't approve of that kind of activity, and I proceeded to
work with him for the next 2 years, pretending that I had reformed
him, and he didn't do this sort of thing anymore. The parallel is
obvious with El Salvador today, where the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>, the state department,
works with the death squads.</p>

<p> They don't meet the death squads on the streets where they're
actually chopping up people or laying them down on the street and
running trucks over their heads. The <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> people in <ent type='GPE'>San Salvador</ent> meet
the police chiefs, and the people who run the death squads, and they
do liaise with them, they meet them beside the swimming pool of the
villas. And it's a sophisticated, civilized kind of relationship.
And they talk about their children, who are going to school at <ent type='ORG'>UCLA</ent> or
<ent type='ORG'>Harvard</ent> and other schools, and they don't talk about the horrors of
what's being done. They pretend like it isn't true.</p>

<p> What I ran into in addition to that was a corruption in the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> and
the intelligence business that made me question very seriously what it
was all about, including what I was doing ... risking my life ... what
I found was that the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>, us, the case officers, were not permitted to
report about the corruption in the South <ent type='GPE'>Vietnam</ent>ese army....</p>

<p> Now, the corruption was so bad, that the S. <ent type='GPE'>Vietnam</ent>ese army was a
skeleton army. Colonels would let the troops go home if they would
come in once a month and sign the pay vouchers so the colonel could
pocket the money. Then he could sell half of the uniforms and boots
and M-16's to the <ent type='NORP'>communist</ent> forces - that was their major supply, just
as it is in El Salvador today. He could use half of the trucks to
haul produce, half of the helicopters to haul heroin.</p>

<p> And the <ent type='ORG'>Army</ent> couldn't fight. And we lived with it, and we saw it,
and there was no doubt - everybody talked about it openly. We could
provide all kinds of proof, and they wouldn't let us report it. Now
this was a serious problem because the south was attacked in the
winter of 1975, and it collapsed like a big vase hit by a
sledgehammer. And the U.S. was humiliated, and that was the dramatic
end of our long involvement in <ent type='GPE'>Vietnam</ent>....</p>

<p> I had been designated as the task-force commander that would run
this secret war [in <ent type='GPE'>Angola</ent> in 1975 and 1976].... and what I figured
out was that in this job, I would sit on a sub-committee of the
National <ent type='ORG'>Security Council</ent>, this office that <ent type='PERSON'>Larry Devlin</ent> has told me
about where they had access to all the information about <ent type='GPE'>Angola</ent>, about
the whole world, and I would finally understand national security.
And I couldn't resist the opportunity to know. I knew the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> was not
a worthwhile organization, I had learned that the hard way. But the
question was where did the U.S. government fit into this thing, and I
had a chance to see for myself in the next big secret war....</p>

<p> I wanted to know if wise men were making difficult decisions based
on truly important, threatening information, threatening to our
national security interests. If that had been the case, I still
planned to get out of the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>, but I would know that the system, the
invisible government, our national security complex, was in fact
justified and worth while. And so I took the job.... <ent type='ORG'>Suffice</ent> it to
say I wouldn't be standing in front of you tonight if I had found
these wise men making these tough decisions. What I found, quite
frankly, was fat old men sleeping through sub-committee meetings of
the <ent type='ORG'>NSC</ent> in which we were making decisions that were killing people in
<ent type='LOC'>Africa</ent>. I mean literally. Senior ambassador Ed Mulcahy... would go
to sleep in nearly every one of these meetings....</p>

<p> You can change the names in my book [about <ent type='GPE'>Angola</ent>] [13] and you've
got <ent type='GPE'>Nicaragua</ent>.... the basic structure, all the way through including
the mining of harbors, we addressed all of these issues. The point is
that the U.S. led the way at every step of the escalation of the
fighting. We said it was the <ent type='NORP'>Soviets</ent> and the <ent type='NORP'>Cubans</ent> that were doing
it. It was the U.S. that was escalating the fighting. There would
have been no war if we hadn't gone in first. We put arms in, they put
arms in. We put advisors in, they answered with advisors. We put in
<ent type='NORP'>Zairian</ent> para-commando battalions, they put in <ent type='NORP'>Cuban</ent> army troops. We
brought in the S. <ent type='LOC'>Africa</ent>n army, they brought in the <ent type='NORP'>Cuban</ent> army. And
they pushed us away. They blew us away because we were lying, we were
covering ourselves with lies, and they were telling the truth. And it
was not a war that we could fight. We didn't have interests there
that should have been defended that way.</p>

<p> There was never a study run that evaluated the <ent type='ORG'>MPLA</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>FNLA</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>UNITA</ent>,
the three movements in the country, to decide which one was the better
one. The assistant secretary of state for <ent type='LOC'>Africa</ent>n affairs, Nathaniel
Davis, no bleeding-heart liberal (he was known by some people in the
business as the butcher of <ent type='PERSON'>Santiago</ent>), he said we should stay out of
the conflict and work with whoever eventually won, and that was
obviously the <ent type='ORG'>MPLA</ent>. Our consul in <ent type='GPE'>Luanda</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Tom Killoran</ent>, vigorously
argued that the <ent type='ORG'>MPLA</ent> was the best qualified to run the country and the
friendliest to the U.S.</p>

<p> We brushed these people aside, forced <ent type='PERSON'>Matt Davis</ent> to resign, and
proceeded with our war. The <ent type='ORG'>MPLA</ent> said they wanted to be our friends,
they didn't want to be pushed into the arms of <ent type='GPE'>the Soviet Union</ent>; they
begged us not to fight them, they wanted to work with us. We said
they wanted a cheap victory, they wanted a walk-over, they wanted to
be un-opposed, that we wouldn't give them a cheap victory, we would
make them earn it, so to speak. And we did. 10000 <ent type='LOC'>Africa</ent>ns died and
they won the victory that they were winning anyway.</p>

<p> Now, the most significant thing that I got out of all of this, in
addition to the fact that our rationales were basically false, was
that we lied. To just about everybody involved. One third of my
staff in this task force that I put together in <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, commanding
this global operation, pulling strings all over the world to focus
pressure onto <ent type='GPE'>Angola</ent>, and military activities into <ent type='GPE'>Angola</ent>, one third
of my staff was propagandists, who were working, in every way they
could think of, to get stories into the U.S. press, <ent type='ORG'>the world press</ent>,
to create this picture of <ent type='NORP'>Cubans</ent> raping <ent type='GPE'>Angola</ent>ns, <ent type='NORP'>Cubans</ent> and <ent type='NORP'>Soviets</ent>
introducing arms into the conflict, <ent type='NORP'>Cubans</ent> and <ent type='NORP'>Russians</ent> trying to take
over the world.</p>

<p> Our ambassador to <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> Nations, <ent type='PERSON'>Patrick Moynihan</ent>, he read
continuous statements of our position to the <ent type='ORG'>Security Council</ent>, the
general assembly, and the press conferences, saying the <ent type='NORP'>Russians</ent> and
<ent type='NORP'>Cubans</ent> were responsible for the conflict, and that we were staying
out, and that we deplored the militarization of the conflict.</p>

<p> And every statement he made was false. And every statement he made
was originated in the sub-committee of the <ent type='ORG'>NSC</ent> that I sat on as we
managed this thing. The state department press person read these
position papers daily to the press. We would write papers for him.
Four paragraphs. We would call him on the phone and say, 'call us 10
minutes before you go on, the situation could change overnight, we'll
tell you which paragraph to read. And all four paragraphs would be
false. Nothing to do with the truth. Designed to play on events, to
create this impression of <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> and <ent type='NORP'>Cuban</ent> aggression in <ent type='GPE'>Angola</ent>. When
they were in fact responding to our initiatives.</p>

<p> And the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> director was required by law to brief the <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>.
This <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> director <ent type='PERSON'>Bill Colby</ent> - the same one that dumped our people in
<ent type='GPE'>Vietnam</ent> - he gave 36 briefings of the <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>, the oversight
committees, about what we were doing in <ent type='GPE'>Angola</ent>. And he lied. At 36
formal briefings. And such lies are perjury, and it's a felony to lie
to the <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>.</p>

<p> He lied about our relationship with South <ent type='LOC'>Africa</ent>. We were working
closely with the South <ent type='LOC'>Africa</ent>n army, giving them our arms,
coordinating battles with them, giving them fuel for their tanks and
armored cars. He said we were staying well away from them. They were
concerned about these white mercenaries that were appearing in <ent type='GPE'>Angola</ent>,
a very sensitive issue, hiring whites to go into a black <ent type='LOC'>Africa</ent>n
country, to help you impose your will on that black <ent type='LOC'>Africa</ent>n country by
killing the blacks, a very sensitive issue. The <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent> was
concerned we might be involved in that, and he assured them we had
nothing to do with it.</p>

<p> We had in fact formed four little mercenary armies and delivered
them into <ent type='GPE'>Angola</ent> to do this dirty business for the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>. And he lied
to them about that. They asked if we were putting arms into the
conflict, and he said no, and we were. They asked if we had advisors
inside the country, and he said 'no, we had people going in to look at
the situation and coming back out'. We had 24 people sleeping inside
the country, training in the use of weapons, installing communications
systems, planning battles, and he said, we didn't have anybody inside
the country.</p>

<p> In summary about <ent type='GPE'>Angola</ent>, without U.S. intervention, 10000 people
would be alive that were killed in the thing. The outcome might have
been peaceful, or at least much less bloody. The <ent type='ORG'>MPLA</ent> was winning
when we went in, and they went ahead and won, which was, according to
our consul, the best thing for the country.</p>

<p> At the end of this thing the <ent type='NORP'>Cubans</ent> were entrenched in <ent type='GPE'>Angola</ent>, seen
in the eyes of much of the world as being the heroes that saved these
people from the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> and S. <ent type='LOC'>Africa</ent>n forces. We had allied the U.S.
literally and in the eyes of the world with the S. <ent type='LOC'>Africa</ent>n army, and
that's illegal, and it's impolitic. We had hired white mercenaries
and eventually been identified with them. And that's illegal, and
it's impolitic. And our lies had been visible lies. We were caught
out on those lies. And the world saw the U.S. as liars.</p>

<p> After it was over, you have to ask yourself, was it justified? What
did the <ent type='ORG'>MPLA</ent> do after they had won? Were they lying when they said
they wanted to be our friends? 3 weeks after we were shut down... the
<ent type='ORG'>MPLA</ent> had <ent type='LOC'>Gulf</ent> oil back in <ent type='GPE'>Angola</ent>, pumping the <ent type='GPE'>Angola</ent>n oil from the
oilfields, with U.S. gulf technicians protected by <ent type='NORP'>Cuban</ent> soldiers,
protecting them from <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> mercenaries who were still mucking around in
<ent type='PERSON'>Northern</ent> <ent type='GPE'>Angola</ent>.</p>

<p> You can't trust a <ent type='NORP'>communist</ent>, can you? They proceeded to buy five
737 jets from <ent type='ORG'>Boeing Aircraft</ent> in <ent type='GPE'>Seattle</ent>. And they brought in 52 U.S.
technicians to install the radar systems to land and take-off those
planes. They didn't buy [<ent type='GPE'>the Soviet Union</ent>'s] <ent type='ORG'>Aeroflot</ent>.... David
<ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> himself tours S. <ent type='LOC'>Africa</ent> and comes back and holds press
conferences, in which he says that we have no problem doing business
with the so-called radical states of Southern <ent type='LOC'>Africa</ent>.</p>

<p> I left the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>, I decided that the <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> people needed to know
what we'd done in <ent type='GPE'>Angola</ent>, what we'd done in <ent type='GPE'>Vietnam</ent>. I wrote my book.
I was fortunate - I got it out. It was a best-seller. A lot of
people read it. I was able to take my story to the <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> people.
Got on 60 minutes, and lots and lots of other shows.</p>

<p> I testified to the <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent> and then I began my education in
earnest, after having been taught to fight <ent type='NORP'>communist</ent>s all my life. I
went to see what <ent type='NORP'>communist</ent>s were all about. I went to <ent type='GPE'>Cuba</ent> to see if
they do in fact eat babies for breakfast. And I found they don't. I
went to <ent type='GPE'>Budapest</ent>, a country that even national geographic admits is
working nicely. I went to <ent type='GPE'>Jamaica</ent> to talk to <ent type='PERSON'>Michael Manley</ent> about his
theories of social democracy.</p>

<p> I went to <ent type='GPE'>Grenada</ent> and established a dialogue with <ent type='PERSON'>Maurice</ent> Bishop and
<ent type='PERSON'>Bernard Cord</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Phyllis Cord</ent>, to see - these were all educated
people, and experienced people - and they had a theory, they had
something they wanted to do, they had rationales and explanations -
and I went repeatedly to hear them. And then of course I saw the
U.S., the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> mounting a covert action against them, I saw us
orchestrating our plan to invade the country. 19 days before he was
killed, I was in <ent type='GPE'>Grenada</ent> talking to <ent type='PERSON'>Maurice</ent> Bishop about these things,
these indicators, the statements in the press by Ronald Reagan, and he
and I were both acknowledging that it was almost certain that the U.S.
would invade <ent type='GPE'>Grenada</ent> in the near future.</p>

<p> I read as many books as I could find on the subject - book after
book after book. I've got several hundred books on the shelf over my
desk on the subject of U.S. national security interests. And by the
way, I urge you to read. In television you get capsules of news that
someone else puts together what they want you to hear about the news.
In newspapers you get what the editors select to put in the newspaper.
If you want to know about the world and understand, to educate
yourself, you have to get out and dig, dig up books and articles for
yourself. Read, and find out for yourselves. As you'll see, the
issues are very, very important.</p>

<p> I also was able to meet the players, the people who write, the
people who have done studies, people who are leading different
situations. I went to <ent type='GPE'>Nicaragua</ent> a total of 7 times. This was a major
covert action. It lasted longer and evolved to be bigger than what we
did in <ent type='GPE'>Angola</ent>. It gave me a chance, after running something from
<ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, to go to a country that was under attack, to talk to the
leadership, to talk to the people, to look and see what happens when
you give white phosporous or grenades or bombs or bullets to people,
and they go inside a country, to go and talk to the people, who have
been shot, or hit, or blown up....</p>

<p> We're talking about 10 to 20 thousand covert actions [the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> has
performed since 1961]. What I found was that lots and lots of people
have been killed in these things.... Some of them are very, very
bloody.</p>

<p> The <ent type='NORP'>Indonesian</ent> covert action of 1965, reported by Ralph McGehee, who
was in that area division, and had documents on his desk, in his
custody about that operation. He said that one of the documents
concluded that this was a model operation that should be copied
elsewhere in the world. Not only did it eliminate the effective
<ent type='NORP'>communist</ent> party (<ent type='NORP'>Indonesian</ent> <ent type='NORP'>communist</ent> party), it also eliminated the
entire segment of the population that tended to support the <ent type='NORP'>communist</ent>
party - the ethnic <ent type='NORP'>Chinese</ent>, <ent type='NORP'>Indonesian</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Chinese</ent>. And the CIA's report
put the number of dead at 800000 killed. And that was one covert
action. We're talking about 1 to 3 million people killed in these
things.</p>

<p> Two of these things have led us directly into bloody wars. There
was a covert action against <ent type='GPE'>China</ent>, destabilizing <ent type='GPE'>China</ent>, for many, many
years, with a propaganda campaign to work up a mood, a feeling in this
country, of the evils of <ent type='NORP'>communist</ent> <ent type='GPE'>China</ent>, and attacking them, as we're
doing in <ent type='GPE'>Nicaragua</ent> today, with an army that was being launched against
them to parachute in and boat in and destabilize the country. And
this led us directly into <ent type='EVENT'>the Korean war</ent>.</p>

<p> U.S. intelligence officers worked over <ent type='GPE'>Vietnam</ent> for a total of 25
years, with greater and greater involvement, massive propaganda,
deceiving the <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> people about what was happening. Panicking
people in <ent type='GPE'>Vietnam</ent> to create migrations to the south so they could
photograph it and show how people were fleeing communism. And on and
on, until they got us into the <ent type='GPE'>Vietnam</ent> war, and 2000000 people were
killed.</p>

<p> There is a mood, a sentiment in <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, by our leadership today,
for the past 4 years, that a good <ent type='NORP'>communist</ent> is a dead <ent type='NORP'>communist</ent>. If
you're killing 1 to 3 million <ent type='NORP'>communist</ent>s, that's great. President
Reagan has gone public and said he would reduce <ent type='GPE'>the Soviet Union</ent> to a
pile of ashes. The problem, though, is that these people killed by
our national security activities are not <ent type='NORP'>communist</ent>s. They're not
<ent type='NORP'>Russians</ent>, they're not <ent type='ORG'>KGB</ent>. In the field we used to play chess with
the <ent type='ORG'>KGB</ent> officers, and have drinks with them. It was like professional
football players - we would knock heads on <ent type='LOC'>Sunday</ent>, maybe in an
operation, and then Tuesday you're at a banquet together drinking
toasts and talking.</p>

<p> The people that are dying in these things are people of the third
world. That's the common denominator that you come up with. People of
the third world. People that have the misfortune of being born in the
<ent type='NORP'>Metumba</ent> mountains of the <ent type='GPE'>Congo</ent>, in the jungles of <ent type='LOC'>Southeast Asia</ent>, and
now in the hills of northern <ent type='GPE'>Nicaragua</ent>. Far more <ent type='NORP'>Catholics</ent> than
<ent type='NORP'>communist</ent>s, far more <ent type='NORP'>Buddhists</ent> than <ent type='NORP'>communist</ent>s. Most of them couldn't
give you an intelligent definition of communism, or of capitalism.</p>

<p> <ent type='LOC'><ent type='ORG'>Central</ent> <ent type='GPE'>America</ent></ent> has been a traditional target of U.S. dominion. If
you want to get an easy-read of the history of our involvement in
<ent type='LOC'><ent type='ORG'>Central</ent> <ent type='GPE'>America</ent></ent>, read Walter LaFeber's book, Inevitable Revolutions.
[8] We have dominated the area since 1820. We've had a policy of
dominion, of excluding other countries, other industrial powers from
Europe, from competing with us in the area.</p>

<p> Just to give you an example of how complete this is, and how
military this has been, between 1900 and W.W. II, we had 5000 marines
in <ent type='GPE'>Nicaragua</ent> for a total of 28 years. We invaded the Dominican
Republic 4 times. <ent type='GPE'>Haiti</ent>, we occupied it for 12 years. We put our
troops into <ent type='GPE'>Cuba</ent> 4 times, <ent type='GPE'>Panama</ent> 6 times, <ent type='GPE'>Guatemala</ent> once, plus a <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>
covert action to overthrow the democratic government there once.
<ent type='GPE'>Honduras</ent>, 7 times. And by the way, we put 12000 troops into the
<ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> Union during that same period of time.</p>

<p> In the 1930's there was public and international pressure about our
marines in <ent type='GPE'>Nicaragua</ent>....</p>

<p> The next three leaders of <ent type='GPE'>Guatemala</ent> [after the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> installed the
puppet, Colonel <ent type='PERSON'>Armaz</ent> in a coup] died violent deaths, and amnesty
international tells us that the governments we've supported in power
there since then, have killed 80000 people. You can read about that
one in the book Bitter Fruit, by <ent type='PERSON'>Schlesinger</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Kinzer</ent>. [5] Kinzer's
a <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent> Times Journalist... or <ent type='PERSON'>Jonathan Kwitny</ent>, the Wall Street
Journal reporter, his book Endless Enemies [7] - all discuss this....</p>

<p> However, the money, the millions and millions of dollars we put into
this program [helping <ent type='LOC'><ent type='ORG'>Central</ent> <ent type='GPE'>America</ent></ent>] inevitably went to the rich,
and not to the people of the countries involved. And while we were
doing this, while we were trying, at least saying we were trying, to
correct the problems of <ent type='ORG'>Central</ent> and <ent type='LOC'>Latin America</ent>, the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> was doing
its thing, too. The <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> was in fact forming the police units that are
today the death squads in El Salvador. With the leaders on the CIA's
payroll, trained by the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States.</p>

<p> We had the 'public safety program' going throughout <ent type='ORG'>Central</ent> and
<ent type='LOC'>Latin America</ent> for 26 years, in which we taught them to break up
subversion by interrogating people. Interrogation, including torture,
the way the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> taught it. <ent type='PERSON'>Dan Metrione</ent>, the famous exponent of these
things, did 7 years in <ent type='GPE'>Brazil</ent> and 3 in <ent type='GPE'>Uruguay</ent>, teaching
interrogation, teaching torture. He was supposed to be the master of
the business, how to apply the right amount of pain, at just the right
times, in order to get the response you want from the individual.</p>

<p> They developed a wire. They gave them crank generators, with 'U.S.
<ent type='ORG'>AID</ent>' written on the side, so the people even knew where these things
came from. They developed a wire that was strong enough to carry the
current and fine enough to fit between the teeth, so you could put one
wire between the teeth and the other one in or around the genitals and
you could crank and submit the individual to the greatest amount of
pain, supposedly, that the human body can register.</p>

<p> Now how do you teach torture? <ent type='PERSON'>Dan Metrione</ent>: 'I can teach you about
torture, but sooner or later you'll have to get involved. You'll have
to lay on your hands and try it yourselves.'</p>

<p> .... All they [the guinea pigs, beggars from off the streets] could
do was lie there and scream. And when they would collapse, they would
bring in doctors and shoot them up with vitamin B and rest them up for
the next class. And when they would die, they would mutilate the
bodies and throw them out on the streets, to terrify the population so
they would be afraid of the police and the government.</p>

<p> And this is what the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> was teaching them to do. And one of the
women who was in this program for 2 years - tortured in <ent type='GPE'>Brazil</ent> for 2
years - she testified internationally when she eventually got out.
She said, 'The most horrible thing about it was in fact, that the
people doing the torture were not raving psychopaths.' She couldn't
break mental contact with them the way you could if they were
psychopath. They were very ordinary people....</p>

<p> There's a lesson in all of this. And the lesson is that it isn't
only <ent type='ORG'>Gestapo</ent> maniacs, or <ent type='ORG'>KGB</ent> maniacs, that do inhuman things to other
people, it's people that do inhuman things to other people. And we
are responsible for doing these things, on a massive basis, to people
of the world today. And we do it in a way that gives us this
plausible denial to our own consciences; we create a <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>, a secret
police, we give them a vast budget, and we let them go and run these
programs in our name, and we pretend like we don't know it's going on,
although the information is there for us to know; and we pretend like
it's ok because we're fighting some vague <ent type='NORP'>communist</ent> threat. And we're
just as responsible for these 1 to 3 million people we've slaughtered
and for all the people we've tortured and made miserable, as the
<ent type='ORG'>Gestapo</ent> was the people that they've slaughtered and killed. Genocide
is genocide!</p>

<p> Now we're pouring money into El Salvador. A billion dollars or so.
And it's a documented fact that the... 14 families there that own 60%
of the country are taking out between 2 to 5 billion dollars - it's
called de-capitalization - and putting it in banks in <ent type='GPE'>Miami</ent> and
<ent type='GPE'>Switzerland</ent>. <ent type='PERSON'>Mort Halper</ent>, in testifying to a committee of the
<ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>, he suggested we could simplify the whole thing politically
just by investing our money directly in the <ent type='GPE'>Miami</ent> banks in their names
and just stay out of El Salvador altogether. And the people would be
better off.</p>

<p> <ent type='GPE'>Nicaragua</ent>. What's happening in <ent type='GPE'>Nicaragua</ent> today is covert action.
It's a classic de-stabilization program. In November 16, 1981,
President Reagan allocated 19 million dollars to form an army, a force
of contras, they're called, ex-<ent type='PERSON'>Somoza</ent> national guards, the monsters
who were doing the torture and terror in <ent type='GPE'>Nicaragua</ent> that made the
<ent type='GPE'>Nicaragua</ent>n people rise up and throw out the dictator, and throw out
the guard. We went back to create an army of these people. We are
killing, and killing, and terrorizing people. Not only in <ent type='GPE'>Nicaragua</ent>
but the <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent> has leaked to the press - reported in the <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent>
Times, that there are 50 covert actions going around the world today,
<ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> covert actions going on around the world today.</p>

<p> You have to be asking yourself, why are we destabilizing 50 corners
of the troubled world? Why are we about to go to war in <ent type='GPE'>Nicaragua</ent>,
the <ent type='NORP'><ent type='ORG'>Central</ent> <ent type='NORP'>American</ent></ent> war? It is the function, I suggest, of the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>,
with its 50 de-stabilization programs going around the world today, to
keep the world unstable, and to propagandize the <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> people to
hate, so we will let the establishment spend any amount of money on
arms....</p>

<p> The <ent type='PERSON'>Victor Marquetti</ent> ruling of <ent type='ORG'>the Supreme Court</ent> gave the government
the right to prepublication censorship of books. They challenged 360
items in his 360 page book. He fought it in court, and eventually
they deleted some 60 odd items in his book.</p>

<p> The <ent type='PERSON'>Frank Snep</ent> ruling of <ent type='ORG'>the Supreme Court</ent> gave the government the
right to sue a government employee for damages. If s/he writes an
unauthorized account of the government - which means the people who
are involved in corruption in the government, who see it, who witness
it, like <ent type='PERSON'>Frank Snep</ent> did, like I did - if they try to go public they
can now be punished in civil court. The government took $90000 away
from <ent type='PERSON'>Frank Snep</ent>, his profits from his book, and they've seized the
profits from my own book....</p>

<p> [Reagan passed] <ent type='ORG'>the Intelligence Identities</ent> Protection act, which
makes it a felony to write articles revealing the identities of secret
agents or to write about their activities in a way that would reveal
their identities. Now, what does this mean? In a debate in <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>
- this is very controversial - the supporters of this bill made it
clear.... If agents <ent type='PERSON'>Smith</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Jones</ent> came on this campus, in an
MK-ultra-type experiment, and blew your fiance's head away with LSD,
it would now be a felony to publish an article in your local paper
saying, 'watch out for these 2 turkeys, they're federal agents and
they blew my loved one's head away with LSD'. It would not be a
felony what they had done because that's national security and none of
them were ever punished for those activities.</p>

<p> Efforts to muzzle government employees. President Reagan has been
banging away at this one ever since. Proposing that every government
employee, for the rest of his or her life, would have to submit
anything they wrote to 6 committees of the government for censorship,
for the rest of their lives. To keep the scandals from leaking out...
to keep the <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> people from knowing what the government is really
doing.</p>

<p> Then it starts getting heavy. The 'Pre-emptive Strikes' bill.
President Reagan, working through the Secretary of State <ent type='PERSON'>Shultz</ent>...
almost 2 years ago, submitted the bill that would provide them with
the authority to strike at terrorists before terrorists can do their
terrorism. But this bill... provides that they would be able to do
this in this country as well as overseas. It provides that the
secretary of state would put together a list of people that he
considers to be terrorist, or terrorist supporters, or terrorist
sympathizers. And if your name, or your organization, is put on this
list, they could kick down your door and haul you away, or kill you,
without any due process of the law and search warrants and trial by
jury, and all of that, with impunity.</p>

<p> Now, there was a tremendous outcry on the part of jurists. The New
York Times columns and other newspapers saying, 'this is no different
from Hitler's "night in fog" program', where the government had the
authority to haul people off at night. And they did so by the
thousands. And President Reagan and Secretary <ent type='PERSON'>Shultz</ent> have
persisted.... <ent type='PERSON'>Shultz</ent> has said, 'Yes, we will have to take action on
the basis of information that would never stand up in a court. And
yes, innocent people will have to be killed in the process. But, we
must have this law because of the threat of international terrorism'.</p>

<p> Think a minute. What is 'the threat of international terrorism'?
These things catch a lot of attention. But how many <ent type='NORP'>American</ent>s died in
terrorist actions last year? According to Secretary <ent type='PERSON'>Shultz</ent>, 79. Now,
obviously that's terrible but we killed 55000 people on our highways
with drunken driving; we kill 2500 people in far nastier, bloodier,
mutilating, gang-raping ways in <ent type='GPE'>Nicaragua</ent> last year alone ourselves.
Obviously 79 peoples' death is not enough reason to take away the
protection of <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> citizens, of due process of the law.</p>

<p> But they're pressing for this. The special actions teams that will
do the pre-emptive striking have already been created, and trained in
the defense department.</p>

<p> They're building detention centers. There were 8 kept as mothballs
under the McLaren act after <ent type='EVENT'>World War</ent> II, to detain aliens and
dissidents in the next war, as was done in the next war, as was done
with the <ent type='NORP'>Japanese</ent> people during <ent type='EVENT'>World War</ent> II. They're building 10
more, and army camps, and the... executive memos about these things
say it's for aliens and dissidents in the next national emergency....</p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>FEMA</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>the Federal Emergency Management Agency</ent>, headed by Loius
Guiffrida, a friend of Ed Meese's.... He's going about the country
lobbying and demanding that he be given authority, in the times of
national emergency, to declare martial law, and establish a curfew,
and gun down people who violate the curfew... in <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States.</p>

<p> And then there's Ed <ent type='PERSON'>Meese</ent>, as I said. The highest law enforcement
officer in the land, President Reagan's closest friend, going around
telling us that the constitution never did guarantee freedom of speech
and press, and due process of the law, and assembly.</p>

<p> What they are planning for this society, and this is why they're
determined to take us into a war if we'll permit it... is the Reagan
revolution.... So he's getting himself some laws so when he puts in
the troops in <ent type='GPE'>Nicaragua</ent>, he can take charge of the <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> people,
and put people in jail, and kick in their doors, and kill them if they
don't like what he's doing....</p>

<p> The question is, 'Are we going to permit our leaders to take away
our freedoms because they have a charming smile and they were nice
movie stars one day, or are we going to stand up and fight, and insist
on our freedoms?' It's up to us - you and I can watch this history
play in the next year and 2 and 3 years.</p>

<p> PART II</p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> COVERT OPERATIONS IN CENTRAL AMERICA, <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> MANIPULATION
OF THE PRESS, <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> EXPERIMENTATION ON THE U.S. PUBLIC</p>

<p> I just got my latest book back from the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> censors. If I had not
submitted it to them, I would have gone to jail, without trial - blow
off juries and all that sort of thing - for having violated our
censorship laws....</p>

<p> In that job [<ent type='GPE'>Angola</ent>] I sat on a sub-committee of the <ent type='ORG'>NSC</ent>, so I was
like a chief of staff, with the GS-18s (like 3-star generals) Henry
Kissinger, <ent type='PERSON'>Bill Colby</ent> (the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> director), the GS-18s and the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>,
making important decisions and my job was to put it all together and
make it happen and run it, an interesting place from which to watch a
covert action being done....</p>

<p> When the world's gotten blocked up before, like a monopoly game
where everything's owned and nobody can make any progress, the way
they erased the board and started over has been to have big world
wars, and erase countries and bomb cities and bomb banks and then
start from scratch again. This is not an option to us now because of
all these 52000 nuclear weapons....</p>

<p> <ent type='GPE'>The United</ent> States <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> is running 50 covert actions, destabilizing
further almost one third of the countries in the world today....</p>

<p> By the way, everything I'm sharing with you tonight is in the public
record. The 50 covert actions - these are secret, but that has been
leaked to us by members of the oversight committee of the <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>. I
urge you not to take my word for anything. I'm going to stand here
and tell you and give you examples of how our leaders lie. Obviously
I could be lying. The only way you can figure it out for yourself is
to educate yourselves. The <ent type='NORP'>French</ent> have a saying, 'them that don't do
politics will be done'. If you don't fill your mind eagerly with the
truth, dig it out from the records, go and see for yourself, then your
mind remains blank and your adrenaline pumps, and you can be mobilized
and excited to do things that are not in your interest to do....</p>

<p> <ent type='GPE'>Nicaragua</ent> is not the biggest covert action, it is the most famous
one. <ent type='GPE'>Afghanistan</ent> is, we spent several hundred million dollars in
<ent type='GPE'>Afghanistan</ent>. We've spent somewhat less than that, but close, in
<ent type='GPE'>Nicaragua</ent>....</p>

<p> [When the U.S. doesn't like a government], they send the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> in,
with its resources and activists, hiring people, hiring agents, to
tear apart the social and economic fabric of the country, as a
technique for putting pressure on the government, hoping that they can
make the government come to the U.S.'s terms, or the government will
collapse altogether and they can engineer a coup d'etat, and have the
thing wind up with their own choice of people in power.</p>

<p> Now ripping apart the economic and social fabric of course is fairly
textbook-ish. What we're talking about is going in and deliberately
creating conditions where the farmer can't get his produce to market,
where children can't go to school, where women are terrified inside
their homes as well as outside their homes, where government
administration and programs grind to a complete halt, where the
hospitals are treating wounded people instead of sick people, where
international capital is scared away and the country goes bankrupt.
If you ask the state department today what is their official
explanation of the purpose of the <ent type='NORP'>Contras</ent>, they say it's to attack
economic targets, meaning, break up the economy of the country. Of
course, they're attacking a lot more.</p>

<p> To destabilize <ent type='GPE'>Nicaragua</ent> beginning in 1981, we began funding this
force of Somoza's ex-national guardsmen, calling them the contras (the
counter-revolutionaries). We created this force, it did not exist
until we allocated money. We've armed them, put uniforms on their
backs, boots on their feet, given them camps in <ent type='GPE'>Honduras</ent> to live in,
medical supplies, doctors, training, leadership, direction, as we've
sent them in to de-stabilize <ent type='GPE'>Nicaragua</ent>. Under our direction they have
systematically been blowing up graineries, saw mills, bridges,
government offices, schools, health centers. They ambush trucks so
the produce can't get to market. They raid farms and villages. The
farmer has to carry a gun while he tries to plow, if he can plow at
all.</p>

<p> If you want one example of hard proof of the CIA's involvement in
this, and their approach to it, dig up 'The Sabotage Manual', that
they were circulating throughout <ent type='GPE'>Nicaragua</ent>, a comic-book type of a
paper, with visual explanations of what you can do to bring a society
to a halt, how you can gum up typewriters, what you can pour in a gas
tank to burn up engines, what you can stuff in a sewage to stop up the
sewage so it won't work, things you can do to make a society simply
cease to function.</p>

<p> Systematically, the contras have been assassinating religious
workers, teachers, health workers, elected officials, government
administrators. You remember the assassination manual? that surfaced
in 1984. It caused such a stir that President Reagan had to address
it himself in the presidential debates with <ent type='PERSON'>Walter Mondale</ent>. They use
terror. This is a technique that they're using to traumatize the
society so that it can't function.</p>

<p> I don't mean to abuse you with verbal violence, but you have to
understand what your government and its agents are doing. They go
into villages, they haul out families. With the children forced to
watch they castrate the father, they peel the skin off his face, they
put a grenade in his mouth and pull the pin. With the children forced
to watch they gang-rape the mother, and slash her breasts off. And
sometimes for variety, they make the parents watch while they do these
things to the children.</p>

<p> This is nobody's propaganda. There have been over 100000 <ent type='NORP'>American</ent>
witnesses for peace who have gone down there and they have filmed and
photographed and witnessed these atrocities immediately after they've
happened, and documented 13000 people killed this way, mostly women
and children. These are the activities done by these contras. The
contras are the people president Reagan calls 'freedom fighters'. He
says they're the moral equivalent of our founding fathers. And the
whole world gasps at this confession of his family traditions.</p>

<p> Read <ent type='ORG'>Contra</ent> Terror by Reed Brodie [1], former assistant Attorney
General of <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent> State. Read The <ent type='NORP'>Contras</ent> by <ent type='PERSON'>Dieter Eich</ent>. [4] Read
With the <ent type='NORP'>Contras</ent> by <ent type='PERSON'>Christopher Dickey</ent>. [2] This is a main-line
journalist, down there on a grant with <ent type='ORG'>the Council</ent> on Foreign
Relations, a slightly to the right of the middle of the road
organization. He writes a book that sets a pox on both your houses,
and then he accounts about going in on patrol with the contras, and
describes their activities. Read Witness for Peace: What We have Seen
and Heard. Read the Lawyer's Commission on Human Rights. Read The
Violations of War on Both Sides by the <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>s Watch. [15] And there
are many, many more documentations of details, of names, of the
incidents that have happened.</p>

<p> Part of a de-stabilization is propaganda, to dis-credit the targeted
government. This one actually began under <ent type='PERSON'>Jimmy Carter</ent>. He
authorized the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> to go in and try to make the Sandinistas look to be
evil. So in 1979 [when] they came in to power, immediately we were
trying to cast them as totalitarian, evil, threatening Marxists.
While they abolished the death sentence, while they released 8000
national guardsmen that they had in their custody that they could have
kept in prison, they said 'no. Unless we have evidence of individual
crimes, we're not going to hold someone in prison just because they
were associated with the former administration.' While they set out
to launch a literacy campaign to teach the people to read and write,
which is something that the dictator <ent type='PERSON'>Somoza</ent>, and us supporting him,
had never bothered to get around to doing. While they set out to
build 2500 clinics to give the country something resembling a public
health policy, and access to medicines, we began to label them as
totalitarian dictators, and to attack them in the press, and to work
with this newspaper 'La Prensa', which - it's finally come out and
been admitted, in <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent> - the U.S. government is funding: a
propaganda arm.</p>

<p> [Reagan and the State dept. have] been claiming they're building a
war machine that threatens the stability of <ent type='LOC'><ent type='ORG'>Central</ent> <ent type='GPE'>America</ent></ent>. Now the
truth is, this small, poor country has been attacked by the world's
richest country under conditions of war, for the last 5 years. Us and
our army - the death they have sustained, the action they have
suffered - it makes it a larger war proportionally than the <ent type='GPE'>Vietnam</ent>
war was to the U.S. In addition to the contra activities, we've had
U.S. <ent type='ORG'>Navy</ent> ships supervising the mining of harbors, we've sent planes
in and bombed the capital, we've had U.S. military planes flying
wing-tip to wing-tip over the country, photographing it, aerial
reconnaissance. They don't have any missiles or jets they can send up
to chase us off. We are at war with them. The have not retaliated
yet with any kind of war action against us, but we do not give them
credit with having the right to defend themselves. So we claim that
the force they built up, which is obviously purely defensive, is an
aggressive force that threatens the stability of all of <ent type='ORG'>Central</ent>
<ent type='GPE'>America</ent>.</p>

<p> We claim the justification for this is the arms that are flowing
from <ent type='GPE'>Nicaragua</ent> to El Salvador, and yet in 5 years of this activity,
President Reagan hasn't been able to show the world one shred of
evidence of any arms flowing from <ent type='GPE'>Nicaragua</ent> into El Salvador.</p>

<p> We launched a campaign to discredit their elections. <ent type='ORG'>International</ent>
observer teams said these were the fairest elections they have
witnessed in <ent type='LOC'><ent type='ORG'>Central</ent> <ent type='GPE'>America</ent></ent> in many years. We said they were
fraudulent, they were rigged, because it was a totalitarian system.
Instead we said, the elections that were held in El Salvador were
models of democracy to be copied elsewhere in the world. And then the
truth came out about that one. And we learned that the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> had spent
2.2 million dollars to make sure that their choice of candidates -
<ent type='PERSON'>Duarte</ent> - would win. They did everything, we're told, by one of their
spokesmen, indirectly, but stuff the ballot boxes....</p>

<p> I'll make a footnote that when I speak out, he [Senator Jesse
Helmes] calls me a traitor, but when something happens he doesn't
like, he doesn't hesitate to go public and reveal the secrets and
embarrass the U.S.</p>

<p> We claim the Sandinistas are smuggling drugs as a technique to
finance their revolution. This doesn't make sense. We're at war with
them, we're dying to catch them getting arms from <ent type='GPE'>the Soviet Union</ent>,
flying things back and forth to <ent type='GPE'>Cuba</ent>. We have airplanes and picket
ships watching everything that flies out of that country, and into it.
How are they going to have a steady flow of drug-smuggling planes into
the U.S.? Not likely! However, there are <ent type='GPE'>Nicaragua</ent>ns, on these bases
in <ent type='GPE'>Honduras</ent>, that have planes flying into <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> training camps in
<ent type='GPE'>Florida</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Alabama</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Louisiana</ent>, several times a week.</p>

<p> Now, obviously i'm not going to stand in front of you and say that
the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> might be involved in drug trafficking, am I? READ THE BOOK.
Read The Politics of Heroin in <ent type='LOC'>Southeast Asia</ent>. For 20 years the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>
was helping the <ent type='ORG'>Kuomantang</ent> to finance itself and then to get rich,
smuggling heroin. When we took over from the <ent type='NORP'>French</ent> in 1954 their
intelligence service had been financing itself by smuggling the heroin
out of <ent type='GPE'>Laos</ent>. We replaced them - we put <ent type='ORG'>Air America</ent>, the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>
subsidiary - it would fly in with crates marked humanitarian aid,
which were arms, and it would fly back out with heroin. And the first
target, market, of this heroin was the U.S. GI's in <ent type='GPE'>Vietnam</ent>. If
anybody in <ent type='GPE'>Nicaragua</ent> is smuggling drugs, it's the contras. Now i've
been saying that since the state department started waving this red
herring around a couple of years ago, and the other day you notice
President Reagan said that the <ent type='GPE'>Nicaragua</ent>ns, the Sandinistas, were
smuggling drugs, and the <ent type='ORG'>DEA</ent> said, 'it ain't true, the contras are
smuggling drugs'.</p>

<p> We claim the Sandinistas are responsible for the terrorism that's
happening anywhere in the world. 'The country club of terrorism' we
call it. There's an incident in <ent type='GPE'>Rome</ent>, and Ed <ent type='PERSON'>Meese</ent> goes on television
and says, 'that country club in <ent type='GPE'>Nicaragua</ent> is training terrorists'. We
blame the Sandinistas for the misery that exists in <ent type='GPE'>Nicaragua</ent> today,
and there is misery, because the world's richest nation has set out to
create conditions of misery, and obviously we're bound to have some
effect. The misery is not the fault of the Sandinistas, it's the
result of our destabilization program. And despite that, and despite
some grumbling in the country, the Sandinistas in their elections got
a much higher percentage of the vote than President Reagan did, who's
supposed to be so popular in this country. And all observers are
saying that people are still hanging together, with the Sandinistas.</p>

<p> Now it gets tricky. We're saying that the justification for more
aid, possibly for an invasion of the country - and mind you, president
Reagan has begun to talk about this, and the Secretary of Defense
<ent type='PERSON'>Weinberger</ent> began to say that it's inevitable - we claim that the
justification is that <ent type='GPE'>the Soviet Union</ent> now has invested 500 million
dollars in arms in military to make it its big client state, the
<ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> bastion in this hemisphere. And that's true. They do have a
lot of arms in there now. But the question is, how did they get
invited in? You have to ask yourself, what's the purpose of this
destabilization program? For this I direct you back to the Newsweek
article in Sept. 1981, where they announce the fact that the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> was
beginning to put together this force of Somoza's ex-guard. Newsweek
described it as 'the only truly evil, totally unacceptable factor in
the <ent type='GPE'>Nicaragua</ent>n equation'. They noted that neither <ent type='ORG'>the white house</ent> nor
the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> pretended it ever could have a chance of winning. So then
they asked, rhetorically, 'what's the point?' and they concluded that
the point is that by attacking the country, you can force the
Sandinistas into a more radical position, from which you have more
ammunition to attack them.</p>

<p> And that's what we've accomplished now. They've had to get <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent>
aid to defend themselves from the attack from the world's richest
country, and now we can stand up to the <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> people and say, 'see?
they have all the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> aid'. Make no doubt of it, it's the game
plan of the Reagan Administration to have a war in <ent type='GPE'>Nicaragua</ent>, they
have been working on this since 1981, they have been stopped by the
will of the <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> people so far, but they're working harder than
ever to engineer their war there.</p>

<p> Now, <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> destabilizations are nothing new, they didn't begin with
<ent type='GPE'>Nicaragua</ent>. We've done it before, once or twice. Like the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>
committee, investigating <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> covert action in 1975, found that we had
run several hundred a year, and we'd been in the business of running
covert actions, the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> has, for 4 decades. You're talking about 10
to 20 thousand covert actions.</p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> apologists leap up and say, 'well, most of these things are not
so bloody'. And that's true. You're giving a politician some money
so he'll throw his party in this direction or that one, or make false
speeches on your behalf, or something like that. It may be
non-violent, but it's still illegal intervention in other countries'
affairs, raising the question of whether or not we are going to have a
world in which law, rules of behaviour, are respected, or is it going
to be a world of bullies, where the strongest can violate and
brutalize the weakest, and ignore the laws?</p>

<p> But many of these things are very bloody indeed, and we know a lot
about a lot of them. Investigations by the <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>, testimony by <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>
directors, testimony by <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> case officers, books written by <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> case
officers, documents gotten out of the government under the freedom of
information act, books that are written by by pulitzer-prize-winning
journalists who've documented their cases. And you can go and read
from these things, classic <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> operations that we know about, some of
them very bloody indeed. <ent type='GPE'>Guatemala</ent> 1954, <ent type='GPE'>Brazil</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Guyana</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Chile</ent>, the
<ent type='GPE'>Congo</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Iran</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Panama</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Peru</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Bolivia</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Equador</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Uruguay</ent> - the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>
organized the overthrow of constitutional democracies. Read the book
Covert Action: 35 years of Deception by the journalist <ent type='PERSON'>Godswood</ent>. [6]
Remember the <ent type='PERSON'>Henry Kissinger</ent> quote before the <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent> when he was
being grilled to explain what they had done to overthrow the
democratic government in <ent type='GPE'>Chile</ent>, in which the President, Salvador
Allende had been killed. And he said, 'The issues are much too
important for the <ent type='GPE'>Chile</ent>an voters to be left to decide for themselves'.</p>

<p> We had covert actions against <ent type='GPE'>China</ent>, very much like what we're doing
against <ent type='GPE'>Nicaragua</ent> today, that led us directly into <ent type='EVENT'>the Korean war</ent>,
where we fought <ent type='GPE'>China</ent> in <ent type='GPE'>Korea</ent>. We had a long covert action in
<ent type='GPE'>Vietnam</ent>, very much like the one that we're running in <ent type='GPE'>Nicaragua</ent> today,
that tracked us directly into the <ent type='GPE'>Vietnam</ent> war. Read the book, The
Hidden History of the <ent type='GPE'>Korea</ent>n War by I. F. Stone. [14] Read Deadly
Deceits by Ralph McGehee [9] for the <ent type='GPE'>Vietnam</ent> story. In <ent type='GPE'>Thailand</ent>, the
<ent type='GPE'>Congo</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Laos</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Vietnam</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Taiwan</ent>, and <ent type='GPE'>Honduras</ent>, the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> put together large
standing armies. In <ent type='GPE'>Vietnam</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Laos</ent>, Cambodia, <ent type='GPE'>Thailand</ent>, the <ent type='GPE'>Congo</ent>,
<ent type='GPE'>Iran</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Nicaragua</ent>, and <ent type='GPE'>Sri Lanka</ent>, the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> armed and encouraged ethnic
minorities to rise up and fight. The first thing we began doing in
<ent type='GPE'>Nicaragua</ent>, 1981 was to fund an element of the <ent type='GPE'>Mesquite</ent> indians, to
give them money and training and arms, so they could rise up and fight
against the government in <ent type='GPE'>Managua</ent>. In El Salvador, <ent type='GPE'>Vietnam</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Korea</ent>,
<ent type='GPE'>Iran</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Uganda</ent> and the <ent type='GPE'>Congo</ent>, the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> helped form and train the death
squads.</p>

<p> In El Salvador specifically, under the '<ent type='ORG'>Alliance for</ent> Progress' in
the early 1960's, the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> helped put together the <ent type='ORG'>treasury</ent> police.
These are the people that haul people out at night today, and run
trucks over their heads. These are the people that the <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>
church tells us, have killed something over 50000 civilians in the
last 5 years. And we have testimony before our <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent> that as late
as 1982, leaders of the <ent type='ORG'>treasury</ent> police were still on the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> payroll.</p>

<p> Then you have the 'Public Safety Program.' I have to take just a
minute on this one because it's a very important principle involved
that we must understand, if we're to understand ourselves and the
world that we live in. In this one, the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> was working with police
forces throughout <ent type='LOC'>Latin America</ent> for about 26 years, teaching them how
to wrap up subversive networks by capturing someone and interrogating
them, torturing them, and then getting names and arresting the others
and going from there. Now, this was such a brutal and such a bloody
operation, that Amnesty <ent type='ORG'>International</ent> began to complain and publish
reports. Then there were United Nations hearings. Then eventually
our <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent> was forced to yield to international pressure and
investigate it, and they found the horror that was being done, and by
law they forced it to stop. You can read these reports -- the Amnesty
<ent type='ORG'>International</ent> findings, and our own <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>ional hearings.</p>

<p> These things kill people. 800000 in <ent type='GPE'>Indonesia</ent> alone according to
CIA's estimate, 12000 in <ent type='GPE'>Nicaragua</ent>, 10000 in the <ent type='GPE'>Angola</ent>n operation
that I was sitting on in <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, managing the task force. They
add up. We'll never know how many people have been killed in them.
Obviously a lot. Obviously at least a million. 800000 in <ent type='GPE'>Indonesia</ent>
alone. Undoubtedly the minimum figure has to be 3 million. Then you
add in a million people killed in <ent type='GPE'>Korea</ent>, 2 million people killed in
the <ent type='GPE'>Vietnam</ent> war, and you're obviously getting into gross millions of
people...</p>

<p> We do not parachute teams into <ent type='GPE'>the Soviet Union</ent> to haul families out
at night and castrate the father with the children watching, because
they have the Bomb, and a big army, and they would parachute teams
right back into our country and do the same thing to us - they're not
scared of us. For slightly different reasons, but also obvious
reasons, we don't do these things in <ent type='GPE'>England</ent>, or <ent type='GPE'>France</ent>, or <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent>,
or <ent type='GPE'>Sweden</ent>, or <ent type='GPE'>Italy</ent>, or <ent type='GPE'>Japan</ent>. What comes out at you immediately is
that these 1 to 3 million direct victims, the dead, and in these other
wars, they're people of the third world, they're citizens of countries
that are too small to defend them from United States brutality and
aggression. They're people of the <ent type='NORP'>Metumba</ent> mountains of the <ent type='GPE'>Congo</ent>, and
the jungles of <ent type='LOC'>Southeast Asia</ent>, and now the hills of northern <ent type='GPE'>Nicaragua</ent>
- 12000 peasants. We have not killed <ent type='ORG'>KGB</ent> or <ent type='NORP'>Russian</ent> army advisors in
<ent type='GPE'>Nicaragua</ent>. We are not killing <ent type='NORP'>Cuban</ent> advisors. We're not killing very
many Sandinistas. The 12000 that we have killed in <ent type='GPE'>Nicaragua</ent> are
peasants, who have the misfortune of living in a CIA's chosen
battlefield. Mostly women and children. <ent type='NORP'>Communists</ent>? Far, far, far
more <ent type='NORP'>Catholics</ent> than anything else.</p>

<p> Now case officers that do these things in places in <ent type='GPE'>Nicaragua</ent>, they
do not come back to the U.S. and click their heels and suddenly become
responsible citizens. They see themselves - they have been
functioning above the laws, of God, and the laws of man - they've come
back to this country, and they've continued their operations as far as
they can get by with them. And we have abundant documentation of that
as well. The MH-Chaos program, exposed in the late 60's and shut
down, re-activated by President Reagan to a degree - we don't have the
details yet - in which they were spending a billion dollars to
manipulate U.S. student, and labor organizations. The MK-ultra
program. For 20 years, working through over 200 medical schools and
mental hospitals, including <ent type='ORG'>Harvard</ent> medical school, <ent type='ORG'>Georgetown</ent>, some
of the biggest places we've got, to experiment on <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> citizens
with disease, and drugs.</p>

<p> They dragged a barge through <ent type='GPE'>San Francisco</ent> bay, leaking a virus, to
measure this technique for crippling a city. They launched a whooping
cough epidemic in a <ent type='GPE'>Long Island</ent> suburb, to see what it would do to the
community if all the kids had whooping cough. Tough shit about the 2
or 3 with weak constitutions that might die in the process. They put
light bulbs in the subways in <ent type='GPE'>Manhattan</ent>, that would create vertigo -
make people have double vision, so you couldn't see straight - and hid
cameras in the walls - to see what would happen at rush hour when the
trains are zipping past - if everybody has vertigo and they can't see
straight and they're bumping into each other.</p>

<p> Colonel <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> - oh yes, and I can't not mention the disease
experimentations - the use of deadly diseases. We launched - when we
were destabilizing <ent type='GPE'>Cuba</ent> for 7 years - we launched the swine fever
epidemic, in the hog population, trying to kill out all of the pigs -
a virus. We experimented in <ent type='GPE'>Haiti</ent> on the people with viruses.</p>

<p> I'm not saying, I do not have the slightest shred of evidence, that
there is any truth or indication to the rumor that the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> and its
experimentations were responsible for <ent type='ORG'>AID</ent>S. But we do have it
documented that the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> has been experimenting on people, with
viruses. And now we have some deadly, killer viruses running around
in society. And it has to make you wonder, and it has to make you
worry.</p>

<p> Colonel <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> wrote from retirement - he was the man who was in
charge of this macabre program - he wrote, 'I toiled whole-heartedly
in the vineyards because it was fun, fun fun. Where else could a
red-blooded <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> boy lie, kill, cheat, steal, rape and pillage
with the blessings of the all highest?' Now that program, the
MK-ultra program, was eventually exposed by the press in 1972,
investigated by the <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>, and shut down by the <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>. You can
dig up the <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>ional record and read it for yourself.</p>

<p> There's one book called 'In Search of the <ent type='NORP'>Manchurian</ent> Candidate'.
It's written by <ent type='PERSON'>John Marks</ent>, based on 14000 documents gotten out of
the government under the Freedom of Information Act. Read for
yourselves. The thing was shut down but not one <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> case officer who
was involved was in any way punished. Not one case officer involved
in these experimentations on the <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> public, lost a single
paycheck for what they had done.</p>

<p> The <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> committee found that the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> had co-opted several hundred
journalists, including some of the biggest names in the business, to
pump its propaganda stories into our media, to teach us to hate Fidel
Castro, and Ho Chi Minh, and the <ent type='NORP'>Chinese</ent>, and whomever. The latest
flap or scandal we had about that was a year and a half ago. Lesley
Gelp, the heavyweight with the <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent> Times, was exposed for having
been working covertly with the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> in 1978 to recruit journalists in
Europe, who would introduce stories, print stories that would create
sympathy for the neutron bomb.</p>

<p> The <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> committee found that they had published over 1000 books,
paying someone to write a book, the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> puts its propaganda lines in
it, the professor or the scholar gets credit for the book and gets the
royalties. The latest flap we had about that was last year. A
professor at <ent type='ORG'>Harvard</ent> was exposed for accepting 105000 dollars from
the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> to write a book about the <ent type='LOC'>Middle East</ent>. Several thousand
professors and graduate students co-opted by the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> to run its
operations on campuses and build files on students.</p>

<p> And then we have evidence - now, which has been hard to collect in
the past but we knew it was happening - of <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> agents participating,
trying to manipulate, our elections. <ent type='ORG'>FDN</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Contra</ent> commanders,
traveling this country on <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> plane tickets, going on television and
pin-pointing a <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>ional and saying, 'That man is soft on
Communism. That man is a Sandinista lover.' A <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> agent going on
television, trying to manipulate our elections.</p>

<p> All of this, to keep <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> safe for freedom and democracy.</p>

<p> In <ent type='GPE'>Nicaragua</ent> the objective is to stop the <ent type='NORP'>Cuban</ent> and <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent>
take-over, we say. Another big operation in which we said the same
thing was <ent type='GPE'>Angola</ent>, 1975, my little war. We were saying exactly the
same thing - <ent type='NORP'>Cubans</ent> and <ent type='NORP'>Soviets</ent>.</p>

<p> Now I will not going into great detail about this one tonight
because I wrote a book about it, I detailed it. And you can get a
copy of that book and read it for yourselves. I have to urge you,
however - please do not rush out and buy a copy of that book because
the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> sued me. All of my profits go to the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>, so if you buy a
copy of the book you'll be donating 65 cents to the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>. So check it
out from your library!</p>

<p> If you have to buy a copy, well buy one copy and share it with all
your friends. If your bookstore is doing real well and you want to
just sort of put a copy down in your belt...</p>

<p> I don't know what the solution is when a society gets into
censorship, government censorship, but that's what we're in now. Do
the rules change? I just got my book back, my latest book back from
the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> censors. If I had not submitted it to them, I would have gone
to jail, without trial - blow off juries and all that sort of thing -
for having violated our censorship laws....</p>

<p> So now we have the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> running the operation in <ent type='GPE'>Nicaragua</ent>, lying to
us, running 50 covert actions, and gearing us up for our next war, the
<ent type='NORP'><ent type='ORG'>Central</ent> <ent type='NORP'>American</ent></ent> war. Let there be no doubt about it, President
Reagan has a fixation on <ent type='GPE'>Nicaragua</ent>. He came into office saying that
we shouldn't be afraid of war, saying we have to face and erase the
scars of the <ent type='GPE'>Vietnam</ent> war. He said in 1983, 'We will do whatever is
necessary to reverse the situation in <ent type='GPE'>Nicaragua</ent>', meaning get rid of
the Sandinistas. Admiral LaRoque, at the Center for Defense
Information in <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, says this is the most elaborately prepared
invasion that the U.S. has ever done. At least that he's witnessed in
his 40 years of association with our military.</p>

<p> We have rehearsed the invasion of <ent type='GPE'>Nicaragua</ent> in operations Big Pine
I, Big Pine II, Ocean Venture, <ent type='GPE'>Grenada</ent>, Big Pine III. We have troops
right now in <ent type='GPE'>Honduras</ent> preparing. We've built 12 bases, including 8
airstrips. Obviously we don't need 8 airstrips in <ent type='GPE'>Honduras</ent> for any
purpose, except to support the invasion of <ent type='GPE'>Nicaragua</ent>. We've built
radar stations around, to survey and watch. Some of these ventures
have been huge ones. Hundreds of airplanes, 30000 troops, rehearsing
the invasion of <ent type='GPE'>Nicaragua</ent>.</p>

<p> And of course, <ent type='NORP'>American</ent>s are being given this negative view of these
evil <ent type='NORP'>Communist</ent> dictators in <ent type='GPE'>Managua</ent>, just two days drive from
<ent type='GPE'>Harlington</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Texas</ent>. (They drive faster than I do by the way). I saw
an ad on TV just two days ago in which they said that it was just two
hours from <ent type='GPE'>Managua</ent> to <ent type='GPE'>Texas</ent>. All of this getting us ready for the
invasion of <ent type='GPE'>Nicaragua</ent>, for our next war.</p>

<p> Most of the people - 75% of the people - are polled as being against
this action. However, President <ent type='PERSON'>Eisenhower</ent> said, 'The people of the
world genuinely want peace. Someday the leadership of the world are
going to have to give in and give it to them'. But to date, the
leaders never have, they've always been able to outwit the people, us,
and get us into the wars when they've chosen to do so.</p>

<p> People ask, how is this possible? I get this all the time....
<ent type='NORP'>American</ent>s are decent people. They are nice people. And they're
insulated in the worlds that they live in, and they don't understand
and we don't read our history. History is the history of war. Of
leaders of countries finding reasons and rationales to send the young
men off to fight.</p>

<p> In our country we talk about peace. But look at our own record. We
have over 200 incidents in which we put our troops into other
countries to force them to our will. Now we're being prepared to hate
the Sandinistas. The leaders are doing exactly what they have done
time and again throughout history. In the past we were taught to hate
and fight the <ent type='NORP'>Seminole</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Indians</ent>, after the leaders decided to annex
<ent type='GPE'>Florida</ent>. To hate and fight the Cherokee <ent type='NORP'>Indians</ent> after they found gold
in <ent type='GPE'>Georgia</ent>. To hate and fight <ent type='GPE'>Mexico</ent> twice. We annexed <ent type='GPE'>Texas</ent>, New
<ent type='GPE'>Mexico</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Arizona</ent>, part of <ent type='GPE'>Colorado</ent>, and <ent type='GPE'>California</ent>.</p>

<p> In each of these wars the leaders have worked to organize, to
orchestrate public opinion. And then when they got people worked up,
they had a trigger that would flash, that would make people angry
enough that we could go in and do....</p>

<p> We have a feeling that the <ent type='GPE'>Vietnam</ent> war was the first one in which
the people resisted. But once again, we haven't read our history.
<ent type='PERSON'>Kate Richards</ent>-O'Hare. In 1915, she said about WW I, 'The Women of the
U.S. are nothing but brutesalles, producing sons to be put in the
army, to be made into fertilizer'. She was jailed for 5 years for
anti-war talk.</p>

<p> The lessons of the <ent type='GPE'>Vietnam</ent> war for the <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> people is that it
was a tragic mistake.... 58000 of our own young people were killed, 2
million <ent type='GPE'>Vietnam</ent>ese were killed. We withdrew, and our position wound
up actually stronger in the <ent type='LOC'>Pacific</ent> basin.</p>

<p> You look around this society today to see if there's any evidence of
our preparations for war, and it hits you in the face....</p>

<p> 'Join the <ent type='ORG'>Army</ent>. Be all that you can be'. Now if there was truth in
advertising, obviously those commercials would show a few seconds of
young men with their legs blown off at the knees, young men with their
intestines wrapped around their necks because that's what war is
really all about.</p>

<p> If there was honesty on the part of the army and the government,
they would tell about the <ent type='GPE'>Vietnam</ent> veterans. More of whom died violent
deaths from suicide after they came back from <ent type='GPE'>Vietnam</ent> then died in the
fighting itself.</p>

<p> Then you have President Reagan.... He talks about the glory of war,
but you have to ask yourself, where was he when wars were being fought
that he was young enough to fight in them? <ent type='EVENT'>World War</ent> II, and the
<ent type='GPE'>Korea</ent>n war. Where he was was in <ent type='GPE'>Hollywood</ent>, making films, where the
blood was catsup, and you could wash it off and go out to dinner
afterwards....</p>

<p> Where was <ent type='PERSON'>Gordon Liddy</ent> when he was young enough to go and fight in a
war? He was hiding out in the U.S. running sloppy, illegal,
un-professional breaking and entering operations. Now you'll forgive
my egotism, at that time I was running professional breaking and
entering operations....</p>

<p> What about <ent type='PERSON'>Rambo</ent> himself? <ent type='PERSON'>Sylvester Stallone</ent>. Where was Sylvester
Stallone during the <ent type='GPE'>Vietnam</ent> war? He got a draft deferment for a
physical disability, and taught physical education in a girls' school
in <ent type='GPE'>Switzerland</ent> during the war.</p>

<p> Getting back to President Reagan. He really did say that 'you can
always call cruise missiles back'.... Now, you can call back a B-52,
and you can call back a submarine, but a cruise missile is
different.... When it lands, it goes boom!. And I would prefer that
the man with the finger on the button could understand the difference.
This is the man that calls the MX a peace-maker. This is the man
who's gone on television and told us that nuclear war could be
winnable. This is the man who's gone on television and proposed that
we might want to drop demonstration [atom] bombs in Europe to show
people that we're serious people. This is the man who likens the
<ent type='NORP'>Contras</ent> to the moral equivalents of our own founding fathers. This is
the man who says South <ent type='LOC'>Africa</ent> is making progress on racial equality.
This is the man who says that the Sandinistas are hunting down and
hounding and persecuting <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> in <ent type='GPE'>Nicaragua</ent>. And the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> leaders go
on TV the next day in this country and say there are 5 <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> families
in <ent type='GPE'>Nicaragua</ent>, and they're not having any problems at all. This is the
man who says that they're financing their revolution by smuggling
drugs into the U.S. And the <ent type='ORG'>DEA</ent> says, 'It ain't true, it's president
Reagan's <ent type='NORP'>Contras</ent> that are doing it'....</p>

<p> [When Reagan was governor of <ent type='GPE'>California</ent>, Reagan] said 'If there has
to be a bloodbath then let's get it over with'. Now you have to think
about this a minute. A leader of the U.S. seriously proposing a
bloodbath of our own youth. There was an outcry of the press, so 3
days later he said it again to make sure no one had misunderstood him.</p>

<p> Read. You have to read to inform yourselves. Read The Book of
Quotes [12]. Read On Reagan: The Man and the Presidency [3] by <ent type='PERSON'>Ronnie</ent>
Dugger. It gets heavy. Dugger concludes in his last chapter that
President Reagan has a fixation on <ent type='GPE'>Armageddon</ent>. <ent type='ORG'>The Village Voice</ent> 18
months ago published an article citing the 11 times that President
Reagan publicly has talked about the fact that we are all living out
<ent type='GPE'>Armageddon</ent> today....</p>

<p> [Reagan] has <ent type='PERSON'>Jerry Falwell</ent> into the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> House. This is the man
that preaches that we should get on our knees and beg for God to send
the rapture down. Hell's fires on earth so the chosen can go up on
high and all the other people can burn in hell's fires on earth.
President Reagan sees himself as playing the role of the greatest
leader of all times forever. Leading us into <ent type='GPE'>Armageddon</ent>. As he goes
out at the end of his long life, we'll all go out with him....</p>

<p> Why does the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> run 10000 brutal covert actions? Why are we
destabilizing a third of the countries in the world today when there's
so much instability and misery already? Why are our leaders now
taking us into another war? Why are we systematically taught to hate
and fight other people?</p>

<p> What you have to understand is the politics of paranoia. The
easiest... buttons to punch are the buttons of macho, aggression,
paranoia, hate, anger, and fear. The <ent type='NORP'>Communists</ent> are in <ent type='GPE'>Managua</ent> and
that's just 2 hours from <ent type='GPE'>San Diego</ent>, CA. This gets people excited,
they don't think. It's the pep-rally, the football pep-rally factor.
When you get people worked up to hate, they'll let you spend huge
amounts of money on arms.</p>

<p> Read The Power Elite by C. <ent type='PERSON'>Wright Mills</ent>. [11] Read The Permanent War
Complex by <ent type='PERSON'>Seymour Melman</ent>. [10] <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> covert actions have the function
of keeping the world hostile and unstable....</p>

<p> We can't take care of the poor, we can't take care of the old, but
we can spend millions, hundreds of millions of dollars to destabilize
<ent type='GPE'>Nicaragua</ent>....</p>

<p> Why arms instead of schools? .... They can make gigantic profits off
the nuclear arms race because of the hysteria, and the paranoia, and
the secrecy. And that's why they're committed to building more and
more and more weapons, is because they're committed to making a
profit. And that's what the propaganda, and that's what the hysteria
is all about. Now people say, 'What can I do?'....</p>

<p> The youth did rise up and stop the <ent type='GPE'>Vietnam</ent> war....</p>

<p> We have to join hands with the people in <ent type='GPE'>England</ent>, and <ent type='GPE'>France</ent>, and
<ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent>, and <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent>, and <ent type='GPE'>the Soviet Union</ent>, and <ent type='GPE'>China</ent>, and India - the
countries that have the bomb, and the others that are trying to get
it. And give our leaders no choice. They have to find some other way
to do business other than to motivate us through hate and paranoia and
anger and killing, or we'll find other leaders to run the country.</p>

<p> Now, Helen Caldicott, at the end of her lectures, I've heard her
say, very effectively, 'Tell people to get out and get to work on the
problem.... You'll feel better'....</p>

<p> 'What can I do?'.... If you can travel, go to <ent type='GPE'>Nicaragua</ent> and see for
yourself. Go to the <ent type='GPE'>Nevada</ent> test site and see for yourself. Go to
Pantex on <ent type='GPE'>Hiroshima</ent> day this summer, and see the vigil there. The
place where we make 10 nose-cones a day, 70 a week, year in and year
out. He [Admiral LaRock] said, 'I'd tell them, if they feel
comfortable lying down in front of trucks with bombs on them, to lie
down in front of trucks with bombs on them.' But he said, 'I'd tell
them that they can't wait. They've got to start tomorrow, today, and
do it, what they can, every day of their lives'.</p>

<p>[1] Reed Brody.
<ent type='ORG'>Contra</ent> Terror.
??, .</p>

<p>[2] <ent type='PERSON'>Christopher Dickey</ent>.
With the <ent type='NORP'>Contras</ent>.
??, .</p>

<p>[3] Dugger, <ent type='PERSON'>Ronnie</ent>.
On Reagan: The Man and the Presidency.
McGraw-Hill, 1983.</p>

<p>[4] <ent type='PERSON'>Eich</ent>, Dieter.
The <ent type='NORP'>Contras</ent>: Interviews with Anti-Sandinistas.
<ent type='ORG'>Synthesis</ent>, 1985.</p>

<p>[5] <ent type='PERSON'>Kinzer</ent>, Stephan and Stephen <ent type='PERSON'>Schlesinger</ent>.
Bitter Fruit: The Untold Story of the <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> Coup in
<ent type='GPE'>Guatemala</ent>.
<ent type='EVENT'>Doubleday</ent>, 1983.</p>

<p>[6] <ent type='PERSON'>Godswood</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Roy</ent> (editor).
<ent type='ORG'>Covert Actions</ent>: 35 Years of Deception.
Transaction, 1980.</p>

<p>[7] Kwitny, Jonathon.
Endless Enemies: America's <ent type='EVENT'>Worldwide War Against</ent> It's Own Best
Interests.
Congdon and Weed, 1984.</p>

<p>[8] LaFeber, Walter.
Inevitable Revolutions; <ent type='GPE'>The United</ent> States in <ent type='LOC'><ent type='ORG'>Central</ent> <ent type='GPE'>America</ent></ent>.
<ent type='ORG'>Norton</ent>, 1984.</p>

<p>[9] McGehee, Ralph.
Deadly Deceits: My Twenty-Five Years in the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>.
Sheridan Square, 1983.</p>

<p>[10] Melman, <ent type='PERSON'>Seymour</ent>.
<ent type='EVENT'>The Permanent War Complex</ent>.
<ent type='PERSON'>Simon</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Shuster</ent>, 1974.</p>

<p>[11] Mills, C. <ent type='PERSON'>Wright</ent>.
The Power Elite.
<ent type='ORG'>Oxford</ent>, 1956.</p>

<p>[12] ??
The Book of Quotes.
McGraw-Hill, 1979.</p>

<p>[13] <ent type='ORG'>Stockwell</ent>, John.
In Search of Enemies.
<ent type='ORG'>Norton</ent>, 1978.</p>

<p>[14] Stone, I.F.
Hidden History of the <ent type='GPE'>Korea</ent>n War.
Monthly Review, 1969.</p>

<p>[15] The <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>s Watch.
The Violations of War on Both Sides.
??, .</p>

</xml>