<xml><p> (<ent type='ORG'>The Elkhorn</ent> Manifesto) </p>

<p> SHADOW OF THE <ent type='ORG'>SWASTIKA</ent>:</p>

<p> The Real Reason the Government Won't Debate Medical Cannabis and
Industrial Hemp Re-legalization</p>

<p> An Open Letter to All <ent type='NORP'>Americans</ent> by R. <ent type='PERSON'><ent type='PERSON'>William</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Davis</ent></ent> </p>

<p> Documented Evidence of a Secret Business and Political Alliance
Between the U.S. "Establishment" and the <ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent> - Before, During and
After <ent type='EVENT'>World War</ent> II - up to the Present. </p>

<p> PREFACE </p>

<p> Before the Gatewood Galbraith for Governor Campaign in 1991, few
<ent type='NORP'>Kentuckians</ent> knew that the plant that the federal government had
demonized for over 50 years as "<ent type='ORG'>Marijuana</ent> - Assassin of Youth," was,
in fact, Cannabis Hemp, the most traded commodity in the world until
the mid-1800s, and our state's number one crop, industry, and most
important source of revenue, for over 150 years. </p>

<p> Today, thanks to the efforts of pioneer hemp researchers and public
advocates such as Galbraith, <ent type='PERSON'>Jack Fraizer</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Jack Herer</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Chris Conrad</ent>,
Ed Rosenthal, <ent type='PERSON'>Don Wirtshafter</ent> and others, the federal government's
unjustifiable suppression of our state's right to develop our most
valuable and versatile natural resource, is facing increasing
opposition from an informed public. Hemp is now recognized as the
number one agriculturally renewable raw material in the world, and
perhaps the only crop / industry which can guarantee us industrial
and economic independence from the trans-national corporations. </p>

<p> "Shadow of the Swastika" is a follow-up to my earlier work,
"Cannabis Hemp: the Invisible Prohibition Revealed," which I wrote
and published in support of the Galbraith Campaign. Since
publication of that booklet, there has been growing public
acceptance of the evidence that <ent type='ORG'>Marijuana</ent> Prohibition was created in
1937, not to protect society from the "evils of the drug <ent type='ORG'>Marijuana</ent>,"
as the Federal government claimed, but as an act of deliberate
economic and industrial sabotage against the re-emerging Industrial
Hemp Industry. </p>

<p> Previous investigations by hemp researchers have been limited to
the suppression of free-market competition from the hemp industry,
and focused on the activities of three prominent members of
America's corporate, industrial and banking establishment during the
mid-to late-1930s: </p>

<p> WILLIAM RANDOLPH <ent type='ORG'>HEARST</ent>, the newspaper and magazine tycoon.</p>

<p> The expected rebirth of cannabis hemp as a less expensive source of
pulp for paper meant his millions of acres of prime timberland, and
investment in wood pulp papermaking equipment, would soon be worth
much less. In the 1920s, about the same time as the equipment was
developed to economically mass-produce raw hemp into pulp and fiber
for paper, he began the "Reefer Madness" hoax in his newspaper and
magazine publications.</p>

<p> ANDREW <ent type='ORG'>MELLON</ent>, founder of <ent type='ORG'>the Gulf Oil Corporation</ent>.</p>

<p> He knew that cannabis hemp was an alternative industrial raw
material for the production of thousands of products, including fuel
and plastics, which, if allowed to compete in the free-market, would
threaten the future profits of the oil companies. As Secretary of
the <ent type='ORG'>Treasury</ent> he created <ent type='ORG'>the Federal Bureau</ent> of Narcotics, and
appointed his own future nephew-in-law, <ent type='PERSON'>Harry Anslinger</ent>, as
director. Anslinger would later use the sensational, and totally
fabricated, articles published by <ent type='ORG'>Hearst</ent>, to push the <ent type='ORG'>Marijuana</ent> Tax
Act of 1937 through <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>, which successfully destroyed the
rebirth of the cannabis hemp industry. </p>

<p> A prominent member of one <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>ional subcommittee who voted in
favor of this bill was <ent type='PERSON'>Joseph Guffey</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>Pennsylvania</ent>, an oil tycoon
and former business partner of <ent type='PERSON'>Andrew Mellon</ent> in the <ent type='ORG'>Spindletop</ent> oil
fields in <ent type='GPE'>Texas</ent>.</p>

<p> THE DU PONT CHEMICAL CORPORATION,</p>

<p> which owned the patents on synthetic petrochemicals and industrial
processes that promised billions of dollars in future profits from
the sale of wood pulp paper, lead additives for gasoline, synthetic
fibers and plastics, if hemp could be suppressed. At the time, du
Pont family influence in both government and the private sector was
unmatched, according to historians and journalists.</p>

<p> This publication, however, reveals documented historical evidence
that the suppression of the hemp industry was only one key part of a
much larger conspiracy in the 1930s, not only by the three corporate
interests named above, but by many others, as well. </p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>ional records, <ent type='ORG'>FBI</ent> reports and investigations by the
Justice Department, during the 1930s and 1940s, have already
documented evidence of this wider plot. A list of the corporations
named include Du Pont, <ent type='ORG'>Standard Oil</ent>, and General Motors, all of
which were proven to be conspiring with <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> industrial cartels to
eliminate competition world-wide and divide among themselves the
Earth's industrial resources and commercial markets, for profitable
exploitation. </p>

<p> This conspiracy succeeded. It is now obvious that this lack of
serious competition in the industrial raw materials market caused
our present - and totally contrived - addiction to petrochemicals.
Its success is directly responsible for the most troubling problems
we now face in the 1990s; serious damage to our environment,
concentration of economic and political power into fewer and fewer
hands, and the weakening of the rights of individuals and states to
determine their own futures. </p>

<p> It is more and more evident that, given the historical record, the
structure of <ent type='EVENT'>the New World</ent> Order is being built upon the Foundation
of <ent type='ORG'>Marijuana</ent> Prohibition, and only the relegalization of free-market
hemp competition can save us.</p>

<p> R. <ent type='PERSON'><ent type='PERSON'>William</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Davis</ent></ent> July 4, 1996 <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Kentucky</ent></p>

<p> INTRODUCTION </p>

<p> To clearly understand the circumstances which existed during the
1930s and 1940s, and are the subject of this booklet, it would be
helpful to first put the hemp / petrochemical conflict into
historical perspective. The events which took place in the years
leading up to <ent type='EVENT'>World War</ent> II were a continuation of a struggle between
agricultural and industrial interests that began before the <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n
<ent type='EVENT'>Revolution</ent>, a struggle which has yet to be decided, even today. </p>

<p> AGRICULTURE VS. INDUSTRY </p>

<p> The historical record, at least as it has been presented to us in
the public school system, is that <ent type='EVENT'>the Civil War</ent> was fought to end
slavery. This is not the whole story. The truth of the matter is
that it was also a clash between <ent type='PERSON'>Northern</ent> industrialists and
<ent type='NORP'>Southern</ent> agriculturists, over control of the expansion into the
newly opened <ent type='ORG'>West</ent>. </p>

<p> In 1845, <ent type='PERSON'>Abraham Lincoln</ent> wrote, "I hold it a paramount duty of us
in the free states due to the union of the states, and perhaps to
liberty itself, to let the slavery of other states alone." (1) </p>

<p> Concerning the <ent type='ORG'>West</ent>ern territories, he said "The whole <ent type='ORG'>Nation</ent> is
interested that the best use shall be made of these territories. We
want them for homes and free white people. This they cannot be, to
any considerable extent, if slavery be planted within them." (2) </p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>Lincoln</ent> was caught in the middle between the <ent type='PERSON'>Northern</ent>
industrialists and the <ent type='NORP'>Southern</ent> agriculturists, who both wanted to
dominate <ent type='ORG'>West</ent>ern expansion because of the wealth it offered. The
industrialists knew that the agriculturists depended on slavery
because cotton, upon which <ent type='NORP'>Southern</ent> wealth was based, was very labor
intensive and required the inexpensive labor that slavery provided.
They knew that if the <ent type='ORG'>West</ent>ern lands were declared "free states" then
the <ent type='NORP'>Southern</ent> agriculturists would be unable to compete, and would be
forced to leave <ent type='ORG'>West</ent>ern expansion, and its potential profits, to the
<ent type='PERSON'>Northern</ent> industrialists. </p>

<p> Quoting "<ent type='ORG'>The Irony</ent> of Democracy," by <ent type='PERSON'>Thomas</ent> R. <ent type='PERSON'>Dye</ent> and T. Harmon
<ent type='PERSON'>Zeigler</ent>,</p>

<p> "The importance of <ent type='EVENT'>the Civil War</ent> for America's elite structure was
the commanding position that the new industrial capitalists won
during the course of the struggle. . . . The economic transformation
of <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States from an agricultural to an industrial nation
reached the crescendo of a revolution in the second half of the
nineteenth century. </p>

<p> "<ent type='EVENT'>Civil War</ent> profits compounded the capital of the industrialists and
placed them in a position to dominate the economic life of the
nation. Moreover, when the <ent type='NORP'>Southern</ent> planters were removed from the
national scene, the government in <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent> became the exclusive
domain of the new industrial leaders." (3)</p>

<p> The <ent type='PERSON'>Northern</ent> industrialists used this increased capital to build
the system of transcontinental railways, linking the <ent type='PERSON'>Northeast</ent> with
both the <ent type='LOC'>South</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>West</ent>. The labor for this undertaking was from the
<ent type='PERSON'>Northeast</ent>ern Establishment's own source of cheap labor - recently
freed slaves and poor immigrants from Europe and <ent type='GPE'>China</ent> - who
suffered under living conditions which were often little better than
those which existed under the Slave System just a few years before. </p>

<p> It was during the years between <ent type='EVENT'>the Civil War</ent> and the beginning of
<ent type='ORG'>the Twentieth</ent> Century that the <ent type='PERSON'>Northern</ent> industrialists altered the
role of the <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n government. Originally established by the
<ent type='EVENT'>Revolution</ent> to protect and preserve the lives, property and freedoms
of all <ent type='NORP'>Americans</ent> from repressive government, it was transformed into
an agency to protect the economic future of <ent type='PERSON'>Northern</ent> industrialists. </p>

<p> "[T]he industrial elites," according to <ent type='PERSON'>Dye</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Zeigler</ent>, "saw no
objection to legislation if it furthered their success in business.
Unrestricted competition might prove who was the fittest, but as an
added precaution to insure that the industrial capitalists
themselves emerged as the fittest, these new elites also insisted
upon government subsidies, patents, tariffs, loans, and massive
giveaways of land and other natural resources." (4) </p>

<p> The struggle between <ent type='ORG'>West</ent>ern farmers and the railroads owned by the
<ent type='PERSON'>Northern</ent> industrialists is a good example. To protect their
interests, citizens created "the <ent type='ORG'>Grange</ent>," an organization which
helped to enact state laws regulating the "ruthless aggression" of
the railroads. In 1877, these laws were upheld by <ent type='ORG'>the Supreme Court</ent>
in the <ent type='PERSON'>Munn</ent> v. <ent type='GPE'>Illinois</ent> decision. But, a few years later, Justice
<ent type='PERSON'>Stephen</ent> A. <ent type='ORG'>Field</ent> changed the role, and the very definition, of the
corporation. He gave a new interpretation to the Fourteenth
Amendment that actually gave corporations legal status as citizens .
. . as artificial persons. (5) </p>

<p> It was not long after this change in the interpretation of the
Fourteenth Amendment that <ent type='PERSON'>John</ent> D. <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent>, the father of the
modern-day corporation, created the great <ent type='ORG'>Standard Oil Corporation</ent>
which, by the late 1880s, gained control over 90% of all the oil
refineries in <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>. (6) </p>

<p> The roots of 20th Century <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n politics can best be illustrated
by the 1896 Presidential Election, won by <ent type='NORP'>Republican</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>William</ent>
McKinley by a landslide. The McKinley campaign was directed by
<ent type='PERSON'>Marcus Alonzo Hanna</ent> of <ent type='ORG'>Standard Oil</ent> and raised a $16000000
campaign fund from wealthy fellow industrialists, (an amount that
was unmatched in Presidential campaigns until the 1960s). The major
theme of the campaign, and one that would echo far into the future,
was "what's good for business is good for the country." (7) </p>

<p> This emerging political and judicial misuse of power in <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> was
feared by <ent type='PERSON'>Thomas</ent> Jefferson who, in 1787, wrote, "I think our
governments will remain virtuous for many centuries; as long as they
remain chiefly agricultural; and this will be as long as there shall
be vacant lands in any part of <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>. When they get piled upon one
another in large cities as in Europe they will become corrupt as in
Europe." (8) </p>

<p> It is important to remember that the <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n <ent type='EVENT'>Revolution</ent> was a
clash between the agriculturists in the colonies, and the <ent type='NORP'>British</ent>
industrialists who controlled the government in <ent type='GPE'>England</ent>. Almost 100
years later <ent type='EVENT'>the Civil War</ent> was fought as a continuation of the same
basic struggle, but with the victory going back to the
industrialists. This began the erosion of the <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n government
"of the people, for the people and by the people." The buying of the
1896 Presidential Election, by Hanna of <ent type='ORG'>Standard Oil</ent> and the
<ent type='PERSON'>Northern</ent> industrial interests, was the next important step on the
long road to the <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n government "of the corporation, for the
corporation and by the corporation." </p>

<p> A few years later, <ent type='EVENT'>World War</ent> I would forge an even closer
relationship between corporations and government in <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent>
States, as well as around the world. <ent type='PERSON'>Anthony Sampson</ent>, in his book
"<ent type='ORG'>The Arms Bazaar</ent>," notes that "the <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n companies, led by US
Steel and du Pont, were transformed by war orders. US Steel, which
had absorbed Carnegie's old steel company, had made average annual
profits in the four pre-war years of $105 million, while in the four
war years they were $240 million; and du Pont's average profit went
up from $6 million to $58 million. . . . </p>

<p> "Certainly the arms companies had become much richer through the
war, and there were widespread suspicions that they were actually
trying to prolong it." (9) </p>

<p> The bottom line is, of course, victory or profit, and in what
proportions? To what lengths would this nation's top industrial
leaders go to secure their share of the profits before and during
the next "war to end all war?" </p>

<p> NOTES: INTRODUCTION</p>

<p> 1.<ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n Political Tradition, Hofstadter, p. 109. (As reprinted
in <ent type='ORG'>The Irony</ent> of Democracy, <ent type='PERSON'>Thomas</ent> R. <ent type='PERSON'>Dye</ent> and L. <ent type='PERSON'>Harmon Zeigler</ent>, p.
72) 2.<ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n Political Tradition, p. 113. (As reprinted in The
Irony of Democracy, p. 72) 3.Irony of Democracy, p. 73 4.<ent type='PERSON'>Ibid</ent>., p.
74 5.<ent type='PERSON'>Ibid</ent>., p. 75 6.<ent type='PERSON'>Ibid</ent>., p. 76 7.<ent type='PERSON'>Ibid</ent>., p. 82 8.<ent type='PERSON'>Ibid</ent>., p. 62 9.The
<ent type='ORG'>Arms Bazaar</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Anthony Sampson</ent>, p. 65</p>

<p> U.S. CORPORATIONS AND THE <ent type='ORG'>NAZIS</ent> </p>

<p> "A clique of U.S. industrialists is hell-bent to bring a fascist
state to supplant our democratic government and is working closely
with the fascist regime in <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Italy</ent>. I have had plenty of
opportunity in my post in <ent type='GPE'>Berlin</ent> to witness how close some of our
<ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n ruling families are to the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> regime. . . . </p>

<p> "Certain <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n industrialists had a great deal to do with
bringing fascist regimes into being in both <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Italy</ent>. They
extended aid to help Fascism occupy the seat of power, and they are
helping to keep it there." - <ent type='PERSON'>William</ent> E. <ent type='PERSON'>Dodd</ent>, U.S. Ambassador to
<ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent>, 1937.(1)</p>

<p> A large volume of documentary evidence exists that reveals that
many of the richest, most powerful men in <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States, and the
giant corporations they controlled, were secretly allied with the
<ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent>, both before and during <ent type='EVENT'>World War</ent> II, even after war was
declared between <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>. This alliance began with U.S.
corporate investment during the reconstruction of post-<ent type='EVENT'>World War</ent> I
<ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> in the 1920s and, years later, included financial,
industrial and military aid to the <ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent>. </p>

<p> On the pages which follow we will review which prominent <ent type='NORP'>Americans</ent>
and corporations were involved, what aid and comfort they gave our
nation's enemies - treasonable offenses during time of war, and
investigations into these matters which produced evidence of a
US/<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> corporate conspiracy to bring a fascist state to <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>,
and eliminate competition in the industrial raw materials market in
order to force world-wide dependance on oil-based petrochemicals. </p>

<p> WILLIAM RANDOLPH <ent type='ORG'>HEARST</ent> </p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>Hearst</ent>, who was so concerned about the <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n public's health and
safety on the matter of marijuana use, apparently had no such fears
when it came to <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> and the <ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent>. According to journalist <ent type='PERSON'>George</ent>
<ent type='PERSON'>Seldes</ent>:</p>

<p> ". . . <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> had the support of the most widely circulated
magazine in history, 'Readers Digest,' as well as nineteen big-city
newspapers and one of the three great <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n news agencies, the
$220-million <ent type='ORG'>Hearst</ent> press empire. </p>

<p> ". . . <ent type='PERSON'>William</ent> Randolph <ent type='ORG'>Hearst</ent>, Sr., . . . was the lord of all the
press lords in <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States. The millions who read the <ent type='ORG'>Hearst</ent>
newspapers and magazines and saw <ent type='ORG'>Hearst</ent> newsreels in the nation's
moviehouses had their minds poisoned by <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> propaganda. </p>

<p> "It was . . . disclosed first to President <ent type='PERSON'>Roosevelt</ent> [by Ambassador
<ent type='PERSON'>Dodd</ent>] almost on the day it happened, in September 1934, and it is
detailed in the book 'Ambassador Dodd's Diary,' published in 1941,
and again in libel-proof documents on file in the courts of the
state of <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent>. <ent type='PERSON'>William</ent> E. <ent type='PERSON'>Dodd</ent>, professor of history [at the
University of <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>], told me about the <ent type='ORG'>Hearst</ent> sell-out . . . </p>

<p> "According to Ambassador <ent type='PERSON'>Dodd</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Hearst</ent> came to take the waters at
<ent type='ORG'>Bad Nauheim</ent> in September 1934, and <ent type='PERSON'>Dodd</ent> somehow learned immediately
that <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> had sent two of his most trusted <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> propagandists,
<ent type='ORG'>Hanfstangel</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Rosenberg</ent>, to ask <ent type='ORG'>Hearst</ent> how <ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent>m could present a
better image in <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States. When <ent type='ORG'>Hearst</ent> went to <ent type='GPE'>Berlin</ent> later
in the month, he was taken to see <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent>." </p>

<p> <ent type='PERSON'>Seldes</ent> reports that a $400000 a year deal was struck between
<ent type='ORG'>Hearst</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent>, and signed by Doctor <ent type='PERSON'>Joseph Goebbels</ent>, the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>
propaganda minister. "<ent type='ORG'>Hearst</ent>," continues <ent type='PERSON'>Seldes</ent>, "completely changed
the editorial policy of his nineteen daily newspapers the same month
he got the money." </p>

<p> In the court documents filed on behalf of <ent type='PERSON'>Dan Gillmor</ent>, publisher of
a magazine named "Friday," in response to a lawsuit by <ent type='ORG'>Hearst</ent>, under
item 61, he states: "Promptly after this said visit with Adolf
<ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> and the making of said arrangements. . . said plaintiff,
<ent type='PERSON'>William</ent> Randolph <ent type='ORG'>Hearst</ent>, instructed all <ent type='ORG'>Hearst</ent> press correspondents
in <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent>, including those of <ent type='ORG'>INS</ent> [Hearst's International News
Service] to report happenings in <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> only in a friendly' manner.
All of such correspondents reporting happenings in <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent>
accurately and without friendliness, sympathy and bias for the
actions of the then <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> government, were transferred elsewhere,
discharged, or forced to resign. . . ." </p>

<p> In the late 1930s, <ent type='PERSON'>Seldes</ent> recounts, when "several sedition
indictments [were brought by] <ent type='ORG'>the Department</ent> of Justice . . .
against a score or two of <ent type='NORP'>Americans</ent>, the defendants included an
unusually large minority of newspaper men and women, most of them
<ent type='ORG'>Hearst</ent> employees." (2) </p>

<p> ANDREW <ent type='ORG'>MELLON</ent> </p>

<p> "<ent type='PERSON'>Thurman Arnold</ent>, as assistant district attorney of <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent>
States, his assistant, <ent type='PERSON'>Norman Littell</ent>, and several <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>ional
investigations, have produced incontrovertible evidence that some of
our biggest monopolies entered into secret agreements with the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>
cartels and divided the world up among them," states <ent type='PERSON'>Seldes</ent> in his
book, "Facts and Fascism," published in 1943. "Most notorious of all
was <ent type='ORG'>Alcoa</ent>, the Mellon-<ent type='PERSON'>Davis</ent>-Duke monopoly which is largely
responsible for the fact <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> did not have the aluminum with
which to build airplanes before and after <ent type='PERSON'>Pearl Harbor</ent>, while
<ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> had an unlimited supply." (3)</p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>Alcoa</ent> sabotage of <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n war production had already cost the U.S.
"10000 fighters or 1665 bombers," according to <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>man <ent type='PERSON'>Pierce</ent>
of <ent type='GPE'>Oregon</ent> speaking in May 1941, because of "the effort to protect
Alcoa's monopolistic position. . ." </p>

<p> "If <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> loses this war," said Secretary of the <ent type='ORG'>Interior</ent>
[Harold] <ent type='ORG'>Ickes</ent>, June 26, 1941, "it can thank the Aluminum
Corporation of <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>." </p>

<p> "By its cartel agreement with I.G. <ent type='ORG'>Farben</ent>, controlled by <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent>,"
writes <ent type='PERSON'>Seldes</ent>, "<ent type='ORG'>Alcoa</ent> sabotaged the aluminum program of the U.S. air
force. <ent type='ORG'>The Truman Committee</ent> [on <ent type='ORG'>Nation</ent>al Defense, chaired by then-Senator <ent type='PERSON'>Harry</ent> S. <ent type='PERSON'>Truman</ent> in 1942] heard testimony that Alcoa's
representative, A.H. Bunker, $1-a-year head of the aluminum section
of O.P.M., prevented work on our $600000000 aluminum expansion
program." (4) </p>

<p> DU PONT AND GENERAL MOTORS </p>

<p> General Motors is included here because, by 1929, the Du Pont
corporation had acquired controlling interest in, and had
interlocking directorships with, General Motors. </p>

<p> Irenee du Pont, "the most imposing and powerful member of the
clan," according to biographer and historian <ent type='PERSON'><ent type='PERSON'>Charles</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Higham</ent></ent>, "was
obsessed with Hitler's principles." "He keenly followed the career
of the future <ent type='PERSON'>Fuhrer</ent> in the 1920s, and on September 7, 1926, in a
speech to the <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n Chemical Society, he advocated a race of
supermen, to be achieved by injecting special drugs into them in
boyhood to make their characters to order." Higham's book on this
subject, "Trading with the Enemy: An Expose of the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>-<ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n
Money Plot 1933-1949," is highly recommended. </p>

<p> Du Pont's anti-Semitism "matched that of <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent>" and, in 1933, the
Du Ponts "began financing native fascist groups in <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> . . ."
one of which <ent type='PERSON'>Higham</ent> identifies as the <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n Liberty League: "a
<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> organization whipping up hatred of blacks and <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>," and the
"love of <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent>. </p>

<p> "Financed . . . to the tune of $500000 the first year, the Liberty
League had a lavish thirty-one-room office in <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent>, branches in
twenty-six colleges, and fifteen subsidiary organizations nationwide
that distributed fifty million copies of its <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> pamphlets. . . . </p>

<p> "The Du Ponts' fascistic behavior was seen in 1936, when Irenee du
Pont used General Motors money to finance the notorious Black
Legion. This terrorist organization had as its purpose the
prevention of automobile workers from unionizing. The members wore
hoods and black robes, with skulls and crossbones. They fire-bombed
union meetings, murdered union organizers, often by beating them to
death, and dedicated their lives to destroying <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> and <ent type='NORP'>communist</ent>s.
They linked to the Ku Klux Klan. . . . It was brought out that at
least fifty people, many of them blacks, had been butchered by the
Legion." (5)</p>

<p> Du Pont support of <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> extended into the very heart of the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>
war machine as well, according to <ent type='PERSON'>Higham</ent>, and several other
researchers: "General Motors, under the control of the Du Pont
family of <ent type='GPE'>Delaware</ent>, played a part in collaboration" with the <ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent>. </p>

<p> "Between 1932 and 1939, bosses of General Motors poured $30 million
into I.G. <ent type='ORG'>Farben</ent> plants . . ." Further, <ent type='PERSON'>Higham</ent> informs us that by
"the mid-1930s, General Motors was committed to full-scale
production of trucks, armored cars, and tanks in <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent>." (6) </p>

<p> Researchers <ent type='PERSON'>Morton Mintz</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Jerry</ent> S. <ent type='PERSON'>Cohen</ent>, in their book, "Power
Inc.," describe the Du Pont-GM-<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> relationship in these terms:</p>

<p> ". . . In 1929, [Du Pont-controlled] GM acquired the largest
automobile company in <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Adam Opel</ent>, A.G. This predestined the
subsidiary to become important to the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> war effort. In a heavily
documented study presented to the Senate Subcommittee on Antitrust
and Monopoly in February 1974, <ent type='GPE'>Bradford</ent> C. <ent type='ORG'>Snell</ent>, an assistant
subcommittee counsel, wrote: </p>

<p> "'GM's participation in Germany's preparation for war began in
1935. That year its <ent type='ORG'>Opel</ent> subsidiary cooperated with the <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent> in
locating a new heavy truck facility at Brandenburg, which military
officials advised would be less vulnerable to enemy air attacks.
During the succeeding years, GM supplied the <ent type='ORG'>Wehrmact</ent> with <ent type='ORG'>Opel</ent>
"<ent type='ORG'>Blitz</ent>" trucks from the Brandenburg complex. For these and other
contributions to [the <ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent>] wartime preparations, GM's chief
executive for overseas operations [<ent type='PERSON'>James</ent> <ent type='LOC'>Mooney</ent>] was awarded the
Order of the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Eagle</ent> (first class) by Adolf <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent>.'"</p>

<p> Du Pont-GM <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> collaboration, according to <ent type='ORG'>Snell</ent>, included the
participation of <ent type='ORG'>Standard Oil</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>New Jersey</ent> [now <ent type='ORG'>Exxon</ent>] in one, very
important arrangement. GM and <ent type='ORG'>Standard Oil</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>New Jersey</ent> formed a
joint subsidiary with the giant <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> chemical cartel, I.G. <ent type='ORG'>Farben</ent>,
named <ent type='ORG'>Ethyl</ent> G.m.b.H. [now <ent type='ORG'>Ethyl</ent>, Inc.] which, according to <ent type='ORG'>Snell</ent>:
"provided the mechanized <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> armies with synthetic tetraethyl
fuel [leaded gas]. During 1936-39, at the urgent request of <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>
officials who realized that Germany's scarce petroleum reserves
would not satisfy war demands, GM and <ent type='ORG'>Exxon</ent> joined with <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>
chemical interests in the erection of the lead-tetraethyl plants.
According to captured <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> records, these facilities contributed
substantially to the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> war effort: 'The fact that since the
beginning of <ent type='ORG'>the war</ent> we could produce lead-tetraethyl is entirely
due to the circumstances that, shortly before, the <ent type='NORP'>Americans</ent> [Du
Pont, GM and <ent type='ORG'>Standard Oil</ent>] had presented us with the production
plants complete with experimental knowledge. Without lead-tetraethyl
the present method of warfare would be unthinkable.'" (7) </p>

<p> At about the same time the Du Ponts were serving the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> cause in
<ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent>, they were involved in a <ent type='NORP'>Fascist</ent> plot to overthrow the
United States government. </p>

<p> "Along with friends of <ent type='ORG'>the Morgan Bank</ent> and General Motors," in
early 1934, writes <ent type='PERSON'>Higham</ent>, "certain Du Pont backers financed a coup
d'etat that would overthrow the President with the aid of a $3
million-funded army of terrorists . . ." The object was to force
<ent type='PERSON'>Roosevelt</ent> "to take orders from businessmen as part of a fascist
government or face the alternative of imprisonment and execution . .
." </p>

<p> <ent type='PERSON'>Higham</ent> reports that "Du Pont men allegedly held an urgent series of
meetings with the <ent type='ORG'>Morgans</ent>," to choose who would lead this "bizarre
conspiracy." "They finally settled on one of the most popular
soldiers in <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>, General Smedly <ent type='PERSON'>Butler</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>Pennsylvania</ent>." <ent type='PERSON'>Butler</ent>
was approached by "fascist attorney" Gerald MacGuire (an official of
the <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n Legion), who attempted to recruit <ent type='PERSON'>Butler</ent> into the role
of an <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent>. </p>

<p> "<ent type='PERSON'>Butler</ent> was horrified," but played along with MacGuire until, a
short time later, he notified <ent type='ORG'>the <ent type='ORG'>White</ent> <ent type='ORG'>House</ent></ent> of the plot. <ent type='PERSON'>Roosevelt</ent>
considered having "the leaders of the houses of <ent type='ORG'>Morgan and</ent> Du Pont"
arrested, but feared that "it would create an unthinkable national
crisis in the midst of a depression and perhaps another Wall Street
crash." <ent type='PERSON'>Roosevelt</ent> decided the best way to defuse the plot was to
expose it, and leaked the story to the press. </p>

<p> "The newspapers ran the story of the attempted coup on the front
page, but generally ridiculed it as absurd and preposterous." But an
investigation by the <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>ional Committee on Un-<ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n
Activities - 74th <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>, first session, <ent type='ORG'>House</ent> of Representatives,
Investigation of <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> and other propaganda - was begun later that
same year. </p>

<p> "It was four years," continues <ent type='PERSON'>Higham</ent>, "before the committee dared
to publish its report in a white paper that was marked for
'restricted circulation.' They were forced to admit that 'certain
persons made an attempt to establish a fascist organization in this
country . . . [The] committee was able to verify all the pertinent
statements made by General <ent type='PERSON'>Butler</ent>.' This admission that the entire
plan was deadly in intent was not accompanied by the imprisonment of
anybody. Further investigations disclosed that over a million people
had been guaranteed to join the scheme and that the arms and
munitions necessary would have been supplied by <ent type='ORG'>Remington</ent>, a Du Pont
subsidiary." (8)</p>

<p> The names of important individuals and groups involved in the
conspiracy were suppressed by the committee, but later revealed by
<ent type='PERSON'>Seldes</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Philadelphia Record</ent> reporter <ent type='PERSON'>Paul French</ent>, and <ent type='PERSON'>Jules Archer</ent>,
author of the book, "The Plot to Seize <ent type='ORG'>the <ent type='ORG'>White</ent> <ent type='ORG'>House</ent></ent>." Included
were <ent type='PERSON'>John</ent> W. <ent type='PERSON'>Davis</ent> (attorney for the J.P. Morgan banking group),
<ent type='PERSON'>Robert Sterling Clark</ent> (Wall Street broker and heir to the Singer
sewing machine fortune), <ent type='PERSON'>William</ent> Doyle (<ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n Legion official),
and the <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n Liberty League (backed by executives from J.P.
<ent type='ORG'>Morgan and</ent> Co., <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> interests, E.F. Hutton, and Du Pont-controlled General Motors). (9) </p>

<p> THE US/<ent type='PERSON'>NAZI CARTEL</ent> AGREEMENT </p>

<p> "On November 23, 1937," states <ent type='PERSON'>Higham</ent>, "representatives of General
Motors held a secret meeting in <ent type='GPE'>Boston</ent> with Baron Manfred von
Killinger, who was . . . in charge of <ent type='ORG'>West</ent> Coast espionage [for the
<ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent>], and Baron <ent type='PERSON'>von Tipplekirsch</ent>, <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> consul general and <ent type='ORG'>Gestapo</ent>
leader in <ent type='GPE'>Boston</ent>. This group signed a joint agreement showing total
commitment to the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> cause for the indefinite future. . . ." (10) </p>

<p> <ent type='PERSON'>Seldes</ent> describes the plotters as "the great owners and rulers of
<ent type='GPE'>America</ent> who planned world domination through political and military
Fascism" including "several leading <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n industrialists, members
of the <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States, and representatives of large
business and political organizations . . ." </p>

<p> He obtained the text of the agreement, and published it in his
newsletter, "In Fact," on July 13, 1942. The plan "goes much further
than the mere cartel conspiracies of <ent type='ORG'>Big Business</ent> of both
countries," writes <ent type='PERSON'>Seldes</ent>, "because it has political clauses and
points to a bigger conspiracy of money and politicians such as
helped betray <ent type='GPE'>Norway</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>France</ent> and other lands to the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> machine.
The most powerful fortress in <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> is the production monopolies,
but its betrayal would involve, as it did in <ent type='GPE'>France</ent>, the
participation of some of the most powerful figures of the political
as well as the industrial world." (11) </p>

<p> STANDARD OIL OF <ent type='GPE'>NEW JERSEY</ent> (Now <ent type='ORG'>Exxon</ent>) </p>

<p> "On February 27, 1942," according to <ent type='PERSON'>Higham</ent>, "<ent type='PERSON'>Arnold</ent>, with
documents stuffed under his arms, . . . strode into the lion's den
of <ent type='ORG'>Standard</ent> at 30 <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> Plaza. Just behind him were Secretary
of the <ent type='ORG'>Navy</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Franklin Knox</ent> and Secretary of the <ent type='ORG'>Army</ent> Henry L.
<ent type='ORG'>Stimson</ent>." They confronted <ent type='ORG'>Standard</ent> official <ent type='PERSON'>William</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Farish</ent> and
"<ent type='PERSON'>Arnold</ent> sharply laid down his charges" that "by continuing to favor
<ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> in rubber deal and patent arrangements," <ent type='ORG'>Standard Oil</ent> "had
acted against the interests of the <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n government . . .
suggested a fine of $1.5 million and a consent decree whereby
<ent type='ORG'>Standard</ent> would turn over for the duration all the patents" in
question. </p>

<p> "<ent type='ORG'>Farish</ent> rejected the proposal on the spot. He pointed out that
<ent type='ORG'>Standard</ent>" was also selling the U.S. a "high percentage" of the fuel
being used by the <ent type='ORG'>Army</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Navy</ent>, and <ent type='ORG'>Air Force</ent> "making it possible for
<ent type='GPE'>America</ent> to win <ent type='ORG'>the war</ent>. Where would <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> be without it?"</p>

<p> Blackmail? Yes, says <ent type='PERSON'>Higham</ent>. And effective. <ent type='PERSON'>Arnold</ent> was finally
reduced to asking the oil company official "to what <ent type='ORG'>Standard Oil</ent>
would agree. After all, there had to be at least token punishment. .
. . <ent type='PERSON'>Arnold</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Stimson</ent>, and <ent type='PERSON'>Knox</ent> soon realized they had no power to
compare with that of <ent type='ORG'>Standard</ent>." </p>

<p> The price <ent type='ORG'>Standard Oil</ent> "agreed" to pay for its crime? A modest fine
of a few thousand dollars divided up among ten defendants. "<ent type='ORG'>Farish</ent>
paid $1000, or a quarter of one week's salary, for having betrayed
<ent type='GPE'>America</ent>." </p>

<p> In <ent type='GPE'>New Jersey</ent>, charges of "criminal conspiracy with the enemy" were
filed against <ent type='ORG'>Standard</ent>, then "dropped in return for <ent type='ORG'>Standard</ent>
releasing its patents and paying the modest fine." But <ent type='PERSON'>Arnold</ent>, and
his ally, Secretary of the <ent type='ORG'>Interior</ent> Harold <ent type='ORG'>Ickes</ent>, weren't finished
with <ent type='ORG'>Standard Oil</ent> just yet. They approached Senator <ent type='PERSON'>Truman</ent>, chairman
of the Senate Special Committee Investigating the <ent type='ORG'>Nation</ent>al Defense
Program. "With great enthusiasm Give 'em Hell <ent type='PERSON'>Harry</ent> embarked on a
series of hearings in March 1942, in order to disclose the truth
about <ent type='ORG'>Standard</ent>." </p>

<p> Between the 26th and the 28th of March, 1942, <ent type='PERSON'>Arnold</ent> "produced
documents showing that <ent type='ORG'>Standard</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>Farben</ent> in <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> had literally
carved up the world markets, with oil and chemical monopolies all
over the map," according to <ent type='PERSON'>Higham</ent>. (12) </p>

<p> <ent type='PERSON'>Mintz</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Cohen</ent> describe the confrontation:</p>

<p> "Four months after <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States entered <ent type='EVENT'>World War</ent> II, the
Justice Department obtained an indictment of <ent type='ORG'>Exxon</ent> and its principal
officers for having made arrangements, starting in the late 1920s
with I.G. <ent type='ORG'>Farben</ent> involving patent sharing and division of world
markets. Jersey <ent type='ORG'>Standard</ent> agreed not to develop processes for the
manufacture of synthetic rubber; in exchange, <ent type='ORG'>Farben</ent> agreed not to
compete in the <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n petroleum market. After war broke out in
Europe, but before the attack on <ent type='PERSON'>Pearl Harbor</ent>, executives of
<ent type='ORG'>Standard Oil</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>Farben</ent>, at a meeting in <ent type='GPE'>Holland</ent>, established a
'modus vivendi' for continuing the arrangements in event of war
between <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States and <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> - although the arrangements
interfered with the ability of <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States to make synthetic
rubber desperately needed after it entered <ent type='ORG'>the war</ent> in December 1941.
Rather than face a criminal trial, <ent type='ORG'>Exxon</ent> and the indicted executives
entered no-contest pleas - the legal equivalent of guilty pleas -
and were fined the minor sums which were the maximum amounts
permitted by law. A few days later, on March 26, 1942, the Senate
Special Committee Investigating the <ent type='ORG'>Nation</ent>al Defense Program held a
hearing at which <ent type='PERSON'>Thurman Arnold</ent>, chief of the <ent type='ORG'>Antitrust Division</ent>,
put into the record documents on which the [criminal] indictment had
been based, including a memo from a <ent type='ORG'>Standard Oil</ent> official on the
'modus vivendi' agreed to in <ent type='GPE'>Holland</ent>. After the hearing, the
committee chairman, <ent type='PERSON'>Harry</ent> S. <ent type='PERSON'>Truman</ent>, characterized the arrangements
as treasonable." (13)</p>

<p> Another source book on this subject of US / <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> corporate
activities is "<ent type='EVENT'>The Secret War Against</ent> the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>," by <ent type='PERSON'>Mark Aarons</ent> and
<ent type='PERSON'>John</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Loftus</ent>. Here is their version of the events:</p>

<p> "Before <ent type='ORG'>the war</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Standard</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>New Jersey</ent> had forged a synthetic oil
and rubber cartel with the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>-controlled I.G. <ent type='ORG'>Farben</ent>," which
"worked well until <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States joined <ent type='ORG'>the war</ent> in 1941. . . .
Next to the <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent>s, I.G. <ent type='ORG'>Farben</ent> owned the largest share of
stock in <ent type='ORG'>Standard Oil</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>New Jersey</ent>. Among other things, <ent type='ORG'>Standard</ent>
had provided <ent type='ORG'>Farben</ent> with its synthetic rubber patents and technical
knowledge, while <ent type='ORG'>Farben</ent> had kept its patents to itself, under strict
instructions from the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> government."</p>

<p> Evidence which <ent type='PERSON'>Thurman Arnold</ent> turned over to the <ent type='PERSON'>Truman</ent> Committee,
which <ent type='PERSON'>Truman</ent> would declare "treasonous," included "Standard's 1939
letter renewing its agreement, which made it clear that the
<ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent>s' company was prepared to work with the <ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent> whether
their own government was at war with the Third <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent> or not.
Truman's Senate Committee on the <ent type='ORG'>Nation</ent>al Defense was outraged and
began to probe into the whole scandalous arrangement, much to the
discomfort of <ent type='PERSON'>John</ent> D. <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent>, Jr. Suddenly, however, the whole
matter was dropped. </p>

<p> "There was a reason for Rockefeller's escape: blackmail. According
to the former intelligence officers we interviewed on this point,
the blackmail was simple and powerful: The <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent> brothers [<ent type='PERSON'>John</ent>
<ent type='ORG'>Foster</ent>, later Secretary of State, and <ent type='PERSON'>Allen</ent>, later director of the
<ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>] had one of their clients threaten to interrupt the U.S. oil
supply during wartime." </p>

<p> When confronted by <ent type='PERSON'>Arnold</ent> on the <ent type='ORG'>Standard</ent> - <ent type='ORG'>Farben</ent> arrangement
"<ent type='ORG'>Standard</ent> executives made it clear that the entire U.S. war effort
was fueled by their oil and it could be stopped. . . . The <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n
government had no choice but to go along if it wanted to win the
war." (14) </p>

<p> July 13, 1944, <ent type='PERSON'>Ralph</ent> W. Gallagher, attorney for <ent type='ORG'>Standard Oil</ent>, filed
a lawsuit against the U.S. government's seizure of the contested
patents. "On November 7, 1945, Judge <ent type='PERSON'>Charles</ent> E. <ent type='PERSON'>Wyzanski</ent> gave his
verdict," according to <ent type='PERSON'>Higham</ent>. "He decided that the government had
been entitled to seize the patents. Gallagher appealed. On September
22, 1947, Judge <ent type='PERSON'>Charles</ent> Clark delivered the final word on the
subject. He said, '<ent type='ORG'>Standard Oil</ent> can be considered an enemy national
in view of its relationships with I.G. <ent type='ORG'>Farben</ent> after <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent>
States and <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> had become active enemies.' The appeal was
denied." (15) </p>

<p> One aspect of this <ent type='ORG'>Standard</ent> - I.G. <ent type='ORG'>Farben</ent> relationship, revealed in
testimony during the <ent type='ORG'>Patents Committee</ent> hearings, chaired by Senator
Homer T. Bone in May 1942, is of interest to those who seek direct
evidence of a conspiracy by big oil companies to suppress
development of synthetic substitutes to petrochemical products such
as industrial chemicals, aircraft lubricants and fuel, all of which
can be made from hemp: </p>

<p> "On May 6th, <ent type='PERSON'>John</ent> R. <ent type='ORG'>Jacobs</ent>, Jr., of the Attorney General's
department, testified that <ent type='ORG'>Standard</ent> had interfered with the <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n
explosives industry by blocking the use of a method of producing
synthetic ammonia. As a result of its deals with <ent type='ORG'>Farben</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent>
States had been unable to get the use of this vital process even
after <ent type='PERSON'>Pearl Harbor</ent>. Also, <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States had been restricted in
techniques of producing hydrogen from natural gas and from obtaining
paraflow, a product used for airplane lubrication at high altitudes.
. . ." </p>

<p> On August 7th, "<ent type='GPE'>Texas</ent> oil operator C.R. <ent type='PERSON'>Starnes</ent> appeared to testify
that <ent type='ORG'>Standard</ent> had blocked him at every turn in his efforts to
produce synthetic rubber after <ent type='PERSON'>Pearl Harbor</ent>. . . ." </p>

<p> On August 12th, "<ent type='PERSON'>John</ent> R. <ent type='ORG'>Jacobs</ent> reappeared in an <ent type='ORG'>Army</ent> private's
uniform (he had been inducted the day before) to bring up another
disagreeable matter: <ent type='ORG'>Standard</ent> had also, in league with <ent type='ORG'>Farben</ent>,
restricted production of methanol, a wood alcohol that was sometimes
used as motor fuel." (16) </p>

<p> The restriction against methanol production apparently did not
apply to the <ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent>, however. "As late as April 1943," <ent type='PERSON'>Higham</ent>
reveals, "General Motors in <ent type='GPE'>Stockholm</ent> [<ent type='GPE'>Sweden</ent>] was reported as
trading with the enemy. . . . Further documents show that, as with
<ent type='ORG'>Ford</ent>, repairs on <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> army trucks and conversion from gasoline to
wood-gasoline production were being handled by GM in <ent type='GPE'>Switzerland</ent>."
(17) </p>

<p> The use of hemp as a source of methanol was known to the <ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent>,
revealed in the pamphlet "The Humorous Hemp Primer," published in
<ent type='GPE'>Berlin</ent>, also in 1943. This document, recently re-published in the
1995 edition of "Hemp and the <ent type='ORG'>Marijuana</ent> Conspiracy: The Emperor
Wears No Clothes," by veteran hemp conspiracy researcher <ent type='PERSON'>Jack Herer</ent>,
states that:</p>

<p> "<ent type='ORG'>Crops</ent> should not only provide food in large quantities, they can
provide raw materials for industry. . . . Among such raw materials
of especially high value is hemp . . . </p>

<p> "The woody part of this large plant is not to be thrown out, since
it can easily be used for surface coatings for the finest floors. It
also provides paper and cardboard, building materials and wall
paneling. Further processing will even produce wood sugar and wood
gas. . . .</p>

<p> "Anyone who grows hemp today need not fear a lack of a market,
because hemp, as useful as it is, will be purchased in unlimited
amounts." (18) </p>

<p> The <ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent> obviously considered hemp a vital war material that could
be used to produce methanol, or "wood gas," at the same time, in
1943, that Du Pont-controlled General Motors in <ent type='GPE'>Switzerland</ent> was
"converting from gasoline to wood-gasoline production." This, taken
into consideration along with the earlier statement that <ent type='ORG'>Standard</ent>
Oil-I.G. <ent type='ORG'>Farben</ent> had "restricted production of methanol" and the GM-<ent type='ORG'>Standard Oil</ent>-I.G. <ent type='ORG'>Farben</ent> joint venture, <ent type='ORG'>Ethyl</ent>, Inc., whose
profitability depended on the production of lead-tetraethyl for oil-based petrochemical gasoline - in direct competition with the
alternative methanol, or "wood gas," certainly opens new avenues of
investigation into the existence of a conspiracy against hemp as an
alternative, and competing, industrial raw material, by these very
same corporations which sold <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> out to the <ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent> for profit and
control of world resources and markets. </p>

<p> "Just after <ent type='PERSON'>Pearl Harbor</ent>," writes <ent type='PERSON'>Seldes</ent>, "the Assistant Attorney
General, Mr. <ent type='PERSON'>Thurman Arnold</ent>, issued a sensational report of the
sabotage of the national [war production] program, the first report
naming the practices which were later to be referred to as the
treason of big business in wartime. Said Mr. <ent type='PERSON'>Arnold</ent>:</p>

<p> "Looking back over 10 months of defense effort we can now see how
much it has been hampered by the attitude of powerful basic
industries who have feared to expand their production because
expansion would endanger their future control of industry. </p>

<p> "Anti-trust investigations during the past year have shown that
there is not an organized basic industry in <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States which
has not been restricting production by some device or other in order
to avoid what they call 'ruinous overproduction after <ent type='ORG'>the war</ent>'."
(19)</p>

<p> By "ruinous overproduction," of course, they meant free-market
competition. So, to question the existence of an industrial
conspiracy against competition, during the 1930s and 1940s, is
pointless. It has long been totally documented by volumes of
evidence, available in the public record. And among this list of
convicted corporate conspirators are murderers, racists, pro-<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>
collaborators, blackmailers and <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n <ent type='NORP'>Fascist</ent>s who plotted at
least one armed take-over of the U.S. government. And the list is
not yet complete. </p>

<p> THE <ent type='ORG'>FORD</ent> MOTOR COMPANY </p>

<p> Henry <ent type='ORG'>Ford</ent>, writes <ent type='PERSON'>Higham</ent>, "admired <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> from the beginning, when
the future <ent type='PERSON'>Fuhrer</ent> was a struggling and obscure fanatic. He shared
with <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> a fanatical hatred of <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>." </p>

<p> "Ford's book 'The International Jew' was issued in 1927. A virulent
anti-<ent type='NORP'>Semitic</ent> tract, it was still being distributed in Latin <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>
and the <ent type='NORP'>Arab</ent> countries as late as 1945. <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> admired the book and
it influenced him deeply. Visitors to Hitler's headquarters at the
Brown <ent type='ORG'>House</ent> in <ent type='GPE'>Munich</ent> noticed a large photograph of Henry <ent type='ORG'>Ford</ent>
hanging in his office. Stacked high on the table outside were copies
of Ford's book. As early as 1923," when <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> heard that <ent type='ORG'>Ford</ent> was
planning to run for President, he "told an interviewer from the
'<ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>-Tribune,' 'I wish that I could send some of my shock troops
to <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> and other big <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n cities to help'." </p>

<p> As late as 1940, <ent type='ORG'>Ford</ent> Motor Company "refused to build aircraft
engines for <ent type='GPE'>England</ent> and instead built supplies of the 5-ton military
trucks that were the backbone of <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> army transportation." (20) </p>

<p> The <ent type='ORG'>Ford</ent> Motor Company was also aware of the potential of hemp as
an alternative industrial resource, devoting many years research to
the subject. </p>

<p> In a 1989 <ent type='ORG'>ABC</ent> Radio broadcast, <ent type='PERSON'>Hugh Downs</ent> reported that in the
1930s, "the <ent type='ORG'>Ford</ent> Motor Company also saw a future in biomass fuels.
<ent type='ORG'>Ford</ent> operated a successful biomass conversion plant that included
hemp at their <ent type='LOC'>Iron Mountain</ent> facility in <ent type='GPE'>Michigan</ent>. <ent type='ORG'>Ford</ent> engineers
extracted methanol, charcoal fuel, tar, pitch, ethyl acetate, and
creosote - all fundamental ingredients for modern industry, and now
supplied by oil-related industries. . . . Henry Ford's experiments
with methanol promised cheap, readily-available fuel." (21) </p>

<p> As reported in "<ent type='ORG'>Popular Mechanics</ent>" in December, 1941, Ford's
research represented "an industrial revolution in progress . . . a
revolution in materials that will affect every home." (22) </p>

<p> So, it is possible, even likely, that <ent type='ORG'>Ford</ent> and General Motors
conversion "from gasoline to wood-gasoline production" for <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>
<ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent>, as earlier reported by <ent type='PERSON'>Higham</ent>, involved at least some
consideration of hemp as a resource, if not actual production of
"wood-gas" from hemp. After all, <ent type='ORG'>Ford</ent> had already committed several
years and significant research dollars to the subject. </p>

<p> The implication of methanol fuel patents, hemp industry research
and production facilities, all in the hands of this cabal of <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>-allied <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n corporations, during a proven period of anti-competition conspiracies, and wartime blackmail against the U.S.
government, should provide additional support for the hemp
conspiracy theories. The fact is that <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> recognized hemp
as a vital war material - one which, just before America's entrance
into <ent type='EVENT'>World War</ent> II, was positioned to compete in the free-market
against the products controlled by the Pro-<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n
corporations. Unrestricted expansion of United States industrial
hemp production threatened not only the profits of these treasonous
corporations, but the degree of their control over America's
production of vital war materials. </p>

<p> This view of hemp, not as a "dangerous drug" but as a vital war
material, was acknowledged by <ent type='ORG'>the Kentucky Legislature</ent> a little over
100 years before the <ent type='NORP'>Japanese</ent> sneak attack on <ent type='PERSON'>Pearl Harbor</ent>. In 1841,
according to Professor <ent type='PERSON'>James</ent> F. <ent type='ORG'>Hopkins</ent>, author of "A History of the
Hemp Industry in <ent type='GPE'>Kentucky</ent>," published by <ent type='ORG'>the University</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>Kentucky</ent>
Press in 1951: </p>

<p> "When the farmers of <ent type='GPE'>Woodford County</ent> [KY] assembled in October,
1841, to consider a program of hemp production for the <ent type='ORG'>navy</ent>, they
only went as far as to express an opinion that the government should
employ a rope spinner in <ent type='GPE'>Kentucky</ent> for the purpose of converting the
fiber into yarns, which could be transported much more cheaply and
safely than the bulky raw material. <ent type='ORG'>The Committee</ent> on Agriculture of
the <ent type='GPE'>Kentucky</ent> <ent type='ORG'>House</ent> of Representatives inquired into the matter early
in 1842 . . . </p>

<p> "Both houses of <ent type='ORG'>the General Assembly</ent> sent to the Senators and
<ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>men from <ent type='GPE'>Kentucky</ent> a request that they use their 'best
exertions' to have established in the state one or more agencies for
the inspection and manufacture of hemp for the <ent type='ORG'>navy</ent>. A select
committee of <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>, appointed to consider the resolutions from
<ent type='GPE'>Kentucky</ent>, reported three resolutions of its own: that the <ent type='ORG'>navy</ent> be
directed to construct a factory at <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent> 'for the purpose of
depositing and manufacturing . . . such hempen fabrics of domestic
water-rotted hemp as the public service may require'; that
inspectors be appointed to test the fiber that might be offered for
sale; and that, after due notice to the public, purchase of the
necessary amount of fiber be made at the factory. <ent type='ORG'>The Committee</ent>
contended that its plan would build up during peacetime a source of
hemp which would be vitally important in case of war, encourage
<ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n agriculture and manufactures, and decrease the unfavorable
balance of trade." (23) </p>

<p> [NOTE: For many years we <ent type='NORP'>Kentuckians</ent> have had a good deal of our
heritage and history buried beneath a thick layer of propaganda from
a source of power and control in this country which knows neither
honor nor justice. Now, we are learning the truth. Our history as a
state built upon the foundation of a long-and dishonestly-outlawed
industry endures.] </p>

<p> INTERNATIONAL TELEPHONE AND TELEGRAPH </p>

<p> Even after <ent type='PERSON'>Pearl Harbor</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>ITT</ent> was working for the <ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent>, reports
<ent type='PERSON'>Higham</ent>: ". . . the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> army, <ent type='ORG'>navy</ent>, and air force contracted with
<ent type='ORG'>ITT</ent> for the manufacture of switchboards, telephones, alarm gongs,
buoys, air raid warning devices, radar equipment, and thirty
thousand fuses per month for artillery shells used to kill <ent type='NORP'>British</ent>
and <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n troops." </p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>ITT</ent> also "supplied ingredients for the rocket bombs that fell on
<ent type='GPE'>London</ent>," and other devices as well, without which "it would have
been impossible for the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> air force to kill <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n and
<ent type='NORP'>British</ent> troops, for the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> army to fight the <ent type='ORG'>Allies</ent> in <ent type='GPE'>Africa</ent>,
<ent type='GPE'>Italy</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>France</ent>, and <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent>, for <ent type='GPE'>England</ent> to have been bombed, or for
<ent type='ORG'>Allied</ent> ships to have been attacked at sea." (24) </p>

<p> In 1938, "following a series of meetings with <ent type='ORG'>Luftwaffe</ent> chief
<ent type='PERSON'>Herman Goring</ent>, [<ent type='ORG'>ITT</ent> founder and chairman <ent type='PERSON'>Sosthenes</ent>] Behn encouraged
ITT's Lorenz subsidiary to purchase 28 percent of the Focke-Wulf
firm, manufacturer of the bombers that were to sink so many <ent type='ORG'>Allied</ent>
ships during <ent type='ORG'>the war</ent>," according to researcher and author Jim
Hougan. (25) </p>

<p> <ent type='PERSON'>Anthony Sampson</ent>, in "<ent type='LOC'>The Sovereign</ent> State of <ent type='ORG'>ITT</ent>," reports on what
is perhaps the most bizarre aspect of the US/<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> corporate
partnership, war reparations:</p>

<p> ". . . <ent type='ORG'>ITT</ent> now presents itself as the innocent victim of the Second
<ent type='EVENT'>World War</ent>, and has been handsomely recompensed for its injuries. In
1967, nearly thirty years after the events, <ent type='ORG'>ITT</ent> actually managed to
obtain $27 million in compensation from the <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n government, for
war damage to Focke-Wulf plants - on the basis that they were
<ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n property bombed by <ent type='ORG'>Allied</ent> bombers." (26)</p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>The Foreign Claims Settlement Commission</ent> was responsible for this
payment to <ent type='ORG'>ITT</ent>, and other U.S. corporations as well. </p>

<p> <ent type='GPE'>Bradford</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Snell</ent> reports that "After the cessation of hostilities, GM
and <ent type='ORG'>Ford</ent> demanded reparations from the U.S. Government for wartime
damages sustained by their Axis facilities as a result of <ent type='ORG'>Allied</ent>
bombing. By 1967 GM had collected more than $33 million in
reparations and Federal tax benefits for damages to its warplane and
motor vehicle properties in formerly Axis territories . . . <ent type='ORG'>Ford</ent>
received a little less than $1 million, primarily as a result of
damages sustained by its military truck complex at <ent type='GPE'>Cologne</ent>." (27) </p>

<p> ALLEN <ent type='PERSON'>DULLES</ent>: ARCHITECT OF THE US-<ent type='NORP'>NAZI</ent> NETWORK </p>

<p> Contemporary history records <ent type='PERSON'>Allen</ent> <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent> as one of America's top
spymasters, from his early days in <ent type='ORG'>the Office</ent> of Strategic Services
(<ent type='ORG'>OSS</ent>) in <ent type='EVENT'>World War</ent> II, to his position as Director of the <ent type='ORG'>Central</ent>
Intelligence Agency (<ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>) in the 1950s and early 1960s (until
President <ent type='PERSON'>John</ent> F. <ent type='PERSON'>Kennedy</ent> fired him over <ent type='ORG'>the Bay</ent> of Pigs disaster in
1961), and finally to his membership on the controversial <ent type='PERSON'>Warren</ent>
Commission, which investigated President Kennedy's assassination.
Until recently, his pivotal role in promoting a U.S. corporate
relationship with the <ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent> was little known. <ent type='ORG'>Loftus</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Aarons</ent>
describe the post-<ent type='EVENT'>World War</ent> I role of <ent type='PERSON'>Allen</ent>, and his brother, <ent type='PERSON'>John</ent>
<ent type='ORG'>Foster</ent>, in the following terms:</p>

<p> "We first turn to Dulles's creation of international finance
networks for the benefit of the <ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent>. In the beginning, moving
money into the Third <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent> was quite legal. Lawyers saw to that. And
<ent type='PERSON'>Allen</ent> and his brother <ent type='PERSON'>John</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Foster</ent> were not just any lawyers. They
were international finance specialists for the powerful Wall Street
law firm of <ent type='PERSON'>Sullivan</ent> &amp; <ent type='ORG'>Cromwell</ent>. . . . </p>

<p> "The <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent> brothers were the ones who convinced <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n
businessmen to avoid U.S. government regulation by investing in
<ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent>. It began with the Versailles Treaty, in which they played
no small role. After <ent type='EVENT'>World War</ent> I the defeated <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> government
promised to pay war reparations to the <ent type='ORG'>Allies</ent> in gold, but <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent>
had no gold. It had to borrow the gold from <ent type='PERSON'>Sullivan</ent> &amp; Cromwell's
clients in <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States. Nearly 70 percent of the money that
flowed into <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> during the 1930s came from investors in the
United States, many of them <ent type='PERSON'>Sullivan</ent> &amp; <ent type='ORG'>Cromwell</ent> clients. . . </p>

<p> "<ent type='ORG'>Foster</ent> <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent>, as a member of the board of I.G. <ent type='ORG'>Farben</ent>, seems to
have had little difficulty in getting along with whoever was in
charge. Some of our sources insist that both <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent> brothers made
substantial but indirect contributions to the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> party as the
price of continued influence inside the new <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> order. . . ."
(28)</p>

<p> NOTES: U.S. CORPORATIONS AND THE <ent type='ORG'>NAZIS</ent></p>

<p> 1.Facts and Fascism, <ent type='PERSON'>George</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Seldes</ent>, p. 122 Trading with the Enemy,
<ent type='PERSON'><ent type='PERSON'>Charles</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Higham</ent></ent>, p. 167 2.Even the Gods Can't Change History, <ent type='PERSON'>Seldes</ent>,
pp. 140-144 3.Facts and Fascism, p. 68 4.<ent type='PERSON'>Ibid</ent>., p. 262 5.Trading
with the Enemy, pp. 162-165 6.<ent type='PERSON'>Ibid</ent>., p. 166 7.Power, Inc., Morton
and <ent type='PERSON'>Mintz</ent>, pp. 497-499 8.Trading with the Enemy, pp. 163-165 9.The
Plot to Seize <ent type='ORG'>the <ent type='ORG'>White</ent> <ent type='ORG'>House</ent></ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Jules Archer</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Hawthorn Books</ent>, 1973
(Quoted from It's A Conspiracy, <ent type='ORG'>Nation</ent>al Insecurity Council,
<ent type='LOC'>Earth</ent>Works Press, 1992, pp. 179-184) 10.Trading with the Enemy, pp.
167-168 11.Facts and Fascism, pp. 68-70 12.Trading with the Enemy,
pp. 45-46 13.Power, Inc, pp. 499-500 14.<ent type='EVENT'>The Secret War Against</ent> The
<ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Aarons</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>Loftus</ent>, pp. 44-65 15.Trading with the Enemy, pp.
61-62 16.<ent type='PERSON'>Ibid</ent>., pp. 49-52 17.<ent type='PERSON'>Ibid</ent>., p. 176 18.The Emperor Wears No
Clothes, <ent type='PERSON'>Jack Herer</ent>, pp. 127-130 19.One Thousand <ent type='NORP'>Americans</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Seldes</ent>,
pp. 142-143 20.Trading with the Enemy, pp. 154-156 21.Ain't Nobody's
Business If You Do, p. 734 22.<ent type='ORG'>Popular Mechanics</ent> Magazine, Vol. 76,
No. 6, Dec. 1941 (The Emperor Wears No Clothes, 1995 edition, p.
199) 23.A History of the Hemp Industry in <ent type='GPE'>Kentucky</ent>, Professor <ent type='PERSON'>James</ent>
F. <ent type='ORG'>Hopkins</ent>, University of <ent type='GPE'>Kentucky</ent> Press, 1951 24.Trading with the
Enemy, p. 99 25.Spooks, <ent type='PERSON'>Jim Hougan</ent>, pp. 423-424 26.<ent type='LOC'>The Sovereign</ent>
State of <ent type='ORG'>ITT</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Anthony Sampson</ent>, p. 47 (Power, Inc., pp. 500-501)
27.GM and the <ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent>, by <ent type='GPE'>Bradford</ent> C. <ent type='ORG'>Snell</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Ramparts</ent> Magazine, June
1974, pp. 14-16 (Democracy for the Few, <ent type='PERSON'>Michael Parenti</ent>, pp. 91-92)
28.<ent type='EVENT'>The Secret War Against</ent> the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, pp. 55-60</p>

<p> THE NEW WORLD (<ent type='ORG'>DIS</ent>)ORDER </p>

<p> "The first truth is that the liberty of a democracy is not safe if
the people tolerate the growth of private power to a point where it
becomes stronger than their democratic state itself. That, in
essence, is fascism - ownership of government by an individual, by a
group, or by any other controlling power. </p>

<p> "Among us today a concentration of private power without equal in
history is growing." - President Franklin Delano <ent type='PERSON'>Roosevelt</ent> (1) </p>

<p> As mentioned earlier, the secret U.S./<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> corporate alliance
during <ent type='EVENT'>World War</ent> II was the result of substantial <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n
investment in post-<ent type='EVENT'>World War</ent> I <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent>. In order to protect these
investments, and the accumulating profits, the U.S. multinational
corporations remained an important part of the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> war machine
until the final defeat of <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> in 1945. What effect did the end
of <ent type='EVENT'>World War</ent> II have on this faction of <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> collaborators? </p>

<p> In this section we will review the evidence, much of it from
recently de-classified documents, that this pro-<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> faction, rather
than facing charges of high treason, became an integral part of the
United States national security apparatus, extending its fascist
influence in both foreign and domestic policies and, in effect,
creating what has been referred to as America's "Invisible
Government." The excuse, of course, was Communism. </p>

<p> THE BUGGING OF WALL STREET </p>

<p> <ent type='PERSON'>Aarons</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>Loftus</ent>' research, which documents the <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent> brothers'
pro-<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> activities, did not go unnoticed. "Before his death, former
<ent type='ORG'>Supreme Court</ent> Justice <ent type='PERSON'>Arthur Goldberg</ent> granted one of the authors an
interview. Justice <ent type='PERSON'>Goldberg</ent> had served in U.S. intelligence during
<ent type='EVENT'>World War</ent> II. Although he said little in public, he had collected
information on the <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent> boys' activities over the years. His
verdict was blunt. 'The <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent> brothers were traitors.' They had
betrayed their country, by giving aid and comfort to the enemy in
time of war." (2) </p>

<p> Much of what is now known about the activities of the <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent>
brothers and other <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> collaborators in banking and
industry came as a result of a top-secret joint U.S.-<ent type='NORP'>British</ent>
intelligence program known as <ent type='ORG'>the Ultra</ent> Project. "Prior to the
United States' entry into <ent type='ORG'>the war</ent>," write <ent type='ORG'>Loftus</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Aarons</ent>,
"<ent type='PERSON'>Roosevelt</ent> permitted <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> intelligence to wiretap <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n
targets.</p>

<p> "According to our sources in the intelligence community, the area
of coverage included a good bit of the <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent> financial district,
several floors of <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> Plaza, part of the RCA Building, two
prominent clubs, and various shipping firms. . . . </p>

<p> "The wiretap unit reported to Sir <ent type='PERSON'>William</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Stephen</ent>son, a Canadian
electronics genius better known by his code name, '<ent type='ORG'>Intrepid</ent>.' From
his headquarters in the <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> building, <ent type='PERSON'>Stephen</ent>son's job was
to identify U.S. companies that were aiding the <ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent>." (3) </p>

<p> "Several months before <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States declared war," continue
<ent type='ORG'>Loftus</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Aarons</ent>, "<ent type='PERSON'>Bill Donovan</ent> invited <ent type='PERSON'>Allen</ent> <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent> to head up the
<ent type='GPE'>New York</ent> branch of <ent type='ORG'>the Office</ent> of the Coordinator of Information
(COI), President Roosevelt's new intelligence agency and the
precursor to <ent type='ORG'>the Office</ent> of Strategic Services (<ent type='ORG'>OSS</ent>). Its primary
mission was to collect information against the <ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent> and their
collaborators. In other words, <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent> was asked to inform on his own
clients in <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent>. . . ." </p>

<p> "<ent type='PERSON'>Roosevelt</ent> had approved his selection as head of the COI <ent type='GPE'>Manhattan</ent>
branch because he wanted <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent> where the <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> wiretappers could
keep an eye on him. . . . </p>

<p> "One floor below <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent> was <ent type='PERSON'>Stephen</ent>son's wiretap shop. Inside
Dulles's operation was one of Roosevelt's spies, <ent type='PERSON'>Arthur Goldberg</ent> . .
." who, "confirmed . . . that Dulles's appointment was a setup. . .
. </p>

<p> "<ent type='PERSON'>Roosevelt</ent> was giving <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent> enough rope to hang himself. From
<ent type='PERSON'>Stephen</ent>son's <ent type='GPE'>Manhattan</ent> wiretaps, it is known that <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent> was
continuing to work with his <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> business clients, who wanted to
remove <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> and install a puppet of their own who would make peace
with the <ent type='ORG'>West</ent> while forging an alliance against <ent type='PERSON'>Stalin</ent>. It was to be
a kinder, gentler Third <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent>, favorably disposed to <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n
financial interests. . . . (4) </p>

<p> "The wiretap evidence against <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent> originally was collected by a
special section of Operation Safehaven, the U.S. <ent type='ORG'>Treasury</ent>
Department's effort to trace the movement of stolen <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> booty
towards the end of <ent type='ORG'>the war</ent>. <ent type='PERSON'>Roosevelt</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>Treasury</ent> Secretary Henry
Morganthau had set up <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent> by giving him the one assignment -
intelligence chief in <ent type='GPE'>Switzerland</ent> - where he would be most tempted
to aid his <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> clients with their money laundering."</p>

<p> <ent type='PERSON'>Roosevelt</ent> had one thing in mind: "The sudden release of the
Safehaven intercepts would force a public outcry to bring treason
charges against those <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n businessmen who aided the
enemy in time of war." Among the targets were <ent type='PERSON'>Allen</ent> <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent>, Henry
<ent type='ORG'>Ford</ent>, and other U.S. industrialists. (5) </p>

<p> The plan failed, however, due to <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent> being "tipped off . . .
that he was under surveillance" in time to cover his tracks. One
possible source of the leak was Vice President <ent type='PERSON'>Henry Wallace</ent>, "who
constantly shared information with his brother-in-law, the <ent type='NORP'>Swiss</ent>
minister in <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent> during <ent type='ORG'>the war</ent>." </p>

<p> "<ent type='PERSON'>Wallace</ent>," the authors reveal, "gave many details of his secret
meetings with <ent type='PERSON'>Roosevelt</ent> to the <ent type='NORP'>Swiss</ent> diplomat." The problem was
that, at the time, the <ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent> "had recruited the head of the <ent type='NORP'>Swiss</ent>
secret service." </p>

<p> It is, perhaps, no coincidence that <ent type='PERSON'>Roosevelt</ent> dropped <ent type='PERSON'>Wallace</ent>
during the 1944 election, choosing instead Senator <ent type='PERSON'>Harry</ent> S. <ent type='PERSON'>Truman</ent>
as his new running mate. (6) </p>

<p> THE ENEMY OF MY ENEMY</p>

<p> "After the <ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent>' 1943 defeat at <ent type='PERSON'>Stalin</ent>grad," write <ent type='ORG'>Loftus</ent> and
<ent type='PERSON'>Aarons</ent>, "various <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> businessmen realized they were on the losing
side and made plans to evacuate their wealth. The <ent type='PERSON'>Peron</ent> government
in <ent type='GPE'>Argentina</ent> was receiving the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> flight capital with open arms,
and <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent> helped it hide the money. . . . </p>

<p> "The Guinness Book of Records lists the missing <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent>sbank treasure
[estimated at $2.5 billion dollars] as the greatest unsolved bank
robbery in history. Where did it go? . . . . </p>

<p> "According to our source, the bulk of the treasure was simply
shipped a very short distance across <ent type='GPE'>Austria</ent> and through the Brenner
Pass into <ent type='GPE'>Italy</ent>. Dulles's contacts were waiting at the <ent type='ORG'>Vatican</ent>. The
<ent type='NORP'>German</ent>-<ent type='ORG'>Vatican</ent> connection was how <ent type='PERSON'>Allen</ent> <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent> and the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>
industrialists planned to get away with it. . . ." (7)</p>

<p> The effort was successful, according to the authors, who state that
the "vast bulk of the wealth of the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> empire" which "disappeared
before the end of <ent type='EVENT'>World War</ent> II" reappeared "within a decade in the
hands of the same men who financed Hitler's war against the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>.
<ent type='PERSON'>Allen</ent> Dulles's clients were not defeated, only inconvenienced." The
authors identify two of Dulles's accomplices as <ent type='PERSON'>James</ent> Jesus <ent type='PERSON'>Angleton</ent>
and his father, <ent type='PERSON'><ent type='PERSON'>Hugh</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Angleton</ent></ent>. The <ent type='ORG'>Angletons</ent> were members of X-2,
the <ent type='ORG'>OSS</ent> counterintelligence branch in <ent type='GPE'>Italy</ent>, in 1943. </p>

<p> Like <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'><ent type='PERSON'>Hugh</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Angleton</ent></ent> was financially involved with Axis
powers. He was the European representative for <ent type='ORG'>Nation</ent>al Cash
Register in <ent type='GPE'>Italy</ent> before <ent type='ORG'>the war</ent> and business associate of <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent>.
When <ent type='EVENT'>World War</ent> II broke out, the authors write, </p>

<p> ". . . <ent type='PERSON'>Angleton</ent> was crushed financially as all his investments were
in enemy hands. </p>

<p> "Like Dulles's clients, he wanted his money back. Like <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Hugh</ent>
offered his services to the <ent type='ORG'>OSS</ent>." With high-placed contacts in
Mussolini's <ent type='ORG'>Interior</ent> Ministry, <ent type='PERSON'>Hugh</ent> was accepted and "promoted
rapidly in U.S. intelligence. He became second in command to Colonel
<ent type='PERSON'>Clifton Carter</ent>, the <ent type='ORG'>OSS</ent> commander in <ent type='GPE'>Italy</ent> at the end of <ent type='EVENT'>World War</ent>
II." (8)</p>

<p> Perhaps the most controversial information which is now emerging
with the release of recently declassified documents concerning World
War II, is the role of the <ent type='ORG'>Vatican</ent>, both in its pre-war <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>
investments, and its role in helping <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> war criminals escape
justice after <ent type='ORG'>the war</ent>. Concerning the <ent type='ORG'>Vatican</ent>-<ent type='NORP'>German</ent> investments,
<ent type='ORG'>Loftus</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Aarons</ent> are quite clear:</p>

<p> "That the <ent type='ORG'>Vatican</ent> encouraged such investments and even donated
money to <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> himself cannot be denied. A <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> nun, Sister
<ent type='PERSON'>Pascalina</ent>, was present at its creation. In the early 1920s she was
the housekeeper for Archbishop of the <ent type='ORG'>Vatican</ent>-<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> connection . . .
<ent type='PERSON'>Eugenio Pacelli</ent>, then the papal nuncio in <ent type='GPE'>Munich</ent>. sister <ent type='PERSON'>Pascalina</ent>
vividly recalls receiving Adolf <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> late one night and watching
the archbishop give <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> a large amount of <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> money."</p>

<p> In addition, <ent type='PERSON'>Eugenio Pacelli</ent> </p>

<p> "later convinced the <ent type='ORG'>Vatican</ent> to invest millions of dollars in the
rising <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> economy, money from the Vatican's land settlement that
ended the Pope's claim of sovereignty over territory outside the
walls of <ent type='ORG'>Vatican</ent> City. It was <ent type='PERSON'>Pacelli</ent> who negotiated the Concordat
with <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> and then had to deal with the consequences of his own
mistakes when he became pope on the eve of <ent type='EVENT'>World War</ent> II. </p>

<p> "The <ent type='ORG'>Vatican</ent> and the <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent> brothers had the same problem. Once
their money was in Hitler's hands, how would they get it back?"</p>

<p> The authors interviewed "a former colonel in U.S. Military
Intelligence who specialized in tracing enemy assets. He claimed
that only a tiny portion of the <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent>bank's gold ingots actually
reached the <ent type='ORG'>Vatican</ent> Bank, while the rest was held in cooperative
banks in <ent type='GPE'>Belgium</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Liechtenstein</ent>, and especially <ent type='GPE'>Switzerland</ent>." It was
only necessary to transfer the paperwork on the gold, not the gold
itself. Since, by that time, <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent> knew his telegraph
communications were being monitored by the <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> wiretap operation
in <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent>, he instead used couriers to "ensure absolute secrecy in
moving the foreign currency and the ownership documents out of
<ent type='GPE'>Switzerland</ent> . . . special agents of the <ent type='ORG'>Vatican</ent> who had diplomatic
immunity to move back and forth across both <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>Allied</ent> lines. .
. ." (9)</p>

<p> ". . . . The Vatican's eminence grise for <ent type='NORP'>Balkan</ent> intelligence, the
<ent type='NORP'>Bosnian</ent>-<ent type='NORP'>Croat</ent> priest <ent type='PERSON'>Krunoslav Draganovic</ent>, was involved in
transporting large quantities of <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> booty, especially gold
bullion, from <ent type='GPE'>Austria</ent> to the safety of the Holy See with the help of
the <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent>-<ent type='PERSON'>Angleton</ent> clique in <ent type='GPE'>Rome</ent>. Some of the booty was
transported in truck convoys run by <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> troops. Other shipments
were carried in U.S. <ent type='ORG'>Army</ent> jeeps provided to Father <ent type='PERSON'>Draganovic</ent> so
that he could conduct pastoral visits' on behalf of the <ent type='ORG'>Vatican</ent>. </p>

<p> "Another ardent <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> propagandist and agent, <ent type='NORP'>Slovenian</ent> bishop
<ent type='PERSON'>Gregory Rozman</ent>, was sent to <ent type='GPE'>Bern</ent> with the help of Dulles's friends
in U.S. intelligence. Declassified U.S. intelligence files confirm
that Bishop <ent type='PERSON'>Rozman</ent> was suspected of trying to arrange the transfer
of huge quantities of <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>-controlled gold and <ent type='ORG'>West</ent>ern currency that
had been discreetly secreted in <ent type='NORP'>Swiss</ent> banks during <ent type='ORG'>the war</ent>. For a
few months the <ent type='ORG'>Allies</ent> prevented <ent type='PERSON'>Rozman</ent> from gaining access to this
treasure, but then the way was mysteriously cleared. In fact, the
<ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent>-<ent type='ORG'>Vatican</ent> connection had fixed it, and before too long the
bishop obtained the loot for his <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> friends, who were hiding in
<ent type='GPE'>Argentina</ent>. </p>

<p> "Such instances turned out to be only the tip of the iceberg. It
has long been acknowledged that it was <ent type='PERSON'>Allen</ent> <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent> who tipped off
General <ent type='ORG'>Patton</ent> about the buried <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> treasure that lay in the path
of the U.S. Third <ent type='ORG'>Army</ent>. <ent type='ORG'>Patton</ent> explicitly urged General <ent type='PERSON'>Eisenhower</ent>
to conceal as much of the gold as possible, but his advice was
refused. </p>

<p> "Our sources claim that <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent> and his colleagues exerted a great
deal of influence to ensure that <ent type='ORG'>West</ent>ern investments in <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent>
were not seized by the <ent type='ORG'>Allies</ent> as reparations for the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>. After
all, much of 'Hitler's Gold' had originally belonged to the bankers
in <ent type='GPE'>London</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent>. The . . . captured <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> loot went
underground. . . . </p>

<p> "In the cause of anticommunism, and to retrieve its own investments
in <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent>, the <ent type='ORG'>Vatican</ent> agreed to become part of Dulles's smuggling
window, through which the <ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent> and their treasure could be moved to
safety." (10)</p>

<p> On April 12th, 1945, <ent type='PERSON'>Roosevelt</ent> died, and <ent type='PERSON'>Truman</ent> became President.
May 7th, <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> surrendered after the suicide of Adolf <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent>.
September 2nd, <ent type='GPE'>Japan</ent> surrendered. </p>

<p> <ent type='EVENT'>World War</ent> II finally ended, but at the cost of more than 35000000
lives, over half that amount civilians. The death toll for the
United States was 294000. (11) </p>

<p> A PLEDGE BETRAYED</p>

<p> "<ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent> and some of his friends volunteered for postwar service
with the government not out of patriotism but of necessity,"
according to <ent type='ORG'>Loftus</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Aarons</ent>. "They had to be in positions of
power to suppress the evidence of their own dealings with the <ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent>.
The Safehaven investigation was quickly stripped from <ent type='ORG'>Treasury</ent> . . .
and turned over to the State Department. There Dulles's friends
shredded the index to the interlocking corporations and blocked
further investigations. </p>

<p> "<ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent> had this goal in mind: Not a single <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n businessman
was ever going to be convicted of treason for helping the <ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent>.
None ever was, despite the evidence. According to one of our sources
in the intelligence community, the U.S. <ent type='ORG'>Army</ent> Counter Intelligence
Corps had two large '<ent type='ORG'>Civilian Internment Centers</ent>' in Occupied
<ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent>, code named '<ent type='ORG'>Ashcan</ent>' and '<ent type='PERSON'>Dustbin</ent>.' The <ent type='ORG'>CIC</ent> had identified
and captured a large number of U.S. citizens who had stayed in
<ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> and aided the Third <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent> all through <ent type='EVENT'>World War</ent> II. The
evidence of their treason was overwhelming. The captured <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>
records were horribly incriminating. </p>

<p> "Yet <ent type='PERSON'>Victor Wohreheide</ent>, the young Justice Department attorney
responsible for preparing the treason trials, suddenly ordered the
prisoners' release. All of the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> collaborators were allowed to
return to <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States and reclaim their citizenship. At the
same time, another Justice Department attorney, O. <ent type='PERSON'>John</ent> Rogge, who
dared to make a speech about <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> collaborators in <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States
was quickly fired. However, the attorney who buried the treason
cases was later promoted to special assistant attorney general. </p>

<p> "<ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent> and his clients had won. The proof is in the bottom line.
Forty years after <ent type='EVENT'>World War</ent> II, Fortune magazine published a list of
the hundred richest men in the world. There were no <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> on the
list. The great fortunes of the <ent type='PERSON'>Rothschilds</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Warburgs</ent> had been
diminished to insignificance by the <ent type='EVENT'>Depression</ent>, the <ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent>, and World
War II. </p>

<p> "Near the top of the list were several multibillionaires who had
been prominent members of Hitler's inner circle. A few even had
served time in <ent type='ORG'>Allied</ent> prisons as <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> war criminals, but they were
all released quickly. The bottom line is that the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> businessmen
survived <ent type='ORG'>the war</ent> with their fortunes intact and rebuilt their
industrial empires to become the richest men in the world. Dulles's
clients got away with it. President Roosevelt's dream of putting the
<ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent>' moneymen on trial died with him."</p>

<p> <ent type='GPE'>England</ent> also failed to see justice done, according to the authors:
"The <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> authorities in <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> ordered the U.S. <ent type='ORG'>Army</ent> to release
all of the VIP <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent> and hand over the evidence against
them. Even before Roosevelt's death, <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>ill had already begun to
withdraw from his commitment to prosecute <ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent>." The reason?" Too
many <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> industries might be seized as <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> fronts. Too many
upper-class collaborators might have to be prosecuted. The <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>s
were defeated, and the <ent type='NORP'>Soviets</ent> were now the enemy.</p>

<p> "Funding for <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> war crimes investigations suddenly dried up.
<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> bankers such as <ent type='PERSON'>Herman Abs</ent> were released from prison to work as
economic advisers in the <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> zone of <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent>. The history of
<ent type='NORP'>British</ent> 'efforts' to punish <ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent> after <ent type='ORG'>the war</ent> is aptly summarized
in <ent type='PERSON'>Tom Bower</ent>'s book, 'The Pledge betrayed'. . . . </p>

<p> "The pattern was repeated all over the remnants of the Third <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent>.
Despite direct orders from President <ent type='PERSON'>Truman</ent> and General <ent type='PERSON'>Eisenhower</ent>,
I.G. <ent type='ORG'>Farben</ent>, the citadel of the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> industrialists, was never
dismantled. Dulles's clients demanded, and received, <ent type='ORG'>Allied</ent>
compensation for bomb damage to their factories in <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent>. Only a
few of the top <ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent> were executed. Most of the rest were released
from prison within a few years. Others, . . . would go virtually
unpunished. No one ever investigated the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> sympathizers in
<ent type='ORG'>West</ent>ern intelligence who had made it all possible." (12)</p>

<p> As we have seen, the <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n industrialists who did business with
the <ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent> were in no way inconvenienced by war crimes trials, and
even received compensation for damages to their <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> war plants.
Some <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> industrialists were charged and convicted by the <ent type='GPE'>Nuremberg</ent>
war crimes trials but, in their book, "The <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n Establishment,"
authors <ent type='PERSON'>Leonard</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Mark Silk</ent> observe that in the late 1940s "the
United States and its leaders faced an agonizing moral problem in
coming to terms with those <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> industrialists who had willingly
done business with the <ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent> and who were now just as willing to do
business with the <ent type='NORP'>Americans</ent> in the reconstruction of <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent>. The
problem was dramatized when those <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> industrialists who had been
convicted of war crimes at <ent type='GPE'>Nuremberg</ent> were all released from
<ent type='PERSON'>Landsberg</ent> prison in early 1951, their sentences commuted by the
<ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n High Commissioner [of <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> Occupation], <ent type='PERSON'>John</ent> J. McCloy. </p>

<p> ". . . . Whatever the motivation," the authors continue, "the
blanket release of the convicted industrialists was taken within
<ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> - and by them - as a sign that businessmen were not to be
seriously blamed for their involvement in matters for which others
were hanged or suffered long imprisonment." (13) </p>

<p> The motivation for the mass release of imprisoned <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> war
criminals is described in the book, "The New <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> and the Old
<ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent>," by T.H. Tetens, an expert in <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> affairs. </p>

<p> Tetens observes that in "1950, when <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent> showed its eagerness
to create a new <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> army of 500000 men, the SS [at that time
reorganized into a neo-<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> front group called <ent type='ORG'>HIAG</ent>, which stands
for 'mutual assistance,' a so-called veterans organization],
together with the old <ent type='NORP'>Wehrmacht</ent> officers, started an all-out
campaign for the immediate release of all war criminals. It was a
superbly organized blackmail action, enjoying wide support from the
public, from all parties, and carried toward success by Dr.
Adenauer's astute maneuverings. </p>

<p> "The Chancellor suggested an inconspicuous way to solve the problem
with 'parole,' 'sick leave,' and other roundabout methods. The more
the U.S. High Commission in <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> showed leniency, however, the
stronger the pressure became: either 'all so-called war criminals
are released or there will be no <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> army.' <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n diplomats
followed Dr. Adenauer's plan to feed the nationalistic monster
piecemeal. Every few days we quietly released one or two more from
prison - the <ent type='ORG'>Krupps</ent>, the I.G. <ent type='ORG'>Farben</ent> directors, and dozens of former
<ent type='NORP'>Wehrmacht</ent> Generals. On friendly advice from <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, the <ent type='NORP'>British</ent>
and the <ent type='NORP'>French</ent>, extremely reluctant, had to follow suit. When the
supply dried up, there remained behind bars only the SS, the mass
murderers from <ent type='LOC'>Dachau</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Belsen</ent>, and <ent type='ORG'>Buchenwald</ent>, and the toughs from
<ent type='ORG'>the Waffen</ent> SS who had massacred <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n, <ent type='NORP'>British</ent>, and Canadian
prisoners of war. This put High Commissioner <ent type='PERSON'>John</ent> McCloy in a most
embarrassing position. . . ." </p>

<p> Tetens explains how Chancellor <ent type='PERSON'>Adenauer</ent> helped High Commissioner
McCloy and the U.S. State Department avoid this embarrassment:
<ent type='PERSON'>Adenauer</ent> "suggested the formation of a review board, with three
<ent type='NORP'>German</ent> members sitting in and having equal voice in making
recommendations. The whole procedure was to be shrouded in secrecy,
and it was decided that the names of those released should not be
revealed to the public. In this way the last few hundred 'poor
devils,' those SS mass killers and sadists, were quietly set free
within two or three years." (14) </p>

<p> <ent type='PERSON'>Christopher Simpson</ent>, in his extensively documented book on the
subject of U.S. recruitment of <ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent>, "Blowback," goes into more
detail of the backgrounds of those released: </p>

<p> "The beneficiaries of this act included, for example, all of the
convicted concentration camp doctors; all of the top judges who had
administered the <ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent>' 'special courts'" and dozens of similar
cases. In addition, "McCloy's clemency decisions for the <ent type='PERSON'>Landsberg</ent>
inmates set in motion a much broader process that eventually freed
hundreds of other convicted <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> war criminals over the next five
years. . . . By the winter of 1950-1951 the most senior levels of
the U.S. government had decided to abrogate their wartime pledge to
bring <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> war criminals to justice. . . . in the interests of
preserving <ent type='ORG'>West</ent> <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> military support for <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n leadership in
the cold war. While <ent type='NORP'>nazism</ent> and Hitler's inner circle continued to be
publicly condemned throughout the <ent type='ORG'>West</ent>, the actual investigation and
prosecution of specific <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> crimes came to a standstill." (15) </p>

<p> One case merits special attention: <ent type='PERSON'>Sepp Dietrich</ent>, "the organizer of
the Fuehrer's bodyguard. <ent type='PERSON'>Dietrich</ent> carried out Hitler's personal
murder assignments" and, Tetens continues, "was in charge of the
liquidation of the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> population in the city of <ent type='GPE'>Kharkov</ent>. During
the Battle of the Bulge his troops committed the <ent type='ORG'>Malmedy</ent> massacre,
killing more than 600 military and civilian prisoners, among them
115 <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n G.I.s. He was sentenced to death, and the sentence was
later commuted to life imprisonment. In 1955 he was one of the last
poor devils' quietly released from prison and greeted by the <ent type='GPE'>Bonn</ent>
government with the homecoming pay of 6000 marks." (16) </p>

<p> In a "<ent type='GPE'>New York</ent> Times" article published February 1, 1951, one
prominent <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n expressed support for the reduction of sentences
for those responsible for the mass murder of the 600 unarmed
prisoners of war at <ent type='ORG'>Malmedy</ent>, describing the decision as "extremely
wise." The <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n was Senator Joseph <ent type='PERSON'>McCarthy</ent>, <ent type='NORP'>Republican</ent> from
<ent type='GPE'>Wisconsin</ent>. </p>

<p> Tetens observes that, despite the wide-spread fear by "the <ent type='NORP'>French</ent>,
the <ent type='NORP'>British</ent>, and the smaller European countries" of a re-militarized
<ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent>, "the outbreak of <ent type='EVENT'>the Korean War</ent> (June 1950) brought a total
change. The provisions which banned all military and veterans'
organizations lost all their meaning and were no longer enforced.
<ent type='ORG'>West</ent>ern <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> was allowed by the <ent type='ORG'>Allies</ent> to set up its own General
Staff, camouflaged under the name <ent type='ORG'>Blank Office</ent>. Supported by <ent type='GPE'>Bonn</ent>
and tolerated by <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States, a nation-wide network was
created to reactivate the experienced officers and the man power of
the old <ent type='NORP'>Wehrmacht</ent>. The short period of 1950-51 must be marked as the
time when Hitler's old officers, SS leaders, and [<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>] party
functionaries returned to power and influence." (17) </p>

<p> Tetens' comment that the Nazi's return to power in <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> was
"tolerated by <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States" was a historical understatement. By
the time Tetens' book was published in 1961, hundreds of convicted
<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> war criminals had already been smuggled out of <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> to avoid
prosecution at <ent type='ORG'>the war</ent> crimes trials at <ent type='GPE'>Nuremberg</ent>, recruited by, and
on the payroll of several U.S. government agencies, including the
<ent type='ORG'>Army</ent> <ent type='ORG'>CIC</ent>, the <ent type='ORG'>OSS</ent>, and <ent type='ORG'>the Office</ent> of Policy Coordination within the
State Department. </p>

<p> Over the past fifty years, it is now documented, these <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>nized
fugitive <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> war criminals have been involved in, and in many cases
in charge of, many U.S. government covert operations --
international weapons smuggling, drug cartels, <ent type='ORG'>Central</ent> <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n
death squads, right wing anti-<ent type='NORP'>communist</ent> dictatorships, LSD mind
control experiments -- the <ent type='NORP'>Republican</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Nation</ent>al Committee's Ethnic
Heritage Councils, and the Presidential campaigns of <ent type='PERSON'>Richard Nixon</ent>,
Ronald Reagan, and <ent type='PERSON'>George</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent>. </p>

<p> THE GEHLEN ORGANIZATION </p>

<p> Probably the most influential <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> to come to work for <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent>
States intelligence agencies during <ent type='EVENT'>the Cold War</ent> was named <ent type='PERSON'>Gehlen</ent>. </p>

<p> "Reinhard <ent type='PERSON'>Gehlen</ent>," writes author <ent type='PERSON'>Christopher Simpson</ent>, "Hitler's
most senior military intelligence officer on the eastern front, had
begun planning his surrender to <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States at least as early
as the fall of 1944." Of "several hundred" high-ranking <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>
officers who switched sides at the end of <ent type='EVENT'>World War</ent> II, <ent type='PERSON'>Gehlen</ent>
"proved to be the most important of them all. </p>

<p> "In early March 1945 <ent type='PERSON'>Gehlen</ent> and a small group of his most senior
officers carefully microfilmed the vast holdings on the <ent type='GPE'>USSR</ent> in the
. . . military intelligence section of the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> army's general
staff. They packed the film in watertight steel drums and secretly
buried it in remote mountain meadows scattered through the <ent type='GPE'>Austria</ent>n
<ent type='LOC'>Alps</ent>. Then, on May 22, 1945, <ent type='PERSON'>Gehlen</ent> and his top aides surrendered to
an <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n Counter-intelligence Corps [<ent type='ORG'>CIC</ent>] team." (18) </p>

<p> According to Tetens: ". . . [<ent type='PERSON'>Gehlen</ent>] immediately asked for an
interview with the commanding officer . . ." and offered <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent>
States "his intelligence staff, spy apparatus, and the priceless
files for future service." </p>

<p> <ent type='PERSON'>Gehlen</ent> was sent to <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent> and his offer was taken. "The
<ent type='ORG'>Pentagon</ent>-<ent type='PERSON'>Gehlen</ent> agreement," states Tetens, "in practice guaranteed
the continuation of the all-important <ent type='ORG'>Abwehr</ent> division of the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>
General Staff. Hundreds of <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> army and SS officers were quietly
released from internment camps and joined Gehlen's headquarters in
<ent type='LOC'>the Spessart Mountains</ent> in central <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent>. When the staff had grown
to three thousand men, the Bureau <ent type='PERSON'>Gehlen</ent> opened a closely guarded
twenty-five-acre compound near <ent type='GPE'>Pullach</ent>, south of <ent type='GPE'>Munich</ent>, operating
under the innocent name of the <ent type='LOC'>South</ent> <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> Industrial Development
Organization. . . . </p>

<p> "Within a few years the <ent type='PERSON'>Gehlen</ent> apparatus had grown by leaps and
bounds. In the early fifties it was estimated that the organization
employed up to 4000 intelligence specialists in <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent>, mainly
former army and SS officers, and that more than 4000 V-men
(undercover agents) were active throughout the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent>-bloc
countries. Gehlen's spy network stretches from <ent type='GPE'>Korea</ent> to <ent type='GPE'>Cairo</ent>, from
<ent type='LOC'>Siberia</ent> to Santiago de <ent type='GPE'>Chile</ent>. . . . When <ent type='GPE'>the Federal Republic</ent> [of
<ent type='ORG'>West</ent> <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent>] became a sovereign state in 1955, the Bureau <ent type='PERSON'>Gehlen</ent>
was openly recognized as the official intelligence arm of the <ent type='GPE'>Bonn</ent>
government." (19) </p>

<p> How important was the <ent type='PERSON'>Gehlen</ent> Org, as it became known, to the
history of <ent type='EVENT'>the Cold War</ent>? Simpson's research documents that it was
perhaps the most significant element of all:</p>

<p> ". . . . The Org became the most important eyes and ears for U.S.
intelligence inside the closed societies of the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> bloc. 'In
1946 [U.S.] intelligence files on the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> Union were virtually
empty,' says <ent type='PERSON'>Harry</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Rositzke</ent>, the CIA's former chief of espionage
inside the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> Union. '. . . . <ent type='PERSON'>Rositzke</ent> worked closely with
<ent type='PERSON'>Gehlen</ent> during the formative years of the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> and credits Gehlen's
organization with playing a "primary role" in filling the empty file
folders during that period. . . .' </p>

<p> "'<ent type='PERSON'>Gehlen</ent> had to make his money by creating a threat that we were
afraid of,' says <ent type='PERSON'>Victor Marchetti</ent>, formerly the CIA's chief analyst
of <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> strategic war plans and capabilities, 'so we would give
him more money to tell us about it.' He continues: 'In my opinion,
the <ent type='PERSON'>Gehlen</ent> Organization provided nothing worthwhile for the
understanding or estimating <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> military or political
capabilities in <ent type='ORG'>Eastern</ent> Europe or anywhere else.' Employing <ent type='PERSON'>Gehlen</ent>
was 'a waste of time, money, and effort, except that maybe he had
some CI [counter-intelligence] value, because practically everybody
in his organization was sucking off both tits.'" (20) </p>

<p> By 'sucking off both tits' <ent type='ORG'>Marchetti</ent> is referring to the fact that
Gehlen's elaborate operation was penetrated by <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> spies at the
very time it was our most important source of intelligence upon
which <ent type='EVENT'>the Cold War</ent> was based. In fact, the <ent type='NORP'>Communists</ent> had
infiltrated <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> intelligence long before <ent type='PERSON'>Gehlen</ent> switched sides. </p>

<p> TRIPLE CR<ent type='ORG'>OSS</ent> </p>

<p> "In each generation," write <ent type='PERSON'>Aarons</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>Loftus</ent>,"<ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> intelligence
created 'anti-<ent type='NORP'>Communist</ent>' emigre front groups, ostensibly to foment
revolution and topple <ent type='NORP'>Bolshevism</ent>. The front groups attracted support
from the <ent type='ORG'>West</ent>. Considerable financial assistance was supplied and
close ties forged with various <ent type='ORG'>West</ent>ern intelligence services. This
enabled the <ent type='NORP'>Communist</ent> double agents running the front groups to co-opt the legitimate emigre opposition, splinter their leadership and
provoke them into premature and poorly organized rebellions which
were easily defeated. More importantly, the false front groups were
a vehicle for long-term <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> penetration of <ent type='ORG'>West</ent>ern society. . .
." </p>

<p> The authors identify one of these groups as the <ent type='ORG'>Narodny</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Trudovoi</ent>
Soyuz (<ent type='ORG'>NTS</ent>), or <ent type='ORG'>the People</ent>'s Labour Alliance. The <ent type='ORG'>NTS</ent> represented
itself as a group of anti-<ent type='NORP'>communist</ent> "moles" inside the <ent type='ORG'>Kremlin</ent> and,
in the 1920s, recruited a <ent type='NORP'>Communist</ent> agent named Prince Anton
Vasilevich <ent type='NORP'>Turkel</ent>. <ent type='NORP'>Turkel</ent>, who actually worked for <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> Military
intelligence (<ent type='ORG'>GRU</ent>), went on to penetrate <ent type='NORP'>French</ent>, <ent type='NORP'>Japanese</ent>, <ent type='NORP'>Italian</ent>,
<ent type='NORP'>British</ent>, <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>, and even the <ent type='ORG'>Vatican</ent> intelligence services before
the end of <ent type='EVENT'>World War</ent> II. </p>

<p> "After <ent type='EVENT'>World War</ent> II, <ent type='NORP'>Turkel</ent> worked for <ent type='ORG'>West</ent> <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> intelligence
(the <ent type='PERSON'>Gehlen</ent> Org), collaborated with many of the spy services of
<ent type='ORG'>NATO</ent>, including the <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n Military Intelligence Service (MIS -
for offensive intelligence), the US <ent type='ORG'>Army</ent> Counter Intelligence Corps
(<ent type='ORG'>CIC</ent> - for defensive purposes), the ultra-secret State Department
Office of Policy Co-ordination and <ent type='ORG'>the Central Intelligence Agency</ent>.
. ." (21) </p>

<p> "Just before <ent type='EVENT'>World War</ent> II began," according to the authors, "an
<ent type='GPE'>Austria</ent>n Jew named <ent type='PERSON'>Richard Kauder</ent> created a secret intelligence
network, code named <ent type='ORG'>MAX</ent>." <ent type='ORG'>Kauder</ent>, using the name of [<ent type='PERSON'>Max</ent>] Klatt -
Turkel's intelligence chief ["Unholy <ent type='ORG'>Trinity</ent>," <ent type='PERSON'>Aarons</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>Loftus</ent>, p.
166] - "worked exclusively for Admiral <ent type='PERSON'>Wilhelm Canaris</ent>, the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>
spy chief who collaborated with the <ent type='ORG'>Vatican</ent> and the <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> to
topple <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> during <ent type='ORG'>the war</ent> [the group known as the Black
Orchestra]." </p>

<p> The <ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent> thought the <ent type='PERSON'>Max</ent> network was made up of "so-called <ent type='NORP'>Fascist</ent>
<ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>" who "were willing to spy against the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> Union, not for the
glory of the Third <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent> but to save themselves and their families
from the concentration camps." The <ent type='PERSON'>Max</ent> network was supposed to have
had "the only communication link to a secret network of '<ent type='ORG'>White</ent>'
<ent type='NORP'>Russian</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Fascist</ent>s inside the <ent type='ORG'>Kremlin</ent> [Turkel's <ent type='ORG'>NTS</ent>], who had
supposedly infiltrated Stalin's military headquarters prior to World
War II." But, the authors continue, "the <ent type='PERSON'>Max</ent> network was not made up
of <ent type='NORP'>Fascist</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>. They were, in fact, <ent type='NORP'>Communist</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> who risked their
lives inside the heart of the Third Reich's intelligence service." </p>

<p> The <ent type='PERSON'>Max</ent> network actually misled the <ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent>, feeding them false
intelligence on the capabilities and intentions of the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> Union,
leading "the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> divisions into a series of death traps on the
<ent type='ORG'>Eastern</ent> front." The <ent type='PERSON'>Max</ent> double-agents were responsible for the <ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent>
defeats at <ent type='PERSON'>Stalin</ent>grad, "the giant battle of Kursk where Hitler's
tank divisions were slaughtered. The final sting," continue the
authors, "was to mislead <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> into believing that the Red army
was on the verge of collapse in 1944, when in fact the <ent type='NORP'>Soviets</ent> were
preparing for the most massive onslaught of <ent type='ORG'>the war</ent>. </p>

<p> "It would not be an exaggeration to say that the '<ent type='NORP'>Fascist</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>' of
the <ent type='PERSON'>Max</ent> network did more to defeat the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> army than all the
<ent type='ORG'>West</ent>ern intelligence services combined. Seventy percent of all
Hitler's divisions were destroyed on the <ent type='ORG'>Eastern</ent> front, largely as a
result of the misleading intelligence supplied by <ent type='PERSON'>Max</ent>." (22) </p>

<p> When <ent type='PERSON'>Gehlen</ent> was recruited by <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States, <ent type='PERSON'>Allen</ent> <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent>
ordered the ex-<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> spymaster to "revive the <ent type='PERSON'>Max</ent> network." <ent type='PERSON'>Gehlen</ent>
already had plans to do just that, intending "to make Turkel's <ent type='PERSON'>Max</ent>
network the centerpiece of his new <ent type='ORG'>West</ent> <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> intelligence agency.
As soon as a <ent type='NORP'>Republican</ent> president was elected in <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States,
<ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent> intended to take over the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> and make <ent type='PERSON'>Gehlen</ent> and <ent type='NORP'>Turkel</ent> the
heart of his anti-<ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> network. The <ent type='NORP'>Soviets</ent>, of course, were
delighted as they watched <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Gehlen</ent> attempt to plant a
<ent type='NORP'>Communist</ent> spy ring in the heart of <ent type='ORG'>West</ent>ern intelligence. . . .</p>

<p> ". . . [E]ventually, in 1956, the <ent type='ORG'>Allies</ent> decided that the whole
thing had been a giant <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent>-controlled operation. Dozens of
operations, hundreds of agents, thousands of innocent civilians had
been betrayed. . . . </p>

<p> ". . . [T]hree years after <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent> became head of <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> in 1953, his
pet '<ent type='NORP'>Fascist</ent>,' <ent type='NORP'>Turkel</ent>, broadcast the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> codes to start the
Hungarian uprising prematurely. Thousands of innocent Hungarians
rushed on to the streets of <ent type='GPE'>Budapest</ent> to start the revolution.
Instead of <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n paratroopers dropping supplies, they found
<ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> tanks waiting in the suburbs."</p>

<p> By 1959, the collapse of Dulles's spy network was almost total:
"U.S. Military Intelligence admitted to the <ent type='ORG'>Nation</ent>al Security
Council that it did not have a single network of couriers or safe
houses left in <ent type='NORP'>Communist</ent> territory, apart from East <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent>.
Dulles's <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> 'freedom fighters' had sold him out." (23) </p>

<p> COLD WARRIORS </p>

<p> It was <ent type='PERSON'>Harry</ent> Rositze who best described the attitude of <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent>
States military-intelligence establishment after the end of World
War II: "Any bastard as long as he was anti-<ent type='NORP'>Communist</ent>." Rositze, the
"former head of secret operations inside the <ent type='GPE'>USSR</ent>" for the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>, was
correct. (24) </p>

<p> We have seen that many <ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent> - including those who committed
atrocities - returned to positions of power and influence inside
<ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> after <ent type='ORG'>the war</ent>. Unknown until fairly recently was the extent
of <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> recruitment by U.S. intelligence agencies and political
organizations, in the 1940s and 1950s. </p>

<p> Perhaps the most publicized program of <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> recruitment is that of
Project Paperclip, which involved the collection of <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> rocket
scientists and facilities, all of which were later incorporated into
the U.S. Space Program. <ent type='PERSON'>Klaus Barbie</ent>'s employment by the U.S. State
Department in the 1940s is another well-known incident. <ent type='PERSON'>Barbie</ent>, head
of the <ent type='ORG'>Gestapo</ent> in <ent type='PERSON'>Lyons</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>France</ent>, was known as the "<ent type='PERSON'>Butcher</ent> of <ent type='PERSON'>Lyons</ent>"
and was sought by the <ent type='NORP'>French</ent> Government for atrocities committed
against <ent type='NORP'>French</ent> Resistance fighters captured by the <ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent>. <ent type='PERSON'>Barbie</ent> was
recruited as a U.S. intelligence "asset" in 1947 by one branch of
the State Department's Counter-intelligence Corps (<ent type='ORG'>CIC</ent>), while
another branch, the Operation Selection Board, a joint U.S./<ent type='NORP'>British</ent>
project, was trying to put him in prison for war crimes. </p>

<p> Eventually, according to <ent type='PERSON'>Aarons</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>Loftus</ent>, "Barbie's employment
(and protection) by the <ent type='NORP'>Americans</ent> began to reach <ent type='NORP'>French</ent> newspapers
and politicians at least as early as 1948. They, in turn brought
increasing pressure on the U.S. government through publicity and
eventually through official notes requesting Barbie's extradition
from <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent>. That, in the final analysis, is why the <ent type='ORG'>CIC</ent> chose to
provide <ent type='PERSON'>Barbie</ent> with a new identity and safe passage to <ent type='GPE'>Argentina</ent> in
1951, while thousands of other ex-<ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent> who had been 'of interest'
to the <ent type='ORG'>CIC</ent> at one time or another have simply lived out their lives
in <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent>. If the <ent type='ORG'>CIC</ent> had dumped <ent type='PERSON'>Barbie</ent> when the <ent type='NORP'>French</ent> government
began requesting his extradition, he would have had plenty of
compromising things to say about the <ent type='ORG'>CIC</ent>. . ." (25) </p>

<p> But when <ent type='PERSON'>Barbie</ent> was eventually captured by <ent type='NORP'>Bolivian</ent> authorities in
the early 1980s, and returned to <ent type='GPE'>France</ent> to face charges of war
crimes, the U.S. government was forced to conduct an investigation
into the <ent type='PERSON'>Barbie</ent> affair. The official position? ". . . [T]his
investigation concluded that <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States had indeed protected
<ent type='PERSON'>Barbie</ent> in Europe and engineered his escape but that <ent type='PERSON'>Barbie</ent> was the
only such <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> who had been assisted in this fashion." (26) </p>

<p> As documented previously, this statement was false. Hundreds,
perhaps thousands, of <ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent> were employed by the several U.S.
agencies, from the <ent type='ORG'>CIC</ent> to the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>, and used in covert operations
overseas, as our first line of defense against Communism. Others,
equally as guilty of wartime atrocities, were brought into the
United States for domestic political purposes. This aspect of the
U.S.-<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> connection is well-documented, and deserves closer
attention by the mainstream press. </p>

<p> One of the first researchers to reveal the connections between the
U.S. government and the <ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent>, was a lady named <ent type='PERSON'><ent type='PERSON'>Mae</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Brussell</ent></ent> of
<ent type='GPE'>Carmel</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>California</ent>. Her career as a conspiracy researcher and host
of the weekly radio program "<ent type='ORG'>World Watchers International</ent>" began
with the <ent type='PERSON'>Kennedy</ent> assassination. "In ferreting out every morsel from
the <ent type='PERSON'>Warren</ent> Report," writes <ent type='PERSON'>Jonathan Vankin</ent>, author of the book
"Conspiracies, Cover-ups and Crimes," "supplementing her research
with untold amounts of reading from the '<ent type='GPE'>New York</ent> Times' to 'Soldier
of Fortune,' <ent type='ORG'>Brussell</ent> discovered not merely a conspiracy of a few
renegade <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> agents, <ent type='ORG'>Mafiosi</ent>, and <ent type='PERSON'>Castro</ent> haters behind Kennedy's
death, but a vast, invisible institutional structure layered into
the very fabric of the U.S. political system.</p>

<p> "Comprising the government within a government were not just spies,
gangsters, and <ent type='NORP'>Cubans</ent>, but <ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent>. <ent type='PERSON'>Mae</ent> found that many of the
commission witnesses -- whose testimony established <ent type='PERSON'>Oswald</ent> as a lone
nut' -- had never even spoken to <ent type='PERSON'>Oswald</ent>, or knew him only slightly.
The bulk of them were <ent type='ORG'>White</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Russian</ent> emigres living in <ent type='GPE'>Dallas</ent>.
Extreme in their anti-Communism, they were often affiliated with
groups set up by the SS in <ent type='EVENT'>World War</ent> II -- <ent type='ORG'>Eastern</ent> European ethnic
armies used by the <ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent> to carry out their dirtiest work. </p>

<p> "<ent type='ORG'>Brussell</ent> also discovered an episode from history rarely reported
in the media, and not often taught in universities. Those same
collaborationist groups were absorbed by United States intelligence
agencies. They hooked up with the spy net of <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> General Reinhard
<ent type='PERSON'>Gehlen</ent>, Hitler's <ent type='ORG'>Eastern</ent> Front espionage chief."</p>

<p> "'This is a story of how key <ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent> . . . anticipated military
disaster and laid plans to transplant <ent type='NORP'>nazism</ent>, intact but disguised,
in havens in the <ent type='ORG'>West</ent>,' wrote <ent type='PERSON'><ent type='PERSON'>Mae</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Brussell</ent></ent> in 1983. She didn't
author too many articles, but this one, 'The <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> Connection to the
<ent type='PERSON'>John</ent> F. <ent type='PERSON'>Kennedy</ent> Assassination' (in 'The Rebel,' a short-lived
political magazine published by '<ent type='ORG'>Hustler</ent>' impresario <ent type='PERSON'>Larry Flynt</ent>),
was definitive, albeit convoluted. </p>

<p> "'It is a story that climaxes in <ent type='GPE'>Dallas</ent> on November 22, 1963, when
<ent type='PERSON'>John</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Kennedy</ent> was struck down,' Brussell's article continued. 'And it
is a story with an aftermath -- America's slide to the brink of
Fascism.'" </p>

<p> <ent type='PERSON'><ent type='PERSON'>Mae</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Brussell</ent></ent> quit broadcasting her radio show in Spring of 1988,
after receiving a death threat from a "man who is said to have
identified himself as 'a fascist and proud of it.'" </p>

<p> The last project she worked on, before her death from cancer on
October 3, 1988, writes the author, "was a study of Satanic cults --
within the U.S. military. The hidden fascist oligarchy had
progressed far beyond the need for patsies like <ent type='PERSON'>Oswald</ent>. They were
now able, <ent type='ORG'>Brussell</ent> asserted, to hypnotically program assassins. </p>

<p> "Satanic cults are the state of the art in brainwashing. With
drugs, sex, and violence, they strip any semblance of moral thought.
They are perfect for use in creating killers. The United States
military, <ent type='ORG'>Brussell</ent> found, was using them." (27) </p>

<p> NOTES: THE NEW WORLD (<ent type='ORG'>DIS</ent>)ORDER</p>

<p> 1.One Thousand <ent type='NORP'>Americans</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>George</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Seldes</ent>, p. 5-6 2.The Secret War
Against the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Loftus</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Aarons</ent>, p. 71 3.<ent type='PERSON'>Ibid</ent>., pp. 73-74
4.<ent type='PERSON'>Ibid</ent>., pp. 75-76 5.<ent type='PERSON'>Ibid</ent>., p. 77 6.<ent type='PERSON'>Ibid</ent>., p. 78 7.<ent type='PERSON'>Ibid</ent>., pp. 79-80
8.<ent type='PERSON'>Ibid</ent>., pp. 82-83 9.<ent type='PERSON'>Ibid</ent>., pp. 84-85 10.<ent type='PERSON'>Ibid</ent>., pp. 85-86 11.Tragedy
and Hope, Prof. Carrol Quigley, p. 827 12.Secret War Against the
<ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, pp. 100-102 13.The <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n Establishment, <ent type='PERSON'>Leonard</ent> and Mark
Silk, p. 249 14.The New <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> and the Old <ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent>, T.H. Tetens, pp.
99-102 15.Blowback: America's recruitment of <ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent> and its effects
on <ent type='EVENT'>the Cold War</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Christopher Simpson</ent>, pp. 191-192 16.The New <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent>
and the Old <ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent>, p. 103 17.<ent type='PERSON'>Ibid</ent>., pp. 112-113 18.Blowback, pp. 40-41 19.The New <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> and the Old <ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent>, pp. 42-43 20.Blowback, pp.
54-55 21.Unholy <ent type='ORG'>Trinity</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Mark Aarons</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>John</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Loftus</ent>, pp. 151-152
22.<ent type='EVENT'>The Secret War Against</ent> the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, pp. 135-136 23.<ent type='PERSON'>Ibid</ent>., pp. 151-152 24.Blowback, p. 159 25.<ent type='PERSON'>Ibid</ent>., pp. 187-189 26.<ent type='PERSON'>Ibid</ent>., pp. 192-193
27.Conspiracies, Cover-ups and Crimes, <ent type='PERSON'>Jonathan Vankin</ent>, pp. 101-104</p>

<p> RICHARD MILHOUSE <ent type='PERSON'>NIXON</ent> </p>

<p> In this section we will explore the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> connections of Richard
<ent type='PERSON'>Nixon</ent>. To do so we must return to the years just after the end of
<ent type='EVENT'>World War</ent> II and, of course, a man named <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent>. </p>

<p> The irony of Nixon's political career ending with a cover-up can
only be appreciated with the knowledge that this turbulent career
also began with one. <ent type='ORG'>Loftus</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Aarons</ent> state that: </p>

<p> "According to several of our sources among the 'old spies,' Richard
Nixon's political career began in 1945, when he was the <ent type='ORG'>navy</ent> officer
temporarily assigned to review . . . captured <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> documents." The
documents in question revealed <ent type='ORG'>the war</ent>time record of Karl Blessing,
"former <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent>sbank officer and then head of the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> oil cartel,
<ent type='GPE'>Kontinentale</ent> Ol A.G. '<ent type='PERSON'>Konti</ent>' was in partnership with Dulles's
principal <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> client, I.G. <ent type='ORG'>Farben</ent>. Both companies had despicable
records regarding their treatment of <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> during the <ent type='EVENT'>Holocaust</ent>.
After <ent type='ORG'>the war</ent> <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent> not only 'lost' Blessings <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> party records,
but he helped peddle a false biography in the ever-gullible 'New
York Times.'" </p>

<p> The authors' sources reveal that not only did <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent> help cover up
his <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> client's record, he "personally vouched for Blessing as an
anti-<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> in order to protect continued control of <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> oil
interests in <ent type='LOC'>the Middle East</ent>. Blessing's <ent type='PERSON'>Konti</ent> was the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> link to
<ent type='PERSON'>Iben Saud</ent> [King of Saudi <ent type='NORP'>Arab</ent>ia] and <ent type='ORG'>Aramco</ent> [the <ent type='NORP'>Arab</ent>ian-<ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n
Oil Company]. If Blessing went down, he could have taken a lot of
people with him, including <ent type='PERSON'>Allen</ent> <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent>. The cover-up worked, except
that U.S. <ent type='ORG'>Naval Intelligence</ent> scrutinized a set of the captured <ent type='PERSON'>Konti</ent>
records." </p>

<p> According to the "old spies," <ent type='PERSON'>Allen</ent> <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent> made a deal with the
young <ent type='ORG'>navy</ent> officer who was reviewing the <ent type='PERSON'>Konti</ent> files - Richard
<ent type='PERSON'>Nixon</ent>. <ent type='PERSON'>Nixon</ent> would help <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent> bury the <ent type='PERSON'>Konti</ent> files. In return,
<ent type='PERSON'>Allen</ent> <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent> "arranged to finance [Nixon's] first congressional
campaign against <ent type='PERSON'>Jerry</ent> Voorhis." (1) </p>

<p> Dulles's support for <ent type='PERSON'>Nixon</ent> paid off in 1947 when, as the freshman
congressman from <ent type='GPE'>California</ent>, he "saved <ent type='PERSON'>John</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Foster</ent> <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent>
considerable embarrassment by privately pointing out that
confidential government files showed that one of Foster's foundation
employees, <ent type='PERSON'>Alger Hiss</ent>, was allegedly a <ent type='NORP'>Communist</ent>. The <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent>
brothers took <ent type='PERSON'>Nixon</ent> under their wing and escorted him on a tour of
<ent type='NORP'>Fascist</ent> 'freedom fighter' operations in <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent>, apparently in
anticipation that the young congressman would be useful after Dewey
became president." [He would be useful anyway, despite the fact that
incumbent President <ent type='PERSON'>Truman</ent> won reelection in 1948, defeating Dewey.]
(2) </p>

<p> After Truman's victory, write the authors, "<ent type='PERSON'>Nixon</ent> became <ent type='PERSON'>Allen</ent>
Dulles's mouthpiece in <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>. Both he and Senator Joseph <ent type='PERSON'>McCarthy</ent>
received volumes of classified information to support the charge
that the <ent type='PERSON'>Truman</ent> administration was filled with 'pinkos.' When
<ent type='PERSON'>McCarthy</ent> went too far in his <ent type='NORP'>Communist</ent> investigations, it was <ent type='PERSON'>Nixon</ent>
who worked with his next-door neighbor, <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> director <ent type='PERSON'>Bedell Smith</ent>,
to steer the investigations away from the intelligence community.</p>

<p> "The <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> was grateful for Nixon's assistance, but did not know the
reason for it. <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent> had been recruiting <ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent> under the cover of
the State Department's Office of Policy Coordination, whose chief,
<ent type='PERSON'>Frank Wisner</ent>, had systematically recruited the <ent type='ORG'>Eastern</ent> European
emigre networks that had worked first for the SS, then the <ent type='NORP'>British</ent>,
and finally <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent>. </p>

<p> "The <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> did not know it, but <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent> was bringing them to the
United States less for intelligence purposes than for political
advantage. The <ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent>' job quickly became to get out the vote for the
<ent type='NORP'>Republican</ent>s. One <ent type='NORP'>Israeli</ent> intelligence officer joked that when <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent>
used the phrase 'Never Again,' he was not talking about the
<ent type='EVENT'>Holocaust</ent> but about Dewey's narrow loss to <ent type='PERSON'>Truman</ent>. In the eyes of
the <ent type='NORP'>Israeli</ent>s, <ent type='PERSON'>Allen</ent> <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent> was the demon who infected <ent type='ORG'>West</ent>ern
intelligence with <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> recruits. </p>

<p> "In preparation for the 1952 <ent type='PERSON'>Eisenhower</ent>-<ent type='PERSON'>Nixon</ent> campaign, the
<ent type='NORP'>Republican</ent>s formed an <ent type='ORG'>Ethnic Division</ent>, which, to put it bluntly,
recruited the 'displaced <ent type='NORP'>Fascist</ent>s' who arrived in <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States
after <ent type='EVENT'>World War</ent> II. Like similar migrant organizations in several
<ent type='ORG'>West</ent>ern countries, the <ent type='ORG'>Ethnic Division</ent> attracted a significant
number of <ent type='ORG'>Central</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>Eastern</ent> European <ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent>, who had been recruited
by the SS as political and police leaders during the <ent type='EVENT'>Holocaust</ent>.
These <ent type='NORP'>Fascist</ent> emigres supported the <ent type='PERSON'>Eisenhower</ent>-<ent type='PERSON'>Nixon</ent> 'liberation'
policy as the quickest means of getting back into power in their
former homelands and made a significant contribution 'in its first
operation (1951/1952).'"</p>

<p> The authors point out that "over the years the <ent type='NORP'>Democrats</ent> had
acquired one or two <ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent> of their own, such as <ent type='PERSON'>Tscherim Soobzokov</ent>,
a former member of <ent type='ORG'>the Caucasian</ent> SS who worked as a party boss in
<ent type='GPE'>New Jersey</ent>. But in 90 percent of the cases, the members of Hitler's
political organization went to the <ent type='NORP'>Republican</ent>s. In fact, from the
very beginning, the word had been put around among <ent type='ORG'>Eastern</ent> European
<ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent> that <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Nixon</ent> were the men to see, especially if you
were a rich <ent type='NORP'>Fascist</ent> . . ." (3) </p>

<p> This relationship between <ent type='PERSON'>Richard Nixon</ent> and the <ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent> developed
because both he and <ent type='PERSON'>Allen</ent> <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent> "blamed Governor Dewey's razor-thin
loss to <ent type='PERSON'>Truman</ent> in the 1948 presidential election on the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> vote.
When [<ent type='PERSON'>Nixon</ent>] became Eisenhower's vice president in 1952, <ent type='PERSON'>Nixon</ent> was
determined to build his own ethnic base.</p>

<p> "Vice President Nixon's secret political war of <ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent> against <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>
in <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n politics was never investigated at the time. The foreign
language-speaking <ent type='NORP'>Croat</ent>ian and other <ent type='NORP'>Fascist</ent> emigre groups had a
ready-made network for contacting and mobilizing the <ent type='ORG'>Eastern</ent>
European ethnic bloc. There is a very high correlation between <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>
domestic subsidies to <ent type='NORP'>Fascist</ent> 'freedom fighters' during the 1950s
and the leadership of the <ent type='NORP'>Republican</ent> party's ethnic campaign groups.
The motive for under-the-table financing was clear: <ent type='PERSON'>Nixon</ent> used <ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent>
to offset the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> vote for the <ent type='NORP'>Democrats</ent>. </p>

<p> "In 1952 <ent type='PERSON'>Nixon</ent> had formed an <ent type='ORG'>Ethnic Division</ent> within the <ent type='NORP'>Republican</ent>
<ent type='ORG'>Nation</ent>al Committee. 'Displaced <ent type='NORP'>Fascist</ent>s, hoping to be returned to
power by an <ent type='PERSON'>Eisenhower</ent>-<ent type='PERSON'>Nixon</ent> "liberation" policy signed on' with the
committee. In 1953, when <ent type='NORP'>Republican</ent>s were in office, the immigration
laws were changed to admit <ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent>, even members of the SS. They
flooded into the country. <ent type='PERSON'>Nixon</ent> himself oversaw the new immigration
program. As vice president, he even received <ent type='ORG'>Eastern</ent> European
<ent type='NORP'>Fascist</ent>s in <ent type='ORG'>the <ent type='ORG'>White</ent> <ent type='ORG'>House</ent></ent>. After a long, long journey, the
<ent type='NORP'>Croat</ent>ian <ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent> had found a new home in <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States, where they
reestablished their networks. </p>

<p> "In 1968 <ent type='PERSON'>Nixon</ent> promised that if he won the presidential election,
he would create a permanent ethnic council within the <ent type='NORP'>Republican</ent>
party. Previously the <ent type='ORG'>Ethnic Division</ent> was allowed to surface only
during presidential campaigns. Nixon's promise was carried out after
the 1972 election, during [<ent type='PERSON'>George</ent>] Bush's tenure as chairman of the
<ent type='NORP'>Republican</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Nation</ent>al Committee. The <ent type='NORP'>Croat</ent>ian Ustashis became an
integral part of the campaign structure of <ent type='NORP'>Republican</ent> politics,
along with several other <ent type='NORP'>Fascist</ent> organizations." (4)</p>

<p> The authors describe Nixon's pro-<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> activities in no uncertain
terms: "<ent type='PERSON'>Nixon</ent> himself personally recruited ex-<ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent> for his 1968
presidential campaign. Moreover, Vice President <ent type='PERSON'>Nixon</ent> became the
point man for the <ent type='PERSON'>Eisenhower</ent> administration on covert operations and
personally supervised <ent type='PERSON'>Allen</ent> Dulles's projects while <ent type='PERSON'>Ike</ent> was ill in
1956 and 1957." (5) </p>

<p> One of the <ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent> recruited by candidate <ent type='PERSON'>Nixon</ent> was <ent type='PERSON'>Laszlo Pasztor</ent>,
described by <ent type='PERSON'>Aarons</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>Loftus</ent> as "the founding chair of Nixon's
<ent type='NORP'>Republican</ent> Heritage Groups council" who, "during <ent type='EVENT'>World War</ent> II . . .
was a diplomat in <ent type='GPE'>Berlin</ent> representing the <ent type='ORG'>Arrow Cross</ent> government of
<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> Hungary, which supervised the extermination of the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent>
population.</p>

<p> "[A]fter <ent type='PERSON'>Nixon</ent> won [the 1968 Presidential Election], he approved
Pasztor's appointment as chief organizer of the ethnic council. Not
surprisingly, Pasztor's 'choices for filling emigre slots as the
council was being formed included various <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> collaborationist
organizations.' The former <ent type='NORP'>Fascist</ent>s were coming out of the closet in
droves. </p>

<p> "The policy of the <ent type='PERSON'>Nixon</ent> <ent type='ORG'>White</ent> <ent type='ORG'>House</ent> was an 'open door' for emigre
<ent type='NORP'>Fascist</ent>s, and through the door came such guests as <ent type='PERSON'>Ivan Docheff</ent>,
head of the Bulgarian <ent type='ORG'>Nation</ent>al Front and chairman of the <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n
Friends of the Anti-Bolshevik Bloc of <ent type='ORG'>Nation</ent>s (ABN). . . . an
organization dominated by war criminals and fugitive <ent type='NORP'>Fascist</ent>s. Yet
<ent type='PERSON'>Nixon</ent> welcomed them with open arms and even had <ent type='ORG'>Docheff</ent> to breakfast
for a prayer meeting to celebrate Captive <ent type='ORG'>Nation</ent>s Week." (6) </p>

<p> "During Nixon's 'Four More Years' campaign in 1971-1972, Laszlo
<ent type='ORG'>Pasztor</ent> again played a key role in marshaling the ethnic vote. No
longer a marginal player on the fringes, now he held a key position
as the <ent type='NORP'>Republican</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Nation</ent>al Committee's nationalities director. . . . </p>

<p> "The <ent type='NORP'>Republican</ent> leadership cannot claim ignorance as a defense.
[Syndicated Columnist <ent type='PERSON'>Jack</ent>] Anderson's famous expose of Nixon's
<ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent> appeared in 'The <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent> Post' at the same time as the
November 1971 convention. Among those mentioned was <ent type='PERSON'>Laszlo Pasztor</ent>,
'the industrious head of the <ent type='ORG'>GOP</ent> ethnic groups, [who] was never
asked about his wartime activities in Hungary by the four <ent type='ORG'>GOP</ent>
officials who interviewed him for his job.' It was too embarrassing
for <ent type='PERSON'>Nixon</ent> to admit that <ent type='ORG'>Pasztor</ent> had been a ranking member of a
<ent type='NORP'>Fascist</ent> government at war with <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States. </p>

<p> ". . . . It is one thing to promote obscure <ent type='ORG'>Eastern</ent> European
<ent type='NORP'>Fascist</ent> movements in the <ent type='NORP'>Republican</ent> party. It is quite another to
let the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent> have a major influence. After 1953, the
<ent type='NORP'>Republican</ent> administration changed the rules, and even members of the
Waffen SS could immigrate to <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States as long as they
claimed only to have fought the <ent type='NORP'>Communists</ent> on the <ent type='ORG'>Eastern</ent> Front."
(7)</p>

<p> The <ent type='NORP'>Republican</ent>/<ent type='PERSON'>Nixon</ent> attraction to <ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent>m was also observed by
<ent type='PERSON'>Robert</ent> J. <ent type='PERSON'>Groden</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Harrison Edward Livingstone</ent>, authors of the
book, "High Treason," dealing with the <ent type='PERSON'>Kennedy</ent> Assassination. <ent type='PERSON'>Groden</ent>
and <ent type='PERSON'>Livingstone</ent> write: "<ent type='PERSON'>Nixon</ent> surrounded himself with what was known
as the <ent type='GPE'>Berlin</ent> Wall, a long succession of advisors with <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>ic
names: We recall at the top of his '<ent type='NORP'>German</ent> General Staff' as it was
also known, <ent type='ORG'>Haldeman</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Erlichman</ent>, Krogh, Kliendienst, <ent type='PERSON'>Kissinger</ent> (the
<ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent>s' emissary) and many others. </p>

<p> "The selection of <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> names was no accident. Many of the
brighter staff people close to <ent type='PERSON'>Nixon</ent> came to him from <ent type='ORG'>the University</ent>
of <ent type='NORP'>Southern</ent> <ent type='GPE'>California</ent>, and <ent type='ORG'>the University</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>California</ent> at Los
Angeles, where there were fraternities that kept alive the vision of
a new <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent>. <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> has for a long time harbored this dark side of
its character, one of violence and the Valhalla of <ent type='PERSON'>Wagner</ent> and
<ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent>. </p>

<p> "But <ent type='PERSON'>Gordon Liddy</ent> was the one in whose mind '<ent type='ORG'>Triumph</ent> of the Will'
was the most alive. Some of these men would watch the great <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>
propaganda films in the basement of <ent type='ORG'>the <ent type='ORG'>White</ent> <ent type='ORG'>House</ent></ent> until all hours
of the night, and drink, in fact, get drunk with their power, with
blind ambition, as one of them wrote." (8) </p>

<p> "According to several of our sources in the intelligence community
who were in a position to know," continue <ent type='ORG'>Loftus</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Aarons</ent>, "the
secret rosters of the <ent type='NORP'>Republican</ent> party's <ent type='ORG'>Nation</ent>alities Council read
like a Who's Who of <ent type='NORP'>Fascist</ent> fugitives. The Republican's <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>
connection is the darkest secret of the <ent type='NORP'>Republican</ent> leadership. The
rosters will never be disclosed to the public. As will be seen in
Chapter 16 dealing with <ent type='PERSON'>George</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent>, the <ent type='NORP'>Fascist</ent> connection is too
widespread for damage control. </p>

<p> "According to a 1988 study by <ent type='PERSON'>Russ Bellant</ent> of <ent type='ORG'>Political Research</ent>
Associates, virtually all of the <ent type='NORP'>Fascist</ent> organizations of <ent type='EVENT'>World War</ent>
II opened up a <ent type='NORP'>Republican</ent> party front group during the <ent type='PERSON'>Nixon</ent>
administration. The caliber of the <ent type='NORP'>Republican</ent> ethnic leaders can be
gauged by one <ent type='GPE'>New Jersey</ent> man, <ent type='PERSON'>Emanuel Jasiuk</ent>, a notorious mass
murderer from what is today called the independent nation of
<ent type='GPE'>Belarus</ent>, formerly part of the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> Union. But not all <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n
ethnic communities are represented in the GOP's ethnic section;
there are no black or <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> heritage groups. . . . </p>

<p> "The truth is that the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> immigrants were 'tar babies' that no
one knew how to get rid of. <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent> had brought in a handful of the
top emigre politicians in the late 1940s. They in turn sponsored
their friends in the 1950s. By the 1960s ex-<ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent> who had originally
fled to <ent type='GPE'>Argentina</ent> were moving to <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States. . . ." (9)</p>

<p> It is clear that, even before the break-in at the <ent type='NORP'>Democrat</ent>ic Party
Headquarters on June 17, 1972, the <ent type='NORP'>Republican</ent>s were on the brink of
having their pro-<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> activities over the past four decades become a
matter of mass-media attention. After <ent type='EVENT'>the Watergate Break</ent>-in, as the
<ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>ional Hearings began to reveal the slush-funds, money-laundering, illegal corporate campaign contributions, the political
sabotage of the 1972 Presidential election process, the involvement
of <ent type='ORG'>ITT</ent> and the <ent type='PERSON'>Nixon</ent> Administration into the assassination of
Salvador <ent type='PERSON'>Allen</ent>de, the democratically elected president of <ent type='GPE'>Chile</ent>, and
many other aspects of <ent type='PERSON'>Nixon</ent>ism, the floodgates of truth were about
to open. Only one thing averted this wholesale learning of the truth
by the <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n people: Nixon's resignation and subsequent pardoning
by his hand-picked successor, Gerald <ent type='ORG'>Ford</ent>. </p>

<p> NOTES: RICHARD MILHOUSE <ent type='PERSON'>NIXON</ent></p>

<p> 1.<ent type='EVENT'>The Secret War Against</ent> the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, p. 221 2.<ent type='PERSON'>Ibid</ent>., pp. 221-222
3.<ent type='PERSON'>Ibid</ent>., pp. 222-223 4.<ent type='PERSON'>Ibid</ent>., pp. 122-123 5.<ent type='PERSON'>Ibid</ent>., pp. 224-225
6.<ent type='PERSON'>Ibid</ent>., pp. 297-298 7.<ent type='PERSON'>Ibid</ent>., pp. 298-299 8.High Treason, <ent type='PERSON'>Robert</ent> J.
<ent type='PERSON'>Groden</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Harrison Edward Livingstone</ent>, pp. 417-418 9.The Secret War
Against the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, pp. 300-301</p>

<p> GEORGE HERBERT WALKER BUSH </p>

<p> Like <ent type='PERSON'>Richard Nixon</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>George</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent> was a strong anti-marijuana/hemp
president, escalating the so-called "war on drugs" begun by <ent type='PERSON'>Nixon</ent>.
And, like <ent type='PERSON'>Nixon</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>George</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent> was deeply involved with supporting the
<ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent> in the Republican's closet. In fact, support for the <ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent> was
a <ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent> family tradition which goes back more than six decades and,
once again, to <ent type='PERSON'>Allen</ent> <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent>. </p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>Loftus</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Aarons</ent> write: "The real story of <ent type='PERSON'>George</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent> starts well
before he launched his own career. It goes back to the 1920s, when
the <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent> brothers and the other pirates of Wall Street were making
their deals with the <ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent>. . . ." </p>

<p> THE BUSH-<ent type='PERSON'>DULLES</ent>-<ent type='NORP'>NAZI</ent> CONNECTION</p>

<p> "<ent type='PERSON'>George</ent> Bush's problems were inherited from his namesake and
maternal grandfather, <ent type='PERSON'>George Herbert</ent> 'Bert' <ent type='PERSON'>Walker</ent>, a native of St.
Louis, who founded the banking and investment firm of G. H. <ent type='PERSON'>Walker</ent>
and Company in 1900. Later the company shifted from St. Louis to the
prestigious address of 1 Wall Street. . . . </p>

<p> "<ent type='PERSON'>Walker</ent> was one of Hitler's most powerful financial supporters in
<ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States. The relationship went all the way back to 1924,
when <ent type='PERSON'>Fritz Thyssen</ent>, the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> industrialist, was financing Hitler's
infant <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> party. As mentioned in earlier chapters, there were
<ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n contributors as well. </p>

<p> "Some <ent type='NORP'>Americans</ent> were just bigots and made their connections to
<ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> through <ent type='PERSON'>Allen</ent> Dulles's firm of <ent type='PERSON'>Sullivan</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>Cromwell</ent> because
they supported Fascism. The <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent> brothers, who were in it for
profit more than ideology, arranged <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n investments in <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>
<ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> in the 1930s to ensure that their clients did well out of
the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> economic recovery. . . . </p>

<p> "<ent type='PERSON'>Sullivan</ent> &amp; <ent type='ORG'>Cromwell</ent> was not the only firm engaged in funding
<ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent>. According to 'The Splendid Blond Beast,' Christopher
Simpson's seminal history of the politics of genocide and profit,
<ent type='ORG'>Brown Brothers</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Harriman</ent> was another bank that specialized in
investments in <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent>. The key figure was Averill <ent type='PERSON'>Harriman</ent>, a
dominating figure in the <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n establishment. . . . </p>

<p> "The firm originally was known as W. A. <ent type='PERSON'>Harriman</ent> &amp; Company. The
link between <ent type='PERSON'>Harriman</ent> &amp; Company's <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n investors and <ent type='ORG'>Thyssen</ent>
started in the 1920s, through <ent type='ORG'>the Union Banking Corporation</ent>, which
began trading in 1924. In just one three-year period, the <ent type='PERSON'>Harriman</ent>
firm sold more than $50 million of <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> bonds to <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n
investors. 'Bert' <ent type='PERSON'>Walker</ent> was <ent type='ORG'>Union Banking</ent>'s president, and the firm
was located in the offices of Averill Harriman's company at 39
<ent type='LOC'>Broadway</ent> in <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent>. </p>

<p> "In 1926 <ent type='PERSON'>Bert Walker</ent> did a favor for his new son-in-law, <ent type='PERSON'>Prescott</ent>
<ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent>. It was the sort of favor families do to help their children
make a start in life, but <ent type='PERSON'>Prescott</ent> came to regret it bitterly.
<ent type='PERSON'>Walker</ent> made <ent type='PERSON'>Prescott</ent> vice president of W. A. <ent type='PERSON'>Harriman</ent>. The problem
was that Walker's specialty was companies that traded with <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent>.
As <ent type='ORG'>Thyssen</ent> and the other <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> industrialists consolidated Hitler's
political power in the 1930s, an <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n financial connection was
needed. According to our sources, <ent type='ORG'>Union Banking</ent> became an out-and-out <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> money-laundering machine. . . . </p>

<p> "In [1931], <ent type='PERSON'>Harriman</ent> &amp; Company merged with a <ent type='NORP'>British</ent>-<ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n
investment company to become <ent type='ORG'>Brown Brothers</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Harriman</ent>. <ent type='PERSON'>Prescott</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent>
became one of the senior partners of the new company, which
relocated to 59 <ent type='LOC'>Broadway</ent>, while <ent type='ORG'>Union Banking</ent> remained at 39
<ent type='LOC'>Broadway</ent>. But in 1934 <ent type='PERSON'>Walker</ent> arranged to put his son-in-law on the
board of directors of <ent type='ORG'>Union Banking</ent>. </p>

<p> "<ent type='PERSON'>Walker</ent> also set up a deal to take over the <ent type='PERSON'>North</ent> <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n
operations of the <ent type='GPE'>Hamburg</ent>-<ent type='ORG'>Amerika Line</ent>, a cover for I.G. Farben's
<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> espionage unit in <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States. The shipping line smuggled
in <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> agents, propaganda, and money for bribing <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n
politicians to see things Hitler's way. The holding company was
Walker's <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n Shipping &amp; <ent type='ORG'>Commerce</ent>, which shared the offices at
39 <ent type='LOC'>Broadway</ent> with <ent type='ORG'>Union Banking</ent>. In an elaborate corporate paper
trail, Harriman's stock in <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n Shipping &amp; <ent type='ORG'>Commerce</ent> was
controlled by yet another holding company, the <ent type='PERSON'>Harriman</ent> Fifteen
Corporation, run out of Walker's office. The directors of this
company were Averill <ent type='PERSON'>Harriman</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Bert Walker</ent>, and <ent type='PERSON'>Prescott</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent>. . . . </p>

<p> ". . . In a November 1935 article in Common Sense, retired marine
general <ent type='ORG'>Smedley</ent> D. <ent type='PERSON'>Butler</ent> blamed <ent type='ORG'>Brown Brothers</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Harriman</ent> for having
the U.S. marines act like 'racketeers' and 'gangsters' in order to
exploit financially the peasants of <ent type='GPE'>Nicaragua</ent>. . . . </p>

<p> ". . . A 1934 congressional investigation alleged that Walker's
'<ent type='GPE'>Hamburg</ent>-<ent type='ORG'>Amerika Line</ent> subsidized a wide range of pro-<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> propaganda
efforts both in <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States.' <ent type='PERSON'>Walker</ent> did not know
it, but one of his <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n employees, <ent type='PERSON'>Dan Harkins</ent>, had blown the
whistle on the spy apparatus to <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>. Harkins, one of our best
sources, became Roosevelt's first double agent . . . [and] kept up
the pretense of being an ardent <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> sympathizer, while reporting to
<ent type='ORG'>Naval Intelligence</ent> on the shipping company's deals with <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>
intelligence.</p>

<p> "Instead of divesting the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> money," continue the authors, "<ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent>
hired a lawyer to hide the assets. The lawyer he hired had
considerable expertise in such underhanded schemes. It was <ent type='PERSON'>Allen</ent>
<ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent>. According to Dulles's client list at <ent type='PERSON'>Sullivan</ent> &amp; <ent type='ORG'>Cromwell</ent>,
his first relationship with <ent type='ORG'>Brown Brothers</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Harriman</ent> was on June 18,
1936. In January 1937 <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent> listed his work for the firm as
'Disposal of Stan [<ent type='ORG'>Standard Oil</ent>] Investing stock.' </p>

<p> "As discussed in Chapter 3, <ent type='ORG'>Standard Oil</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>New Jersey</ent> had
completed a major stock transaction with Dulles's <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> client, I.G.
<ent type='ORG'>Farben</ent>. By the end of January 1937 <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent> had merged all his
cloaking activities into one client account: '<ent type='ORG'>Brown Brothers</ent>
<ent type='PERSON'>Harriman</ent>-Schroeder Rock.' Schroeder, of course, was the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> bank on
whose board <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent> sat. The 'Rock' were the <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent>s of <ent type='ORG'>Standard</ent>
Oil, who were already coming under scrutiny for their <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> deals. By
May 1939 <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent> handled another problem for <ent type='ORG'>Brown Brothers</ent>,
<ent type='PERSON'>Harriman</ent>, their 'Securities Custodian Accounts.' </p>

<p> "If <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent> was trying to conceal how many <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> holding companies
<ent type='ORG'>Brown Brothers</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Harriman</ent> was connected with, he did not do a very
good job. Shortly after <ent type='PERSON'>Pearl Harbor</ent>, word leaked from <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>
that affiliates of <ent type='PERSON'>Prescott</ent> Bush's company were under investigation
for aiding the <ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent> in time of war. . . . </p>

<p> ". . . The government investigation against <ent type='PERSON'>Prescott</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent>
continued. Just before the storm broke, his son, <ent type='PERSON'>George</ent>, abandoned
his plans to enter <ent type='ORG'>Yale</ent> and enlisted in the U.S. <ent type='ORG'>Army</ent>. It was, say
our sources among the former intelligence officers, a valiant
attempt by an eighteen-year-old boy to save the family's honor. </p>

<p> "Young <ent type='PERSON'>George</ent> was in flight school in October 1942, when the U.S.
government charged his father with running <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> front groups in the
United States. Under the Trading with the Enemy Act, all the shares
of <ent type='ORG'>the Union Banking Corporation</ent> were seized, including those held
by <ent type='PERSON'>Prescott</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent> as being in effect held for enemy nationals. Union
Banking, of course, was an affiliate of <ent type='ORG'>Brown Brothers</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Harriman</ent>,
and <ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent> handled the <ent type='PERSON'>Harriman</ent>s' investments as well. </p>

<p> "Once the government had its hands on Bush's books, the whole story
of the intricate web of <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> front corporations began to unravel. A
few days later two of <ent type='ORG'>Union Banking</ent>'s subsidiaries -- the <ent type='GPE'>Holland</ent>
<ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n Trading Corporation and the Seamless Steel Equipment
Corporation -- also were seized. Then the government went after the
<ent type='PERSON'>Harriman</ent> Fifteen Holding Company, which <ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent> shared with his father-in-law, <ent type='PERSON'>Bert Walker</ent>, the <ent type='GPE'>Hamburg</ent>-<ent type='ORG'>Amerika Line</ent>, and the Silesian-<ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n Corporation. The U.S. government found that huge sections
of <ent type='PERSON'>Prescott</ent> Bush's empire had been operated on behalf of <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>
<ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> and had greatly assisted the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> war effort." (1)</p>

<p> EDWIN PAULEY</p>

<p> "Try as he did," continue the authors, "<ent type='PERSON'>George</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent> could not get
away from Dulles's crooked corporate network, which his grandfather
and father had joined in the 1920s. Wherever he turned, <ent type='PERSON'>George</ent> found
that the influence of the <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent> brothers was already there. Even
when he fled to <ent type='GPE'>Texas</ent> to become a successful businessman on his own,
he ran into the pirates of Wall Street. </p>

<p> "One of <ent type='PERSON'>Allen</ent> Dulles's secret spies inside <ent type='ORG'>the Democratic party</ent>
later became <ent type='PERSON'>George</ent> Bush's partner in the <ent type='NORP'>Mexican</ent> oil business.
<ent type='PERSON'>Edwin Pauley</ent>, a <ent type='GPE'>California</ent> oil man, was . . . one of Dulles's covert
agents in the <ent type='PERSON'>Roosevelt</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Truman</ent> administrations . . . a 'big
business' <ent type='NORP'>Democrat</ent>. . . ."</p>

<p> Among the key posts held by <ent type='PERSON'>Pauley</ent> were: treasurer of the
<ent type='NORP'>Democrat</ent>ic <ent type='ORG'>Nation</ent>al Committee, director of the <ent type='NORP'>Democrat</ent>ic convention
in 1944 and, after Truman's election, <ent type='PERSON'>Truman</ent> appointed him the
"Petroleum Coordinator of Lend-Lease Supplies for the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> Union
and <ent type='GPE'>Britain</ent>." </p>

<p> Just after the end of <ent type='EVENT'>World War</ent> II, "in April 1945 <ent type='PERSON'>Truman</ent> appointed
<ent type='PERSON'>Pauley</ent> as the U.S. representative to the <ent type='ORG'>Allied</ent> Reparations
Committee, with the rank of ambassador," as well as "industrial and
commercial advisor to <ent type='ORG'>the Potsdam Conference</ent>, 'where his chief task
was to renegotiate the reparations agreements formulated at <ent type='GPE'>Yalta</ent>.'
As one historian noted, the 'oil industry has always watched
reparations activities carefully.' There was a lot of money
involved, and much of it belonged to the <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent> brothers' clients." </p>

<p> At the same time, report <ent type='ORG'>Loftus</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Aarons</ent>,</p>

<p> "the <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent> brothers were still shifting <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> assets out of Europe
for their clients as well as for their own profit. They didn't want
the <ent type='NORP'>Soviets</ent> to get their hands on these assets or even know that
they existed. <ent type='PERSON'>Pauley</ent> played a significant role in solving this
problem for the <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent> brothers. The major part of <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> Germany's
industrial assets was located in the zones occupied by the West's
forces. As Washington's man on the ground, <ent type='PERSON'>Pauley</ent> managed to deceive
the <ent type='NORP'>Soviets</ent> for long enough to allow <ent type='PERSON'>Allen</ent> <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent> to spirit much of
the remaining <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> assets out to safety. . . . </p>

<p> "<ent type='PERSON'>Pauley</ent>, a key player in the plan to hide the <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent> brothers' <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>
assets, then moved into another post where he could help them
further. After successfully keeping <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> assets in <ent type='NORP'>Fascist</ent> hands,
<ent type='PERSON'>Pauley</ent> was given the job of 'surveying Japan's assets and
determining the amount of its war debt.' Again, it was another job
that was crucial to the <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent> clique's secret financial and
intelligence operations." (2)</p>

<p> After <ent type='PERSON'>Pauley</ent> retired from government work he went back to being an
independent oil man. <ent type='ORG'>Loftus</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Aarons</ent> state that: "In 1958 he
founded <ent type='PERSON'>Pauley</ent> Petroleum which: . . . teamed up with Howard <ent type='PERSON'>Hugh</ent>es
to expand oil production in <ent type='LOC'>the Gulf</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>Mexico</ent>.</p>

<p> "<ent type='PERSON'>Pauley</ent> Petroleum discovered a highly productive offshore petroleum
reserve and in 1959 became involved in a dispute with the <ent type='NORP'>Mexican</ent>
Government, which considered the royalties from the wells to be too
low. </p>

<p> "According to our sources in the intelligence community, the oil
dispute was really a shakedown of the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> by <ent type='NORP'>Mexican</ent> politicians.
<ent type='PERSON'>Hugh</ent>es and <ent type='PERSON'>Pauley</ent> were working for the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> from time to time, while
advancing their own financial interests in the lucrative <ent type='NORP'>Mexican</ent> oil
fields. <ent type='PERSON'>Pauley</ent>, say several of our sources, was the man who invented
an intelligence money-laundering system in <ent type='GPE'>Mexico</ent>, which was later
refined in the 1970s as part of Nixon's <ent type='EVENT'>Watergate</ent> scandal. At one
point <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> agents used <ent type='ORG'>Pemex</ent>, the <ent type='NORP'>Mexican</ent> government's oil monopoly,
as a business cover at the same time <ent type='ORG'>Pemex</ent> was being used as a money
laundry for Pauley's campaign contributions. As we shall see, the
<ent type='NORP'>Mexican</ent>-<ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> connection played an important part in the development
of <ent type='PERSON'>George</ent> Bush's political and intelligence career. . . .</p>

<p> "<ent type='PERSON'>Pauley</ent>, say the 'old spies,' was the man who brought all the
threads of the <ent type='NORP'>Mexican</ent> connection together. He was Bush's business
associate, a front man for Dulles's <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> [<ent type='PERSON'>Allen</ent> <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent> was <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>
director then], and originator of the use of <ent type='NORP'>Mexican</ent> oil fronts to
create a slush fund for <ent type='PERSON'>Richard Nixon</ent>'s various campaigns. . . . </p>

<p> "Although it is not widely known, <ent type='PERSON'>Pauley</ent>, in fact, had been a
committed, if 'secret,' <ent type='PERSON'>Nixon</ent> supporter since 1960. It should be
recalled that <ent type='PERSON'>Nixon</ent> tried to conceal his <ent type='NORP'>Mexican</ent> slush fund during
the <ent type='EVENT'>Watergate</ent> affair by pressuring the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> into a 'national
security' cover-up. The <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>, to its credit, declined to participate.
Unfortunately, others were so enmeshed in Pauley's work for <ent type='PERSON'>Nixon</ent>
that they could never extricate themselves. According to a number of
our intelligence sources, the deals <ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent> cut with <ent type='PERSON'>Pauley</ent> in <ent type='GPE'>Mexico</ent>
catapulted him into political life. In 1960 <ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent> became a protege of
<ent type='PERSON'>Richard Nixon</ent>, who was then running for president of <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent>
States. . . . </p>

<p> "The most intriguing of Bush's early connections was to Richard
<ent type='PERSON'>Nixon</ent>, who as vice president had supervised <ent type='PERSON'>Allen</ent> Dulles's covert
planning for <ent type='ORG'>the Bay</ent> of Pigs [invasion]. For years it has been
rumored that Dulles's client, <ent type='PERSON'>George</ent> Bush's father, was one of the
<ent type='NORP'>Republican</ent> leaders who recruited <ent type='PERSON'>Nixon</ent> to run for <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent> and later
convinced <ent type='PERSON'>Eisenhower</ent> to take him on as vice president. There is no
doubt that the two families were close. <ent type='PERSON'>George</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent> described <ent type='PERSON'>Nixon</ent>
as his 'mentor.' <ent type='PERSON'>Nixon</ent> was a <ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent> supporter in his very first tilt
at politics, during his unsuccessful run for the Senate in 1964, and
turned out again when he entered the <ent type='ORG'>House</ent> two years later. </p>

<p> "After Nixon's landslide victory in 1972, he ordered a general
house cleaning on the basis of loyalty. 'Eliminate everyone,' he
told <ent type='PERSON'>John</ent> Ehrlichman about reappointments, 'except <ent type='PERSON'>George</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent>. <ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent>
will do anything for our cause.' . . . According to Bush's account,
the president told him that 'the place I really need you is over at
the <ent type='ORG'>Nation</ent>al Committee running things.' So, in 1972, <ent type='PERSON'>Nixon</ent> appointed
<ent type='PERSON'>George</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent> as head of the <ent type='NORP'>Republican</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Nation</ent>al Committee. </p>

<p> "It was <ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent> who fulfilled Nixon's promise to make the 'ethnic'
emigres a permanent part of <ent type='NORP'>Republican</ent> politics. In 1972 Nixon's
State Department spokesman confirmed to his <ent type='NORP'>Australian</ent> counterpart
that the ethnic groups were very useful to get out the vote in
several key states. Bush's tenure as head of the <ent type='NORP'>Republican</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Nation</ent>al
Committee exactly coincided with <ent type='PERSON'>Laszlo Pasztor</ent>'s 1972 drive to
transform <ent type='ORG'>the Heritage Groups Council</ent> into the party's official
ethnic arm. The groups <ent type='ORG'>Pasztor</ent> chose as Bush's campaign allies were
the emigre <ent type='NORP'>Fascist</ent>s whom <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent> had brought to <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States. .
. . </p>

<p> ". . . Nearly twenty years later, and after expose's in several
respectable newspapers, <ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent> continued to recruit most of the same
ethnic <ent type='NORP'>Fascist</ent>s, including <ent type='ORG'>Pasztor</ent>, for his own 1988 ethnic outreach
program when he first ran for president. </p>

<p> "According to our sources in the intelligence community," state the
authors, "it was <ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent> who told <ent type='PERSON'>Nixon</ent> that the <ent type='EVENT'>Watergate</ent>
investigations might start uncovering the <ent type='NORP'>Fascist</ent> skeletons in the
<ent type='NORP'>Republican</ent> party's closet. <ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent> himself acknowledges that he wrote
<ent type='PERSON'>Nixon</ent> a letter asking him to step down. The day after <ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent> did so,
<ent type='PERSON'>Nixon</ent> resigned. </p>

<p> "<ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent> had hoped to become Gerald Ford's vice president upon Nixon's
resignation, but he was appointed U.S. ambassador to the UN. Nelson
<ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> became vice president and chief damage controller. He
formed a special commission in an attempt to preempt the Senate's
investigation of the intelligence community. The <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent>
Commission into <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> abuses was filled with old <ent type='ORG'>OPC</ent> [Dulles's Office
of Policy Coordination] hands like Ronald Reagan, who had been the
front man back in the 1950s for the money-laundering organization,
the Crusade for Freedom, which was part of Dulles's <ent type='NORP'>Fascist</ent> 'freedom
fighters' program." (3)</p>

<p> In 1988, Project Censored, a news media censorship research
organization, awarded the honor of "Top Censored story" to the
subject of <ent type='PERSON'>George</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent>. The article revealed "how the major mass
media ignored, overlooked or undercovered at least ten critical
stories reported in America's alternative press that raised serious
questions about the <ent type='NORP'>Republican</ent> candidate, <ent type='PERSON'>George</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent>, dating from
his reported role as a <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> 'asset' in 1963 to his Presidential
campaign's connection with a network of anti-<ent type='NORP'>Semites</ent> with <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> and
fascist affiliations in 1988." (4) </p>

<p> NOTES: GEORGE HERBERT WALKER BUSH</p>

<p> 1.<ent type='EVENT'>The Secret War Against</ent> the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, pp. 357-361 2.<ent type='PERSON'>Ibid</ent>., pp. 362-364
3.<ent type='PERSON'>Ibid</ent>., pp. 365-371 4.The 1993 Project Censored Yearbook: The News
That Didn't Make The News - And Why, Project Censored; Dr. Carl
Jensen, Director., pp. 230.</p>

<p> CONCLUSION </p>

<p> If, before you finished reading this publication, you ever wondered
why the U.S. federal government refuses to consider the medicinal
and industrial value of cannabis hemp, despite widespread and
growing support from the public, medical experts, industry leaders,
and a growing number of state legislators across this nation . . .
you now have the answer. </p>

<p> For the past several generations, <ent type='NORP'>Americans</ent> have been
systematically deceived about the true nature of cannabis hemp. Many
<ent type='NORP'>Americans</ent> have died - victims of political murders. Millions have
been imprisoned, their children and their property taken away, their
futures destroyed. The history of my own state - <ent type='GPE'>Kentucky</ent> - and
others as well, have been "sanitized," rewritten, our heritage
deleted, our citizens defrauded and impoverished to bury the truth. </p>

<p> And if, before you finished reading this publication, you ever
wondered why the U.S. federal government would train and finance
<ent type='ORG'>Central</ent> <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n death squads; or why, while waging the so-called
"war on drugs," the U.S. federal government would operate cocaine
and heroin smuggling operations around the world, bringing in tons
of drugs to places like <ent type='ORG'>Mena</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Arkansas</ent>; or why the U.S. federal
government would "spread democracy" throughout the world by
assassinating democratically elected politicians - both at home and
abroad - replacing them with right-wing dictators and training their
secret police in the latest techniques of torture, terrorism, and
mind control; or why the U.S. federal government would conduct
deadly medical and radiation experiments on unsuspecting citizens -
including pregnant women, the mentally impaired, and children . . .
you now have the answer. </p>

<p> The last question is "what are we going to do about it?" </p>

<p> BIBLIOGRAPHY (By section)</p>

<p> INTRODUCTION</p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>The Irony</ent> of Democracy: An Uncommon Introduction to <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n
Politics - Second Edition, By <ent type='PERSON'>Thomas</ent> R. <ent type='PERSON'>Dye</ent> and L. <ent type='PERSON'>Harmon Zeigler</ent> -
<ent type='ORG'>Duxbury Press</ent>, CA. 1972 </p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>The Arms Bazaar</ent>: From <ent type='GPE'>Lebanon</ent> to <ent type='ORG'>Lockheed</ent> - By <ent type='PERSON'>Anthony Sampson</ent> -
<ent type='ORG'>The Viking Press</ent>, NY. 1977</p>

<p> U. S. CORPORATIONS AND THE <ent type='ORG'>NAZIS</ent></p>

<p> Facts and Fascism - By <ent type='PERSON'>George</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Seldes</ent> (Assisted by Helen <ent type='PERSON'>Seldes</ent>) -
Sixth Edition - In Fact, Inc., NY. 1943 </p>

<p> Trading with the Enemy: An Expose of the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>-<ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n Money Plot
1933-1949 - By <ent type='PERSON'><ent type='PERSON'>Charles</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Higham</ent></ent> - <ent type='ORG'>Delecorte Press</ent>, NY. 1983 </p>

<p> Even the Gods Can't Change History: The Facts Speak for Themselves
- By <ent type='PERSON'>George</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Seldes</ent> - <ent type='PERSON'>Lyle Stuart</ent>, Inc., NJ. 1976 </p>

<p> Power, Inc.: Public and Private Rulers and How to Make Them
Accountable - By <ent type='PERSON'>Morton Mintz</ent> &amp; <ent type='PERSON'>Jerry</ent> S. <ent type='PERSON'>Cohen</ent> - Viking Press, NY.
1976 </p>

<p> The Plot to Seize <ent type='ORG'>the <ent type='ORG'>White</ent> <ent type='ORG'>House</ent></ent> - By <ent type='PERSON'>Jules Archer</ent> - Hawthorn
Books, 1973 </p>

<p> It's A Conspiracy!: The Shocking Truth About America's Favorite
Conspiracy Theories - By <ent type='PERSON'>Michael Litchfield</ent>/The <ent type='ORG'>Nation</ent>al Insecurity
Council - <ent type='LOC'>Earth</ent>Works Press, CA. 1992 </p>

<p> <ent type='EVENT'>The Secret War Against</ent> The <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>: How <ent type='ORG'>West</ent>ern Espionage Betrayed The
<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> People - By <ent type='PERSON'>John</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Loftus</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Mark Aarons</ent> - St. Martin's Press,
NY. 1994 </p>

<p> HEMP &amp; the <ent type='ORG'>Marijuana</ent> Conspiracy: The Emperor Wears No Clothes - By
<ent type='PERSON'>Jack Herer</ent> (Editors: C. Conrad, L. &amp; J. Osburn, E. Komp , and J.
Stout) </p>

<p> H.E.M.P. (Help Eliminate <ent type='ORG'>Marijuana</ent> Prohibition), CA. 1995 </p>

<p> One Thousand <ent type='NORP'>Americans</ent> - By <ent type='PERSON'>George</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Seldes</ent> - BONI &amp; GAER, NY. 1947 </p>

<p> Ain't Nobody's Business If You Do: The Absurdity of Consentual
Crimes in a Free Society - By Peter Mc<ent type='PERSON'>William</ent>s - Prelude Press, CA.
1993 </p>

<p> A History of the Hemp Industry in <ent type='GPE'>Kentucky</ent> - By Professor <ent type='PERSON'>James</ent> F.
<ent type='ORG'>Hopkins</ent> - University of <ent type='GPE'>Kentucky</ent> Press, <ent type='GPE'>Lexington</ent>, KY. 1951 </p>

<p> Spooks: The Haunting of <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> - The Private Use of Secret Agents
- By <ent type='PERSON'>Jim Hougan</ent> - First <ent type='ORG'>Bantam</ent> Edition - <ent type='PERSON'>William</ent> Morrow and Co., NY.
1979 </p>

<p> <ent type='LOC'>The Sovereign</ent> State of <ent type='ORG'>ITT</ent> - By <ent type='PERSON'>Anthony Sampson</ent> - Stein and Day,
NY. 1973 </p>

<p> Democracy for the Few - By <ent type='PERSON'>Michael Parenti</ent> - Fourth Edition - St.
Martin's Press, NY. 1983</p>

<p> THE NEW WORLD (<ent type='ORG'>DIS</ent>)ORDER</p>

<p> Tragedy and Hope: A History of the World in Our Time - By Carroll
Quigley, Second Printing - Wm. Morrison, NY. 1974 </p>

<p> The <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n Establishment - By <ent type='PERSON'>Leonard</ent> Silk &amp; <ent type='PERSON'>Mark Silk</ent>, First
Discus Printing - Avon Books (by arrangement with <ent type='ORG'>Basic Books</ent>), NY.
1981 </p>

<p> The New <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> and the Old <ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent> - By T.H. Tetens - Random <ent type='ORG'>House</ent>,
NY. 1961 </p>

<p> Blowback: America's Recruitment of Nazi's and Its Effect on the
Cold War - By <ent type='PERSON'>Christopher Simpson</ent> - <ent type='ORG'>Weidenfeld</ent> &amp; Nicolson, NY. 1988 </p>

<p> Unholy <ent type='ORG'>Trinity</ent>: The <ent type='ORG'>Vatican</ent>, the <ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent>, and <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> Intelligence -
By <ent type='PERSON'>Mark Aarons</ent> &amp; <ent type='PERSON'>John</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Loftus</ent>, First U.S. Edition - St. Martin's
Press, NY. 1992 </p>

<p> Conspiracies, Cover-Ups and Crimes: From <ent type='PERSON'>JFK</ent> to the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> Terrorist
Connection - By <ent type='PERSON'>Jonathan Vankin</ent> - <ent type='ORG'>Bantam</ent> Doubleday Dell Publishing
Group, Inc., NY. 1992</p>

<p> RICHARD MILHOUSE <ent type='PERSON'>NIXON</ent></p>

<p> High Treason: The Assassination of President <ent type='PERSON'>John</ent> F. <ent type='PERSON'>Kennedy</ent> and
<ent type='EVENT'>the New Evidence</ent> of Conspiracy - By <ent type='PERSON'>Robert</ent> J. <ent type='PERSON'>Groden</ent> and Harrison
Edward <ent type='PERSON'>Livingstone</ent>, Berkley Edition - <ent type='ORG'>Berkley Books</ent>, NY. 1990</p>

<p> GEORGE HERBERT WALKER BUSH</p>

<p> Censored: The News That Didn't Make the News - And Why - By Carl
Jensen - <ent type='ORG'>Shelburne Press</ent>, Inc., NY. 1993</p>

<p> Dedicated to the principals of an open discussion of the issues.
Copy and distribute freely. Please credit direct quotations where
appropriate. R. <ent type='PERSON'><ent type='PERSON'>William</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Davis</ent></ent> - Founder and Director, <ent type='ORG'>The Elkhorn</ent>
Project "Restoring Kentucky's Proud Heritage and Bright Future" All
email responses should be directed to: randy@ka.net Hemp for
Victory! Thank you r </p>

<div> </div>

</xml>