<xml><p>
-------------------------------------------------------------------------------
BLUEPRINT FOR U.S. DICTATORSHIP PLACES INDIVIDUAL RIGHTS AT RISK</p>

<p> By Mike Blair
Exclusive to The SPOTLIGHT</p>

<p><ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, DC -- During <ent type='EVENT'>the Persian Gulf war</ent> and the military buildup
leading to it, President <ent type='PERSON'>George Bush</ent> began using the term "<ent type='EVENT'>New World</ent>
Order," often suggesting that the commitment of so-called multinational
forces involved in the military effort was the beginning of this alleged
worldwide utopia.</p>

<p> Supposedly using the vehicle of <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> Nations, Bush's <ent type='EVENT'>New World</ent>
Order would be the arbitrator of all world problems and the apparatus to
enforce globalist dictates through the use of armed forces combined from
the armies of member nations. The UN law would be, regardless of the
nationalist interests of individual countries, the final word.</p>

<p> Actually, even the mention of a <ent type='EVENT'>New World</ent> Order would normally be
anathema to thinking <ent type='NORP'>Americans</ent> and, in particular, conservative political
leaders and civil libertarians.</p>

<p> SINISTER TECHNOLOGY</p>

<p> It is also surprising to many critics of the move toward one-world
government that <ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent> would even dare choose the term "<ent type='EVENT'>New World</ent> Order" to
define his globalist schemes. However, most <ent type='NORP'>Americans</ent> alive today were
born after <ent type='EVENT'>World War</ent> II, when propaganda of the so-called <ent type='ORG'>Allied</ent> powers
used the terms of "New Order" or "<ent type='EVENT'>New World</ent> Order" to describe in a
sinister way the military efforts of <ent type='GPE'>Japan</ent> and, in particular, <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent>
under <ent type='PERSON'>Adolf Hitler</ent>.</p>

<p> Few, it seems, have taken the time to analyze just what <ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent> has in
mind for his <ent type='EVENT'>New World</ent> Order, of which <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> is to become an integral
part, starting with supplying about 90 percent of the muscle, and young
lives, that tackled and defeated <ent type='NORP'>Iraqi</ent> strongman <ent type='PERSON'>Saddam Hussein</ent>'s <ent type='NORP'>Arab</ent>
legions.</p>

<p> However, patriotic Constitutional scholars know that Bush's <ent type='EVENT'>New World</ent>
Order is the worst attack ever on <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> as a sovereign, independent and
free nation.</p>

<p> BEGAN WITH WILSON</p>

<p> Efforts to form a global government are certainly nothing new.
<ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n political leaders, who were concerned with <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> first, were
able to overcome the internationalist, one-world government machinations of
President <ent type='PERSON'>Woodrow Wilson</ent> following world war I. <ent type='ORG'>Wilson</ent> was prevented from
realizing his visions of a <ent type='EVENT'>New World</ent> Order, through <ent type='ORG'>the League</ent> of Nations,
by a powerful Senate opposition, which refused to rubber-stamp for <ent type='ORG'>Wilson</ent>
U.S. membership in the world body.</p>

<p> A few decades later, however, President <ent type='PERSON'>Franklin Delano Roosevelt</ent>,
near the end of <ent type='EVENT'>World War</ent> II, was able to get his one-world plans under way
by laying the groundwork for today's United Nations, which was completed
under his successor, Harry S. Truman.</p>

<p> A few years later, that membership in an UN-mandated war in <ent type='GPE'>Korea</ent> cost
<ent type='GPE'>America</ent> 35000 young lives.</p>

<p> The problem that one-worlders have always encountered, of course, is
the U.S. Constitution, which has stood as a bulwark against any globalist
schemes.</p>

<p> Nevertheless, <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n presidents since <ent type='PERSON'>Roosevelt</ent> have insidiously
chipped away at the great powers of the people, written into the
Constitution by America's immortal Founding Fathers, with the use of so-called executive orders.</p>

<p> CAUSE FOR ALARM</p>

<p> <ent type='NORP'>Americans</ent> should be deeply alarmed that those presidents have signed a
series of executive orders (<ent type='ORG'>EOs</ent>) which, under the guise of any national
emergency declared by the president serving at the time, can virtually
suspend the Constitution and convert the nation into a virtual
dictatorship. Dissent, peaceful or otherwise, is eliminated.</p>

<p> Those backing efforts to circumvent the Constitution may have gotten
the idea from President <ent type='PERSON'>Abraham Lincoln</ent>, whose use of various extraordinary
powers of his office -- which many Constitutional scholars still insist was
illegal -- suspended various civil rights to curb such problems as draft
riots during <ent type='EVENT'>the Civil War</ent>.</p>

<p> In 1862, <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent> enacted the Enrollment Act to allow the drafting of
young men for <ent type='ORG'>the Union Army</ent>. The act was rife with inequities, such as
the provision which allowed a man to pay $300 or hire a substitute to take
his place. This hated "<ent type='PERSON'>Rich Man</ent>'s Exemption," as it was called, angered
the average <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n of military age and in particular young <ent type='NORP'>Irish</ent>
immigrants in <ent type='GPE'>New York City</ent>.</p>

<p> A riot erupted in <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent> in 1863, and it resulted in <ent type='ORG'>Lincoln</ent> using
some extraordinary powers of his office to keep the <ent type='ORG'>Union</ent> from falling
apart from within.</p>

<p> But over the years, presidents have used these powers for purposes
never intended by the Founding Fathers.</p>

<p> INDIANS VICTIMIZED</p>

<p> President <ent type='PERSON'>John Tyler</ent> used such powers in 1842 to round up <ent type='NORP'>Seminole</ent>
<ent type='NORP'>Indians</ent> in <ent type='GPE'>Georgia</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Florida</ent> and force-march them -- men, women and
children -- to <ent type='GPE'>Arkansas</ent>. This was probably the first use of internment in
<ent type='GPE'>America</ent> to deal with unpopular minorities. It was not the last.</p>

<p> In 1886, the <ent type='PERSON'>Geronimo Chiricahua Apache</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Indians</ent> surrendered to U.S.
troops in the West, were rounded up by order of President <ent type='PERSON'>Grover Cleveland</ent>,
and shipped to internment in <ent type='GPE'>Florida</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Alabama</ent>.</p>

<p> Earlier, during <ent type='EVENT'>the War Between the</ent> States, <ent type='ORG'>Sioux</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Indians</ent> in
<ent type='GPE'>Minnesota</ent>, when there was a delay in paying them their yearly allowance,
began attacking nearby white settlements. <ent type='ORG'>Lincoln</ent> sent in a hastily raised
force of volunteers under Col. H. H. Sibley. Little <ent type='PERSON'>Crow</ent>, leader of the
<ent type='ORG'>Kaposia</ent> band, was decisively defeated by the <ent type='ORG'>Union</ent> troops on September 23,
1862, and more than 2000 <ent type='ORG'>Sioux</ent> were taken captive, although Little <ent type='PERSON'>Crow</ent>
himself and a few followers escaped.</p>

<p> Through the process of a military tribunal, sanctioned by <ent type='ORG'>Lincoln</ent>, 36
<ent type='ORG'>Sioux</ent> leaders were publicly hanged. Whether the <ent type='ORG'>Sioux</ent> executed were
innocent or guilty was apparently immaterial. The revolt was quelled, and
the <ent type='GPE'>Minnesota</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Sioux</ent> were all moved to reservations in <ent type='GPE'>Dakota</ent>.</p>

<p> These instances of the nation's executive branch taking extraordinary
measures to confine, or intern, <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n <ent type='NORP'>Indians</ent> are just a few of many
examples.</p>

<p> More recent examples of interning minorities by executive order
occurred during <ent type='EVENT'>World War</ent> I and <ent type='EVENT'>World War</ent> II.</p>

<p> During <ent type='EVENT'>World War</ent> I, an unknown number of <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>-<ent type='NORP'>Americans</ent> were rounded
up by federal authorities and interned until after the war. In addition,
regardless of the First Amendment of the Constitution, which guarantees
freedom of speech and of the press. <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>-language newspapers, published
within <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>-<ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n communities in <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States, were banned.</p>

<p> WW II INTERNMENTS</p>

<p> After the <ent type='GPE'>Japan</ent>ese attack on <ent type='LOC'>Pearl Harbor</ent> on December 7, 1941, within
days the <ent type='ORG'>FBI</ent> rounded up tens of thousands of <ent type='GPE'>Japan</ent>ese-<ent type='NORP'>Americans</ent>, guilty
only of being of <ent type='GPE'>Japan</ent>ese ancestry, under the authority of an executive
order issued by President <ent type='PERSON'>Franklin Delano Roosevelt</ent>. The lists of those to
be apprehended had been drawn up months earlier, before the war.</p>

<p> Held in concentration camps, the perimeters guarded by U.S. soldiers
armed with machine guns, the mostly innocent and patriotic <ent type='GPE'>Japan</ent>ese-<ent type='NORP'>Americans</ent> were not released until after the war.</p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent> has recently passed legislation extending the nation's
apologies to the <ent type='GPE'>Japan</ent>ese-<ent type='NORP'>Americans</ent> and extending them compensation for
their years of confinement.</p>

<p> However, no apology or compensation has ever been extended to the more
than 8000 <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>-<ent type='NORP'>Americans</ent> who were confined in dozens of jails and camps
across <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States, also by order of <ent type='PERSON'>Roosevelt</ent>.</p>

<p> Many were not released until 1947, a full two years after the end of
the war, in total violation of the Geneva Conventions.</p>

<p> "What happened to me and thousands of others is old history," said
Eberhard <ent type='PERSON'>Fuhr</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>Cincinnati</ent>, who was interned at 17 years of age, "but the
next time it could be any other group, which is then not politically
correct, or out of favor for any other reason (SPOTLIGHT, May 20, 1991).</p>

<p> Fuhr's warning, of course, had already been proved correct just
several months earlier when, under orders of <ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent>, the <ent type='ORG'>FBI</ent> hounded
thousands of innocent <ent type='NORP'>Arab</ent>-<ent type='NORP'>Americans</ent> as the U.S. prepared for the Persian
Gulf conflict.</p>

<p> Only the efforts of a handful of irate U.S. <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>men halted the
harassment but not until after a number of U.S. military bases were
selected as sites of internment camps for <ent type='NORP'>Arab</ent>-<ent type='NORP'>Americans</ent> and war
dissenters.</p>

<div>-----------------</div>

<p>Reproduced with permission from a special supplement to _The Spotlight_,
May 25, 1992. This text may be freely reproduced provided acknowledgement
to The Spotlight appears, including this address:</p>

<p> The SPOTLIGHT
300 Independence Avenue, SE
<ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, DC 20003

</p></xml>