<xml><p>
-------------------------------------------------------------------------------
<ent type='ORG'>DICTATORSHIP</ent> POSSIBLE HERE</p>

<p> By Lawrence Wilmot and Martin Mann
Exclusive to The SPOTLIGHT</p>

<p><ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, DC -- Hidden in the bureaucratic maze <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent> politicians
call "our Constitutional system of government," a little-known federal
agency is quietly making plans to turn <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States into a
dictatorship.</p>

<p> There are "stacks of blueprints" in the top-secret safe of the Federal
Emergency Management Agency (<ent type='ORG'>FEMA</ent>) designed to convert <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> society
into a "command system," a former deputy administrator of the agency has
told The SPOTLIGHT's investigative team.</p>

<p> In a private interview, allowing him to remain anonymous, this highly
placed source confirmed that the procedures developed by <ent type='ORG'>FEMA</ent> to "suspend"
the Constitution and to round up thousands of dissenters nationwide can be
activated by a simple phone call from <ent type='ORG'>the White House</ent>.</p>

<p> "Even people who have become aware of FEMA's existence and know
something about its activities -- not many do -- think the word 'Emergency'
in its designation means it will go into action only in case of a natural
disaster or perhaps a surprise nuclear attack," related this expert.</p>

<p> "In reality, however, this outfit can be mobilized whenever the
politicians occupying <ent type='ORG'>the White House</ent> decide they need special -- and
extra-Constitutional -- powers to impose their will on the nation."</p>

<p> As <ent type='ORG'>Liberty Lobby</ent> first revealed, FEMA's bureaucrats can then proceed
to:</p>

<p> * Take over all farms, ranches or timberland in order to "utilize them
more effectively" as decreed in Executive Order (EO) 11490, the so-called omnibus emergency preparedness decree promulgated by President
<ent type='PERSON'>Richard Nixon</ent> on October 28, 1969.</p>

<p> * Seize all sources of public power: electric, nuclear, petroleum, etc.</p>

<p> * Freeze all wages, prices and bank accounts.</p>

<p> * Take over all communications media.</p>

<p> A FORCE OF FACELESS FEDS</p>

<p> Such totalitarian measures can be imposed by bureaucrats under FEMA's
direction, not just in the face of a cataclysmic upheaval, but "[<ent type='ORG'>w]henever</ent>
necessary for assuring the continuity of the federal government in any
national emergency type situation," decreed a subsequent <ent type='ORG'>White House</ent> ukase,
EO 11921, issued by President <ent type='PERSON'>Gerald Ford</ent> in April 1976.</p>

<p> Can such a blueprint for tyranny be clamped on <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States by a
force of faceless federal officials? It is the role of <ent type='ORG'>FEMA</ent> has been
preparing for most intensively, says the former high agency administrator.</p>

<p> "In recent years, despite talk of spending cuts, FEMA's budget has
been steadily increasing," revealed this knowledgeable source. "It now
stands at somewhere around $3 billion annually. I say 'somewhere' because
part of this agency's funding is appropriated under so-called black
programs, submitted to <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent> with the defense budget without an
explanation of its purpose, aping the secret <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> appropriation."</p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>FEMA</ent> can draw on the defense budget and on the protection of the
secrecy reserved for national security projects because it came into being
under President <ent type='PERSON'>Jimmy Carter</ent> in a move that merged the civil defense and
disaster relief responsibilities formerly shared by the <ent type='ORG'>Pentagon</ent>, the
Commerce Department and <ent type='ORG'>the General Services Administration</ent> under a single
powerful agency.</p>

<p> WHAT'S <ent type='ORG'>FEMA</ent> REALLY UP TO?</p>

<p> But FEMA's real focus is not on disaster relief, knowledgeable sources
say. An investigation of this little-known agency, conducted earlier this
year by <ent type='ORG'>the General Accounting Office</ent> (<ent type='ORG'>GAO</ent>), the congressional watchdog
unit, has found that less than 10 percent of FEMA's staff -- 230
bureaucrats out of an estimated 2600 -- are assigned full-time to
preparing for and dealing with major natural disasters such as storms or
earthquakes.</p>

<p> What, then, is <ent type='ORG'>FEMA</ent> really up to? The SPOTLIGHT's investigative team
has obtained an advance copy of the <ent type='ORG'>GAO</ent> report on this secretive agency.</p>

<p> The study's surprising findings have been reviewed with the help of
well-placed confidential sources, in order to bring into full view, for the
first time, the federal bureaucracy's secret blueprint for tyranny in
<ent type='GPE'>America</ent>.</p>

<div>-----------------</div>

<p>Reproduced with permission from a special supplement to _The Spotlight_,
May 25, 1992. This text may be freely reproduced provided acknowledgement
to The Spotlight appears, including this address:</p>

<p> The SPOTLIGHT
300 Independence Avenue, SE
<ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, DC 20003</p>

</xml>