<xml><p>
VIOLATION OF LAW OF CONSERVATION OF CHARGE
IN SPACE POWER GENERATION PHENOMENON</p>

<p> By</p>

<p> PARAMAHAMSA TEWARI
Chief Project Engineer
Kaiga Project
NUCLEAR POWER CORPORATION
Karwar
INDIA</p>

<p> INTRODUCTION:</p>

<p> It has been hitherto believed in physics that the total electric
charge in the <ent type='ORG'>Universe</ent> is a constant quantity, and if additional
charge appears in some region, it is only at the expense of the
charge deficit in some other regions.</p>

<p> It is a basic law that electric charge is conserved and cannot be
destroyed or created. Precise experiments on a Space Power
Generator (<ent type='ORG'>SPG</ent>) which has been now further developed to demonstrate
the commercial viability of the newly discovered phenomenon of space
power generation however, totally violate the existing law of
conservation of charge, by generating output electrical power much
in excess of the input electrical power.</p>

<p> Since electric charge is a form of basic energy, the law of
conservation of energy will need to be enlarged to incorporate in it
the dynamics of absolute vacuum [1] which in a state of rotation
generates fundamental field to produce electrical charge and energy.</p>

<p> DESCRIPTION OF THE <ent type='ORG'>SPG</ent>:</p>

<p> The <ent type='ORG'>SPG</ent> shown in Fig. 1 is a further developed form of the machines
described [23] in earlier issues of this magazine.</p>

<p> A non-magnetic shaft interconnects two mild steel rotors on which
two electromagnets are mounted. Electric power at 1.5 volt d-c and
high ampheres is drawn from each unit, with the help of copper-graphite brushes when the machine runs at 2860 rpm directly coupled
and driven by an induction motor.</p>

<p> The power is drawn between the inner rotor's cylindrical surface and
the shaft through d-c shunts that enable measurements of high d-c
current.</p>

<p> The <ent type='ORG'>SPG</ent> weighs about 150 Kg. and is fabricated out of 120 mm thick
mild steel plate. The two units enable generation of power at more
than 3 volt d-c by appropriate series connections between the two
coils. The electromagnet's coils are 16 swg super enamelled wire
with 216 turns in each coil.</p>

<p> The feature that brings improvements [4] in this machine is the
larger diameter of the rotors that produces higher d-c voltage at
comparatively lower speed, not exceeding 3000 rpm. Also the twin
units with single coil in each unit double the amount of power.</p>

<p> TEST RESULTS:</p>

<p> The drive motor (DM) takes no-load current of 2.6 amperes (1300
watts) to rotate itself and the <ent type='ORG'>SPG</ent> to overcome windage and friction
at 2870 rpm. The no-load voltage internally generated in each unit
of the <ent type='ORG'>SPG</ent> is adjusted to 1.5 volts d-c between the shaft and the
inner rotor by the control of the d-c excitation current in the two
electromagnet's coils connected in series.</p>

<p> The excitation current is 31 amperes, the total d-c resistance of
the two coils being 2.5 ohms. The power given to the electromagnets
is 31 x 31 x 2.5, that is, 2400 watts. The two shunts with
calibration of 2000 amperes for 75 mv are now connected across the
two output circuits.</p>

<p> The d-c currents measured in each circuit are almost equal to 2613
amperes corresponding to 98 mv reading of the shunt.</p>

<p> The output electrical power of each unit is 2613 x 1.5 watts, that
is, 3919 watts. Total electrical power from the two units is 7839
watts.</p>

<p> As the <ent type='ORG'>SPG</ent> is electrically loaded, the current of DM rises to 10
amperes, showing a rise of 7.4 amperes over the no-load current, and
corresponding to a rise in input electrical power of 3700 watts.</p>

<p> The load current of the DM of 10 amperes amounts to the total
electrical input to the DM of 5000 watts, out of which 1300 watts is
utilised to overcome the no-load losses.</p>

<p> The remaining electrical input of 3700 watts generates 7839 watts of
electrical output power, giving the efficiency of space power
generation in this particular as 211.8%.</p>

<p> Assuming electromagnetic efficiency of the DM as 80%, the efficiency
of the electrical energy generation of the <ent type='ORG'>SPG</ent> will rise to 264.75%.</p>

<p> If the excitation power of 2400 watts given to the <ent type='ORG'>SPG</ent> is deducted
from the total electrical output from the <ent type='ORG'>SPG</ent> of 7839 watts, the
balance electrical output of 5439 watts still exceeds the total
electrical input of 5000 watts by 439 watts, giving the total system
efficiency of 105.9% while, in addition the DM-<ent type='ORG'>SPG</ent> set runs as a
perpetual system drawing 1300 watts of power from space.</p>

<p> QUANTUM OF SPACE POWER:</p>

<p> The quantum of electrical charge produced due to the rotation of
space in a rotating electromagnet and the electrical power produced
when the power is withdrawn through an electric circuit, as
discussed in earlier article [2], is given by,</p>

<p> P = (1.8) LN(r^2)(10^-5)kW
(1)</p>

<p> where, P is power in kW, L is axial length of the <ent type='ORG'>SPG</ent> in centimeter,
N is revolution per second, and 'r' is the radius in centimeter of
the <ent type='ORG'>SPG</ent> on the inner rotor surface.</p>

<p> The derivation of the above relation was based on the assumption
that the radius of the spherical void at the centre of electron as
discussed in space vortex theory [12] is 1.5 x (10^-11) cm.</p>

<p> More precise measurements in space power generation experiments,
however show that the coefficient 1.8 in equation (1) should be 2.5,
and the void radius at electron's centre should be taken as 10^-11
cm. With these corrections the space power equation (1) now
becomes:</p>

<p> P = (2.5) LN(r^2)(10^-5)kW
(2)</p>

<p> substituting the values, L=12, N=47.6, and r=11.43 in (2),</p>

<p> P = 5.85 kW</p>

<p> Since there are two units of the <ent type='ORG'>SPG</ent> on the shaft, total power from
the two units will be 11.7 kW, which is 1.5 times the output power
drawn from the machine in the above test.</p>

<p> With additional brushes and reduced contacts at about 3000 rpm, the
above machine will have capacity to produce about 12 kW of power.</p>

<p> If the <ent type='ORG'>SPG</ent> is driven at 6000 rpm both the voltages and currents will
be doubled, producing 4 times output of 48 kW. Since the excitation
power remains constant, much higher total system efficiency is
expected though the efficiency of the <ent type='ORG'>SPG</ent> as computed above will
remain constant at 211.8%.</p>

<p> CONCLUSION:</p>

<p> Mass-energy equation of <ent type='PERSON'>Einstein</ent> brought forth an universal law that
an electron like all matter contains in its structure energy. A
further enlargement of this law is that electron is itself energy,
where "energy" in physical terms is a state of vacuum in rotation.</p>

<p> Even at ordinary speed of rotation of an electromagnet, the interatomic space of the iron core develops velocity fields of vacuum
that qualitatively act like additional charge within the rotating
system and liberate orbital electrons of the iron atoms.</p>

<p> With the interaction of the magnetic field the free electrons form
polarites [23].</p>

<p> It is possible to commercially develop a machine that can not only
rotate itself perpetually but also generate additional electrical
charge in kilowatts and higher range.</p>

<p> The law of conservation of charge and the law of conservation of
energy are applicable within the systems confined to material
interactions alone and not to the medium of space which is a dynamic
entity that can rotate and create charge at ordinary speeds, and can
rotate and create electrons at speed of light.</p>

<p> REFERENCES:</p>

<p> 1. <ent type='PERSON'>Paramahamsa Tewari</ent> - "Beyond Matter", Printwell Publications,
<ent type='GPE'>Aligarh</ent>, India (1984).</p>

<p> 2. <ent type='PERSON'>Paramahamsa Tewari</ent> - "Generation of Electrical Power from
Absolute Vacuum by High Speed Rotation of conducting Magnetic
Cylinder",
Magnets in Your Future, Vol. 1 No. 8, August 1986, P.O. Box 580,
<ent type='NORP'>Temecula</ent>, CA 92390, <ent type='GPE'>USA</ent>.</p>

<p> 3. <ent type='PERSON'>Paramahamsa Tewari</ent> - "Interaction of Electron and <ent type='ORG'>Magnetic Field</ent>
in Space Power Generation Phenomenon", Magnets in Your Future,
Vol. 2 No. 12, December 1987, P.O. Box 580, <ent type='NORP'>Temecula</ent>, Ca. 92390,
<ent type='GPE'>USA</ent>.</p>

<p> 4. Report on the Initial Testing Phase of DePalma Energy
Corporation, N1 Electrical Power Generator, 6-1-1988 -
Bruce DePalma, DePalma Energy Corporation, 1060 <ent type='ORG'>Channel Drive</ent>,
<ent type='GPE'>Santa Barbara</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>California</ent>
93108, (805) 969-6442.</p>

<p>X-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-X</p>

<p> Another file downloaded from: NIRVANAnet(tm)</p>

<p> &amp; <ent type='ORG'>the Temple</ent> of the Screaming Electron Jeff Hunter 510-935-5845
Rat Head Ratsnatcher 510-524-3649
Burn This Flag Zardoz 408-363-9766
<ent type='PERSON'>realitycheck Poindexter Fortran</ent> 415-567-7043
Lies Unlimited <ent type='PERSON'>Mick Freen</ent> 415-583-4102</p>

<p> Specializing in conversations, obscure information, high explosives,
arcane knowledge, political extremism, diversive sexuality,
insane speculation, and wild rumours. ALL-TEXT BBS SYSTEMS.</p>

<p> Full access for first-time callers. We don't want to know who you are,
where you live, or what your phone number is. We are not Big Brother.</p>

<p> "Raw Data for Raw Nerves"</p>

<p>X-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-X
</p></xml>