<xml>

<p> A QUICK LESSON IN DO-IT-YOURSELF EMBALMING</p>

<p>FROM 'THE BATHROOM ALMANAC' BY GUS MCLEAVY (<ent type='ORG'>FREDERICK FELL PUBLISHERS</ent>, INC.)</p>

<p>TYPED IN 80 COLUMNS BY BIG BAD BARBARIAN (PARDON MY BAD TASTE.)</p>

<p> TO BEGIN, YOU'LL NEED THREE TO SIX GALLONS OF EMBALMING FLUID. IF YOU
CAN'T FIND A BRAND NAME FLUID YOU CAN MIX YOUR OWN, USING <ent type='ORG'>DYED</ent> AND <ent type='ORG'>PERFUMED</ent>
FORMALDEHYDES, GLYCERINE, BORAX, PHENOL, <ent type='ORG'>ALCOHOL</ent>, AND WATER. THE PROPORTIONS
AREN'T TOO IMPORTANT TO THE FINISHED PRODUCT, AS DR. JESSE CARR WILL EXPLAIN
LATER.</p>

<p> FIRST OF ALL, THE MOUTH MUST BE SEWN TOGETHER AT THE INSIDE OF THE LIPS.
(THE NEEDLE IS BROUGHT OUT THROUGH THE NOSTRIL, USUALLY THE LEFT ONE.) THEN
YOU TAKE A TROCAR, A LONG HOLLOW NEEDLE ATTACHED TO A <ent type='ORG'>TUBE</ent>. DRAIN THE CONTENTS
OF THE <ent type='ORG'>ABDOMINAL</ent> AND CHEST CAVITIES, AND REPLACE THE REMOVED MATTER WITH CAVITY
FLUID. PUMP OUT THE CIRCULATORY SYSTEM, REPLACE THE BLOOD AND PLASMA WITH THE
ENBALMING SOLUTION, AND THAT'S ABOUT IT. IN EIGHT TO TEN HOURS THE TISSUES WILL
BE FIRM AND DRY, AND READY FOR 'COSMETIC RESTORATION.'</p>

<p> CAREFUL, THOUGH! REGULAR ENBALMING FLUID WORKS DIFFERENTLY ON VARIOUS
BODIES ACCORDING TO THE CAUSE OF DEATH. WHILE IT WILL GIVE A PLEASANT PINK GLOW
TO THE FLESH OF A VICTIM OF CARBON MONOXIDE POISONING, WHEN IT IS USED ON
SOMEONE <ent type='ORG'>WHO</ent> DIED OF JAUNDICE IT IMPARTS A GREEN TINGE THAT REQUIRES A LOT OF
MAKE-UP TO CONCEAL.</p>

<p> ALTHOUGH IT IS WIDELY BELIEVED TO PRESERVE A BURIED BODY, EMBALMING IN
FACT DOES NO SUCH THING. IF IT HAS ANY WORTHWHILE PURPOSE AT ALL, IT IS TO MAKE
THE OPEN <ent type='ORG'>CASKET</ent> FUNERAL MORE PALATABLE. DR. JESSE CARR IS NO FRIEND OF THE
MORTUARY INDUSTRY, BUT HE IS A FORMER CHIEF OF PATHOLOGY AT SAN FRANCISCO
GENERAL HOSPITAL AND PROFESSOR OF PATHOLOGY AT THE UNIVERSITY OF CALIFORNIA
MEDICAL SCHOOL, AND HERE'S WHAT HE HAS TO SAY ABOUT IT:</p>

<p> AN EXHUMED BODY IS A <ent type='ORG'>REPUGNANT</ent>, MOLDY, FOUL-LOOKING OBJECT. IT'S NOT
THE IMAGE OF ONE <ent type='ORG'>WHO</ent> HAS BEEN LOVED . . . THE BODY ITSELF MAY BE
INTACT, AS FAR AS CONTOURS AND SO ON; BUT THE SILK LINING OF THE
<ent type='ORG'>CASKET</ent> IS ALL STAINED WITH BODY FLUIDS, THE WOOD IS ROTTING, AND THE
BODY IS COVERED WITH MOLD . . . IF YOU SEAL UP A <ent type='ORG'>CASKET</ent> SO IT IS
MORE OR LESS <ent type='ORG'>AIRTIGHT</ent>, YOU SEAL IN THE <ent type='ORG'>ANAEROBIC</ent> BACTERIA - THE KIND
THAT <ent type='ORG'>THRIVE</ent> IN AN AIRLESS ATMOSPHERE, YOU SEE. THESE ARE THE
PUTREFACTIVE BACTERIA, AND THE RESULTS OF THEIR GROWTH ARE PRETTY
HORRIBLE . . . YOU'RE BETTER OFF WITH A <ent type='ORG'>SHROUD</ent>, AND NO <ent type='ORG'>CASKET</ent> AT
ALL.</p>

<p> ///////////////////////////////////////////////////////
// The PIRATES' HOLLOW //
// 415-236-2371 //
// over 12 <ent type='PERSON'>Megs</ent> of Elite Text Files //
// ROR-ALUCARD //
// <ent type='NORP'>Sysop</ent>: Doctor <ent type='PERSON'>Murdock</ent> //
// C0-<ent type='NORP'>Sysop</ent>s: That One, Sir Death, Sid Gnarly &amp; Finn //
// //
// "The Gates of Hell are open night and day; //
// <ent type='PERSON'>Smooth</ent> is the Descent, and <ent type='ORG'>Easy</ent> is the way.." //
///////////////////////////////////////////////////////</p>

<div> </div>

<p>X-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-X</p>

<p> Another file downloaded from: NIRVANAnet(tm)</p>

<p> &amp; <ent type='ORG'>the Temple</ent> of the Screaming Electron Jeff Hunter 510-935-5845
Rat Head Ratsnatcher 510-524-3649
Burn This Flag Zardoz 408-363-9766
<ent type='PERSON'>realitycheck Poindexter Fortran</ent> 415-567-7043
Lies Unlimited <ent type='PERSON'>Mick Freen</ent> 415-583-4102</p>

<p> Specializing in conversations, obscure information, high explosives,
arcane knowledge, political extremism, diversive sexuality,
insane speculation, and wild rumours. ALL-TEXT BBS SYSTEMS.</p>

<p> Full access for first-time callers. We don't want to know who you are,
where you live, or what your phone number is. We are not Big Brother.</p>

<p> "Raw Data for Raw Nerves"

X-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-X
</p></xml>