<xml><p>
----<ent type='ORG'>FEMA</ent> pt 2 continued ----------------------------------------------



Even those Executive Orders which have been made public tend to
raise as many questions as they answer about what actions were
considered and actually implemented. On January 8, 1991, <ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent> signed
Executive Order 12742, National Security Industrial Responsiveness,
which ordered the rapid mobilization of resources such as food,
energy, construction materials and civil transportation to meet
national <ent type='ORG'>sec</ent>urity requirements. There was, however, no mention in
this or any other EO of <ent type='ORG'>the National Defense Executive Reserve</ent> (<ent type='ORG'>NDER</ent>)
plan administered under <ent type='ORG'>FEMA</ent>. This plan, which had been activated
during <ent type='EVENT'>World War</ent> II and <ent type='EVENT'>the Korean War</ent>, permits the federal government
during a state of emergency to bring into government certain
unidentified individuals. On January 7, 1991 the "<ent type='ORG'>Wall Street Journal</ent>
Europe" reported that industry and government officials were studying
a plan which would permit the federal government to "borrow" as many
as 50 oil company executives and put them to work streamlining the
flow of energy in case of a prolonged engagement or disruption of
supply. <ent type='ORG'>Antitrust</ent> waivers were also being pursued and oil companies
were engaged in emergency preparedness exercises with <ent type='ORG'>the Department</ent>
of Energy.[5]

Wasting the Environment
In one case the use of <ent type='ORG'>sec</ent>ret powers was discovered by a watchdog
group and revealed in the press. In August 1990, correspondence
passed between Colin McMillan, Assistant Secretary of <ent type='ORG'>Defense for</ent>
Production and Logistics and <ent type='PERSON'>Michael Deland</ent>, Chair of <ent type='ORG'>the White House</ent>
Council on Environmental Quality. The letters responded to
presidential and <ent type='ORG'>National Security Council</ent> directives to deal with
increased industrial production and logistics arising from the
situation in <ent type='LOC'>the Middle East</ent>. The communications revealed that the
<ent type='ORG'>Pentagon</ent> had found it necessary to request emergency waivers to U.S.
environmental restrictions.[6]
The agreement to waive <ent type='ORG'>the National Environmental Policy Act</ent> (1970)
came in August. Because of it, the <ent type='ORG'>Pentagon</ent> was allowed to test new
weapons in the western U.S., increase production of materiel and
launch new activities at military bases without the complex public
review normally required. The information on the waiver was
eventually released by the <ent type='GPE'>Boston</ent>-based <ent type='ORG'>National Toxic Campaign Fund</ent>
(<ent type='ORG'>NTCF</ent>), an environmental group which investigates pollution on the
nation's military bases. It was not until January 30, 1991, five
months after it went into effect, that the "<ent type='ORG'>New York</ent> Times," acting
on the <ent type='ORG'>NTCF</ent> information, reported that <ent type='ORG'>the White House</ent> had bypassed
the usual legal requirement for environmental impact statements on
<ent type='ORG'>Pentagon</ent> projects.[7] So far, no specific executive order or
presidential finding authorizing this waiver has been discovered.
Other environmental waivers could also have been enacted without
the public being informed. Under a state of national emergency, U.S.
warships can be exempted from international conventions on
pollution[8] and public vessels can be allowed to dispose of
potentially infectious medical wastes into the oceans.[9] The
President can also suspend any of the statutory provisions regarding
the production, testing, transportation, deployment, and disposal of
chemical and biological warfare agents (50 <ent type='ORG'>USC</ent> <ent type='ORG'>sec</ent>. 1515). He could
also defer destruction of up to 10 percent of lethal chemical agents
and munitions that existed on November 8, 1985.[10]
One Executive Order which was made public dealt with "<ent type='ORG'>Chemical</ent> and
Biological Weapons Proliferation." Signed by <ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent> on November 16,
1990, EO 12735 leaves the impression that <ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent> is ordering an
increased effort to end the proliferation of chemical and biological
weapons. The order states that these weapons "constitute a threat to
national <ent type='ORG'>sec</ent>urity and foreign policy" and declares a national
emergency to deal with the threat. To confront this threat, <ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent>
ordered international negotiations, the imposition of controls,
licenses, and sanctions against foreign persons and countries for
proliferation. Conveniently, the order grants <ent type='ORG'>the Secretaries</ent> of
State and the <ent type='ORG'>Treasury</ent> the power to exempt the U.S. military.
In February of 1991, the Omnibus Export Amendments Act was passed
by <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent> compatible with EO 12735. It imposed sanctions on
countries and companies developing or using chemical or biological
weapons. <ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent> signed the law, although he had rejected the identical
measure the year before because it did not give him the executive
power to waive all sanctions if he thought the national interest
required it.[11] The new bill, however, met Bush's requirements.

____________________________________________________________________
| BUSH'S EXECUTIVE ORDERS
| * EO 12722 "Blocking <ent type='GPE'>Iraq</ent>i Government Property and
Prohibiting Transactions With <ent type='GPE'>Iraq</ent>," Aug. 2, 1990.
| * EO 12723 "Blocking <ent type='GPE'>Kuwait</ent>i Government Property," Aug. 2,
1990.
| * EO 12724 "Blocking <ent type='GPE'>Iraq</ent>i Government Property and
Prohibiting Transactions With <ent type='GPE'>Iraq</ent>," Aug. 9, 1990.
| * EO 12725 "Blocking <ent type='GPE'>Kuwait</ent>i Government Property and
Prohibiting Transactions With <ent type='GPE'>Kuwait</ent>," Aug. 9, 1990.
| * EO 12727 "Ordering <ent type='ORG'>the Selected Reserve</ent> of the Armed
Forces to Active Duty," Aug. 22, 1990.
| * EO 12728 "Delegating the President's Authority To
Suspend Any Provision of Law Relating to the Promotion,
Retirement, or Separation of Members of <ent type='ORG'>the Armed Forces</ent>,"
Aug. 22, 1990.
| * EO 12733 "Authorizing the Extension of the Period of
Active Duty of Personnel of <ent type='ORG'>the Selected Reserve</ent> of the
Armed Forces," Nov. 13, 1990.
| * EO 12734 "National Emergency Construction Authority," Nov.
14, 1990.
| * EO 12735 "<ent type='ORG'>Chemical</ent> and Biological Weapons Proliferation,"
Nov. 16, 1990.
| * EO 12738 "Administration of Foreign Assistance and Related
Functions and Arms Export Control," Dec. 14, 1990.
| * EO 12742 "National Security Industrial Responsiveness,"
Jan. 8, 1991.
| * EO 12743 "Ordering the Ready Reserve of <ent type='ORG'>the Armed Forces</ent>
to Active Duty," Jan. 18, 1991.
| * EO 12744 "Designation of Arabian Peninsula Areas, Airspace
and Adjacent Waters as a Combat Zone," Jan. 21, 1991.
| * EO 12750 "Designation of Arabian Peninsula Areas, Airspace
and Adjacent Waters as the Persian <ent type='LOC'>Gulf</ent> Desert Shield
Area," Feb. 14, 1991.
| * EO 12751 "Health Care Services for Operation Desert
Storm," Feb. 14, 1991.
--------------------------------------------------------------------

Going Off Budget
Although some of the powers which <ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent> assumed in order to conduct
<ent type='EVENT'>the Gulf War</ent> were taken openly, they received little public discussion
or reporting by the media.
In October, when the winds of <ent type='EVENT'>the Gulf War</ent> were merely a breeze,
<ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent> used his executive emergency powers to extend his budget
authority. This action made the 1991 fiscal budget agreement between
<ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent> and the President one of the first U.S. casualties of the
war. While on one hand the deal froze arms spending through 1996, it
also allowed <ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent> to put the cost of <ent type='EVENT'>the Gulf War</ent> "off budget." Thus,
using its emergency powers, the <ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent> administration could:

* incur a deficit which exceeds congressional budget authority;

* prevent <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent> from raising a point of order over the
excessive spending;[12]

* waive the requirement that the Secretary of <ent type='ORG'>Defense</ent> submit
estimates to <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent> prior to deployment of a major defense
acquisition system;

* and exempt the <ent type='ORG'>Pentagon</ent> from congressional restrictions on
hiring private contractors.[13]

While there is no published evidence on which powers <ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent> actually
invoked, the administration was able to push through the 1990 Omnibus
Reconciliation Act. This legislation put a cap on domestic spending,
created a record $300 billion deficit, and undermined the <ent type='PERSON'>Gramm</ent>-Rudman-Hollings Act intended to reduce the federal deficit. Although
<ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent> agreed to pay for the war through supplemental appropriations
and approved a $42.2 billion supplemental bill and a $4.8 billion
companion "dire emergency supplemental appropriation,"[14] it
specified that the supplemental budget should not be used to finance
costs the <ent type='ORG'>Pentagon</ent> would normally experience.[15]
Lawrence <ent type='PERSON'>Korb</ent>, a <ent type='ORG'>Pentagon</ent> official in the Reagan administration,
believes that the <ent type='ORG'>Pentagon</ent> has already violated the spirit of the 1990
Omnibus Reconciliation Act. It switched funding for the <ent type='ORG'>Patriot</ent>,
Tomahawk, Hellfire and <ent type='ORG'>HARM</ent> missiles from its regular budget to the
supplemental budget; added normal wear and tear of equipment to
supplemental appropriations; and made supplemental requests which
ignore a planned 25% reduction in the armed forces by 1995.[16]

The Cost In Liberty Lost
Under emergency circumstances, using 50 <ent type='ORG'>USC</ent> <ent type='ORG'>sec</ent>. 1811, the
President could direct the Attorney General to authorize electronic
surveillance of aliens and <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> citizens in order to obtain
foreign intelligence information without a court order.[17] No
Executive Order has been published which activates emergency powers to
wiretap or to engage in counter-terrorist activity. Nonetheless,
there is substantial evidence that such activities have taken place.
According to the <ent type='ORG'>New York</ent>-based <ent type='ORG'>Center for</ent> Constitutional Rights, the
<ent type='ORG'>FBI</ent> launched an anti-terrorist campaign which included a broad sweep
of Arab-<ent type='NORP'>American</ent>s. Starting in August, the <ent type='ORG'>FBI</ent> questioned, detained,
and harassed Arab-<ent type='NORP'>American</ent>s in <ent type='GPE'>California</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>New York</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Ohio</ent>,
<ent type='GPE'>Pennsylvania</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Virginia</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Maryland</ent>, and <ent type='GPE'>Colorado</ent>.[18]
A <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> agent asked <ent type='ORG'>the University</ent> of Connecticut for a list of all
foreign students at the institution, along with their country of
origin, major field of study, and the names of their academic
advisers. He was particularly interested in students from the Middle
East and explained that the <ent type='ORG'>Agency</ent> intended to open a file on each of
the students. Anti-war groups have also reported several break-ins of
their offices and many suspected electronic surveillance of their
telephones.[19]

Pool of Disinformation
Emergency powers to control the means of communications in the U.S.
in the name of national <ent type='ORG'>sec</ent>urity were never formally declared. There
was no need for <ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent> to do so since most of the media voluntarily and
even eagerly cooperated in their own censorship. Reporters covering
the Coalition forces in the <ent type='LOC'>Gulf</ent> region operated under restrictions
imposed by the U.S. military. They were, among other things, barred
from traveling without a military escort, limited in their forays into
the field to small escorted groups called "pools," and required to
submit all reports and film to military censors for clearance. Some
reporters complained that the rules limited their ability to gather
information independently, thereby obstructing informed and objective
reporting.[20]
Three <ent type='ORG'>Pentagon</ent> press officials in the <ent type='LOC'>Gulf</ent> region admitted to James
LeMoyne of the "<ent type='ORG'>New York</ent> Times" that they spent significant time
analyzing reporters' stories in order to shape the coverage in the
Pentagon's favor. In the early days of the deployment, <ent type='ORG'>Pentagon</ent> press
officers warned reporters who asked hard questions that they were seen
as "anti-military" and that their requests for interviews with senior
commanders and visits to the field were in jeopardy. The military
often staged events solely for the cameras and would stop televised
interviews in progress when it did not like what was being portrayed.
Although filed soon after the beginning of the war, a lawsuit
challenging the constitutionality of press restrictions was not heard
until after the war ended. It was then dismissed when the judge ruled
that since the war had ended, the issues raised had become moot. The
legal status of the restrictions--initially tested during the U.S.
invasions of <ent type='GPE'>Grenada</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Panama</ent>--remains unsettled.

A <ent type='ORG'>National Misfortune</ent>
It will be years before researchers and journalists are able to
ferret through the maze of government documents and give a full
appraisal of the impact of the President's emergency powers on
domestic affairs. It is likely, however, that with a post-war
presidential approval rating exceeding 75 percent, the domestic
casualties will continue to mount with few objections. Paradoxically,
even though the U.S. public put pressure on <ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent> to send relief for
the 500000 <ent type='GPE'>Iraq</ent>i Kurdish refugees, it is unlikely the same outcry
will be heard for the 37 million <ent type='NORP'>American</ent>s without health insurance,
the 32 million living in poverty, or the country's five million hungry
children. The U.S. may even help rebuild <ent type='GPE'>Kuwait</ent>i and <ent type='GPE'>Iraq</ent>i civilian
infrastructures it destroyed during the war while leaving its own
education system in decay, domestic transportation infrastructures
crumbling, and inner city war zones uninhabitable. And, while the
U.S. assists <ent type='GPE'>Kuwait</ent> in cleaning up its environmental disaster, it will
increase pollution at home. Indeed, as the long-dead <ent type='NORP'>Prussian</ent> field
marshal prophesied, "a war, even the most victorious, is a national
misfortune."

FOOTNOTES:

1. The administrative guideline was established under Reagan in Executive
Order 12656, November 181988, "<ent type='ORG'>Federal Register</ent>," vol. 23, no. 266.

2. For instance, <ent type='ORG'>National Security Council</ent> policy papers or National
Security Directives (<ent type='ORG'>NSD</ent>) or <ent type='ORG'>National Security Decision Directives</ent>
(<ent type='ORG'>NSD</ent>D) have today evolved into a network of shadowy, wide-ranging and
potent executive powers. These are <ent type='ORG'>sec</ent>ret instruments, maintained in
a top <ent type='ORG'>sec</ent>urity classified state and are not shared with <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>. For
an excellent discussion see: Harold C. <ent type='ORG'>Relyea</ent>, The Coming of Secret
Law, "Government Information Quarterly," Vol. 5, November 1988; see
also: <ent type='PERSON'>Eve Pell</ent>, "The Backbone of Hidden Government," "The Nation,"
June 191990.

3. "Letter to <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>ional Leaders Reporting on the National Emergency
With Respect to <ent type='GPE'>Iraq</ent>," February, 11, 1991, "Weekly Compilation of
Presidential Documents: Administration of George <ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent>," (<ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>,
DC: U.S. Government Printing Office), pp. 158-61.

4. The U.S. now has states of emergency with <ent type='GPE'>Iran</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Iraq</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Syria</ent>.

5. <ent type='PERSON'>Allanna Sullivan</ent>, "U.S. Oil Concerns Confident Of Riding Out Short <ent type='LOC'>Gulf</ent>
War," "<ent type='ORG'>Wall Street Journal</ent> Europe," January 7, 1991.

6. Colin McMillan, Letter to <ent type='PERSON'>Michael Deland</ent>, Chairman, Council on
Environmental Quality (<ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, DC: Executive Office of the
President), August 24, 1990; <ent type='PERSON'>Michael</ent> R. Deland, Letter to Colin
McMillan, Assistant Secretary of <ent type='ORG'>Defense for</ent> Production and Logistics
(<ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, DC: Department of <ent type='ORG'>Defense</ent>), August 291990.

7. <ent type='PERSON'>Keith Schneider</ent>, "<ent type='ORG'>Pentagon</ent> Wins Waiver Of Environmental Rule," "<ent type='ORG'>New York</ent>
Times," January 30, 1991.

8. 33 U.S. Code (<ent type='ORG'>USC</ent>) <ent type='ORG'>sec</ent>. 1902 9(b).

9. 33 <ent type='ORG'>USC</ent> <ent type='ORG'>sec</ent>. 2503 l(b).

10. 50 <ent type='ORG'>USC</ent> <ent type='ORG'>sec</ent>. 1521(b) (3)(A).

ll. <ent type='PERSON'>Adam Clymer</ent>, "<ent type='ORG'>New Bill Mandates Sanctions</ent> On Makers of <ent type='ORG'>Chemical</ent> Arms,"
"<ent type='ORG'>New York</ent> Times," February 22, 1991.

12. 31 <ent type='ORG'>USC</ent> O10005 (f); 2 <ent type='ORG'>USC</ent> O632 (i), 6419 (d), 907a (b); and Public
Law 101-508, Title X999, <ent type='ORG'>sec</ent>. 13101.

13. 10 <ent type='ORG'>USC</ent> <ent type='ORG'>sec</ent>. 2434/2461 9F.

14. When the <ent type='ORG'>Pentagon</ent> expected the war to last months and oil prices to
skyrocket, it projected the incremental cost of deploying and
redeploying the forces and waging war at about $70 billion. The
administration sought and received $56 billion in pledges from allies
such as <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Japan</ent> and Saudi Arabia. Although the military's
estimates of casualties and the war's duration were highly inflated,
today their budget estimates remain at around $70 billion even though
the <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>ional Budget office estimates that cost at only $40
billion, $16 billion less than allied pledges.

15. <ent type='PERSON'>Michael</ent> Kamish, "After <ent type='EVENT'>The War</ent>: At Home, An Unconquered Recession,"
"<ent type='GPE'>Boston</ent> Globe," March 6, 1991; <ent type='PERSON'>Peter Passell</ent>, "<ent type='ORG'>The Big Spoils</ent> From a
Bargain War," "<ent type='ORG'>New York</ent> Times," March 3, 1991; and <ent type='PERSON'>Alan Abelson</ent>, "A
War Dividend For The <ent type='ORG'>Defense</ent> Industry?" "Barron's," March 18, 1991.

16. Lawrence <ent type='PERSON'>Korb</ent>, "The Pentagon's Creative Budgetry Is Out of Line,"
"<ent type='ORG'>International Herald Tribune</ent>," April 5, 199l.

17. Many of the powers against aliens are automatically invoked during a
national emergency or state of war. Under the Alien Enemies Act (50
<ent type='ORG'>USC</ent> <ent type='ORG'>sec</ent>. 21), the President can issue an order to apprehend, restrain,
<ent type='ORG'>sec</ent>ure and remove all subjects of a hostile nation over 13 years old.
Other statutes conferring special powers on the President with regard
to aliens that may be exercised in times of war or emergencies but are
not confined to such circumstances, are: exclusion of all or certain
classes of aliens from entry into the U.S. when their entry may be
"detrimental to the interests of <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States" (8 <ent type='ORG'>USC</ent> <ent type='ORG'>sec</ent>. 1182(f));
imposition of travel restrictions on aliens within the U.S. (8 <ent type='ORG'>USC</ent> <ent type='ORG'>sec</ent>.
1185); and requiring aliens to be fingerprinted (8 <ent type='ORG'>USC</ent> <ent type='ORG'>sec</ent>. 1302).

18. <ent type='PERSON'>Ann Talamas</ent>, "<ent type='ORG'>FBI</ent> Targets Arab-<ent type='NORP'>American</ent>s," "<ent type='ORG'>CAIB</ent>," Spring 1991, p. 4.

19. "Anti-Repression Project Bulletin" (<ent type='ORG'>New York</ent>: <ent type='ORG'>Center for</ent>
Constitutional Rights), January 23, 1991.

20. James DeParle, "Long Series of Military Decisions Led to <ent type='LOC'>Gulf</ent> War News
Censorship," "<ent type='ORG'>New York</ent> Times," May 5, 1991.

21. James LeMoyne, "A Correspondent's Tale: Pentagon's Strategy for the
Press: Good News or No News," "<ent type='ORG'>New York</ent> Times," February 17, 1991.

______________________________________________________________________________
Covert Action INFORMATION BULLETIN

Back Issues

No. 1 (July 1978): <ent type='PERSON'>Agee</ent> on <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>; <ent type='NORP'>Cuban</ent> exile trial; consumer research-<ent type='GPE'>Jamaica</ent>.*
No. 2 (Oct. 1978): How <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> recruits diplomats; researching undercover
officers; double agent in <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>.*
No. 3 (Jan. 1979): <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> attacks <ent type='ORG'>CAIB</ent>; <ent type='ORG'>sec</ent>ret supp. to <ent type='ORG'>Army</ent> field manual;
spying on host countries.*
No. 4 (Apr.-May 1979): U.S. spies in <ent type='NORP'>Italian</ent> services; <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> in <ent type='GPE'>Spain</ent>; <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>
recruiting for <ent type='LOC'>Africa</ent>; subversive academics; <ent type='GPE'>Angola</ent>.*
No. 5 (July-Aug. 1979): U.S. intelligence in <ent type='LOC'><ent type='NORP'>South</ent>east <ent type='LOC'>Asia</ent></ent>; <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> in
<ent type='GPE'>Denmark</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Sweden</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Grenada</ent>.*
No. 6 (Oct. 1979): U.S. in <ent type='LOC'>Caribbean</ent>; <ent type='NORP'>Cuban</ent> exile terrorists; <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> plans
for <ent type='GPE'>Nicaragua</ent>; CIA's <ent type='ORG'>sec</ent>ret "Perspectives for Intelligence."*
No. 7 (Dec. 1979-Jan. 1980): Media destabilization in <ent type='GPE'>Jamaica</ent>; Robert
<ent type='ORG'>Moss</ent>; <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> budget; media operations; <ent type='ORG'>UNITA</ent>; <ent type='GPE'>Iran</ent>.*
No. 8 (Mar.-Apr. 1980): Attacks on <ent type='PERSON'>Agee</ent>; U.S. intelligence legislation;
<ent type='ORG'>CAIB</ent> statement to <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>; <ent type='GPE'>Zimbabwe</ent>; <ent type='PERSON'>Northern</ent> Ireland.
No. 9 (June 1980): <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent> in <ent type='GPE'>Norway</ent>; <ent type='PERSON'>Glomar Explorer</ent>; mind control; <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent>.
No. 10 (Aug.-Sept. 1980): <ent type='LOC'>Caribbean</ent>; destabilization in <ent type='GPE'>Jamaica</ent>; <ent type='GPE'>Guyana</ent>;
<ent type='GPE'>Grenada</ent> bombing; "The <ent type='PERSON'>Spike</ent>"; deep cover manual.
No. 11 (Dec. 1980): Rightwing terrorism; <ent type='GPE'>South Korea</ent>; K<ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>; <ent type='GPE'>Portugal</ent>;
<ent type='GPE'>Guyana</ent>; <ent type='LOC'>Caribbean</ent>; AFIO; <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent> interview.
No. 12 (Apr. 1981): U.S. in <ent type='GPE'>Salvador</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Guatemala</ent>; New Right; William
Casey; <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> in <ent type='GPE'>Mozambique</ent>; mail surveillance.*
No. 13 (July-Aug. 1981): <ent type='NORP'>South</ent> <ent type='LOC'>Africa</ent> documents; <ent type='GPE'>Namibia</ent>; mercenaries;
the <ent type='ORG'>Klan</ent>; Globe Aero; <ent type='GPE'>Angola</ent>; <ent type='GPE'>Mozambique</ent>; <ent type='ORG'>BOSS</ent>; <ent type='LOC'>Central America</ent>;
<ent type='PERSON'>Max Hugel</ent>; mail surveillance.
No. 14-15 (Oct. 1981): Complete index to nos. 1-12; review of intelligence
legislation; <ent type='ORG'>CAIB</ent> plans; extended Naming Names.
No. 16 (Mar. 1982): <ent type='ORG'>Green Beret</ent> torture in <ent type='GPE'>Salvador</ent>; <ent type='NORP'>Argentine</ent> death squads;
<ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> media ops; <ent type='GPE'>Seychelles</ent>; <ent type='GPE'>Angola</ent>; <ent type='GPE'>Mozambique</ent>; the <ent type='ORG'>Klan</ent>; Nugan Hand.*
No. 17 (Summer 1982): CBW History; <ent type='NORP'>Cuban</ent> dengue epidemic; <ent type='PERSON'>Scott Barnes</ent>
and yellow rain lies; mystery death in <ent type='GPE'>Bangkok</ent>.*
No. 18 (Winter 1983): <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> &amp; religion; "<ent type='ORG'>sec</ent>ret" war in <ent type='GPE'>Nicaragua</ent>; Opus Dei;
<ent type='GPE'>Miskitos</ent>; evangelicals-<ent type='GPE'>Guatemala</ent>; <ent type='ORG'>Summer Inst</ent>. of Linguistics; World
Medical Relief; <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> &amp; <ent type='ORG'>BOSS</ent>; torture S. <ent type='LOC'>Africa</ent>; <ent type='GPE'>Vietnam</ent> defoliation.*
No. 19 (Spring-Summer 1983): <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> &amp; media; history of disinformation;
"plot" against <ent type='PERSON'>Pope</ent>; <ent type='GPE'>Grenada</ent> airport; <ent type='PERSON'>Georgie Anne Geyer</ent>.
No. 20 (Winter 1984): Invasion of <ent type='GPE'>Grenada</ent>; war in <ent type='GPE'>Nicaragua</ent>; Ft. Huachuca;
<ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>South Korea</ent> in <ent type='LOC'>Central America</ent>; <ent type='ORG'>KAL</ent> flight 007.
No. 21 (Spring 1984): N.Y. Times and the <ent type='GPE'>Salvador</ent> election; Time and
Newsweek in distortions; Accuracy in Media; <ent type='GPE'>Nicaragua</ent>.
No. 22 (Fall 1984): Mercenaries &amp; terrorism; Soldier of Fortune; "privatizing"
the war in <ent type='GPE'>Nicaragua</ent>; U.S.-<ent type='NORP'>South</ent> <ent type='LOC'>Africa</ent>n terrorism; <ent type='NORP'>Italian</ent> fascists.
No. 23 (Spring 1985): Special issue on "plot" to kill the <ent type='PERSON'>Pope</ent> and the
"<ent type='NORP'>Bulgarian</ent> Connection"; <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> ties to <ent type='NORP'>Turkish</ent> and <ent type='NORP'>Italian</ent> <ent type='ORG'>neofascists</ent>.
No. 24 (Summer 1985): State repression, infiltrators, provocateurs;
sanctuary movement; <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Indian</ent> Movement; <ent type='PERSON'>Leonard Peltier</ent>;
<ent type='ORG'>NASSCO</ent> strike; Arnaud de Borchgrave, <ent type='LOC'>Moon</ent>, and <ent type='ORG'>Moss</ent>; Tetra Tech.
No. 25 (Winter 1986): U.S., <ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent>, and the <ent type='ORG'>Vatican</ent>; Knights of Malta;
Greek civil war and <ent type='NORP'>Eleni</ent>; <ent type='ORG'>WACL</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Nicaragua</ent>; torture.
No. 26 (Summer 1986): U.S. state terrorism; <ent type='PERSON'>Vernon Walters</ent>; <ent type='GPE'>Libya</ent> bombing;
contra agents; <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent> and <ent type='NORP'>South</ent> <ent type='LOC'>Africa</ent>; Duarte; media in Costa
Rica; democracy in <ent type='GPE'>Nicaragua</ent>; plus complete index to nos. 13-25.*
No. 27 (Spring 1987): Special: Religious Right; <ent type='ORG'>New York</ent> Times and <ent type='PERSON'>Pope</ent>
Plot; Carlucci; <ent type='NORP'>South</ent>ern Air Transport; <ent type='PERSON'>Michael</ent> Ledeen.*
No. 28 (Summer 1987): Special: <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> and drugs: S.E. <ent type='LOC'>Asia</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Afghanistan</ent>,
<ent type='LOC'>Central America</ent>; Nugan Hand; <ent type='ORG'>MKULTRA</ent> in <ent type='GPE'>Canada</ent>; <ent type='ORG'>Delta Force</ent>;
special <ent type='ORG'>sec</ent>tion on AIDS theories and CBW.*
No. 29 (Winter 1988): Special issue on <ent type='NORP'>Pacific</ent>: Philippines, <ent type='GPE'>Fiji</ent>, New
Zealand, <ent type='GPE'>Belau</ent>, <ent type='NORP'>Kanaky</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Vanuatu</ent>; atom testing; media on <ent type='GPE'>Nicaragua</ent>;
Reader's Digest; <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> in <ent type='GPE'>Cuba</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Tibet</ent>; <ent type='PERSON'>Agee</ent> on "Veil;" more on AIDS.*
No. 30 (Summer 1989): Special: <ent type='LOC'>Middle East</ent>: The intifada, <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent>i arms
sales; <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent> in <ent type='LOC'>Africa</ent>; disinformation and <ent type='GPE'>Libya</ent>; CIA's William
Buckley; the <ent type='NORP'>Afghan</ent> arms pipeline and contra lobby.
No. 31 (Winter 1989): Special issue on domestic surveillance. The <ent type='ORG'>FBI</ent>; <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>
on campus; Office of Public Diplomacy; Lexington Prison; <ent type='GPE'>Puerto Rico</ent>.
No. 32 (Summer 1989): Tenth Year Anniversary Issue: The Best of <ent type='ORG'>CAIB</ent>.
Includes articles from our earliest issues, Naming Names, <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> at home,
abroad, and in the media. Ten-year perspective by Philip <ent type='PERSON'>Agee</ent>.
No. 33 (Winter 1990): The <ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent> Issue: <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> agents for <ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent>; Terrorism Task
Force; El <ent type='GPE'>Salvador</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Nicaragua</ent> intervention; <ent type='NORP'>Republicans</ent> and <ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent>.
No. 34 (Summer 1990): Assassination of <ent type='PERSON'>Martin Luther King</ent> Jr; <ent type='GPE'>Nicaragua</ent>n
elections; <ent type='NORP'>South</ent> <ent type='LOC'>Africa</ent>n death squads; U.S. and <ent type='PERSON'>Pol Pot</ent>; Pan Am
Flight 103; <ent type='PERSON'>Noriega</ent> and the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>; <ent type='ORG'>Council for National Policy</ent>.
No. 35 (Fall 1990): Special: Eastern Europe; Analysis-Persian <ent type='LOC'>Gulf</ent> and
<ent type='GPE'>Cuba</ent>; massacres in <ent type='GPE'>Indonesia</ent>; <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>Banks</ent>; <ent type='GPE'>Iran</ent>-contra
No. 36 (Spring 1991): Racism &amp; Nat. Security: <ent type='ORG'>FBI</ent> v. Arab-<ent type='NORP'>American</ent>s &amp; Black
Officials; Special: Destabilizing <ent type='LOC'>Africa</ent>: <ent type='GPE'>Chad</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Uganda</ent>, S. <ent type='LOC'>Africa</ent>,
<ent type='GPE'>Angola</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Mozambique</ent>, Zaire; <ent type='GPE'>Haiti</ent>; <ent type='GPE'>Panama</ent>; <ent type='LOC'>Gulf</ent> War; COINTELPRO "art."
No. 37 (Summer 1990): Special: <ent type='LOC'>Gulf</ent> War: Media; U.N.; <ent type='GPE'>Libya</ent>; <ent type='GPE'>Iran</ent>;
Domestic costs; <ent type='PERSON'>North</ent> Korea Next? Illegal Arms Deals.

* Available in Photocopy only

Subscriptions (4 issues/year) (check one)

___$17 one year ___$32 two years U.S.
___$22 one year ___$42 two years <ent type='GPE'>Canada</ent>/Mexico
___$27 one year ___$52 two years <ent type='LOC'>Latin America</ent>/Europe
___$29 one year ___$56 two years Other
$5 per year addition charge for institutions

Books, etc.
$25 "Dirty Work II: The <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> in <ent type='LOC'>Africa</ent>," Ray, et al.
$10 "Deadly Deceits: 25 Years in <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>," McGehee
$8 "Secret Contenders: <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> and <ent type='EVENT'>Cold War</ent>," Beck
$6.50 "White Paper/Whitewash," <ent type='PERSON'>Agee</ent>/Poelchau
$10 "On The Run," <ent type='PERSON'>Agee</ent>
$1 "No <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>" buttons (additionals $.50)

BACK ISSUES: <ent type='ORG'>Circle</ent> above, or list below. $6 per copy in U.S.
Airmail: <ent type='GPE'>Canada</ent>/Mexico add $2; other countries add $4.

<ent type='ORG'>CAIB</ent>, P.O. Box 34583, <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, DC 20043

--
daveus rattus

yer friendly neighborhood ratman

KOYAANISQATSI

ko.yan.nis.qatsi (from <ent type='EVENT'>the Hopi Language</ent>) n. 1. crazy life. 2. life
in turmoil. 3. life out of balance. 4. life disintegrating.
5. a state of life that calls for another way of living.



KOYAANISQATSI

ko.yan.nis.qatsi (from <ent type='EVENT'>the Hopi Language</ent>) n. 1. crazy life. 2. life
in turmoil. 3. life out of balance. 4. life disintegrating.
5. a state of life that calls for another way of living.


</p></xml>