<xml><p>Subject: Leaflet: <ent type='NORP'>Freemasonry</ent> and Society</p>

<p>This is the text of a leaflet published by by <ent type='ORG'>the Board</ent> of
General Purposes of <ent type='ORG'>the United Grand Lodge</ent> of England in 1987.</p>

<p> <ent type='NORP'>Freemasonry</ent> and Society</p>

<p>Introduction:
This leaflet is intended to expand a topic mentioned in the
leaflet "What is <ent type='NORP'>Freemasonry</ent>". It explains <ent type='ORG'>the United Grand Lodge</ent> of
England's view on <ent type='NORP'>Freemasonry</ent> and Society.</p>

<p>Respect for the law:
<ent type='NORP'>Freemasonry</ent> demands from its members a respect for the law of any
country in which a man may work and live.</p>

<p>Principles:
The principles of <ent type='NORP'>Freemasonry</ent> do not in any way conflict with its
members' duties as citizens, whether at work or at home or in public
life, but on the contrary should strengthen them in fulfulling their
private and public responsibilities.

Use of Membership:
A <ent type='NORP'>Freemason</ent> must not use his membership to promote his own or
anyone else's business, professional or personal interests. This is
made clear directly or by inference several times during a Freemason's
early career so that no <ent type='NORP'>Freemason</ent> can pretend to be ignorant of it. A
<ent type='NORP'>Freemason</ent> who transgresses this rule may be suspended from <ent type='NORP'>Masonic</ent>
activities or even expelled.</p>

<p>Family:
<ent type='NORP'>Freemasonry</ent> should not be allowed to harm a man's family or
other connections by taking too much of his time or his money or
causing him to act in any other way against their interests.</p>

<p>Duty as a citizen:
A Freemason's duty as a citizen must always prevail over any
obligation to other <ent type='NORP'>Freemason</ent>s, and any attempt to shield a <ent type='NORP'>Freemason</ent>
who has acted dishonourably or unlawfully or to confer an unfair
advantage on another <ent type='NORP'>Freemason</ent> is contrary to this prime duty.</p>

<p>Personal or business difficulties:
If it could be proved by evidence that any personal failure or
business difficulty was attributable to '<ent type='NORP'>Masonic</ent> influence', <ent type='NORP'>Masonic</ent>
authority would take a serious view of the fact, as it would be
contrary to the principles of <ent type='NORP'>Freemasonry</ent>.</p>

<p>Secrecy:</p>

<p>* <ent type='NORP'>Freemasonry</ent> is not a secret society.</p>

<p>* Like many other societies, it regards some of its internal affairs
as private matters for its members.</p>

<p>* There is no secret about its aims and principles. Copies of the
constitutions and rules can be obtained from <ent type='NORP'>Freemason</ent>s' Hall by
interested members of the public.</p>

<p>* The secrets of <ent type='NORP'>Freemasonry</ent> are concerned with its traditional modes
of recognition. Its ceremonies are private.</p>

<p>* In ordinary conversation there is very little about <ent type='NORP'>Freemasonry</ent>
which may not be discussed.

* On inquiry for acceptable reasons, <ent type='NORP'>Freemsons</ent> are free and will be
proud to acknowledge their own membership.
</p></xml>