<xml><p>
Part 1, U.S. Government Practices Germ Warfare on U.S. Population
~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~</p>

<p>GARY NULL:
..... also would say that they would go to <ent type='GPE'>Argentina</ent>, and they would
work with farm workers, and they would allow people to consume milk
without any evidence that it was safe. No one can verify that
something is going to be safe in everyone who consumes something
when you have no long-term studies. Why wasn't it done in <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>?
And how do we know that other organizations have not done tests on
<ent type='GPE'>America</ent>ns? And what groups or populations do they choose? Not once
was there any comment, editorially, in any of the media -- that I'm
aware of, at least -- that questioned the idea that you could take a
group of people: South <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>ns, a sub-group: farmers, and use
them as human guinea pigs.</p>

<p>Now think for a moment, just on a moral level. Do we have the right
to assume that a minority person from another country is any less
valuable, as a human being, than an <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n? That's for each of
you to decide for yourself. From my perspective, I think it's
important to respect all life, and therefore, I couldn't imagine
doing an experiment on a <ent type='NORP'>Mongolian</ent> child or a <ent type='NORP'>Sudanese</ent> family --
and not because the world wouldn't know what I had done, but because
they are part of the human spirit. But that wasn't questioned!</p>

<p>And Secondly, what do we know about the <ent type='ORG'>Wistar Institute</ent>? If it had
done THIS deed -- and it did, indeed, do this deed -- then what else
has it done? What other politics has it engaged in? The fact that
it was associated with the Pan <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n Health Organization is VERY
serious for me because I remember, long before this episode,
finding that the Pan <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n Health Organization and one of its
individuals had made a very, very aggressive and assertive effort
to destroy the reputation, the background and the credibility of
one Doctor Lawrence <ent type='PERSON'>Burton</ent> of the <ent type='GPE'>Bahamas</ent>. And it was upon the
recommendation of that Pan <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n Health Organization -- claiming
that Burton's therapy didn't work and that they had come in and
investigated his work -- that <ent type='ORG'>the Bahamian Government</ent> was willing
to, in effect, close down Burton's clinic. I remember writing
extensively -- after I went down to the <ent type='GPE'>Bahamas</ent>, and followed up on
THEIR work, and interviewed people from their organization -- that
they had done sloppy work. And their work was unscientific, when it
concerned <ent type='PERSON'>Burton</ent>, and it should never have been given credibility.
I considered it scandalous. And I wrote about it. And I wrote about
the people involved.</p>

<p>But, here they were, going along with the <ent type='ORG'>Wistar Institute</ent>.
And no one asked: Who is on their [Wistar's] board of directors?
What other organizations are they involved with? What other boards
are THEIR board members associated with? No one wanted to track it
back. And no one did.</p>

<p>Now in <ent type='ORG'>the United</ent> States, concern over the moral implications of
this experiment also was questioned, particularly since a large
portion of the funding for the development of the vaccine was
provided by the <ent type='ORG'>Federal Government</ent>. Now, according to <ent type='ORG'>the New York</ent>
Times:</p>

<p>(quote)
"Federal officials and scientists in <ent type='ORG'>the United</ent> States said it
raised questions about the adequacy of a new Reagan
Administration program to regulate products of bio-technology
research."
(unquote)</p>

<p>What is especially disturbing about the incident of Wistar's
insistence that it had not done anything wrong was:</p>

<p> (quote)
"because <ent type='GPE'>Argentina</ent> has no rules governing the bio-technology
industry, and <ent type='ORG'>the United</ent> States rules did not apply."
(unquote)</p>

<p>Now think of that for a moment. Just think of that. Because a
country has no rules governing bio-technology, and we do, that is
to assume that those rules, which we have held are important here
(for obvious reasons), wouldn't apply to another country? I'm sure
if you went to <ent type='GPE'>Bali</ent>, you wouldn't find any rules on bio-technology.
Does that mean that you should go there and test the subjects of
that country? Of course not! Who ARE these people at <ent type='ORG'>Wistar</ent>? Why
aren't they investigated? Why hasn't 60 MINUTES done a piece? Why
hasn't 20/20 done a piece on them? I think it's reprehensible
journalism, when there are so many red flags, and this kind of
logic is used, and it is not followed through on.</p>

<p>While commenting on the <ent type='ORG'>Wistar Institute</ent>'s conduct in the matter,
<ent type='ORG'>the New York</ent> Times cites Doctor <ent type='PERSON'>David</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Kingsbury</ent>[sp], Assistant
Director of <ent type='ORG'>the National Science</ent> Foundation, who was instrumental
in the creation of the current regulations governing the testing
of genetically-engineered products. He said:</p>

<p> (quote)
"I'm not bothered by the idea of <ent type='ORG'>the United</ent> States Research
Institute and companies going abroad for testing. But I am
appalled that they did it without the knowledge of that
country. Given the volatility and concern on this issue, you
just don't do things like that."
(unquote)</p>

<p>I would challenge Doctor <ent type='PERSON'>Kingsbury</ent>. I find it appalling that we
would assume that we could go abroad to do testing if other
countries don't have the knowledge of the conseqeunces of testing.
If they had been given an opportunity to determine the pros and
cons, then, fine. Let someone test. But what if they are innocent
in not knowing anything about what's being done.</p>

<p>Nor was the <ent type='ORG'>Wistar Institute</ent> the only party involved to see this
done, and in using obscure loopholes. <ent type='ORG'>The National Institutes</ent> of
Health, which provided Government funds for the development of the
vaccine, denied any responsibility for the failure to properly
oversee the experiment</p>

<p> (quote)
"because the actual trial itself did not use Government money."
(unquote)</p>

<p>That was according to <ent type='PERSON'>Warren Leary</ent> on a report titled "Argentines
Report Infection by Altered Farm Virus" on January 22, 1988. That
was later.
(to be continued only if someone will volunteer
to post to Usenet the remaining episodes of this
series, which I will e-mail to that volunteer.)
John DiNardo jad@blythe.org
* * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * *</p>

<p> If you agree that this information is vital to the defense and
the preservation of our free society, please assist in its
dissemination by posting it to computer bulletin boards and by
posting hardcopies in public places, both on and off campus.
The Usenet newsgroup alt.bbs.lists provides dial-in numbers
of BBSs.</p>

<p> John DiNardo</p>

<p>This INFO was taken off of:</p>

<p> Prowler's DOMAIN
1.7+ <ent type='ORG'>Gigabytes</ent>/4 phone lines
<special> 100% <ent type='ORG'>RIP GRAPHICS SUPPORTED</ent> </special>
GREAT NEW RIP GRAPHICS GAME Online
Special areas For Adults, Teens, and Kids
ALL Original, All High RES, All Great Gifs
Great Collection of Game Trainers, Solves
Editors, Cracks, Maps, Docs, Help files
Immediate File Downloads on your FIRST Call
(509) 327-8922 14.4k Ring-Down to all four lines
(509) 327-8827 28.8k Hayes Optima 288
Largest Collection of HOME IMPROVEMENT/DIY Files around
Over 186 <ent type='PERSON'>Megs</ent> of Programs for Windows
Medical/Religion/Educational/<ent type='EVENT'>UFOs</ent> files
<ent type='ORG'>International Message Networks</ent>:
PrimeNet (the only 100% <ent type='ORG'>Christian Network</ent>)
CCi (great subjects for everyone)
ZoNet (Enviromental, Natural Law, Politics,
RPG, <ent type='PERSON'>Starwars</ent>, UFO's, more)
Search-Net (UFO's, New Age, Conspiracy, Cover-Ups, etc)
<ent type='ORG'>House Plant Care</ent> and Help message base
And all the Best Online games many are registered</p>

</xml>