<xml>

<p>Subject: WILL OUR GVT IMPLANT OUR CHILDREN?</p>

<p>So you bloody skeptics think it can't happen here huh??? Wake Up!!!!!Comments
in upper case are all mine!</p>

<p>Samurai_Writer</p>

<p>Subject: <ent type='ORG'>KIDSCAN</ent> - Electronic Big Brother.</p>

<p>Chanced upon an episode of that <ent type='NORP'>Australian</ent> TV show "Beyond 2000" last night
on <ent type='ORG'>TDC</ent>. I arrived at the tail end of a story about a device called
"<ent type='ORG'>KIDSCAN</ent>". This appears to be an adaptation of a lab-animal ID tag that
is regularly advertized in the weekly science journals like "<ent type='ORG'>AAAS</ent> SCIENCE"
and "NATURE". What you have is a tiny glass capsule containing a passive
radio re-transmitter designed to be injected directly under the skin of
the animal. These things are very tiny - looks like maybe 0.75x2.0 mm.
They are designed to derive energy from an RF field and then re-transmit
at another frequency. The transmission contains a multi-digit ID code that
allows each animal to be positively identified.
[I CHANCED UPON AN ARTICLE IN <ent type='ORG'>THE SAN FRANCISCO CHRONICLE</ent> THAT DESCRIBED
THE ABOVE DEVICE IN ACTIVE USE IN MARIN COUNTY ON ALL PETS WHOSE OWNERS
ARE WILLING TO HAVE THEM IMPLANTED. I URGE YOU ALL TO GO AND BUY THE BOOK
"BEHOLD A PALE HORSE" BY <ent type='PERSON'>WILLIAM COOPER</ent>!!...Samurai_Writer]</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>KIDSCAN</ent> is the same principal ... but is being sold as something you have
implanted into your children - for their health and safety according to
the seller. These versions appear to be a little larger and can transmit
for a several block radius. The idea is to have a transmitter/reciever
every few blocks ... kinda like a small cellular phone system. This way,
the exact location of your precious progeny can be tracked every few
minutes and, I suppose, a time-map of your childs activities can be
provided. There is no reason that sensors could not be added to detect
cocaine/reefer/alcohol/nicotine/contraceptive substances/neural and
brain activity etc.. [THIS IS GREAT HUH? WHAT <ent type='ORG'>NEXT</ent>?!?! JUST SAY ..NO!]</p>

<p>The angle is perfect. It is easy to drive parents to paranoia about their
kids safety. The kids are very much the property of their parents and
suffer diminished rights when it comes to this style of intrusion. Any
half-ass advertizer could concoct some horrific TV commercials demonstrating
how this product can 'save' your child from something. If the price is
right - and technology just gets better and cheaper - they could sell
millions of these things. </p>

<p>Another obvious use is for felons - especially those on parole or out on
bail pending an appeal. Their location, and perhaps their activities,
could be easily monitored. After felons comes the mentally retarded,
altzheimers patients, petty criminals, 'suspicious persons' ... right
down to every single human being. [MY FAMILY ADOPTED A PHRASE I CONCOCTED
AS A CHILD WHEN STUDYING THE CONSTITUTION IN SCHOOL, "BETTER DEAD THAN LED"
AND I STILL BELIEVE THAT EVEN MORE SO TODAY....RECALL THE REVOLUTIONARY WAR!
MEN AN WOMEN WHO WERE WILLING TO SACRIFICE ALL TO ELIMINATE THE ENEMY!]</p>

<p>Masons rule - If it CAN be detected, someone will discover a pressing
reason TO detect it. </p>

<p>Many discount the ability of interested parties to institute anything
resembling a totalitarian system upon the <ent type='GPE'>USA</ent>. They point to such
failed attempts as the 'War on Drugs', the <ent type='PERSON'>McCarthy</ent> ant-pinko purge etc..
The usual reasoning goes that you would have to have a policeman following
each and every person 24 hours a day to prevent/ensure an activity. Well,
thanks to microelectronics - here is such a policeman. Start with the kids
and the obviously dangerous and then slowly find reasons to expand the
coverage - 'security' being a great catch-all reason.
[NOT ME FOLKS! THE FIRST PERSON TO TRY TO <ent type='ORG'>ENFORCE</ent> THIS UPON ME OR MINE WILL
BE SURPRISED AT THE RECEPTION THAT PERSON WILL RECEIVE....FREEDOM!!!!!] </p>

<p>Wake-up and smell the coffee people ... technology has made the aspiring
totalitarians job easy ! </p>

<p>-- Jim Mason </p>

<p>Subject: Re: <ent type='ORG'>KIDSCAN</ent> - Electronic Big Brother.</p>

<p>Supporters of the U.S. "Right to Keep and <ent type='ORG'>Bear Arms</ent>" have been awake
and smelling the coffee for a long, LONG time.</p>

<p>The electronic monitoring chip idea was proposed by the gun controllers-anti-<ent type='ORG'>RKBA</ent> community many years ago. Just recently in a <ent type='ORG'>Chicago Tribune</ent>
column by the fool Clarence Page, an editor(?), it showed up again.
The anti-<ent type='ORG'>RKBA</ent> never quits dreaming of new ways to destroy the <ent type='ORG'>RKBA</ent>
of the masses.</p>

<p>In terms of kids, the latest <ent type='ORG'>New Wave Gun Control</ent> strategem is the
"Kids &amp; Guns" conumdrum. A near simultaneous growth of news stories
concerning the 'awful' Kids'n Guns combo has hit the news media, as
well as the editorial and op-ed pages and Eye-Nitwit-News TV. These
are given a so-called "air of credibility" by government financed
"studies" released to show the assertion that the "disease" of
guns has "infected" the non-adult community. Further publicity is
given to reinforce the idea of "firearms-infection" by getting
some medical groups such as pediatricians to endorse ballistic weapons
bans, up to and including BB guns.</p>

<p>These have the effect of gun control activists masquerating as "concerned
citizens" passing <ent type='PERSON'>Bill</ent> of Right Free Zones i.e. Gun Free School Zones
and "Child-Firearm-Safety" laws i.e. you are defacto negligent if a
child accidentally shoots another, since the child used your gun and
"Make-Your-Weapon-Useless-Trigger-Lock" laws. Of course, the ultimate
version of this is the <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, D.C. law which states that having
an assembled firearm in your home is illegal.</p>

<p>And, of course, the whole point of all this is to restrict a person's
right to weapons and usage as much as possible for the moment, for
tommorrow is another day to foist ever-MORE gun controls on the hapless
<ent type='NORP'>American</ent> citizen.

</p></xml>