<xml><p>Provided courtesy of A-albionic Research, PO Box 20273, <ent type='GPE'>Ferndale</ent>, MI 48220
fax 313-885-1181
e-mail: jhdaugh@mail.msen.com</p>

<p>------------------------------------------------------------------------------
"<ent type='ORG'><ent type='GPE'>Bavaria</ent>n <ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent></ent>" FAQ.
Ver 1.2
<ent type='PERSON'>Peter Trei</ent>
Jan 1994</p>

<div>---------------------------------------------------------------------------</div>

<p> A lot of references appear in some newsgroups to the "<ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent>".
I'm trying to gather together some source material on the subject, to
produce some sort of FAQ file.</p>

<div>---------------------------------------------------------------------------</div>

<p> Here's three articles from the "Coil's <ent type='NORP'>Masonic</ent> Encyclopedia",
1961, by <ent type='PERSON'>Henry Wilson Coil</ent>, 33rd degree. This is an excellent, albeit
slightly idiosyncratic reference work. Coil had a low opinion the
Catholicism, and it shows.</p>

<p> Of course, this being a *<ent type='NORP'>Masonic</ent>* encyclopedia, the articles are
written from that viewpoint.</p>

<p>--------------------
Rites:
- <ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>Bavaria</ent>. </p>

<p> This order was first called the Order of <ent type='NORP'>Perfectibilists</ent>, and was
a fairly shortlived, meteoric, controversial society formed May 1,
1776, in <ent type='GPE'>Bavaria</ent>, by <ent type='PERSON'>Adam Weishaupt</ent>, aided by Baron <ent type='PERSON'>von Knigge</ent> and
others, suppressed in 1784, and entirely disappeared by the close of
the century. It was not primarily <ent type='NORP'>Masonic</ent>, and evidently not founded by
any <ent type='NORP'>Masonic</ent> authority, though it pirated or prarphrased <ent type='NORP'>Masonic</ent> rituals
and at one time or another had a number of prominent <ent type='NORP'>Freemasons</ent> in the
group. <ent type='NORP'>Freemasonry</ent> has received a great many denunciations from several
sources by reason of the aberrations of the <ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent>, and the enemies
of <ent type='NORP'>Freemasonry</ent> encouraged the idea that <ent type='ORG'>Illuminism and</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Freemasonry</ent> were
the same. For details of the lives of <ent type='PERSON'>Weishaupt</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Knigge</ent>, reference
must be made to those titles in the general text but, since <ent type='ORG'>Illuminism</ent>
was their creation and developed as they directed, their acts are
material and discussed here.</p>

<p> <ent type='PERSON'>Adam Weishaupt</ent>, Professor of Canon Law at <ent type='ORG'>the University</ent> of
<ent type='GPE'>Ingolstadt</ent>, conceived the idea of founding an order which, by mutual
helpfulness, counsel, and philosophic discussions, would increase
morality and virtue, lay the foundation for the reformation of the
world, and oppose the progress of evil, all of which objectives were
expressed in the name, "Order of <ent type='NORP'>Perfectibilists</ent>" or "<ent type='NORP'>Perfectionists</ent>",
which was soon changed to "<ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent>", which is best translated as
"intellectually inspired". Modesty and humility seems to have been no
trait of <ent type='PERSON'>Weishaupt</ent>, for he was one of the first to attempt to fly with
little knowledge of human aerodynamics. His ambition outweighed his
judgement; his ideals were too refined for a rude world. Like many
other promoters, <ent type='PERSON'>Weishaupt</ent> sought the aid of <ent type='NORP'>Freemasonry</ent> to give his
machine both propulsion and ballast. But it dragged <ent type='NORP'>Freemasonry</ent> down
without helping <ent type='ORG'>Illuminism</ent> very much. He was too shrewd and subtle for
his own good, though such qualities gave him headway for a time.
Although he formerly belonged to the Jesuits, he secured admission to a
lodge of <ent type='NORP'>Freemasons</ent> in 1777. Ironically, that was named "Lodge of
Caution."</p>

<p> We are not informed as to just how <ent type='PERSON'>Weishaupt</ent> became associated
with <ent type='PERSON'>Adolph Franz Friedrich Ludwid</ent> Baron Von <ent type='PERSON'>Knigge</ent>, for the latter
lived in <ent type='PERSON'>North</ent> <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent>, was of the nobility, and, after his initiation
in 1773, showed little interest in <ent type='NORP'>Freemasonry</ent>. But noblemen were found
in abundance in the most fraudulent orders in <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> claiming some
<ent type='NORP'>Masonic</ent> connections. <ent type='PERSON'>Weishaupt</ent>, in 1780, dispatched the Marquis de
Costanzo to propagate <ent type='ORG'>Illuminism</ent> in the north and <ent type='PERSON'>Knigge</ent> probably then
first showed interest in the society. He became more and more
enthusiastic as the plan was revealed to him, and, in 1781, accepted
the invitation to visit <ent type='GPE'>Bavaria</ent> and receive full access to all of
Weishaupt's materials. <ent type='PERSON'>Knigge</ent> not only completed the scale of degrees
but became a proponent of them, bringing to his aid the assistance of
Johann J. C. <ent type='ORG'>Bode</ent>, a prominent <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Mason</ent>. The order was at first
very popular and attracted, it is said, some of the best men in <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent>
and some of the worst. It had 2000 names on its rolls and spread to
<ent type='GPE'>France</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Belgium</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Holland</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Denamrk</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Sweden</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Poland</ent>, Hungary, and <ent type='GPE'>Italy</ent>.
<ent type='PERSON'>Knigge</ent>, especially, was a highly religious and intellectual man and
would have had nothing to do with that or any other order which was
anti-<ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent>, yet, the vicious attacks and accusations by <ent type='PERSON'>Baruel</ent> and
Robison had great influence, and it was even charged that the
<ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent> were themselves agents of the Jesuits, though the latter
were opposing it in their usual secret manner. The <ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent> were
extremely secretive, even identifying themselves and their chapters by
assumed classical names; for examples, <ent type='PERSON'>Weishaupt</ent> was <ent type='PERSON'>Spartacus</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Knigge</ent>
was <ent type='NORP'>Philo</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Ingolstadt</ent>, the headquarters, was <ent type='GPE'>Eleusis</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Austria</ent> was
<ent type='GPE'>Egypt</ent>, etc. Dates were given in a sort of cryptography.</p>

<p> The ceremonies were divided into three principal classes and those
into degrees as follows: I-The Nursery: 1. Preparatory Literary Essay;
2. Novitiate; 3. Minerval; 4. Minor <ent type='ORG'>Illuminatus</ent>; 5. <ent type='ORG'>Magistratus</ent>.
II-Symbolic <ent type='NORP'>Freemasonry</ent>: 1. Apprentice; 2. Fellow Craft; 3. Master; 4.
(a) <ent type='NORP'>Scots</ent> Major <ent type='ORG'>Illuminatus</ent>, (b) <ent type='NORP'>Scots</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Illuminatus</ent> Dirigens
(Directory). III-Mysteries; 1. Lesser: (a) <ent type='ORG'>Presbyter</ent>, Priest, or <ent type='GPE'>Epopt</ent>,
(b) Prince or Regent; Greater: (a) <ent type='ORG'>Magus</ent>; (b) <ent type='PERSON'>Rex</ent> or King (some of
these latter degrees were never completed). </p>

<p> The <ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent> were finally beset by both internal and external
disorders, for <ent type='PERSON'>Weishaupt</ent> found fault with some of Knigge's ritualistic
work and peremptorily ordered it changed, whereupon, <ent type='PERSON'>Knigge</ent> became
disgusted and resigned in 1784. The Jesuits had fought it from the
first and eventually all priests became its active enemies and raised
so much opposition that the Elector of <ent type='GPE'>Bavaria</ent> supressed the Order by
edict, June 22, 1784, many <ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent> being imprisoned and some,
including <ent type='PERSON'>Weishaupt</ent>, being forced to flee the country. Though the first
edict had been obeyed, it was repeated in March and August, 1785. Not
only <ent type='ORG'>Illuminism</ent>, but <ent type='NORP'>Freemasonry</ent> was exterminated in <ent type='GPE'>Bavaria</ent> and
neither ever recovered its former position. The <ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent> seem to have
completely disappeared everywhere by the end of the 18th century.</p>

<p>--------------------
<ent type='PERSON'>Weishaupt</ent>, Adam</p>

<p> Founder of the <ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>Bavaria</ent>, born at Inglstadt, 1748,
died 1811. He was educated in law and attained the rank of Professor in
1772 at <ent type='ORG'>the University</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>Ingolstadt</ent>. He had been educated by the
Jesuits but acquired a dislike for them, and in his professional life,
he was soon in conflict with the whole clergy, partly because he held
the chair of Canon Law, which had always been held by an ecclesiastic.
In conferences with his students in whom he planted liberal ideas on
religion and philosophy, and he soon conceived of a close association
of enlightened or intellectual persons who might advance the moral and
intellectual qualities of themselves as well as others. This idea
materialized as the <ent type='ORG'>Illuminates</ent> or <ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent>, who at first had no
connection with <ent type='NORP'>Freemasonry</ent>. In 1777, he was admitted to <ent type='PERSON'>Lodge Theodore</ent>
of Good Counsel (translated by some as <ent type='PERSON'>Lodge Theodore</ent> of Caution) at
<ent type='GPE'>Munich</ent>, and from that time, he sought to interrelate the affairs of his
<ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent> with <ent type='NORP'>Freemasonry</ent>. </p>

<p> He soon formed an association with Baron <ent type='PERSON'>von Knigge</ent>, an able and
upright man from north <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent>, and the two might have accomplished
their objectives and some good had it not been for the opposition of
the Jesuits (who were still powerful though banished from <ent type='GPE'>Bavaria</ent>) and
the <ent type='NORP'>Roman Catholic</ent> clergy. Moreover <ent type='PERSON'>Weishaupt</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Knigge</ent> could not
agree upon some of the latters' ritualistic interpretations. From the
literature on the subject of <ent type='ORG'>Illuminism and</ent> from the caustic remarks of
<ent type='NORP'>Masonic</ent> writers, we might suppose that this order or movement lasted a
long time, but the whole drama opened with the organization of the
<ent type='NORP'>Perfectionists</ent> in 1766 and, 18 years later in 1784, the <ent type='GPE'>Bavaria</ent>n
government banned all secret associations. The next year, <ent type='PERSON'>Weishaupt</ent> was
discharged from his position at <ent type='ORG'>the University</ent> and banished from the
country. He fled to <ent type='ORG'>Gotha</ent> and found asylum with Duke <ent type='PERSON'>Ernest</ent> of that
little city, remaining there until his death in 1811. In <ent type='ORG'>Gotha</ent>, he
published a number of works, those on <ent type='ORG'>Illuminism</ent> being: "A Picture of
<ent type='ORG'>Illuminism</ent>", 1786; "A Complete History of the Persecutions of the
<ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent> in <ent type='GPE'>Bavaria</ent>", 1785 (only the first of two planned volumes
published); "An Apology for the <ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent>", 1786; "An Improved System
of <ent type='ORG'>Illuminism</ent>", 1787, and others.</p>

<p> The most objective writers on the subject give <ent type='PERSON'>Weishaupt</ent> credit
for being of high moral character and a profound thinker, and it is
worth noting that his associate, <ent type='PERSON'>Knigge</ent>, spoke with great respect of
his intellectual powers. It appears, however, that he was the victim of
at least two powerful forces, first, the vindictive hate of <ent type='ORG'>the Church</ent>
of Rome and the <ent type='GPE'>Bavaria</ent>n government and, secondly, his own inadequate
judgement of how to launch a revolutionary and more or less secret
movement such as <ent type='ORG'>Illuminism</ent>. He was really employing methods of the
Jesuits, for his whole order seems to have been composed of spies and
counter spies, and only those most adept at scheming and trickery were
advanced. The candidates all had pseudonyms, that of <ent type='PERSON'>Weishaupt</ent> being
<ent type='PERSON'>Spartacus</ent>, and those who became too inquisitive about matters as to
which their suspicions were aroused were turned out. If the purpose had
been philosophic, ethical, or for the improvement of the mind or
salvation of the soul, it need never to have been quite so secretive,
and from the <ent type='NORP'>Masonic</ent> standpoint, <ent type='PERSON'>Weishaupt</ent> was not justified in using
the Fraternity as the vehicle for his scheme, good or bad, though he
had ample precedents on all sides.</p>

<p>--------------------
<ent type='PERSON'>Knigge</ent>, Baron von (Adolph F. R. L.) </p>

<p> <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Freemason</ent> and, in part, founder of the <ent type='ORG'><ent type='GPE'>Bavaria</ent>n <ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent></ent>.
He was born near <ent type='GPE'>Hanover</ent> in 1752, and died at <ent type='GPE'>Bremen</ent> in 1796. He was
initiated in a lodge of <ent type='ORG'>the Strict Observance</ent> at Cassel in 1772, but,
for a time, seemed uninterested in the <ent type='ORG'>Society</ent>, thogh later becoming
one of the foremost <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> writers on the subject. He published "On
the Jesuits, <ent type='NORP'>Freemasons</ent>, and Rosicrucians, 1781, anon.; "Essay on
<ent type='NORP'>Freemasonry</ent>", 1784; "Contribution towards the latest history of the
Order of <ent type='NORP'>Freemasons</ent>", 1786; and "Philo's final Declaration", 1788. He
also wrote many non-<ent type='NORP'>Masonic</ent> works, one being "On Conversation with
Men", towards the end of his career and after a sad experience with the
<ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent> and disappointment with <ent type='ORG'>the Strict Observance</ent>, causing him
therein to devote much space to secret societies and denunciation of
<ent type='NORP'>Freemasonry</ent>. The most interesting and significant part of Knigge's
career was his participation with <ent type='PERSON'>Weishaupt</ent> in the promotion of the
<ent type='ORG'><ent type='GPE'>Bavaria</ent>n <ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent></ent>, he being almost an equal party.</p>

<div>---------------------------------------------------------------------------</div>

<p> A look at the Harvard <ent type='ORG'>University</ent> Library Catalog shows that there
was an <ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent> panic in <ent type='LOC'>New England</ent> in the late 1790's.</p>

<p> After that, very few people seem to have had <ent type='ORG'>Illuminism</ent> on their
minds. In the 1950s and 60's, about the only people who seem to mention
it were the John Birch <ent type='ORG'>Society</ent>.</p>

<p> In the mid-70's, <ent type='PERSON'>Robert Shea</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Robert Anton Wilson</ent> restarted
popular speculation with their fictional "<ent type='ORG'>Illuminatus</ent>!" trilogy. This
mixes actual history with conspiracy theory and pure invention, and
very deliberately produces doubts in the reader's mind as to the
nature of reality - a technique which the authors refer to as "guerilla
ontology", in pursuit of "Operation Mindf*ck." They were apparently
turned on to <ent type='ORG'>Illuminism</ent> by some of the correspondance they received
while working as letters column editors at <ent type='ORG'>Playboy</ent> magazine.</p>

<p> At the core of <ent type='ORG'>Illuminatus</ent>! is an aeons-old conflict between the
conspiracies representing the forces of order, bureaucracy, and
repression, represented by the <ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent>, and the conspiracies
representing the forces of chaos, spontaneity and freedom,
representing by the <ent type='ORG'>Erisians</ent> (followers of <ent type='ORG'>Eris</ent>, the <ent type='NORP'>Greek</ent> goddess of
discord). The plot involves every conspiracy you've ever heard of,
many you havent, monomaniacal midgets, golden submarines, giant squid,
ancient Atlantis, zombie <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> stormtroopers, and a good deal of sex.
<ent type='PERSON'>Wilson</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>Shea</ent> drew heavily on <ent type='ORG'>Akron Darual</ent>'s "History of Secret
Societies", the 'Principia Discordia' of the <ent type='ORG'>Erisians</ent>, many kinds of
fringe conspiracy theory, and their own imaginations. One of their
conceits is that <ent type='PERSON'>Adam Weishaupt</ent>, founder of the <ent type='ORG'><ent type='GPE'>Bavaria</ent>n <ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent></ent>,
secretly murdered <ent type='PERSON'>George Washington</ent> and took his place.</p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>Illuminatus</ent>! became an underground bestseller, and while <ent type='ORG'>Shea</ent> seems
to have been content to sit back and enjoy the royalties, <ent type='PERSON'>Wilson</ent> has
worked the interest it developed into a minor industry. He has brought
out a steady stream of fiction and "non-fiction" concerning the
<ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent> and related topics, noteably the "Schrodinger's Cat"
trilogy, "The <ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent> Papers", "Cosmic Trigger - The Final Secret of
the <ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent>", and most recently the "Historical <ent type='ORG'>Illuminatus</ent> Series",
which is up to four books.</p>

<p> [The following paragraph is a personal opinion.]</p>

<p> I've met <ent type='PERSON'>Wilson</ent>, and my impression is that he lacks sincerity. I
don't think he actually believes in the continuing existence of the
<ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent>, but knows he's stumbled onto a goldmine. He does seem
serious about some of the psychological theories he promotes.</p>

<p> A couple other works of interest are the above-mentioned "History
of Secret Societies" by <ent type='ORG'>Akron Daraul</ent>, and <ent type='PERSON'>Neil Wilgus</ent>' "The
<ent type='ORG'>Illuminoids</ent>". HoSS tries to link together a number of groups, claiming
that the <ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent>, the <ent type='ORG'>Mason</ent>s, the <ent type='NORP'>Italian</ent> Carbonari, and the
<ent type='NORP'>Spanish</ent> Alumburados (sp?) are all linked and can be traced back to the
Hashashins of the ancient <ent type='LOC'>Middle East</ent>. "The <ent type='ORG'>Illuminoids</ent>" is
post-<ent type='ORG'>Illuminatus</ent>! and basically catalogs the conspiracy theories
connected to it.</p>

<p> So there you have it - a short-lived, failed, 18th century secret
society, which after being forgotten for nearly 200 years, has seized
the popular imagination through the work of two men. Despite the
paranoia of some of the people on the net, there is not the slightest
shred of evidence that the <ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent> persisted past 1800.

Of course, you may think you are free to doubt me on this. :-)</p>

<p>W .'. <ent type='PERSON'>Peter Trei</ent>
ptrei@mitre.org
Wilder Lodge AF&amp;AM
Leominster MA
------------------------------------------------------------------------------</p>

<p>After I put this out on the net, I received a few responses. The most
interesting gives some <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> sources on the <ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent>. I've touched
up the English a little:</p>

<p>Date: Tue, 27 Oct 92 17:33:17 <ent type='ORG'>MEZ</ent>
From: "Roald A. Zellweger" <special>RZELLWE@<ent type='ORG'>ibm</ent>.gwdg.de</special>
Subject: <ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent></p>

<p> There is, of course, lots of material in <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> available on the
<ent type='ORG'><ent type='GPE'>Bavaria</ent>n <ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent></ent>, esp from the beginning of the century, but also
from the research on the later <ent type='NORP'>Enlightenment</ent> in <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent>, that had it's
height in the 70's.</p>

<p> Goethe and Herder were at times members of the <ent type='GPE'>Bavaria</ent>n
<ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent>, and not only the Duke of <ent type='ORG'>Gotha</ent>, but also <ent type='ORG'>the Dukes</ent> of
Weimar and <ent type='GPE'>Brunswick</ent>, of course since it was <ent type='ORG'>Jesuitic</ent> in form and
heavily anti-<ent type='ORG'>Jesuitic</ent> in everything else...</p>

<p> At the end of 19th century the <ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent>-phobia was promoted and
used by the "Protokolle der Weisen von Zion" ["Protocols of the Elders
of Zion"] rsp. the literary <ent type='ORG'>Vorlage</ent>, a <ent type='NORP'>French</ent> anti-<ent type='NORP'>Napoleonic</ent> fiction,
and later by <ent type='ORG'>Ludendorff</ent>. So the <ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent>-phobia became closely
connected with Fascism's conspiracy theories.</p>

<p> The <ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent> no longer exist, but they influenced methods of
political conspiracy in 19th century and put the fear of a conspiracy
of masons, <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, etc. in the views of the extreme right.</p>

<p> Informative is the Article <ent type='GPE'>Illuminaten</ent> in the Theologische
Realenzyclopedie (<ent type='ORG'>TRE</ent>), the large forthcoming protestant encyclopedia,
Bd.16,p.81-84, providing with the newest (serious!) literature.</p>

<p> Broader, but older, the article <ent type='GPE'>Illuminaten</ent> in Realenzyclopaedie
fuer protestantische <ent type='ORG'>Theologie und Kirche</ent>, Bd.9, Leipzig 1901,
p.61-68, mentioning the <ent type='NORP'>Spanish</ent> Alumbrados as using the same name and
existing later in <ent type='GPE'>France</ent>. The Realenzyclopaedie 3rd Edition is a very
serious work of late 19th century <ent type='ORG'>Historical Research</ent> and of course
from the viewpoint of <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> Kulturprotestantism.</p>

<p> Sources could be found sub <ent type='PERSON'>Knigge</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Weishaupt</ent> in Wolfsohns
Freimaurerbibliographie, <ent type='GPE'>Vienna</ent> (20's or early 30's). Useful is the
Internationales Freimaurerlexikon (<ent type='GPE'>Vienna</ent> 1932). Both Works are from
a (low-degree) masonic viewpoint and esp the latter apologetic against
Ludendorff's conspiracy theory.</p>

<p> Edited sources are: <ent type='PERSON'>Jan Reichold</ent> (ed.): Die <ent type='GPE'>Illuminaten</ent>. Quellen
und Texte zur <ent type='ORG'>Aufklaerungsideologie</ent> des <ent type='GPE'>Illuminatenordens</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Berlin</ent>
((former) DDR) 1984, commentary part of course influenced by Marxism
and <ent type='GPE'>GDR</ent>-ideology, but solid text edition.</p>

<p> <ent type='PERSON'>Richard van Duelman</ent>: Der Geheimbund der <ent type='GPE'>Illuminaten</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Stuttgart</ent>
1975.</p>

<p> If you haven't access to the lexica and could send me a Fax or
snail-mail address, I could send you copies from the articles in
question.</p>

<div>======-*****-=====-*****-=====-*-=**=-*-=====-*****-=====-*****-======</div>

<p> Roald A. Zellweger</p>

<p>Institut fuer Spezialforschungen
Platz <ent type='PERSON'>der Goettinger Sieben</ent> 2
D-3400 Goettingen</p>

<p>phone : +49-551-39 7127
fax : +49-551-9 75 88
bitnet: RZELLWE@<ent type='ORG'>ibm</ent>.gwdg.de</p>

<div>------------------------------------------------------------------------------</div>

<p>Minor bits &amp; bobs:</p>

<p> <ent type='PERSON'>Steve Jackson Games</ent> has a rather nifty conspiracy table top game
called <ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent>, based on the books.</p>

<p> There is a live-action version called GURPS <ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent>, played at
finer SF and gaming conventions.</p>

<p> The "Puzzling Evidence" segment of the film "True Stories",
without mentioning the <ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent> explicitly, gives an entertaining
insight into the mind of a conspiracy theorist.
</p></xml>