<xml><p>Article 638 of alt.conspiracy:
Path: bilver!tarpit!peora!masscomp!think.com!mintaka!mit-eddie!bu.edu!
lll-winken!sun-barr!newstop!sunaus.oz!<ent type='GPE'>softway</ent>!peg!nexus
From: nexus@peg.<ent type='ORG'>UUCP</ent>
Newsgroups: alt.conspiracy
Subject: <ent type='ORG'>Mafia</ent> Control of <ent type='GPE'>Aust</ent> and NZ
<info type="Message-ID"> 606300008@peg</info>
Date: 10 Jan 91 12:41:13 GMT
Lines: 1294
Nf-ID: #N:peg:606300008:000:58868
Nf-From: peg.<ent type='ORG'>UUCP</ent>!nexus Jan 10 14:13:00 1991</p>

<p>Cc: agarton conf:alt.conspiracy csherman <ent type='ORG'>demtas</ent> fm2ser radio5uv rrosen
Subject: <ent type='ORG'>Mafia</ent> Control of <ent type='GPE'>Aust</ent> and NZ</p>

<p>The following file was posted to our office recently. It is quite
long, approx 56K and contains some very amazing information, such
as <ent type='NORP'>Swiss</ent> Account Numbers of high profile people on <ent type='ORG'>Mafia</ent> Payrolls.
You may be surprised at some of the names mentioned here.</p>

<p>It also contains references to <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> operations to place subliminal
TV broadcasts throughout <ent type='GPE'>Aust</ent>ralia and NZ, and other countries.</p>

<p>Happy reading.
***************************************************************************</p>

<p>The Opal File</p>

<p>The Round Table Finan<ent type='ORG'>cia</ent>l Takeover of <ent type='GPE'>Aust</ent>ralia and <ent type='GPE'>New Zealand</ent></p>

<p>- A 20 Year History In Brief</p>

<p>"Fear them not, therefore; for there is nothing covered that shall not be
revealed; and hidden, that shall shall not be known. "What I tell you in
darkness, that espeak in light; and what ye hear in the ear, that proclaim
upon the housetops." Matthew</p>

<p>18th May, 1967: <ent type='GPE'>Texas</ent> oil billionaire <ent type='PERSON'>Nelson Bunker</ent> Hunt, using a
sophisticated satellite technique to detect global deposits, discovers a
huge oil source south of <ent type='GPE'>New Zealand</ent> in <ent type='LOC'>the Great South Basin</ent>.</p>

<p>10th June, 1967: Hunt and <ent type='GPE'>New Zealand</ent> Finance Minister reach an agreement:
Hunt will receive sole drilling rights and <ent type='PERSON'>Muldoon</ent> will receive a
$US100000 non-repayable loan from <ent type='ORG'>the Placid Oil</ent> Co (Hunt's).</p>

<p>8th September, 1967: <ent type='ORG'>Placid Oil</ent> granted drilling rights to the Great South
Basin.</p>

<p>10th May, 1968: <ent type='NORP'>Hawaiian</ent> meeting between <ent type='ORG'>Onassis</ent> and top lieutenants,
<ent type='PERSON'>William Colby</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Gerald Parsky</ent>, to discuss establishment of a new front
company in <ent type='GPE'>Aust</ent>ralia - <ent type='GPE'>Aust</ent>ral<ent type='NORP'>asian</ent> and <ent type='LOC'>Pacific</ent> Holdings Limited - to be
managed by <ent type='PERSON'>Michael Hand</ent>. Using <ent type='ORG'>Onassis</ent>-<ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> banks, <ent type='ORG'>Chase Manhattan</ent>
and <ent type='ORG'>Shroders</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Travelodge Management Ltd</ent> sets up another front to link the
operations to the US.</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>Onassis</ent> crowned head of the <ent type='ORG'>Mafia</ent>; <ent type='PERSON'>Colby</ent> (head of <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> covert operations in
S.E. <ent type='LOC'>Asia</ent>) ran the <ent type='ORG'>Onassis</ent> heroin operations in the Golden Triangle (<ent type='GPE'>Laos</ent>,
<ent type='GPE'>Burma</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Thailand</ent>) with 200 Green Beret Mercenaries - ie <ent type='ORG'>the Phoenix</ent>
Program.</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Gerald Parsky</ent> deputy to ex-<ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>/<ent type='ORG'>FBI</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Robert Maheu</ent> in the <ent type='ORG'>Howard Hughes</ent>
organization, took orders from <ent type='ORG'>Onassis</ent> and was made responsible for
laundering skim money from the <ent type='ORG'>Onassis</ent> casino operations in <ent type='GPE'>Las Vegas</ent> and
the Bahamas.</p>

<p>Mid-July, 1968: <ent type='ORG'>Placid Oil</ent> Co and the <ent type='ORG'>Seven Sisters</ent> (major oil companies)
begin <ent type='LOC'>Great South Basin</ent> oil exploration - Hunt Finances 45.5% of
exploration costs, <ent type='LOC'>Gulf</ent> Oil 14.5%, <ent type='ORG'>Shell</ent> (US) 10%, B.P. Oil 10%, Standard
Oil <ent type='GPE'>California</ent> 10%, <ent type='ORG'>Mobil</ent> 6.5% and <ent type='ORG'>Arco</ent> 6.5%.</p>

<p>12th October, 1968: Hunt and <ent type='ORG'>Seven Sisters</ent> announce confirmation of new oil
source comparable to the <ent type='NORP'>Alaskan</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>North</ent> Slope - gas reserves estimated at
150 times larger than the <ent type='ORG'>Kapuni</ent> Field.</p>

<p>Early 1969: <ent type='ORG'>Mafia</ent> consolidates its banking operations; David <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent>
becomes Chairman of <ent type='ORG'>Chase Manhattan</ent>; Wriston at <ent type='ORG'>Citibank</ent> and Michele
Sindona captures <ent type='ORG'>the Vatican Bank</ent>, Partnership <ent type='LOC'>Pacific</ent> launched by Bank of
<ent type='GPE'>America</ent>, Bank of Tokyo and Bank of New <ent type='GPE'>South Wales</ent>.</p>

<p>24th February, 1969: <ent type='ORG'>Onassis</ent> calls <ent type='ORG'>Council</ent> meeting in <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent> to discuss
strategy to monopolise <ent type='LOC'>the Great South Basin</ent> discovery. <ent type='ORG'>Council</ent> members
included <ent type='PERSON'>Nelson</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> and John McCloy, who managed the <ent type='ORG'>Seven Sisters</ent>,
and David <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> managed the Mafia's banking operations.</p>

<p>McCloy outlines the plan to capture all oil and mineral resources in
<ent type='GPE'>Aust</ent>ralia and N.Z.</p>

<p>10th March, 1969: <ent type='PERSON'>Parsky</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Colby</ent> use <ent type='GPE'>Aust</ent>ral<ent type='NORP'>asian</ent> and <ent type='LOC'>Pacific</ent> Holdings to
set up a 'front' company in <ent type='GPE'>Aust</ent>ralia. Using old banks - <ent type='ORG'>Mellon Bank</ent> and
<ent type='ORG'>Pittsburgh National Bank</ent>, they buy control of near-bankrupt Industrial
Equity Ltd (I.E.L.) managed by <ent type='GPE'>New Zealand</ent>er <ent type='PERSON'>Ron Brierly</ent>.</p>

<p>A'<ent type='LOC'>Asia</ent>n and <ent type='LOC'>Pacific</ent> Holdings' 'consultant' <ent type='PERSON'>Bob Seldon</ent> helps <ent type='PERSON'>Michael Hand</ent>
set up the new organization. <ent type='PERSON'>Seldon</ent> took orders from <ent type='ORG'>Mellon</ent> and Pittsburgh
<ent type='ORG'>National Bank</ent>s, while Hand was directly responsible to <ent type='PERSON'>Gerald Parsky</ent> and
<ent type='PERSON'>William Colby</ent>. <ent type='PERSON'>Ron Brierly</ent> would take orders from Hand.</p>

<p>24th July, 1969: New board established for I.E.L. includes Hand, <ent type='PERSON'>Seldon</ent>,
<ent type='PERSON'>Ron Brierly</ent>, plus two <ent type='PERSON'>Brierly</ent> asso<ent type='ORG'>cia</ent>tes - <ent type='PERSON'>Frank Nugan</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Bob Jones</ent>.
Both are appointed consultants to A'<ent type='NORP'>asian</ent> and <ent type='LOC'>Pacific</ent> Holdings Ltd.</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Jones</ent> will help <ent type='PERSON'>Brierly</ent> launder funds into real estate (<ent type='PERSON'>Brierly</ent>/<ent type='PERSON'>Jones</ent>
Investments) while <ent type='PERSON'>Seldon</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Nugan</ent> will channel funds into oil and mineral
resources through I.E.L.</p>

<p>October 1969: <ent type='ORG'>Chase Manhattan</ent> begins new operation in <ent type='GPE'>Aust</ent>ralia with
<ent type='ORG'>National Bank</ent> <ent type='GPE'>Aust</ent>ralasia and A.C. Goods Asso<ent type='ORG'>cia</ent>tes - Chase-NBA.</p>

<p>J.C. <ent type='ORG'>Fletcher</ent> appointed chairman of <ent type='ORG'>Seven Sisters</ent>' company - British
Petroleum (N.Z.).</p>

<p>17th February 1970: <ent type='PERSON'>Gerald Parsky</ent> sets up a new heroin-dollar laundry in
<ent type='GPE'>Aust</ent>ralia - <ent type='GPE'>Aust</ent>ralian International Finance Corp. using <ent type='ORG'>the Irving Trust</ent>
Co <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent>.</p>

<p>April 1970: <ent type='ORG'>Onassis</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> and the <ent type='ORG'>Seven Sisters</ent> begin setting up the
shadow <ent type='ORG'>World Government</ent> using the <ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent>-controlled banks and the
transnational corporations. In <ent type='GPE'>Melbourne</ent> they set up the <ent type='GPE'>Aust</ent>ralian
International Finance Corporation using:</p>

<p>* <ent type='ORG'>Irving Trust</ent> Co. N.Y. - linked to <ent type='ORG'>Shell Oil</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Continental</ent> Oil, Phillips
Petroleum.</p>

<p>* <ent type='ORG'>Crocker Citizens National</ent> - linked to <ent type='ORG'>Atlantic Richfield</ent> (<ent type='ORG'>Arco</ent>), Standard
Oil of <ent type='GPE'>California</ent> which is <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent>-controlled.</p>

<p>* Bank of <ent type='GPE'>Montreal</ent> - Petro <ent type='GPE'>Canada</ent>, Penarctic Oils, Alberta Gas, <ent type='LOC'>Gulf</ent> Oil.</p>

<p>* <ent type='GPE'>Aust</ent>ralia and <ent type='GPE'>New Zealand</ent> Bank (ANZ).</p>

<p>Meantime, <ent type='NORP'>Japanese</ent> members of One <ent type='ORG'>World Government</ent> move into <ent type='GPE'>New Zealand</ent>,
helped by Finance Minister R. <ent type='PERSON'>Muldoon</ent>; <ent type='ORG'>Mitsubishi</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>Mitsui</ent> make a
profitable deal buying up rights to ironsands helped by <ent type='ORG'>Marcona Corp</ent>. (US)
and <ent type='PERSON'>Todd</ent> (<ent type='ORG'>Shell</ent>/BP/<ent type='PERSON'>Todd</ent>). <ent type='PERSON'>Todd</ent> rewarded with sole <ent type='GPE'>New Zealand</ent> franchise
for <ent type='ORG'>Mitsubishi</ent> vehicles, <ent type='PERSON'>Muldoon</ent> helps <ent type='ORG'>Mitsui</ent> (<ent type='ORG'>Oji Paper</ent> Co) obtain a
lucrative 320 million cubic foot <ent type='ORG'>Kiangaroa Forestry</ent> contract with Carter
Holt.</p>

<p>November, 1970: <ent type='ORG'>Fletcher</ent>s extend the <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Travelodge</ent> operation by
buying control of <ent type='GPE'>New Zealand</ent>'s largest travel company - <ent type='LOC'>Atlantic</ent> and
<ent type='ORG'>Pacific Travel</ent>.</p>

<p>Manufacturers' and Retailers' Acceptance Company (in 1970 changed to
<ent type='PERSON'>Marac</ent>): This firm spe<ent type='ORG'>cia</ent>lises in leasing and factoring (buying debts at a
discount). It also finances imports and exports. The major shareholders
are the <ent type='ORG'>Fletcher</ent> Group (38.0%), the Commer<ent type='ORG'>cia</ent>l Bank of <ent type='GPE'>Aust</ent>ralia Ltd
(24.7%), <ent type='ORG'>NIMU Insurance</ent> (7.7%), Phillips 7Electrical (3.8%), National
Mutual Life Asso<ent type='ORG'>cia</ent>tion (2.4%), <ent type='GPE'>New Zealand</ent> <ent type='ORG'>United Corporation</ent> (4.0%).
The <ent type='ORG'>CBA</ent> is a partner in the supranational Euro-<ent type='LOC'>Pacific</ent> Corporation, the
other partners being the <ent type='ORG'>Midland Bank</ent> (UK), <ent type='ORG'>the United California Bank</ent>
(<ent type='GPE'>USA</ent>), Fuji (<ent type='GPE'>Japan</ent>) and <ent type='ORG'>Societe Generale</ent> de Banque (<ent type='GPE'>France</ent>).</p>

<p>Early 1971: <ent type='ORG'>Onassis</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> begin global operation to buy influence
for the One <ent type='ORG'>World Government</ent> concept. They use <ent type='ORG'>Lockheed</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>North</ent>rop and
<ent type='ORG'>Litton Industries</ent> 'agent' <ent type='PERSON'>Adnan Khashoggi</ent>, to organize operations in the
<ent type='LOC'>Middle East</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Iran</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Indonesia</ent>. I.C.I. set up $2.5 million slush fund to
<ent type='GPE'>Aust</ent>ralia and N.Z.</p>

<p>Finance Minister <ent type='PERSON'>Muldoon</ent> changes law to allow <ent type='ORG'>Mafia</ent>-controlled banks to
begin operations in <ent type='GPE'>New Zealand</ent>. Links also made by N.Z.I. in preparation
for <ent type='ORG'>Paxus</ent> control with <ent type='GPE'>Hong Kong</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Shanghai</ent>; <ent type='ORG'>Wells Fargo</ent> with Broadbank;
<ent type='ORG'>Chase Manhattan</ent> with <ent type='ORG'>General Finance</ent>; Bank of <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>Barclays</ent> with
<ent type='ORG'>Fletcher</ent>s and <ent type='ORG'>Renouf</ent> in <ent type='GPE'>New Zealand</ent> United Corp. All members of the
Business Round Table Organization.</p>

<p>Late 1971: <ent type='LOC'>Gulf</ent> Oil and their man <ent type='PERSON'>Brierly</ent> begin organizing chains of <ent type='ORG'>Shell</ent>
companies and dummy corporations to conceal their takeover operations of
oil, gas and mineral resources and related industries such as vehicle
franchises, vehicle spare parts and finance services - all part of the
<ent type='ORG'>Seven Sisters</ent>' controlled car culture.</p>

<p>To extend links to the US banking operations they buy control of I.S.A.S.
(<ent type='GPE'>NSW</ent>) and I.S.A.S. (Qld), which hold sole franchise for construction and
mining equipment produced by <ent type='ORG'>International Harvester</ent> Credit Co, which is
part of <ent type='ORG'>Chase Manhattan</ent> Bank and asso<ent type='ORG'>cia</ent>ted with F<ent type='ORG'>irs</ent>t <ent type='ORG'>National Bank</ent>
<ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> (Chairman <ent type='PERSON'>Sullivan</ent> also <ent type='ORG'>Executive</ent> Vice-President of Chase
<ent type='GPE'>Manhattan</ent>), <ent type='ORG'>Continental</ent> <ent type='GPE'>Illinois</ent> (linked with <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>Mafia</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Michele Sindona</ent>
of <ent type='ORG'>Vatican Bank</ent>) and Rockefeller's <ent type='ORG'>Standard Oil</ent> of <ent type='NORP'>Indiana</ent> (AMOCO).</p>

<p>I.S.A.S. (Qld) also has strategic holdings in <ent type='PERSON'>North</ent> Flinders Mines,
<ent type='ORG'>Flinders Petroleum</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Apollo International Minerals</ent>.</p>

<p>February 1972: <ent type='ORG'>Onassis</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> help asso<ent type='ORG'>cia</ent>te <ent type='PERSON'>Adnan Khashoggi</ent> buy
<ent type='ORG'>the <ent type='ORG'>Security Pacific</ent> <ent type='ORG'>National Bank</ent></ent> in <ent type='GPE'>California</ent> and take control of the
United <ent type='GPE'>California</ent> Bank through <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>-linked <ent type='ORG'>Lockheed</ent> Aircraft Corporation.
Both banks used by <ent type='ORG'>Onassis</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>Khashoggi</ent> to funnel bribes and payoffs via
the CIA's <ent type='ORG'>Deak Bank</ent> to captive <ent type='NORP'>Japanese</ent> and other crooked politi<ent type='ORG'>cia</ent>ns.
<ent type='ORG'>Security Pacific</ent> also used to 'launder' over $2 million for Nixon's
re-election campaign. <ent type='ORG'>Khashoggi</ent> also buys 21% of <ent type='ORG'>Southern Pacific</ent>
Properties, which is the major stockholder in <ent type='ORG'>Travelodge</ent> (<ent type='GPE'>Aust</ent>), thereby
establishing direct links to <ent type='GPE'>New Zealand</ent>, and U.E.B. and <ent type='ORG'>Fletcher</ent>s through
its equity links with <ent type='ORG'>Travelodge</ent> (N.Z.).</p>

<p>April 1972: <ent type='ORG'>Mafia</ent> banking operations expanded through <ent type='LOC'>New Hebrides</ent> with
establishment of <ent type='GPE'>Aust</ent>ralian International Ltd to finance <ent type='LOC'>Pacific</ent>
development by the oil companies (<ent type='ORG'>Seven Sisters</ent>). Banks involved include
<ent type='ORG'>Irving Trust</ent> NY, Bank of <ent type='GPE'>Montreal</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Crocker International</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Aust</ent>ralia &amp; N.Z.
Bank and the <ent type='ORG'>Mitsubishi</ent> Bank, whose president, <ent type='PERSON'>Nakamaru</ent>, is appointed
Chairman.</p>

<p>26th May, 1972: <ent type='PERSON'>Gerald Parsky</ent> installs <ent type='PERSON'>Michele Sindona</ent> as 'owner' of
<ent type='ORG'><ent type='ORG'>Franklin</ent> <ent type='ORG'>National Bank</ent></ent>, helped by the Gambino <ent type='ORG'>Mafia</ent> family and David
<ent type='PERSON'>Kennedy</ent> - Chairman of <ent type='ORG'>Continental</ent> <ent type='GPE'>Illinois</ent> Bank and Nixon's Secretary of
the <ent type='ORG'>Treasury</ent>.</p>

<p><ent type='LOC'>Pacific</ent> Basin Economic <ent type='ORG'>Council</ent> Conference in <ent type='GPE'>Wellington</ent>, NZ.
Vice-President <ent type='PERSON'>Shigeo Nagano</ent> also chairman of <ent type='ORG'>Nippon Steel</ent> and member of
<ent type='ORG'>Onassis</ent> and other <ent type='ORG'>World Government</ent> organisations. Chairman of NZ
sub-committee, J. <ent type='PERSON'>Mowbray</ent> is also General Manager of <ent type='ORG'>the National Bank</ent>.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, <ent type='PERSON'>Michele Sindona</ent>, acting as the go-between for the <ent type='ORG'>Mafia</ent> and the
<ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>, was the conduit between US and European banks. <ent type='PERSON'>Michele Sindona</ent>'s
<ent type='ORG'>Vatican Bank</ent> and asso<ent type='ORG'>cia</ent>te Calvi's Abrosiano Bank was used to finance <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>
neo-fascist <ent type='NORP'>Italian</ent>/<ent type='NORP'>Latin American</ent> operations through <ent type='PERSON'>Licio Gelli</ent>'s P2
Lodge, which helped to organise the 'death squads' of <ent type='GPE'>Argentina</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Uruguay</ent> a
nd <ent type='GPE'>Chile</ent>. This aided the P2 members such as <ent type='PERSON'>Klaus Barbie</ent> ('The <ent type='PERSON'>Butcher</ent> of
Lyons') and <ent type='PERSON'>Jose Rega</ent> - organizer of the A.A.A. in <ent type='GPE'>Argentina</ent>.</p>

<p>16th August, 1972: <ent type='LOC'>Gulf</ent> Oil asso<ent type='ORG'>cia</ent>te <ent type='PERSON'>Bob Seldon</ent> helps establish new
banking operation, f<ent type='ORG'>irs</ent>t NZ international banks include Bank of New
Zealand, D.F.C. (<ent type='GPE'>Aust</ent>), N.Z.I., <ent type='ORG'>Morgan Guaranty Trust</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Morgan Grenfel</ent> and
S.F. Warburg.</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>Fletcher</ent>s begins expansion overseas with deals signed in <ent type='GPE'>Indonesia</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Fiji</ent>
and <ent type='GPE'>New Guinea</ent>.</p>

<p>December 1972: <ent type='PERSON'>Kirk</ent> elected Prime Minister of <ent type='GPE'>New Zealand</ent>.</p>

<p>February, 1973: <ent type='PERSON'>Gerald Parsky</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>William Colby</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Michael Hand</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Frank Nugan</ent> and
<ent type='PERSON'>Bob Seldon</ent> move to further consolidate the <ent type='ORG'>Mafia</ent> banking operations. In NZ
they acquire 20% <ent type='ORG'>Fletcher</ent> subsidiary <ent type='PERSON'>Marac</ent>, using the <ent type='ORG'>Security Pacific</ent>
<ent type='ORG'>National Bank</ent> helped by <ent type='PERSON'>Marac</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Corporate</ent> secretary <ent type='PERSON'>Alan Hawkins</ent>.</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Frank Nugan</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Michael Hand</ent> use <ent type='ORG'>Fletcher</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>Renouf</ent> and their NZ United
Corporation to link with I.E.L. and <ent type='PERSON'>Brierly</ent> Investments through
cross-shareholding agreement.</p>

<p>In <ent type='GPE'>Aust</ent>ralia, the <ent type='PERSON'>Nugan</ent> Hand Bank begins operations with 30% of the stock
held by A'<ent type='NORP'>asian</ent> and <ent type='LOC'>Pacific</ent> Holdings (100% <ent type='ORG'>Chase Manhattan</ent> Bank), 25% by
CIA's <ent type='ORG'>Air America</ent> (known as 'Air Opium'), 25% by South <ent type='LOC'>Pacific</ent> Properties
and 20% held by <ent type='PERSON'>Seldon</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Nugan</ent> and Hand.</p>

<p>The <ent type='ORG'>Irving Trust</ent> Bank's <ent type='ORG'>New York Branch</ent> establishes US links between the
<ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Nugan</ent> Hand, a worldwide network of 22 banks set up to:</p>

<p>a) 'launder' money from <ent type='ORG'>Onassis</ent> heroin operations in the Golden Triangle
and <ent type='GPE'>Iran</ent>;
b) as a <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> funnel to pro-US political parties in Europe and <ent type='LOC'>Latin America</ent>,
including Colby's P2;
c) a spying conduit for information from Cambodia, <ent type='GPE'>Laos</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Vietnam</ent> and
<ent type='GPE'>Thailand</ent>;
d) finance arms smuggled to <ent type='GPE'>Libya</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Indonesia</ent>, <ent type='LOC'>South America</ent>, <ent type='LOC'>Middle East</ent>
and <ent type='GPE'>Rhodesia</ent> using the CIA's Edward Wilson.</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Colby</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Kissinger</ent> use key <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>Naval Intelligence</ent> officers to oversee
the operation, including Walter <ent type='PERSON'>McDonald</ent> (former Deputy Director <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>), Dale
Holmgren (Flight Service Manager <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> Civil Air Transport), <ent type='PERSON'>Robert Jansen</ent>
(former <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> Station Chief, <ent type='GPE'>Bangkok</ent>) etc.</p>

<p>Heroin flown into <ent type='GPE'>Aust</ent>ralia by CIA's <ent type='ORG'>Air America</ent> and trans-shipped to
<ent type='ORG'>Onassis</ent> lieutenant in <ent type='GPE'>Florida</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Santos Trafficante</ent> Jr, assisted by
<ent type='GPE'>Aust</ent>ralian Federal Bureau of Narcotics offi<ent type='ORG'>cia</ent>ls and co-ordinated by CIA's
<ent type='PERSON'><ent type='PERSON'>Ray</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Cline</ent></ent>.</p>

<p>14th June, 1973: Inauguration of the <ent type='ORG'>Onassis</ent> shadow <ent type='ORG'>World Government</ent> - the
<ent type='ORG'>Trilateral Commission</ent>. Includes over 200 members from the US, Europe and
<ent type='GPE'>Japan</ent> - bankers, government offi<ent type='ORG'>cia</ent>ls, transnational corporations' top
executives, trade unionists, etc. Of the world's largest corporations, 24
directly represented and dozens more through interlocking directorships.</p>

<p>* <ent type='ORG'>Trilateralist</ent> strategy: monopolisation of the world's resources,
production facilities, labour technology, markets, transport and finance.
These aims backed up by the US military and industrial complexes that are
already controlled and backed up by the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>.</p>

<p>18th August, 1973: <ent type='PERSON'><ent type='PERSON'>Ray</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Cline</ent></ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Michael Hand</ent> meet in <ent type='GPE'>Adelaide</ent> to discuss
<ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> plan to establish spying operations in NZ.</p>

<p>September 1973: Seagrams, with strong links to <ent type='ORG'>Chase Manhattan</ent> Bank of
<ent type='GPE'>Montreal</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>Toronto Dominion Bank</ent>, buys 2800 acres of prime land in
<ent type='GPE'>Marlborough</ent> helped by <ent type='PERSON'>Peter Maslen</ent>.</p>

<p>17th February, 1974: <ent type='ORG'>Mafia</ent> sets up <ent type='LOC'>New Hebrides</ent> Bank - Commer<ent type='ORG'>cia</ent>l <ent type='LOC'>Pacific</ent>
Trust Co (<ent type='ORG'>COMPAC</ent>). Banks include <ent type='ORG'>CBA</ent>, Europacific Finance Corporation,
Trustee Executors and Agency Co, Fuji Bank, <ent type='ORG'>Toronto Dominion Bank</ent>, European
<ent type='LOC'>Asia</ent>n Bank and United <ent type='GPE'>California</ent> Bank, <ent type='ORG'>COMPAC</ent> to be used as a cover for
heroin dollar laundering operations.</p>

<p>26th February, 1974: <ent type='PERSON'>Michael Hand</ent> meets <ent type='PERSON'>Bob Jones</ent> in <ent type='GPE'>Wellington</ent> to
implement plans for the CIA's new spying operation - countries targeted
include <ent type='GPE'>France</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Chile</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>West Germany</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent>.</p>

<p>Using the <ent type='PERSON'>Brierly</ent>/<ent type='PERSON'>Jones</ent> Investment funnel, <ent type='PERSON'>Jones</ent> buys building in Willeston
Street which will be rented to <ent type='GPE'>France</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Chile</ent>, another at Plimmer Steps
to house <ent type='GPE'>West Germany</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent>.</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> will set up eavesdropping communications centre inside the Willeston
Street building and another at 163 The Terrace which will link with
equipment installed in the Plimmer Steps building. Four <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> techni<ent type='ORG'>cia</ent>ns
will run the whole operation.</p>

<p>April 1974: Finance Minister <ent type='PERSON'>Rowling</ent> appoints <ent type='PERSON'>Ron Trotter</ent> to the Overseas
Investment Commission, whose chairman, G. Lau, is also a member of the <ent type='PERSON'>Todd</ent>
Foundation (<ent type='ORG'>Shell</ent>/BP/<ent type='PERSON'>Todd</ent>) investment board.</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>Whitlam</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Kirk</ent></p>

<p>Mid-1974: Gough <ent type='ORG'>Whitlam</ent> and Norman <ent type='PERSON'>Kirk</ent> begin a series of moves absolutely
against the <ent type='ORG'>Mafia</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Trilateralist</ent>s. <ent type='ORG'>Whitlam</ent> refuses to waive restrictions on
overseas borrowings to finance <ent type='ORG'>Alwest Aluminium Consortium</ent> of Rupert
<ent type='ORG'>Murdoch</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>BHP</ent> and R.J. <ent type='PERSON'>Reynolds</ent>. <ent type='ORG'>Whitlam</ent> had also ended <ent type='GPE'>Vietnam</ent> War
support, blocked uranium mining and wanted more control over US secret spy
bases - e.g. Pine Gap.</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Kirk</ent> had introduced a new, tough Anti-Monopoly <ent type='PERSON'>Bill</ent> and had tried to
redistribute income from big companies to the labour force through price
regulation and a wages policy.</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Kirk</ent> had also rejected plans to build a second aluminium smelter near
Dunedin and was preparing the Petroleum Amendment <ent type='PERSON'>Bill</ent> to give more control
over <ent type='GPE'>New Zealand</ent> oil resources.</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Kirk</ent> had found out that Hunt Petroleum, drilling in <ent type='LOC'>the Great South Basin</ent>,
had discovered a huge resource of oil comparable in size to the <ent type='PERSON'>North</ent> Sea
or <ent type='NORP'>Alaskan</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>North</ent> Slope. Gas reserves alone now estimated at 30 times
bigger than <ent type='ORG'>Kapuni</ent> and oil reserves of at least 20 billion barrels - enough
for <ent type='GPE'>New Zealand</ent> to be self-sufficient for years. Oil companies completely
hushed up these facts. To have announced a vast new oil source would
probably mean a decline in world oil prices, which would not have allowed
<ent type='ORG'>OPEC</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>Onassis</ent> plans for the <ent type='NORP'>Arabs</ent> to eventuate. N.Z. could be exploited
at a later date, particularly since the <ent type='PERSON'>North</ent> Sea operations were about to
come on stream - <ent type='PERSON'>Kirk</ent> was the last to hold out.</p>

<p>September, 1974: According to <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> sources, <ent type='PERSON'>Kirk</ent> was killed by the
<ent type='ORG'>Trilateralist</ent>s using Sodium Morphate. Rowling's f<ent type='ORG'>irs</ent>t act as NZ Prime
Minister was to withdraw Kirk's Anti-Monopoly <ent type='PERSON'>Bill</ent> and the Petroleum
Amendment <ent type='PERSON'>Bill</ent>.</p>

<p>Later, <ent type='PERSON'>Rowling</ent> was to be rewarded with ambassadorship to <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>.
Incidentally, the Shah of <ent type='GPE'>Iran</ent> was murdered the same way as <ent type='PERSON'>Kirk</ent> on his
arrival in the US.</p>

<p>6th October, 1974: <ent type='PERSON'>Ray</ent> cline implements <ent type='PERSON'>William Colby</ent> plan to oust
<ent type='GPE'>Aust</ent>ralian Prime Minister <ent type='ORG'>Whitlam</ent>. <ent type='PERSON'>Nugan</ent> Hand Bank finances payoffs to
<ent type='PERSON'>Malcolm Fraser</ent> and other pro-US politi<ent type='ORG'>cia</ent>ns. A joint bugging operation
commences between <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> and ASIA.</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Rupert Murdoch</ent>, playing his part, uses his newspapers and television
network to spread lies and misinformation. <ent type='ORG'>Whitlam</ent>, as well as refusing to
waive restrictions on overseas borrowing to finance the aluminium
consortium, had plans to ensure that all corporations were at least 50%
<ent type='GPE'>Aust</ent>ralian-owned. This interfered with the <ent type='ORG'>Seven Sisters</ent>' plans to build
three oil refineries at Cape <ent type='PERSON'>North</ent>umberland in South <ent type='GPE'>Aust</ent>ralia to exploit
<ent type='LOC'>the Great South Basin</ent> discovery.</p>

<p>December, 1974: <ent type='GPE'>Aust</ent>ralian Governor-General <ent type='PERSON'>John Kerr</ent> joins <ent type='PERSON'><ent type='PERSON'>Ray</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Cline</ent></ent>'s
payroll and received his f<ent type='ORG'>irs</ent>t pay-off of $US200000 credited to his
account number 767748 at the <ent type='GPE'>Singapore</ent> branch of the <ent type='PERSON'>Nugan</ent> Hand Bank.</p>

<p>11th November, 1975: Governor-General <ent type='PERSON'>Kerr</ent> sacks the <ent type='ORG'>Whitlam</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Government</ent>.</p>

<p>August 1975: <ent type='PERSON'>Rowling</ent> re-introduces unrecognisable <ent type='ORG'>Commerce</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Bill</ent>, designed
to aid monopolisation of the NZ economy and repeals the News Media
Ownership Act, allowing more foreign ownership of NZ media. The new
legislation does not define monopoly, competition or stipulate permissable
maximum market share, or even ascertain what the public interest is -
resulting in a sell-out to big business.</p>

<p>December, 1975: Election battle between <ent type='PERSON'>Rowling</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Muldoon</ent>. Oil companies
pour thousands of dollars into Muldoon's campaign via <ent type='ORG'>National Bank</ent> (NZ),
whose general manager <ent type='PERSON'>Mowbray</ent> is also a member of <ent type='PERSON'>Todd</ent> Foundations;
Investment Board Director Tudhope also Managing Director <ent type='ORG'>Shell Oil</ent> and
Chairman <ent type='ORG'>Shell</ent>/BP/<ent type='PERSON'>Todd</ent>. <ent type='PERSON'>Muldoon</ent> wins.</p>

<p>February, 1976: <ent type='PERSON'>Muldoon</ent> implements pre-election secret agreement with the
NZ <ent type='ORG'>Seven Sisters</ent>' oil representatives of <ent type='ORG'>Shell</ent>/BP/<ent type='PERSON'>Todd</ent> for helping finance
the <ent type='ORG'>National Party</ent> campaign.</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Muldoon</ent> removes the $3 per barrel oil levy for the <ent type='GPE'>New Zealand</ent> Refining
Company, which increases the oil companies' profits by 100% at the
taxpayers' expense and with all future oil prospecting licenses, the
<ent type='ORG'>Government</ent> has the option to take 51% of any discovery without meeting
exploration costs. This is designed to discourage further exploration,
thereby keeping the lid on <ent type='LOC'>the Great South Basin</ent> discovery.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, in <ent type='GPE'>Aust</ent>ralia, new P.M. <ent type='PERSON'>Malcolm Fraser</ent> reopens uranium mining and
opens the way for takeover of mineral resources with big tax breaks for oil
exploration, coal and mining.</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Muldoon</ent> returns a favour to the oil companies by arranging $US200 million
loan for <ent type='ORG'>Maui Gas Development</ent> for <ent type='ORG'>Shell</ent>/BP/<ent type='PERSON'>Todd</ent>.</p>

<p>September, 1976: With captive politi<ent type='ORG'>cia</ent>ns in place in both <ent type='GPE'>Aust</ent>ralia and
<ent type='GPE'>New Zealand</ent>, the <ent type='NORP'>Internationalists</ent> can now proceed with their strategy of
takeover of the economy and exploitation of natural resources. "In New
Zealand, the elimination of unnecessary competition is fundamental to a
sound economy," <ent type='PERSON'>Brierly</ent> says.</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Parksy</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Colby</ent> use <ent type='PERSON'>Brierly</ent>/<ent type='PERSON'>Jones</ent> Investments as a vehicle to buy into
A.B. Consolidated Holdings in <ent type='GPE'>New Zealand</ent>.</p>

<p>Asso<ent type='ORG'>cia</ent>te of R. <ent type='PERSON'>Jones</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Pat Goodman</ent>, is appointed 'consultant' of A'<ent type='NORP'>asian</ent>
and <ent type='LOC'>Pacific</ent> Holdings.</p>

<p>November, 1976: The <ent type='NORP'>Internationalists</ent> (<ent type='ORG'>Mafia</ent>) set up a NZ money 'funnel'
using Brierley's City Realties. <ent type='ORG'>National Insurance</ent> Co acquires 33% of the
stock. Largest stockholders in <ent type='ORG'>National Insurance</ent> are the US Firemen's
Fund - Chairman and President Myron Du Bain also Vice Chairman of <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n
Express (<ent type='ORG'>Amex</ent>). Chairman of I.E.L. linked <ent type='ORG'>International Harvester</ent>, Archie
McCardell, also <ent type='ORG'>Amex</ent> Director. <ent type='ORG'>Amex</ent> linked with <ent type='ORG'>Chase Manhattan</ent> and Seven
Sisters' <ent type='ORG'>Texaco</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>Mobil</ent>. Du Bain also Director of <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>-linked United
<ent type='GPE'>California</ent> Bank, which is a partner in Commer<ent type='ORG'>cia</ent>l <ent type='LOC'>Pacific</ent> Trust.</p>

<p>To complete the money funnel, <ent type='ORG'>National Insurance</ent> becomes a stockholder in
<ent type='ORG'>Chase Manhattan</ent>'s Chase-NBA. Brierley's declared assets reach $100
million, with shareholder's capital of only $2.5 million - all cash
acquisitions.</p>

<p>3rd February, 1977: <ent type='PERSON'>Parksy</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Colby</ent> close down the <ent type='ORG'>Brierley</ent>/<ent type='PERSON'>Jones</ent>
Investment funnel and open up seperate channels for <ent type='ORG'>Brierley</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Jones</ent>.
<ent type='PERSON'>Jones</ent> will be supplied with 'laundered' funds via <ent type='GPE'>Sydney</ent> branch of the
<ent type='PERSON'>Nugan</ent> Hand Bank, while for Ron <ent type='ORG'>Brierley</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Gerald Parsky</ent> uses Myron Du Bain,
Director of United <ent type='GPE'>California</ent> Bank and also chairman and president of the
US Firemen's Fund, which are the largest stockholders in <ent type='ORG'>National Insurance</ent>
(NZ). Funds to be 'laundered' via <ent type='ORG'>Chase Manhattan</ent> Bank through National
Insurance to City Realty and via United <ent type='GPE'>California</ent> Bank through <ent type='ORG'>COMPAC</ent>
(<ent type='LOC'>New Hebrides</ent>) to <ent type='ORG'>National Insurance</ent> and City Realties.</p>

<p>To expand the Bierley/I.E.L. 'front', <ent type='PERSON'>Parsky</ent> establishes Industrial Equity
<ent type='LOC'>Pacific</ent> (<ent type='GPE'>Hong Kong</ent>).</p>

<p>September 1977: Brierley's new holding company begins operations -
A.B. Consolidated. H.W. <ent type='ORG'>Revell</ent> appointed Deputy Chairman and B. Hancox
General Manager, while newly-appointed directors include S. Cushing,
B. Judge, O. <ent type='PERSON'>Gunn</ent> and P. <ent type='ORG'>Goodman</ent>, linked with <ent type='ORG'>Renouf</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Fletcher</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Papps</ent>
through I.E.L./N.Z.U.C.</p>

<p>* Strategy: To target and divide key sectors of the economy for takeover,
exploitation and monopolization. Operations to extend to use <ent type='GPE'>Hong Kong</ent>
facility, I.E.P. <ent type='ORG'>Fletcher</ent>s to extend the <ent type='ORG'>Khashoggi</ent>/<ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Travelodge</ent>
operation by taking holdings in <ent type='ORG'>Vacation Hotels</ent> and Intercontinental
Properties (<ent type='ORG'>Renouf</ent> Chairman).</p>

<p>October, 1977: <ent type='PERSON'>Muldoon</ent> and JOhn <ent type='PERSON'>Todd</ent> - <ent type='ORG'>Shell</ent>/BP/<ent type='PERSON'>Todd</ent> - sign an agreement.
NZ Govt would take 24.5% holding in <ent type='LOC'>the Great South Basin</ent> for $1.65
<ent type='PERSON'>Bill</ent>ion. Hunt would reduce his holding from 45.5% to 27.5% and <ent type='ORG'>Arco</ent> would
sell its 6.5%.</p>

<p>* Reason: Hunt did not possess the technology to pump oil from deep water;
<ent type='LOC'>Gulf</ent> possessed the technology but did not tell Hunt. <ent type='ORG'>Arco</ent> was not told
anything and were swindled out of its 6.5% concession.</p>

<p>November, 1977: <ent type='PERSON'>Muldoon</ent> introduces the S.I.S Amendment <ent type='PERSON'>Bill</ent>, designed to
keep the economy free of obstruction and to help uncover obstructive
elements. Telephone taps, mail tampering and other surveillance methods
approved after <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> input on contents of legislation.</p>

<p>Late 1977: <ent type='PERSON'>Muldoon</ent> travels to the US to meet top <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> offi<ent type='ORG'>cia</ent>ls,
including <ent type='ORG'>Trilateralist</ent>s' Deputy Secretary of State, <ent type='PERSON'>Warren Christopher</ent>,
and <ent type='PERSON'>Richard Bolbrooke</ent>, who were in charge of the new "South <ent type='LOC'>Pacific</ent> Desk"
at the State Department established by <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> to target exploitation
of both <ent type='GPE'>New Zealand</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Aust</ent>ralia. In <ent type='GPE'>Los Angeles</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Muldoon</ent> meets top
<ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> offi<ent type='ORG'>cia</ent>ls, <ent type='PERSON'>Robert Anderson</ent> (<ent type='ORG'>Rockwell</ent> Chairman, also Director of
Kashoggi's <ent type='ORG'>Security Pacific</ent> <ent type='ORG'>National Bank</ent>) and P. Larkin (<ent type='ORG'>Rockwell</ent>
Director, also Chairman, <ent type='ORG'>Executive</ent> Committee <ent type='ORG'>Security Pacific</ent> <ent type='ORG'>National Bank</ent>
and Director of <ent type='PERSON'>Marac</ent>).</p>

<p>April, 1978: <ent type='PERSON'>Muldoon</ent> sets up <ent type='ORG'>Petrocorp</ent>. <ent type='GPE'>New Zealand</ent> taxpayers pay for the
exploration costs but the oil companies control all distribution outlets.
<ent type='PERSON'>Muldoon</ent> blocks development of <ent type='LOC'>Maui</ent> B as restructured supplies mean higher
prices and bigger profits for <ent type='ORG'>Shell</ent>/BP/<ent type='PERSON'>Todd</ent>. <ent type='LOC'>South Island</ent> gas market not
developed as <ent type='LOC'>Great South Basin</ent> fields closer than <ent type='ORG'>Kapuni</ent>. Plans develop
for re-opening of <ent type='ORG'>National Parks</ent> for mineral exploitation.</p>

<p>22nd July, 1978: Director of <ent type='GPE'>Aust</ent>ralian Federal Bureau of Narcotics
suspends his investigation into the <ent type='PERSON'>Nugan</ent> Hand Bank after pressure from the
<ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Aust</ent>ralian politi<ent type='ORG'>cia</ent>ns controlled by <ent type='ORG'>Mafia</ent>, particularly Malcolm
Fraser.</p>

<p>Brierly's declared assets reach $200 million, with shareholders' funds only
$17 million.</p>

<p>May, 1979: <ent type='ORG'>Trilateral Commission</ent> secretary <ent type='PERSON'>Zbignieu Brzezinski</ent> appoints
<ent type='PERSON'>Muldoon</ent> chairman of Board of Governors of IMF/<ent type='ORG'>World Bank</ent> on orders of
David <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent>. <ent type='PERSON'>Muldoon</ent> would head three-man administration committee
which included Canadian Finance Minister <ent type='PERSON'>Mitchell Sharp</ent>, key figure in the
<ent type='ORG'>Mafia</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Council</ent> and the <ent type='ORG'>Trilateral Commission</ent>. <ent type='GPE'>Aust</ent>ralian Treasurer McMahon
also involved.</p>

<p>8th June, 1979: <ent type='PERSON'>Michael Hand</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Frank Nugan</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Brierley</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>James Fetcher</ent> meet
in Hand's <ent type='GPE'>Sydney</ent> penthouse to discuss the establishment of the <ent type='GPE'>New Zealand</ent>
<ent type='ORG'>Mafia</ent> organization.</p>

<p>Mid-1979: <ent type='LOC'>Gulf</ent> Oil using its man <ent type='ORG'>Brierley</ent>, begins operations designed to
capture key sectors of the economy. A.B Consolidated restructured into the
<ent type='ORG'>Goodman</ent> Group and <ent type='ORG'>Goodman</ent> to run operations but with the majority of the
stock held by IEL and <ent type='ORG'>Brierley</ent> using <ent type='ORG'>Shell</ent> companies plus dummy
corporations.</p>

<p>* Strategy: To take over food and produce resources, <ent type='ORG'>Brierley</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>Fletcher</ent>
restructured a small private company, H.W. Smith, using <ent type='PERSON'>Cyril Smith</ent> as
Chairman but with key executives Judge, <ent type='PERSON'>Collins</ent> and McKenzie.
<ent type='PERSON'>Bob Jones</ent> helps.</p>

<p>Private company used, as no <ent type='ORG'>Commerce</ent> Commission control, accounts not
published, no public disclosure of transactions. Bunting is established as
a shell company and the <ent type='LOC'>South Island</ent> is targeted for asset-stripping and
takeover, as well as key sectors of the automobile industry.</p>

<p>Unlimited funds channelled through City Realties, NZUC and <ent type='PERSON'>Marac</ent>.
<ent type='ORG'>UEB</ent> extends <ent type='ORG'>Travelodge</ent> operations by buying control of Transholdings, which
has strategic holdings in <ent type='ORG'>Vacation Hotels</ent> and Tourist Corp. <ent type='GPE'>Fiji</ent> Holdings.</p>

<p>17th August, 1979: <ent type='GPE'>New Zealand</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Mafia</ent> inaugral meeting in <ent type='GPE'>Sydney</ent> including
Hand, <ent type='ORG'>Brierley</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Fletcher</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Goodman</ent>, R.<ent type='ORG'>Trotter</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Alan Hawkins</ent> and L.<ent type='PERSON'>Papps</ent>.</p>

<p>Key sectors of the economy would be taken over - food, using <ent type='ORG'>Goodman</ent>;
forestry and farming, using <ent type='ORG'>Fletcher</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>Trotter</ent>; property, using <ent type='ORG'>Brierley</ent>
and <ent type='PERSON'>Jones</ent>. <ent type='ORG'>Brierley</ent>, Hand and <ent type='PERSON'>Papps</ent> would be responsible for banking,
insurance and finance, while <ent type='ORG'>Hand and Hawkins</ent> would be responsible for
setting up new "laundry" channels into <ent type='GPE'>New Zealand</ent>.</p>

<p>The economy would be taken over using cheap loans of less than 5%, while
consumers would pay 28%.</p>

<p>October, 1979: BP Oil begis $100 million joint venture deal with <ent type='ORG'>Fletcher</ent>
and <ent type='ORG'>Trotter</ent> at Tasman.</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Muldoon</ent> makes secret deal with oil companies which effectively robs New
Zealand taxpayers by giving <ent type='ORG'>Shell</ent>/BP/<ent type='PERSON'>Todd</ent> the <ent type='LOC'>Maui</ent> Gas deal. Normally the
granting of drilling rights on public land is done using a worldwide system
which incorporates an auction tender system. <ent type='PERSON'>Muldoon</ent> bypassed this.
Also, <ent type='ORG'>Shell</ent>/BP/<ent type='PERSON'>Todd</ent> pays no tax on <ent type='ORG'>Kapuni</ent> profits, while putting funds into
<ent type='LOC'>Maui</ent> development.</p>

<p>19th November, 1979: Secret meeting in <ent type='GPE'>Auckland</ent> between <ent type='PERSON'>Muldoon</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Fletcher</ent>
and <ent type='ORG'>Trotter</ent> to transfer 43% <ent type='ORG'>Tasman Pulp and Paper</ent> held by <ent type='GPE'>New Zealand</ent>
<ent type='ORG'>Government</ent> to <ent type='ORG'>Challenge Corporation</ent> (Chairman <ent type='ORG'>Trotter</ent>) and <ent type='ORG'>Fletcher</ent>s.
Tasman has lucrative 75-year contract for cheap timber signed in 1955.</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Muldoon</ent> paid off with a $1 million 'non-repayable' loan - $500000 to be
paid into account number 8746665 at <ent type='LOC'>New Hebrides</ent> branch of the <ent type='GPE'>Aust</ent>ralian
International Bank.</p>

<p>November, 1979: <ent type='PERSON'>Muldoon</ent> drops restrictions on foreign investment.
<ent type='ORG'>AMAX</ent> (Stnadard Oil of <ent type='GPE'>California</ent> subsidiary) captures the <ent type='PERSON'>Martha Hill</ent>
goldmine.</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Muldoon</ent> unveils the Government's plans (instructed by <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent>) to form
<ent type='GPE'>New Zealand</ent> into an offshore production base for the multi-national
corporations as benefits include government export incentives, stable
government, cheap labour, and so on.</p>

<p>27th November, 1979: <ent type='PERSON'>Gerald Parsky</ent>'s lieutenant, <ent type='PERSON'>David Kennedy</ent>, meets
<ent type='PERSON'>Muldoon</ent> to deliver $US100000 cash to <ent type='PERSON'>Muldoon</ent> for implementing the
<ent type='NORP'>Internationalists</ent>' <ent type='ORG'>Mafia</ent> Think Big plans.</p>

<p>These plans began with big contracts and guaranteed profits for the Seven
Sisters, <ent type='ORG'>Bechtel</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Mitsubishi</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Mitsui</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Nippon Steel</ent>, <ent type='NORP'>Internationalists</ent>'
<ent type='ORG'>Mafia</ent> banks.</p>

<p>With the experimental petroleum plant, the oil price has to be $50/barrel
to be profitable, yet Mobil's profits are guaranteed.</p>

<p><ent type='GPE'>New Zealand</ent> Steel is to be expanded 500%, even though there was a global
steel glut of 50%.</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>Fletcher</ent>s own 10% of <ent type='GPE'>New Zealand</ent> Steel and are majority stockholders in
<ent type='LOC'>Pacific</ent> Steel and control monopoly over wire rod, reinforcing steel. Also,
<ent type='GPE'>New Zealand</ent> taxpayers subsidize <ent type='ORG'>Fletcher</ent>s' profits.</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Muldoon</ent> introduces the National Development <ent type='PERSON'>Bill</ent> with 'fast-track'
legislation, to keep the economy 'free of obstruction' for long-term
monopolization.</p>

<p>C.E.R. plan introduced, designed to integrate the economies of <ent type='GPE'>Aust</ent>ralia
and <ent type='GPE'>New Zealand</ent> with the <ent type='ORG'>Trilateral Commission</ent> for the purpose of
exploiting the South <ent type='LOC'>Pacific</ent> countries and as a 'back-door' entrance into
<ent type='GPE'>China</ent> - the world's largest untapped consumer market. <ent type='GPE'>New Zealand</ent> is also
the closest country to <ent type='LOC'>Antarctica</ent>, which has a vast mineral resource for
future exploitation.</p>

<p>"Think Big" projects begin, even though <ent type='PERSON'>Muldoon</ent> aware of studies that show
<ent type='GPE'>New Zealand</ent> could conserve up to 40% of energy consumption using existing
technology, which would mean funds could be invested elsewhere to lower
consumer prices, lower inflation rates, less demand for imported oil and
increased employment by creating new industry to manufacture and install
energy-saving technology. None of these options seriously considered as
all would lessen profits for members of the <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> organizations.</p>

<p>December 1979: <ent type='PERSON'>Muldoon</ent> unveils 'stage two' of a four-stage plan to exploit
<ent type='LOC'>the Great South Basin</ent> discovery. Plan prepared by <ent type='ORG'>Trilateralist</ent> 'Think
Tank' - the Brookings <ent type='ORG'>Institute</ent>.</p>

<p>'Stage Two' includes methanol plant and synthetic petrol plant, which would
initially use gas from the <ent type='LOC'>Maui</ent> field and later would link with underwater
gas pipe from <ent type='LOC'>Campbell Island</ent>.</p>

<p>With the <ent type='GPE'>New Zealand</ent> Steel 500% expansion, 'stage three' of the project and
Think Big contracts to go to <ent type='ORG'>Bechtel</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Fluor Corp</ent>., <ent type='ORG'>Mitsubishi</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Mitsui</ent>,
<ent type='ORG'>Nippon Steel</ent>, etc. All investments would be financed by the <ent type='GPE'>New Zealand</ent>
taxpayer.</p>

<p>17th January, 1980: $500000 deposited in Muldoon's account number 8746665
at the <ent type='GPE'>Aust</ent>ralian International Bank, being the final payment for the
Tasman deal.</p>

<p>Early 1980: <ent type='GPE'>Kashoggi</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Travelodge</ent> operations extended with affiliation
agreement between <ent type='ORG'>Dominion Breweries</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>Western International Hotels</ent>
(Seattle F<ent type='ORG'>irs</ent>t <ent type='ORG'>National Bank</ent>).</p>

<p>May, 1980: Mafia's <ent type='PERSON'>Nugan</ent> Hand banking operation crashes after <ent type='PERSON'>Frank Nugan</ent>
killed. Death ruled as suicide even though no fingerprints found on the
rifle. <ent type='ORG'>Maloney</ent>, Houghton, Yates and Hand shred important documents, but
miss some. <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> helps <ent type='ORG'>Hand and Bank</ent> President <ent type='PERSON'>Donald Beasley</ent> escape to the
U.S. The <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Aust</ent>ralian Security Intelligence Organisation cover
everything up. <ent type='ORG'>Beazley</ent> appointed President of <ent type='GPE'>Miami</ent> City <ent type='ORG'>National Bank</ent>,
run by <ent type='PERSON'>Alberto Dugue</ent> for 'laundering' profits from the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Colombian</ent>
cocaine operation.</p>

<p>There is a probability that <ent type='PERSON'>Michael Hand</ent> killed <ent type='PERSON'>Frank Nugan</ent> because of his
involvement with Hand's fiancee.</p>

<p>25th May, 1980: <ent type='PERSON'>Colby</ent> arrived in <ent type='GPE'>Aust</ent>ralia to discuss replacement of the
<ent type='PERSON'>Nugan</ent> Hand Bank with Hand, <ent type='ORG'>Brierley</ent>, and <ent type='PERSON'>Seldon</ent>. Immediate funding
available from <ent type='GPE'>Sydney</ent> branch of the <ent type='ORG'>Deak Bank</ent>, a separate <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> operation,
and IEL would be used to buy <ent type='ORG'>NZI Corp</ent>., to prepare for future laundering
operations.</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>Maloney</ent>, Houghton, Yates, and Hand would shred all documents leading back
to the <ent type='GPE'>New Zealand</ent> <ent type='LOC'>Great South Basin</ent> connection, and the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> would help
<ent type='ORG'>Hand and Bank</ent> President <ent type='PERSON'>Don</ent>ald <ent type='ORG'>Beazley</ent> escape to the <ent type='GPE'>USA</ent>. The <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>ASIO</ent>
would also cover everything up.</p>

<p>Hand and <ent type='ORG'>Beazley</ent> turn up in <ent type='GPE'>Miami</ent> - <ent type='ORG'>Beazley</ent> appointed President and Hand
'consultant' to the <ent type='GPE'>Miami</ent> City <ent type='ORG'>National Bank</ent>, but also Hand turned up in El
Salvador to help organize bankrolling of the <ent type='NORP'>Contras</ent> with other ex-members
of <ent type='PERSON'>Nugan</ent>-Hand.</p>

<p>23rd June, 1980: <ent type='GPE'>New Zealand</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Mafia</ent>, including <ent type='ORG'>Brierley</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Fletcher</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Trotter</ent>,
<ent type='PERSON'>Jones</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Hawkins</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Goodman</ent>, and <ent type='PERSON'>Papps</ent> meet in <ent type='GPE'>Wellington</ent> to discuss merger of
<ent type='ORG'>Fletcher</ent> Challenge and Tasman.</p>

<p>In order to replace <ent type='PERSON'>Nugan</ent> Hand Bank's 22 world-wide branches, quick moves
are made to buy control of <ent type='ORG'>NZI</ent> by <ent type='GPE'>New Zealand</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Mafia</ent> using <ent type='ORG'>Brierley</ent>, thereby
capturing an established, world-wide organization through the <ent type='GPE'>Hong Kong</ent> and
<ent type='GPE'>Shanghai</ent> Bank, which is also linked to the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> through its subsidiary,
<ent type='ORG'>World Finance Corporation</ent>.</p>

<p>Late 1980: <ent type='ORG'>Fletcher</ent>s, with strong <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> links, obtains lucrative
contracts on US Bases in the <ent type='LOC'>Pacific</ent> and joint ventures in Saudi Arabia and
Iraq.</p>

<p>Control extended over <ent type='GPE'>New Zealand</ent> natural resources - <ent type='ORG'>Fletcher</ent> Challenge
and <ent type='ORG'>Tasman Pulp and Paper</ent> merged. NZFP takes control of M.S.D. Spiers and
Moore Le Messurier (<ent type='GPE'>Aust</ent>). <ent type='ORG'>Brierley</ent> begins joint venture with NZFP through
<ent type='PERSON'>Williamson</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Jeffrey</ent>. I.E.L, through <ent type='ORG'>Goodman</ent>, buys 20% of <ent type='ORG'>Watties</ent> and
begins cross-shareholding agreement. <ent type='ORG'>Goodman</ent> continues buying up control
of NZ bakeries and flour-mills.</p>

<p>February, 1981: <ent type='ORG'>TNL</ent>., <ent type='ORG'>Brierley</ent>, AMOIL and <ent type='ORG'>MIM</ent> Holdings begin joint gold
mining operation. <ent type='ORG'>MIM</ent> major shareholder is ASARCO (US), whose Chairman,
<ent type='PERSON'>Barber</ent>, is also Director of <ent type='ORG'>Chase Manhattan</ent> Bank.</p>

<p><ent type='GPE'>New Zealand</ent> Insurance and <ent type='NORP'>South British</ent> merger.</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>Parliamentarians For World</ent> Order - <ent type='PERSON'>Richard Prebble</ent> elected one of twelve
councillors.</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>Fletcher</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Papps</ent> (Chairman <ent type='ORG'>UEB</ent>) sell their hotel operations to
<ent type='NORP'>Singaporian</ent> interest closely asso<ent type='ORG'>cia</ent>ted with the <ent type='PERSON'>Pritzker</ent> family - owners
of the Hyatt Hotel chain. <ent type='PERSON'>Bueton Kanter</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Pritzker</ent> family lawyer and
Director of <ent type='ORG'>Hyatt Hotels</ent>, who helped arrange the deal, was an old family
partner of <ent type='PERSON'>Paul Helliwell</ent> (<ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> paymaster for <ent type='ORG'>the Bay</ent> of Pigs' fiasco) and
had helped the <ent type='PERSON'>Pritzker</ent> family set up tax shelters using the CIA's
<ent type='ORG'>Mercantile Bank</ent> and Trust and the <ent type='ORG'>Castle Bank</ent>, which had been set up by
<ent type='ORG'>Helliwell</ent> for 'laundering' profits from the <ent type='ORG'>Onassis</ent> heroin operations as
well as 'skim money' from the <ent type='ORG'>Hughes</ent> casino operations in <ent type='GPE'>Las Vegas</ent>.</p>

<p>Others who used these banks include Richard <ent type='PERSON'>Nixon</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Bebe Rozo</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Robert Vesco</ent>,
<ent type='ORG'>Teamsters Union</ent>, etc.</p>

<p>12th March, 1981: <ent type='ORG'>Brierley</ent> calls secret meeting in <ent type='GPE'>Auckland</ent>, which
includes <ent type='PERSON'>Jones</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Fletcher</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Hawkins</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Papps</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Burton Kanter</ent>, to discuss
transfer of the <ent type='ORG'>Fletcher</ent> Challenge and <ent type='ORG'>UEB</ent> hotel operations to the
<ent type='GPE'>Singapore</ent> front company controlled by the <ent type='PERSON'>Pritzker</ent> family.</p>

<p>20th July, 1981: <ent type='PERSON'>Parsky</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Colby</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Brierley</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Seldon</ent> meet in <ent type='GPE'>Sydney</ent> with
two new members, <ent type='PERSON'>Kerr</ent>y Packer and <ent type='PERSON'>Alan Bond</ent>.</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>Chase Manhattan</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>Security Pacific</ent> <ent type='ORG'>National Bank</ent> will acquire 60% of
Packer's company, with the stock being held in <ent type='GPE'>Aust</ent>ralia, and 35% Bond's
company, with the stock being held in <ent type='GPE'>Hong Kong</ent>.</p>

<p>August 1981: <ent type='LOC'>Gulf</ent> Oil, using <ent type='ORG'>Brierley</ent>, strengthens its hold over New
Zealand natural resources. <ent type='ORG'>Cue Energy</ent> launched, starring Lawrey and <ent type='PERSON'>Gunn</ent>.
<ent type='ORG'>NZOG</ent> launched with strategic holdings by <ent type='PERSON'>Jones</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Renouf</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>Brierley</ent> with
licenses in PPD 38206 and 38204 - both next to Hunt's <ent type='LOC'>Great South Basin</ent>
discovery, <ent type='ORG'>NZOG</ent> also controls 80 million tons of coal through the Pike
River Coal Company.</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>Brierley</ent>-controlled <ent type='GPE'>Wellington</ent> Gas, <ent type='ORG'>Christchurch Gas</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Auckland</ent> and Hawkes
Bay Gas and Dual Fuel Systems (A'<ent type='LOC'>Asia</ent>) which controls the vehicle gas
conversion market.</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>Liquigas Limited</ent> set up to distribute LPG, controlled by <ent type='ORG'>Shell</ent>/BP/<ent type='PERSON'>Todd</ent> and
<ent type='ORG'>Fletcher</ent> Challenge.</p>

<p>15th February, 1982: <ent type='ORG'>Brierley</ent> calls <ent type='GPE'>New Zealand</ent> meeting - <ent type='PERSON'>Jones</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Fletcher</ent>,
<ent type='ORG'>Trotter</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Hawkins</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Goodman</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Papps</ent>. New members include <ent type='PERSON'>Bruce</ent> Judge,
J. <ent type='PERSON'>Fernyhough</ent>, and Frank <ent type='ORG'>Renouf</ent>.</p>

<p>With <ent type='PERSON'>Muldoon</ent> about to deregulate the liquor industry, <ent type='ORG'>Brierley</ent> and
<ent type='PERSON'>Fernyhough</ent> plan to buy up the <ent type='GPE'>New Zealand</ent> liquor industry, along with its
outlets, <ent type='ORG'>Lion Breweries</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>Rothmans</ent> to help.</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>Brierley</ent> will do the same in <ent type='GPE'>Aust</ent>ralia. J.R. <ent type='ORG'>Fletcher</ent> becomes Managing
Director of Brierley's <ent type='ORG'>Dominion Breweries</ent> to oversee operations. <ent type='ORG'>Rothmans</ent>
and <ent type='ORG'>Brierley</ent> (through <ent type='ORG'>Goodman</ent>) have equal holdings in Saudicapital Corp.
Lion Directors <ent type='PERSON'>Myers</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Fernyhough</ent> also stockholders in <ent type='ORG'>NZOG</ent>.</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>Fletcher</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>Brierley</ent> begin their takeover of the freezing works industry.
<ent type='ORG'>FCL</ent> buys into <ent type='LOC'>South Island</ent> works while <ent type='ORG'>Brierley</ent> begins takeover of Waitaki
NZR through <ent type='ORG'>Watties</ent> with the help of <ent type='ORG'>Athol Hutton</ent>.</p>

<p>With Think Big projects beginning, <ent type='ORG'>Fletcher</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>Trotter</ent> plan to take
strategic holdings in NZ Cement, <ent type='ORG'>Wilkins Davies</ent>, Steel &amp; Tube etc., and
<ent type='ORG'>Brierley</ent> would use <ent type='ORG'>Renouf</ent> to take 3% stake of the <ent type='PERSON'>Martha Hill</ent> gold-mine.</p>

<p>Also targetted are clothing, footwear, carpet manufacture and more of the
auto industry for takeover and monopolization.</p>

<p>June, 1982: Meantime, in <ent type='GPE'>Aust</ent>ralia, a new money funnel begins. H.W Smith
buys obscure <ent type='ORG'>South Pine Quarries</ent>, which is renamed <ent type='PERSON'>Ariadne</ent> (<ent type='GPE'>Aust</ent>). South
Pine Quarries owns 50% of Coal-Liquid Inc., with the other half owned by US
Defence contractors Mc<ent type='PERSON'>Don</ent>nell <ent type='PERSON'>Douglas</ent>. Coal-Liquid renamed Impala
Securities.</p>

<p>The common link between <ent type='LOC'>Gulf</ent> Oil and Mc<ent type='PERSON'>Don</ent>nell <ent type='PERSON'>Douglas</ent> is the CIA's
<ent type='ORG'>Mercantile Bank</ent> and Trust, which both companies use for world-wide bribery
and payoff operations. Mc<ent type='PERSON'>Don</ent>nell <ent type='PERSON'>Douglas</ent> offi<ent type='ORG'>cia</ent>ls McKeough and
G.T. <ent type='PERSON'>Hawkins</ent> later appointed directors of <ent type='ORG'>Impala Securities</ent>.</p>

<p>US links strengthened through Industrial Equity <ent type='LOC'>Pacific</ent>, which acquires
part of <ent type='ORG'>Higbee Company</ent> in <ent type='GPE'>Cleveland</ent>, which in turn is closely linked to the
National City Bank of <ent type='GPE'>Cleveland</ent>. This bank is closely asso<ent type='ORG'>cia</ent>ted with <ent type='LOC'>Gulf</ent>
Oil's bank, <ent type='ORG'>Pittsburgh National</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>Mellon Bank</ent>.</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Bruce</ent> Judge installed as <ent type='PERSON'>Ariadne</ent> manager.</p>

<p>July, 1982: Media takeover begins. <ent type='ORG'>Brierley</ent> takes 24% NZ News Ltd and
begins buying up private radio. <ent type='PERSON'>Rupert Murdoch</ent> helps.</p>

<p>27th July, 1982. <ent type='ORG'>Brierley</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Jones</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>Goodman</ent> meet in <ent type='GPE'>Auckland</ent> with two
<ent type='NORP'>Japanese</ent> members of the <ent type='ORG'>Trilateral Commission</ent> to discuss integration of the
<ent type='GPE'>New Zealand</ent> economy into the <ent type='LOC'>Pacific</ent> Rim economy. <ent type='ORG'>Trilateralist</ent>s include:
<ent type='PERSON'>Takeshi Watanabe</ent> (<ent type='NORP'>Japanese</ent> Chairman of <ent type='ORG'>Trilateral Commission</ent>) and Daigo
Miyado (Chairman <ent type='ORG'>Sanwa Bank</ent>).</p>

<p>The <ent type='GPE'>Japan</ent>/<ent type='GPE'>New Zealand</ent> Business <ent type='ORG'>Council</ent> would be established to coordinate
policy with <ent type='ORG'>Goodman</ent> appointed as Chairman.</p>

<p>17th August, 1982: Inauguration of restructured US <ent type='ORG'>Mafia</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Council</ent> - rulers
include David <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent>, responsible for Banking; John McCloy; Redman
<ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> and J.D. <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent>, who would run the <ent type='ORG'>Seven Sisters</ent>.</p>

<p>Second-tier <ent type='ORG'>Council</ent> includes:</p>

<p> * <ent type='PERSON'>Gerald Parsky</ent> - responsible for heroin and cocaine operations
* <ent type='PERSON'>William Simon</ent> - responsible for running the Presidency, <ent type='ORG'>Cabinet</ent>, etc
* <ent type='PERSON'>Katherine Graham</ent> - link to arms manufacturers
* <ent type='PERSON'>Zbigniew Brzezinski</ent> - link to National Security <ent type='ORG'>Council</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>
* George S. <ent type='ORG'>Franklin</ent> - link to <ent type='ORG'>FBI</ent></p>

<p>Third-tier <ent type='ORG'>Council</ent> includes:</p>

<p> * <ent type='PERSON'>Zbigniew Brzezinski</ent> - Secretary
* <ent type='PERSON'>Gerald Parsky</ent> - <ent type='ORG'>Heroin Cocaine</ent> operations
* <ent type='PERSON'>William Colby</ent> - crack operations, assassinations
* John N. Perkins - banking, laundering
* <ent type='PERSON'>Leonard Woodcock</ent> - labour, unions
* <ent type='PERSON'>Mitchell Sharp</ent> - banking
* <ent type='PERSON'>William Simon</ent> - presidency, <ent type='ORG'>Cabinet</ent>
* Ernest C. <ent type='ORG'>Arbuckly</ent> - arms manufacturers
* George W. Bull - <ent type='GPE'>Bildrberg</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>Council</ent> of Foreign Relations
* <ent type='PERSON'>Katherine Graham</ent> - arms manufacturers
* Alden W. Clausen - <ent type='ORG'>World Bank</ent>, IMF
* Willam T. <ent type='ORG'>Coleman</ent> - <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>
* Archibald K. Davis - media, radio, television, and newspapers
* George S. <ent type='ORG'>Franklin</ent> - <ent type='ORG'>FBI</ent>, and <ent type='ORG'>Trilateral Commission</ent> co-ordinator
* J.D. <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> - to "spy" on the 15 man council.</p>

<p>September, 1982: <ent type='ORG'>Goodman</ent> now helps establish the <ent type='GPE'>Japan</ent>/<ent type='GPE'>New Zealand</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Council</ent>
with <ent type='ORG'>the Bank</ent> of Tokyo and <ent type='ORG'>the Industrial Bank</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>Japan</ent>. <ent type='ORG'>Tokai Pulp</ent> Co.
buys shareholding in NZFP, which also begins joint venture with <ent type='ORG'>Shell Oil</ent>.</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>Fletcher</ent> Challenge strengthens links with the <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> organization by
acquiring the Canadian operations of <ent type='ORG'>Crown Zellerbach</ent>, whose chairman is
also director of <ent type='LOC'>Gulf</ent> Oil. <ent type='ORG'>Crown Zellerbach</ent> Corp. has direct connections
to <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> through directors <ent type='PERSON'>Mumford</ent>, Hendrickson and <ent type='GPE'>Granville</ent>, to
United <ent type='GPE'>California</ent> Bank through <ent type='PERSON'>Roth</ent> and to <ent type='ORG'>the Bank</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> through
Chairman C.R. <ent type='ORG'>Dahl</ent>.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Robert <ent type='PERSON'>Jones</ent> Investments floated to extend operations of City
Realties, Ilmond Properties, <ent type='ORG'>Chase Corp</ent>., etc.</p>

<p>The <ent type='ORG'>Commerce</ent> Building in <ent type='GPE'>Auckland</ent> sold to Robert <ent type='PERSON'>Jones</ent> Investments by
Robert <ent type='PERSON'>Jones</ent> Holdings for $950000 when recently it was offered on the
market for $200000. A quick $750000 for <ent type='PERSON'>Jones</ent>. Robert <ent type='PERSON'>Jones</ent> Investments
was set up by <ent type='ORG'>Brierley</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Jones</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Hawkins</ent>.</p>

<p>8th December, 1982: <ent type='PERSON'>Mitchell Sharp</ent> heads top-level <ent type='ORG'>Mafia</ent> meeting in San
Francisco. Others include <ent type='PERSON'>Parsky</ent>, Perkins, Woodcock and C.R. <ent type='ORG'>Dahl</ent> -
Chairman of <ent type='ORG'>Crown Zellermach</ent>.</p>

<p>Also present are - <ent type='ORG'>Brierley</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Trotter</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Fletcher</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Seldon</ent>. Meeting to
discuss <ent type='LOC'>Great South Basin</ent> exploitation strategy with f<ent type='ORG'>irs</ent>t priority being
monopolization of the economy; second priority to establish oil refineries
and related industries; third to integrate <ent type='GPE'>New Zealand</ent> economy into
Trilateral economy and, fourth, to concentrate power back to the U.S
through the <ent type='ORG'>Seven Sisters</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Chase Manhattan</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>Security Pacific</ent> National
Bank.</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>Fletcher</ent> Challenge will link <ent type='GPE'>New Zealand</ent> economy directly to the U.S by
merging with Canadian subsidiary of <ent type='ORG'>Crown Zellerbach</ent> with funds provided by
<ent type='ORG'>Security Pacific</ent> <ent type='ORG'>National Bank</ent> and United <ent type='GPE'>California</ent>n Bank.</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>Brierley</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Fletcher</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Trotter</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Seldon</ent> will be <ent type='GPE'>New Zealand</ent> Ruling <ent type='ORG'>Council</ent>,
headed by <ent type='ORG'>Brierley</ent>, who would take orders from <ent type='PERSON'>Gerald Parsky</ent>.</p>

<p>Mid-1983: Brierley's <ent type='PERSON'>Ariadne</ent> (<ent type='GPE'>Aust</ent>) takes control of <ent type='ORG'>Repco</ent> (NZ) through
<ent type='ORG'>Repco</ent> (<ent type='GPE'>Aust</ent>), thereby taking control of key auto-related industry, helped
by <ent type='ORG'>Borg Warner</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>Honeywell</ent> - which are closely asso<ent type='ORG'>cia</ent>ted with IEL
through <ent type='ORG'>International Harvester</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Continental</ent> <ent type='GPE'>Illinois</ent> Bank and the F<ent type='ORG'>irs</ent>t
<ent type='ORG'>National Bank</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>. <ent type='ORG'>Toyota</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>Nissan</ent> also help so that <ent type='ORG'>Brierley</ent> now
largest distributor of auto and industrial parts, largest manufacturer of
pistons, filters and engine bearings, as well as biggest supplier of
forklifts, tractors and agricultural equipment.</p>

<p>Meantime, control is extended over <ent type='LOC'>the Great South Basin</ent> oil source with
Hunt, after big losses resulting from trying to corner the world's silver
market, being forced to sell out some of his concession to <ent type='LOC'>Gulf</ent> Oil, which
uses <ent type='ORG'>Brierley</ent> to set up a new company - <ent type='ORG'>Southern Petroleum</ent> - which takes a
14.5% interest. Hunt retains overall control with 45.5%, Petro-Corp has
40% and Chairman F. Orr, also a Director of <ent type='ORG'>Brierley</ent> - controlled <ent type='ORG'>Watties</ent>.</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>Brierley</ent>, through <ent type='ORG'>Goodman</ent>, takes control of <ent type='ORG'>TNL</ent> Group and its subsidiaries
NZ Motor Bodies and L &amp; M Mining, which has 15% interest in the <ent type='GPE'>Chatham</ent>
Rise, right next to the Hunt concession.</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>Southern Petroleum</ent> set up by <ent type='ORG'>Brierley</ent> in <ent type='GPE'>New Zealand</ent> was spearheaded by the
<ent type='ORG'>Seven Sisters</ent>' companies with <ent type='PERSON'>Gerald Parsky</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>William Colby</ent> initiators.
<ent type='ORG'>Southern Petroleum</ent> to include 21% of <ent type='LOC'>the Great South Basin</ent> held by gulf and
<ent type='ORG'>Mobil</ent> Oil. 90% of this stock held in <ent type='GPE'>Aust</ent>ralia through IEL
(ie Brierley's).</p>

<p>11-12th May, 1983: <ent type='GPE'>New Zealand</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Mafia</ent> meet in <ent type='GPE'>Cook Islands</ent>. Includes
<ent type='ORG'>Brierley</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Trotter</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Fletcher</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Jones</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Hawkins</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Goodman</ent>, Pappas, Judge,
<ent type='ORG'>Renouf</ent>, and <ent type='PERSON'>Fernyhough</ent>. New members include A. <ent type='PERSON'>Gibbs</ent>, McConnell,
H. <ent type='ORG'>Fletcher</ent> and O. <ent type='PERSON'>Gunn</ent>. <ent type='NORP'>Japanese</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Trilateralist</ent>s Takeshi Wataneve and
<ent type='PERSON'>Daigo Miyado</ent> discuss 'integration' of <ent type='GPE'>New Zealand</ent> into the <ent type='LOC'>Pacific</ent> Rim
economies.</p>

<p>A new political party would be established using <ent type='PERSON'>Jones</ent> and financed by the
<ent type='GPE'>New Zealand</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Mafia</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Council</ent>.</p>

<p> * Reason: <ent type='PERSON'>Parsky</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Colby</ent> wanted <ent type='PERSON'>Muldoon</ent> out because he had 'welched'
on a deal to set up two US military deep-water submarine bases planned for
Dusky Sound and Guards Bay in the <ent type='LOC'>South Island</ent>. <ent type='PERSON'>Parsky</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Brierley</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Ray</ent>
<ent type='PERSON'>Cline</ent> hold a separate meeting to discuss the purchase of <ent type='GPE'>New Zealand</ent>
politi<ent type='ORG'>cia</ent>ns, including <ent type='ORG'>Lange</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Douglas</ent> and Bolger.</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Cline</ent> was 'consultant' to the CIA's <ent type='ORG'>Deak Bank</ent>, took orders from <ent type='PERSON'>Colby</ent>, and
was responsible for the 10 <ent type='GPE'>Aust</ent>ralian politi<ent type='ORG'>cia</ent>ns on the CIA's payroll,
including <ent type='PERSON'>Bjelke Petersen</ent>, I. Sinclair, <ent type='PERSON'>Keating</ent>, McMullen, M.Fraser,
D. Anthony, K. Newman, J Carrick, B. <ent type='PERSON'>Cowan</ent> and R. Connor.</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Cline</ent> outlines <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> plan to begin subliminal television advertising.</p>

<p>22nd June, 1983: <ent type='GPE'>New Zealand</ent> politi<ent type='ORG'>cia</ent>n J. Bolger meets <ent type='PERSON'><ent type='PERSON'>Ray</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Cline</ent></ent> in
<ent type='GPE'>Sydney</ent> and agrees to join the organization for a monthly fee of $US20000
to be paid into account number GA1282117 at <ent type='GPE'>Geneva</ent> branch of Credit <ent type='NORP'>Swiss</ent>e.</p>

<p>20th July, 1983: <ent type='GPE'>New Zealand</ent> politi<ent type='ORG'>cia</ent>n R. <ent type='PERSON'>Douglas</ent> meets <ent type='PERSON'><ent type='PERSON'>Ray</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Cline</ent></ent> in
<ent type='GPE'>Wellington</ent> and agrees to join the organization for a monthly fee of
$US10000 to be paid into account number 3791686 at the <ent type='GPE'>Sydney</ent> Branch of
the <ent type='ORG'>Deak Bank</ent>.</p>

<p>July 1983: <ent type='PERSON'>Parsky</ent> launches a new front company, <ent type='ORG'>Chase Corp</ent>oration, with
25% of the stock being held through <ent type='ORG'>Security Pacific</ent> <ent type='ORG'>National Bank</ent> in
<ent type='GPE'>Aust</ent>ralia and 25% held in <ent type='GPE'>Hong Kong</ent> by <ent type='ORG'>Chase Manhattan</ent>. <ent type='ORG'>Brierley</ent> and
<ent type='PERSON'>Hawkins</ent> set up a 'back-door' listing to cover up true-ownership.</p>

<p>August, 1983: <ent type='PERSON'>Muldoon</ent> imposes withholding tax on all offshore borrowing.</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>Chase Manhattan</ent>, United <ent type='GPE'>California</ent> Bank and <ent type='ORG'>Brierley</ent> begin new banking
operation in <ent type='GPE'>New Zealand</ent> to take over the <ent type='ORG'>International Harvester</ent> Credit
Co (NZ), <ent type='GPE'>Aust</ent>ral<ent type='NORP'>asian</ent> Investment Company. Participants include Chase
Manhattan's <ent type='GPE'>Kuwait</ent> <ent type='LOC'>Asia</ent> Bank, D.F.C., Saudicorp (<ent type='ORG'>Brierley</ent> has 12% through
<ent type='ORG'>Goodman</ent>) and United <ent type='GPE'>California</ent>, represented by <ent type='ORG'>National Insurance</ent> which is
part of Equus Holdings.</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>Renouf</ent> sells 20% NZUC to <ent type='ORG'>Barclays</ent> and prepared for expanding of operations
with <ent type='ORG'>Brierley</ent>.</p>

<p>Meantime, <ent type='ORG'>Murdoch</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>Brierley</ent> expand their close ties by each taking a
piece of <ent type='GPE'>New Zealand</ent> Maritime Holdings and with the election imminent,
divide up <ent type='GPE'>New Zealand</ent> media for takeover to increase <ent type='ORG'>Mafia</ent> control.
NZ News buys <ent type='ORG'>Hawkes Bay</ent> News, <ent type='ORG'>Nelson Tribune</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Timaru Herald</ent>, etc.
<ent type='ORG'>Brierley</ent> increases holding in <ent type='ORG'>Hauraki Enterprises</ent> and other private radio
stations. <ent type='ORG'>Brierley</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>Murdoch</ent> have majority stockholding in <ent type='ORG'>NZPA</ent> with
48.5%, while in the UK, <ent type='ORG'>Murdoch</ent> has large stockholding in <ent type='ORG'>Reuters</ent>.</p>

<p>The phoney news becomes THE news.</p>

<p>Head of the <ent type='ORG'>Murdoch</ent> operation is <ent type='PERSON'>Burnett</ent>, who is also on the board of
<ent type='ORG'>Winstones</ent> - a <ent type='ORG'>Brierley</ent> company.</p>

<p>September, 1983: With global heroin epidemic, <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> expands
operations to recycle profits.</p>

<p><ent type='GPE'>New Zealand</ent> <ent type='NORP'>South British</ent> sets up the <ent type='ORG'>IDAPS</ent> computer bureau to establish
international holding companies, dummy corporations, etc and to pursue
aggressive global acquisition program. <ent type='ORG'>IDAPS</ent> linked to satellite bureau in
<ent type='GPE'>Aust</ent>ralia, <ent type='LOC'>Far East</ent>, UK and the US, where the global network is completed
through links with the <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> organization computer network.</p>

<p>General Manager of the operation, <ent type='PERSON'>George Wheller</ent>, previously director of
the international operators of Firemen's Fund (US), Chairman Du Bain,
director of <ent type='ORG'>the United California Bank</ent>, and Vice-Chairman of <ent type='ORG'>Amex</ent>.</p>

<p>As part of the expanded laundry operation, <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> asso<ent type='ORG'>cia</ent>te Adnan
<ent type='GPE'>Kashoggi</ent> establishes new <ent type='GPE'>Aust</ent>ralian bank - <ent type='ORG'>Security Pacific</ent> <ent type='ORG'>National Bank</ent>
(<ent type='GPE'>Aust</ent>). Brierley's part of this operation is to buy up computer companies
such as Andas, CID Distributors (NZ <ent type='ORG'>Apple</ent> computer franchise,etc).</p>

<p>Investment companies begin operations in <ent type='GPE'>Aust</ent>ralia and <ent type='GPE'>New Zealand</ent> to
assist recycle <ent type='ORG'>Mafia</ent> profits.</p>

<p>October 1983: <ent type='ORG'>Brierley</ent> takes over NZFP through <ent type='ORG'>Watties</ent>, helped by newly-appointed chairman <ent type='PERSON'>Papps</ent>. <ent type='PERSON'>Papps</ent> also chairman of NZ Railways and presided
over transport deregulation, the major benefi<ent type='ORG'>cia</ent>ries of which include
<ent type='ORG'>Watties</ent> and Freightways - Managing Director <ent type='PERSON'>Pettigrew</ent> and Director <ent type='PERSON'>Lang</ent>
also both on the NZFP board with <ent type='PERSON'>Papps</ent>.</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Papps</ent> also responsible for the railways' electrification program with big
contracts for <ent type='PERSON'>Cory Wright</ent> &amp; <ent type='ORG'>Slamon</ent>, whose directors include I.I McKay, also
on the board of NZFP.</p>

<p>Late 1983: <ent type='ORG'>AMAX</ent> (So<ent type='ORG'>cia</ent>l) gives <ent type='LOC'>Gulf</ent> Oil a share in the <ent type='PERSON'>Martha Hill</ent> gold
bonanza by selling 15% of its holdings to Briereley through <ent type='ORG'>Goodman</ent>s.
Oil companies say that only $870 million worth of minerals in <ent type='PERSON'>Martha Hill</ent>,
while true figure is closer to $3 billion.</p>

<p>21st January, 1984: <ent type='GPE'>Aust</ent>ralian <ent type='ORG'>Mafia</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Council</ent> meets in <ent type='GPE'>Sydney</ent>. Includes -
<ent type='ORG'>Brierley</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Seldon</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Fletcher</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Jones</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Goodman</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Hawkins</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Papps</ent>, Packer, <ent type='ORG'>Bond</ent>
and <ent type='NORP'>Japanese</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Trilaterist</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Daigo Miyado</ent>. New members include J. <ent type='PERSON'>Elliott</ent>,
L. <ent type='PERSON'>Adler</ent>, and Holme's A'<ent type='ORG'>Court</ent>. <ent type='PERSON'>Seldon</ent> outlines strategy of merging
<ent type='GPE'>Aust</ent>ralian economy with the <ent type='ORG'>Trilateralist</ent> economy through Europe and the
US.</p>

<p>In <ent type='GPE'>Aust</ent>ralia, the <ent type='ORG'>Mafia</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Council</ent> will monopolize the economy with company
takeovers through the use of loans at less than 5%.</p>

<p>Holme's A'Court's company would be taken over using <ent type='ORG'>Security Pacific</ent>
<ent type='ORG'>National Bank</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>Chase Manhattan</ent> Bank, with some of the stock being held
in <ent type='GPE'>London</ent>.</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>Equiticorp</ent> will be launched using <ent type='PERSON'>Hawkins</ent>, with 50% of the stock held by
<ent type='ORG'>Security Pacific</ent> <ent type='ORG'>National Bank</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>Chase Manhattan</ent> in the US <ent type='ORG'>Equiticorp</ent> to
registered in <ent type='GPE'>Hong Kong</ent> to cover up true ownership, and will use the same
laundry as <ent type='ORG'>Chase Corp</ent>oration - <ent type='PERSON'>Hawkins</ent> will set up a maze of shell
companies and dummy organizations to disguise operations.</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Hawkins</ent> previously asso<ent type='ORG'>cia</ent>ted with <ent type='GPE'>Kashoggi</ent> when <ent type='ORG'>Corporate</ent> Secretary of
<ent type='PERSON'>Marac</ent>, and linked with <ent type='ORG'>Renouf</ent> through their stockholding in <ent type='ORG'>CBA</ent> Finance,
which is a partner in Commer<ent type='ORG'>cia</ent>l <ent type='LOC'>Pacific</ent> Trust with United <ent type='GPE'>California</ent> Bank,
<ent type='PERSON'>Hawkins</ent> forms umbrella company with <ent type='ORG'>Chase Corp</ent>l, Jedi Investments and
Teltherm and begins setting up a maze of cross holding companies. <ent type='ORG'>Brierley</ent>
retains his connection through his <ent type='ORG'>Charter Corporation</ent>'s holding in
Teltherm.</p>

<p>January 1984: <ent type='ORG'>Brierley</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Elliott</ent> begin moves to monopolize the food
industry in <ent type='GPE'>Aust</ent>ralasia by merging <ent type='ORG'>Goodman</ent> and the <ent type='ORG'>Elders Group</ent>, while
<ent type='ORG'>Brierley</ent> sells 10% of <ent type='ORG'>Watties</ent> to the NZ Dairy Board - setting the stage for
land takeover and establishment of the <ent type='ORG'>Corporate</ent> Farm.</p>

<p>February 1984: <ent type='GPE'>New Zealand</ent> politi<ent type='ORG'>cia</ent>n D. <ent type='ORG'>Lange</ent> meets <ent type='PERSON'><ent type='PERSON'>Ray</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Cline</ent></ent> in
<ent type='GPE'>Wellington</ent> and agrees to go on the <ent type='ORG'>Mafia</ent> payroll for monthly fee of
$UA40000 paid into account number 5263161 at Commer<ent type='ORG'>cia</ent>l <ent type='LOC'>Pacific</ent> Trust,
<ent type='LOC'>New Hebrides</ent>.</p>

<p>March 1984: <ent type='PERSON'>Muldoon</ent> knighted with GCMG for keeping the economy free of
obstructions for easier takeover and exploitation.</p>

<p>24th May, 1984: Four-man <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> team co-ordinated by <ent type='PERSON'><ent type='PERSON'>Ray</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Cline</ent></ent> arrive in New
Zealand to begin installation of equipment for subliminal television
advertising at five sites - <ent type='ORG'>Waiatarua</ent>, Mt Erin, <ent type='GPE'>Kaukau</ent>, <ent type='LOC'>Sugarloaf</ent> and
Obelisk.</p>

<p>Sophisticated equipment can be installed within one kilometer of TV relay
aerials and all linked to one <ent type='ORG'>IDAPS</ent> computer bureau in <ent type='GPE'>Auckland</ent>.</p>

<p>Same equipment installed in <ent type='GPE'>Aust</ent>ralia August 1985; <ent type='GPE'>Japan</ent> September 1986;
UK February 1987: <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent> 1987. Also, <ent type='ORG'>Amax</ent> geoligists now estimate Martha
Hill gold source could be worth up to $30 billion on strength of high
gold/ton ore assay.</p>

<p>17th July, 1984: In <ent type='GPE'>New Zealand</ent>, subliminal advertising begins on Channel
Two between 6pm and midnight - hours later extended to begin at noon.
Subliminal messages prepared in the US by the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> and with <ent type='GPE'>New Zealand</ent>
election imminent, tell voters to support <ent type='ORG'>the Labour Party</ent>, the <ent type='GPE'>New Zealand</ent>
Party and to buy <ent type='ORG'>Mafia</ent> company products.</p>

<p><ent type='GPE'>New Zealand</ent> Party was formed to ensure that <ent type='PERSON'>Muldoon</ent> would lose, as Big
Business unhappy with controls over economy. Big campaign contributions
from <ent type='ORG'>Brierley</ent>, the oil companies and the Business Round Table ensure a
<ent type='ORG'>Labour</ent> victory.</p>

<p>Later, <ent type='ORG'>Lange</ent> agrees to repay the favour to <ent type='ORG'>Brierley</ent> by selling the
<ent type='ORG'>Government</ent> holding in the Kariori Pulp Mill to <ent type='ORG'>Winstones</ent>. <ent type='GPE'>New Zealand</ent>
taxpayer loses $100 million.</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>Government</ent> then becomes the arm of big business, using economic policies
provided by the Business Round Table, implemented by Finance Minister Roger
<ent type='PERSON'>Douglas</ent> and the package being sold by David <ent type='ORG'>Lange</ent>, who also keeps up a
noisy <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> directed <ent type='ORG'>ANZUS</ent> withdrawal campaign.</p>

<p> * Reason: 1) <ent type='ORG'>ANZUS</ent> Treaty did not cover <ent type='ORG'>Mafia</ent> requirements over the Great
South Basin discovery;
2) To identify any oppositin or threats within <ent type='GPE'>New Zealand</ent> who
align themselves with supposed <ent type='ORG'>Government</ent> policy, <ent type='ORG'>Lange</ent> increases the <ent type='ORG'>SIS</ent>
budget and strangthens links with the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>.</p>

<p>Brookings <ent type='ORG'>Institute</ent> are the actual designers of the <ent type='GPE'>New Zealand</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Government</ent>
econmomic policies provided by the Business Round Table (NZ <ent type='ORG'>Mafia</ent> front)
and implented by the <ent type='ORG'>Government</ent>.</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Douglas</ent> devalues the dollar and deregulates interest rates, which means
cheaper labor, cheaper capital assets and high mortgage rates, thereby
implementing <ent type='ORG'>Big Business</ent> policy of driving farmers off the land,
establishment of the corporate farm and eventually remove viability of
small business sector, etc.</p>

<p>27th September, 1984: <ent type='GPE'>New Zealand</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Mafia</ent> meets at new 'safe house'
registered under Fernyhough's name, in <ent type='GPE'>Auckland</ent>. Those present include
<ent type='ORG'>Brierley</ent>, J. <ent type='ORG'>Fletcher</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Trotter</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Jones</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Goodman</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Gunn</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Papps</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Hawkins</ent>,
Judge, <ent type='ORG'>Renouf</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Fernyhough</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Gibbs</ent> and McConnell. <ent type='PERSON'>Daigo Miyado</ent> announces
appointment of <ent type='ORG'>Trotter</ent> as International Vice President of the Trilateral
Commission <ent type='LOC'>Pacific</ent> Basin Economic <ent type='ORG'>Council</ent>.</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>Brierley</ent> outlines strategy of privatization of the <ent type='GPE'>New Zealand</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Government</ent>
and the establishment of the <ent type='GPE'>New Zealand</ent> Centre for Independent Studies
which will be chaired by <ent type='PERSON'>Gibbs</ent>, aided by <ent type='PERSON'>Fernyhough</ent> and controlled by
<ent type='PERSON'>Cline</ent>, which will 'advise' <ent type='ORG'>Treasury</ent> on privatization.</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Parsky</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Brierley</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Seldon</ent> hold a separate meeting with <ent type='PERSON'>Parsky</ent>, outlining
plans for an expanded laundry operation which will coincide with the launch
of 'Crack' - a new addictive product developed by <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> chemists for the
world market.</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>Equiticorp</ent> (<ent type='GPE'>Aust</ent>) will be launched with <ent type='PERSON'>Adler</ent> as Manager and a new merchant
bank using <ent type='ORG'>Eldrs</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Goodman</ent> and Jarden.</p>

<p>IEI will merge with <ent type='ORG'>Armco Bank</ent>, which has 20 branches in South East <ent type='LOC'>Asia</ent>;
<ent type='PERSON'>Ariadne</ent> will acquire <ent type='ORG'>the Bank</ent> of Queensland, and <ent type='ORG'>Brierley</ent> Investments will
form a cross-shareholding with <ent type='ORG'>NZI Corp</ent> to further increase control by
their <ent type='ORG'>Mafia</ent> organization. Other plans include the laundering of funds
directly to the <ent type='GPE'>New Zealand</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Aust</ent>ralian <ent type='ORG'>Government</ent>s and the
establishment of key companies within the economies of <ent type='GPE'>New Zealand</ent>,
<ent type='GPE'>Aust</ent>ralia and <ent type='GPE'>Hong Kong</ent>.</p>

<p>The f<ent type='ORG'>irs</ent>t key company will control the food industry in <ent type='GPE'>Aust</ent>ralasia through
merger of Elders, <ent type='ORG'>Goodman</ent>s, <ent type='ORG'>Allied Mills</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Fielder Gillespie</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>Watties</ent>.
<ent type='ORG'>Allied Mills</ent> will control 30% <ent type='ORG'>Goodman</ent>s, 30% Fielder, 20% <ent type='ORG'>Watties</ent> and will
expand into Europe via acquisition of Rank, Hovis McDougall (UK). Allied
Mills will be controlled through IEL.</p>

<p>26th October, 1984: <ent type='ORG'>Trotter</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Hawkins</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Lange</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Douglas</ent> meet in <ent type='GPE'>Wellington</ent>
to implement <ent type='ORG'>Mafia</ent> plans to privatise the <ent type='ORG'>Government</ent> and to deregulate the
banking system.</p>

<p>Late 1984: As part of the <ent type='ORG'>IDAPS</ent> computer-controlled 'laundry' operation,
<ent type='ORG'>Trotter</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>Fletcher</ent> help establish the '<ent type='LOC'>Pacific</ent> Investment Fund' with
<ent type='GPE'>Aust</ent>ralian and <ent type='GPE'>New Zealand</ent> investments to be managed by <ent type='GPE'>Hong Kong</ent> and
<ent type='GPE'>Shanghai</ent> Bank subsidiary, <ent type='PERSON'>Wardley</ent> and the <ent type='NORP'>Japanese</ent> operation controlled by
<ent type='ORG'>Tokyo Trust and Banking Company</ent> - owned by <ent type='ORG'>Sanwa Bank</ent>, Taiyo-Kobe Bank and
<ent type='ORG'>Nomura Securities</ent>. All are members of the <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> <ent type='ORG'>World Government</ent>
organization.</p>

<p>18th July, 1985: <ent type='GPE'>Aust</ent>ralian <ent type='ORG'>Mafia</ent> meet in <ent type='GPE'>Sydney</ent> to discuss privatization
of the <ent type='GPE'>Aust</ent>ralian <ent type='ORG'>Government</ent>. Those present include - <ent type='ORG'>Brierley</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Trotter</ent>,
<ent type='ORG'>Fletcher</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Seldon</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Goodman</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Papps</ent>, Packer, <ent type='ORG'>Bond</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Elliott</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Adler</ent>, and
<ent type='NORP'>Japanese</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Trilateralist</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Daigo Miyado</ent>.</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Cline</ent> will set up <ent type='GPE'>Aust</ent>ralian Centre for Independent Studies to 'advise' the
Treasurer on the takeover of the economy.</p>

<p>Impala <ent type='LOC'>Pacific</ent> will be set up in <ent type='GPE'>Hong Kong</ent> through <ent type='PERSON'>Ariadne</ent> with 60% of the
company stock held by <ent type='ORG'>Chase Manhattan</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>Security Pacific</ent> <ent type='ORG'>National Bank</ent> in
<ent type='GPE'>Aust</ent>ralia. In the UK, Tozer, Kemsly &amp; MIllbourn would be taken over using
<ent type='ORG'>IEP</ent>, while in <ent type='GPE'>Aust</ent>ralia, the Holme's A'<ent type='ORG'>Court</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Bell Group</ent> would be used to
merge with <ent type='GPE'>Hong Kong</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Shanghai</ent> Bank, through Standard &amp; Chartered Bank
(<ent type='GPE'>Hong Kong</ent>), and Marae (NZ) Broadlands (<ent type='GPE'>Aust</ent>) would merge with <ent type='ORG'>NZI</ent>
Corporation.</p>

<p>18th August, 1985: <ent type='PERSON'>Cline</ent> and 6-man <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> team begin installation of
subliminal television equipment in <ent type='GPE'>Sydney</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Brisbane</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Perth</ent>.</p>

<p>8th November1985: <ent type='PERSON'>Parsky</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Colby</ent> and J.D <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> meet in <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent> to
discuss their plans to assassinate McCloy and the <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent>s and to take
control of the <ent type='ORG'>Mafia</ent> organization.</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Colby</ent> would organise an 8-man 'hit squad' to be headed by <ent type='PERSON'>Gordon Liddy</ent> who
had worked for <ent type='PERSON'>Colby</ent> in the 1960's as a <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> contract killer, and was
responsible for over 10 murders including:</p>

<p> * 8/17/61 - two members of the Gambino <ent type='ORG'>Mafia</ent> family in <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent>
* 11/24/63 - Officer <ent type='PERSON'>Tippitt</ent> after the <ent type='PERSON'>Kennedy</ent> assassination in <ent type='GPE'>Dallas</ent>
* 12/18/63 - witness to the <ent type='PERSON'>Kennedy</ent> assassination in <ent type='GPE'>Dallas</ent>
* 4/19/65 - Politi<ent type='ORG'>cia</ent>n in <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>
* 7/27/65 - Politi<ent type='ORG'>cia</ent>n in <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>
* 9/8/65 - Politi<ent type='ORG'>cia</ent>n in <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>
* 11/27/66 - US 'independent' cocaine importer, in <ent type='GPE'>Mexico</ent>.
* 11/25/67 - 'Independent' heroin importer, in <ent type='GPE'>Los Angeles</ent>
* 2/9/69 - Politi<ent type='ORG'>cia</ent>n in <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent></p>

<p>28th November 1985: <ent type='GPE'>Aust</ent>ralian <ent type='ORG'>Mafia</ent> meet in <ent type='GPE'>Sydney</ent> - includes: <ent type='ORG'>Trotter</ent>,
<ent type='ORG'>Fletcher</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Hawkins</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Bond</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Elliott</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Adler</ent> and Holme's A'<ent type='ORG'>Court</ent> - discussed
strategy for merger of <ent type='ORG'>Goodman</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Allied Mills</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Fielde Gillespie Davis</ent>,
<ent type='ORG'>Watties</ent> and Elders with <ent type='ORG'>Chase Manhattan</ent> Bank taking 20%, Elders and IEL
10%, with stock being held through Chase-AMP Bank.</p>

<p>Elders woul be used as major 'vehicle' in the global liquor economy with
<ent type='ORG'>Courage Brewery</ent> in the UK to be used as entry into Europe.</p>

<p>Strategy finalized to take over <ent type='ORG'>BHP</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Aust</ent>ralia's largest company, using H
olme's A'<ent type='ORG'>Court</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Brierley</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Elliott</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Hawkins</ent>.</p>

<p>In <ent type='GPE'>London</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Chase Manhattan</ent> would takeover stockbrokers <ent type='PERSON'>Simon</ent> &amp; Coates who
spe<ent type='ORG'>cia</ent>lize in A'<ent type='LOC'>Asia</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Mafia</ent> owned companies such as <ent type='ORG'>Fletcher</ent> Challenge,
<ent type='ORG'>Brierley</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>NZI Corp</ent>, Elders, <ent type='ORG'>Bell Group</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>BHP</ent>. <ent type='ORG'>Chase Manhattan</ent> could then
issue and buy stock to manipulate the <ent type='GPE'>Aust</ent>ral<ent type='NORP'>asian</ent> economy by increasing
price, paying no taxes, creating inflation, and enslaving the people
through debt to <ent type='ORG'>Mafia</ent> controlled banks.</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Parsky</ent> would oversee the 'launder' of further loans to the NZ <ent type='ORG'>Government</ent>
and would begin to channel 'loans' through the <ent type='GPE'>Aust</ent>ralian <ent type='ORG'>Treasury</ent> using
captive politi<ent type='ORG'>cia</ent>n <ent type='PERSON'>Keating</ent>. Also NZ <ent type='ORG'>Government</ent> building would be sold to
<ent type='PERSON'>Jones</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Aust</ent>ralia <ent type='ORG'>Government</ent> buildings would be sold to <ent type='PERSON'>Adler</ent> which would
then be rented back to the respective <ent type='ORG'>Government</ent>s at inflated prices.</p>

<p>17th November 1986: <ent type='ORG'>Brierley</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Seldon</ent>, Packer, <ent type='ORG'>Bond</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Elliott</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Holme</ent>s
A'<ent type='ORG'>Court</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Adler</ent> meet in <ent type='GPE'>Sydney</ent>. Also present is <ent type='PERSON'>Rupert Murdoch</ent> to assist
in <ent type='PERSON'>Parsky</ent> strategy of media takeover in <ent type='GPE'>Aust</ent>ralasia and the <ent type='LOC'>Pacific</ent> using
Packer and <ent type='ORG'>Bond</ent> (TV and Radio) <ent type='ORG'>Brierley</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>Holme</ent>s A'<ent type='ORG'>Court</ent> (newspapers).</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>Murdoch</ent> takes orders from <ent type='PERSON'>Brzezinski</ent> since his News Corp was taken over in
1982 by <ent type='ORG'>Chase Manhattan</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>Security Pacific</ent> <ent type='ORG'>National Bank</ent>.</p>

<p>At a separate meeting with <ent type='ORG'>Brierley</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Seldon</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Cline</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Parsky</ent> outlines plan
for 'key' Media <ent type='GPE'>Aust</ent>ral<ent type='NORP'>asian</ent> Holding company using the <ent type='ORG'>Bell Group</ent> which
would be taken over by with <ent type='ORG'>Chase Manhattan</ent> holding 27.5% in <ent type='GPE'>London</ent> and the
US. Another 10% of the stock would be held through <ent type='ORG'>Security Pacific</ent>
<ent type='ORG'>National Bank</ent> (US).</p>

<p>8th February 1987: US <ent type='ORG'>Mafia</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Council</ent> meet in <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent> - including David
<ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent>, John McCloy, <ent type='PERSON'>Brzezinski</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Parsky</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Simon</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Katherine Graham</ent>, and
George <ent type='ORG'>Franklin</ent>.</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Brzezinski</ent> outlines plans to invade <ent type='GPE'>Iran</ent> using 75000 strong mercenary army
supported by US Air Force and <ent type='ORG'>Navy</ent> with starting date of 8th February,
1988. An integral part of the plan Saudi and <ent type='GPE'>Kuwait</ent>i oil tankers would fly
the US flag to provoke an <ent type='GPE'>Iran</ent>ian attack so that US invasion of <ent type='GPE'>Iran</ent> would
be 'justified'.</p>

<p> * Reason: The <ent type='ORG'>Seven Sisters</ent> wanted to exploit a secret oil field near
<ent type='PERSON'>Bandar Abbas</ent> discovered in 1976 with estimate 150 billion barrels and also
a huge gold source at <ent type='ORG'>Neyshabur</ent> discovered in 1977.</p>

<p>The <ent type='GPE'>Iran</ent>ian invasion would begin after the World economic system was
collapsed by the <ent type='ORG'>Mafia</ent> controlled banks - target date 17th January 1988.
Other countries on the takeover list include:
* <ent type='GPE'>Mexico</ent> - for oil at <ent type='GPE'>Baisas</ent>
* <ent type='GPE'>Nicaragua</ent> - for oil at Connto
* <ent type='GPE'>Colombia</ent> - for gold at Papayan
* <ent type='GPE'>South Korea</ent> - for gold at Chunchon
* <ent type='GPE'>New Zealand</ent> - for oil in <ent type='LOC'>the Great South Basin</ent>.</p>

<p>(Obviously this part of the plan failed to happen)</p>

<p>Article 639 of alt.conspiracy:
Path: bilver!tarpit!peora!masscomp!dali.cs.montana.edu!decwrl!
elroy.jpl.<ent type='ORG'>nasa</ent>.gov!sdd.hp.com!hplabs!otter.hpl.hp.com!otter!tgg
From: tgg@otter.hpl.hp.com (<ent type='PERSON'>Tom Gardner</ent>)
Newsgroups: alt.conspiracy
Subject: Re: Re: Novus Ordo Seclorum
<info type="Message-ID"> 5900008@otter.hpl.hp.com</info>
Date: 8 Jan 91 09:09:24 GMT
References: <special>8671@uwm.edu</special>
Organization: Hewlett-Packard Laboratories, <ent type='GPE'>Bristol</ent>, UK.
Lines: 18</p>

<p>|There is nothing dangerous about <ent type='NORP'>Freemasonry</ent>. As an
|erisian <ent type='NORP'>Freemason</ent>, I should know. It is mainly a
|club, like the Elks or the Rotary, but one that has
|a far more noble and glorious history, as well as
|one that keeps alive ancient knowledge under
|"secret" veils.</p>

<p>If you believe that then run and read "The <ent type='ORG'>Brotherhood</ent>" by <ent type='PERSON'>Stephen Knight</ent>.
In it he points out why many of the legends/stories/rumours about the
<ent type='NORP'>Freemason</ent>s are nonsense.</p>

<p>He also describes, with examples, the mechanisms by which <ent type='NORP'>Freemasonry</ent> can
be a corrupting influence with deleterious effects on the public at large.</p>

<p>There are serious resons to believe that membership of <ent type='NORP'>Masonic</ent> Lodges and
<ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> churches is mutually incompatible. (BTW, I belong to neither).</p>

<p>A book that is worth reading...</p>

<p>Article 645 of alt.conspiracy:
Path: bilver!tarpit!peora!masscomp!know!news.cs.indiana.edu!<ent type='ORG'>samsung</ent>!
spool2.mu.edu!uunet!sam!khan
From: khan@davidsys.com
Newsgroups: alt.conspiracy
Subject: FREEMASONS ARE ALIVE AND WELL!
<info type="Message-ID"> 6384@davidsys.com</info>
Date: 9 Jan 91 18:49:02 GMT
Organization: DAVID Systems Inc, <ent type='LOC'>Sunnyvale</ent> CA
Lines: 59</p>

<p>Re: Novus Ordo Seclorum.</p>

<p>This phrase is from the FREEMASONS 100%!</p>

<p>I will post more details later.</p>

<p>The <ent type='NORP'>Freemason</ent>s are alive and well in the <ent type='GPE'>USA</ent>. There are 33 degrees of
membership. On the top level are the leaders of various countries.
On the basic level there are people like you and me (ordinary <ent type='ORG'>Joes</ent>).
I do not mean to say I am a <ent type='NORP'>Freemason</ent>, by the way.</p>

<p>They are NOT known as <ent type='NORP'>Freemason</ent>s over here; they are known as "lodges".
Thus, the <ent type='ORG'>Shriners</ent>, the Elks, etc. are all the same group.</p>

<p>They are existing from the time of <ent type='PERSON'>Moses</ent>, or maybe even from before that.
It used to be <ent type='NORP'>Greek</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Roman</ent> influenced fraternity. They were outlawed in
<ent type='GPE'>Pakistan</ent> in the late 70's because of their involvement in some
questionable things. It is said that the <ent type='NORP'>Freemason</ent>s want to protect and
maintain a certain status quo in the world (make it safe for the extremely r
ich), but God knows best as to their real aims.</p>

<p>The Lodges are very active in doing some good things for the common man.
The <ent type='ORG'>Shriners</ent> have adopted a pseudo-<ent type='NORP'>Islamic</ent> pose, without having anything
to do with <ent type='ORG'>Islam</ent> as presented in the Quran. The <ent type='ORG'>Shriners</ent> have their own
"prophets" etc.</p>

<p>It is easy to join the <ent type='NORP'>Freemason</ent> fraternity on the basic level. You are
told that it is for uniting all the different nations and religions of the
world. You can only progress (up the 33 degrees) if you are of any use in
your so<ent type='ORG'>cia</ent>l position to the <ent type='NORP'>Freemason</ent>s. You may join as a basic <ent type='NORP'>Freemason</ent>,
and remain so all your life, and it would look like you just joined a
harmless so<ent type='ORG'>cia</ent>l club.</p>

<p>On the top level, their aims are quite different. They do not like any
organization (in the name of religion or anything else) to endanger their
finan<ent type='ORG'>cia</ent>l assets and interests. Some believe that the <ent type='NORP'>Freemason</ent>s have
been successful in completely destroying the faith of ordinary <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent>
by influencing and introducing corruption in the <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> church, and
distorting religious concepts. The big challenge before the <ent type='NORP'>Freemason</ent>s
now is to destroy the organizing power of <ent type='ORG'>Islam</ent>, which they view as the
final threat.</p>

<p>There has been some research done on the <ent type='NORP'>Freemason</ent>s, their introduction
methods, their activities (open and hidden), in <ent type='GPE'>Pakistan</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Egypt</ent> and Saudi
Arabia. If anyone is interested, I can detail everything in my following
posts.</p>

<p>Article 642 of alt.conspiracy:
Path: bilver!tarpit!peora!masscomp!dali.cs.montana.edu!<ent type='ORG'>samsung</ent>!
cs.utexas.edu!wuarchive!uunet!isis!jsanders
From: jsanders@isis.cs.du.edu (<ent type='PERSON'>Jim Sanders</ent>)
Newsgroups: alt.conspiracy
Subject: Re: Novus Ordo Seclorum (<ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent>=Lawyers=Politi<ent type='ORG'>cia</ent>ns/<ent type='ORG'>IRS</ent>/<ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>)
<info type="Message-ID"> 1991Jan9.185143.8679@isis.cs.du.edu</info>
Date: 9 Jan 91 18:51:43 GMT
Reply-To: jsanders@isis.<ent type='ORG'>UUCP</ent> (<ent type='PERSON'>Jim Sanders</ent>)
Organization: Math/CS, University of <ent type='GPE'>Denver</ent>
Lines: 46</p>

<p>This symbol is one of <ent type='ORG'>the Mystic Society</ent> of the <ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent>. The <ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent>
was formed by <ent type='ORG'>the creme</ent> de la creme of Europe's most powerful aristocrats
to perpetuate its iron grip on the peasants, to maintain the status quo,
to keep the rich rich, and the poor masses poor.</p>

<p>J.<ent type='PERSON'>Jaynes</ent> book, "The Origin of Consciousness in the Breakdown Of the
Bicameral Mind," explains how for thousands of years, the masses have been
hypnotized into not thinking for themselves by <ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent> like leaders who
use mysticism, religion, music and propaganda to accomplish this. A person
can still do very hard organized work for these manipulators and actually
still not ever think in a non-bicameral or enlightened state of mind.
This has allowed the world's sadistic, oppressive leaders to screw us for
1000's of years.</p>

<p>It appears that the illuminati had penetrated U.S. government from the
beginning. The <ent type='ORG'>Illuminatus</ent> was formed in 1776 by a lawyer in <ent type='GPE'>Bavaria</ent>.
These esquires snaked their way into the womb of <ent type='NORP'>Amerika</ent> from the <ent type='ORG'>getgo</ent>!
I find it revolting and an infinite slap in the face to see lawyers own
symbol of economic repression on the very money we get shafted for by these
leach lawyers daily.</p>

<p>(In 1776 The European Economic Community (the aristocracy) worried quite
a bit when WE told <ent type='GPE'>England</ent> to get the Hell outta here, so naturally they
regrouped and formed the <ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent> to deal with US and prevent future
colonies from being so eager to toss the king's tea taxes overboard!)</p>

<p>Write to me and I will mail you a that documents my words on how lawyers
(and now <ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent>/<ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>/Heavy Industry) raping <ent type='NORP'>Amerika</ent>!
(WRITE ME + READ IT!)</p>

<div>--</div>

<p>"Don't tread on me!" /*--------------------------------------------------*/
/* Hell even their motto reverberated with snakes */
/* (as this was written on a 1776 <ent type='NORP'>Amerika</ent>n Colonial */
/* Revolutionary flag next to a picture of a snake) */
/*--------------------------------------------------*/
(But I agree with it!)</p>

<p> ______________________________________________________________
:-)
<ent type='PERSON'>jim</ent> oversees the fate of the world from high atop <ent type='GPE'>Boulder</ent>
|______________________________________________________________|
| |
Vote em out! | jsanders@isis.cs.du.edu | (<ent type='PERSON'>jim</ent> sanders)
|______________|___________________________|___________________|</p>

<p>Article 641 of alt.conspiracy:
Path: bilver!tarpit!peora!masscomp!dali.cs.montana.edu!<ent type='ORG'>samsung</ent>!
spool2.mu.edu!uunet!isis!jsanders
From: jsanders@isis.cs.du.edu (<ent type='PERSON'>Jim Sanders</ent>)
Newsgroups: alt.conspiracy
Subject: Re: Novus Ordo...(<ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent>=Lawyers=<ent type='NORP'>Amerika</ent>rapers=<ent type='ORG'>cia</ent>/dea/<ent type='ORG'>irs</ent>)
<info type="Message-ID"> 1991Jan9.185746.9066@isis.cs.du.edu</info>
Date: 9 Jan 91 18:57:46 GMT
Reply-To: jsanders@isis.<ent type='ORG'>UUCP</ent> (<ent type='PERSON'>Jim Sanders</ent>)
Organization: Math/CS, University of <ent type='GPE'>Denver</ent>
Lines: 46</p>

<p>This symbol is one of <ent type='ORG'>the Mystic Society</ent> of the <ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent>. The <ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent>
was formed by <ent type='ORG'>the creme</ent> de la creme of Europe's most powerful aristocrats
to perpetuate its iron grip on the peasants, to maintain the status quo,
to keep the rich rich, and the poor masses poor.</p>

<p>J.<ent type='PERSON'>Jaynes</ent> book, "The Origin of Consciousness in the Breakdown Of the
Bicameral Mind," explains how for thousands of years, the masses have been
hypnotized into not thinking for themselves by <ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent> like leaders who
use mysticism, religion, music and propaganda to accomplish this. A person
can still do very hard organized work for these manipulators and actually
still not ever think in a non-bicameral or enlightened state of mind. This
has allowed the world's sadistic, oppressive leaders to screw us for
1000's of years.</p>

<p>It appears that the illuminati had penetrated U.S. government from the
beginning. The <ent type='ORG'>Illuminatus</ent> was formed in 1776 by a lawyer in <ent type='GPE'>Bavaria</ent>.
These esquires snaked their way into the womb of <ent type='NORP'>Amerika</ent> from the <ent type='ORG'>getgo</ent>!
I find it revolting and an infinite slap in the face to see lawyers own
symbol of economic repression on the very money we get shafted for by these
leach lawyers daily.</p>

<p>(In 1776 The European Economic Community (the aristocracy) worried quite
a bit when WE told <ent type='GPE'>England</ent> to get the Hell outta here, so naturally they
regrouped and formed the <ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent> to deal with US and prevent future colonies
from being so eager to toss the king's tea taxes overboard!)</p>

<p>Write to me and I will mail you a that documents my words
on how lawyers (and now <ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent>/<ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>/Heavy Industry) raping <ent type='NORP'>Amerika</ent>!
(WRITE ME + READ IT!)</p>

<div>--</div>

<p>"Don't tread on me!" /*--------------------------------------------------*/
/* Hell even their motto reverberated with snakes */
/* (as this was written on a 1776 <ent type='NORP'>Amerika</ent>n Colonial */
/* Revolutionary flag next to a picture of a snake) */
/*--------------------------------------------------*/
(But I agree with it!)</p>

<p> ______________________________________________________________
:-)
<ent type='PERSON'>jim</ent> oversees the fate of the world from high atop <ent type='GPE'>Boulder</ent>
|______________________________________________________________|
| |
Vote em out! | jsanders@isis.cs.du.edu | (<ent type='PERSON'>jim</ent> sanders)
|______________|___________________________|___________________|</p>

<p>Article 647 of alt.conspiracy:
Xref: bilver alt.conspiracy:647 rec.arts.books:2999
Path: bilver!tarpit!peora!masscomp!rpi!zaphod.mps.ohio-state.edu!usc!
elroy.jpl.<ent type='ORG'>nasa</ent>.gov!decwrl!world!eff!mnemonic
From: mnemonic@eff.org (<ent type='PERSON'>Mike Godwin</ent>)
Newsgroups: alt.conspiracy,rec.arts.books
Subject: Re: Novus Ordo...(<ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent>=Lawyers=<ent type='NORP'>Amerika</ent>rapers=<ent type='ORG'>cia</ent>/dea/<ent type='ORG'>irs</ent>)
Summary: How silly.
<info type="Message-ID"> 1991Jan9.231009.13623@eff.org</info>
Date: 9 Jan 91 23:10:09 GMT
References: <special>1991Jan9.185746.9066@isis.cs.du.edu</special>
Organization: The <ent type='ORG'>Electronic Frontier</ent> Foundation
Lines: 29</p>

<p>In article <special>1991Jan9.185746.9066@isis.cs.du.edu</special> jsanders@isis.<ent type='ORG'>UUCP</ent>
(<ent type='PERSON'>Jim Sanders</ent>) writes:
&gt;
&gt;J.<ent type='PERSON'>Jaynes</ent> book, "The Origin of Consciousness in the Breakdown Of the
&gt;Bicameral Mind," explains how for thousands of years, the masses have been
&gt;hypnotized into not thinking for themselves by <ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent> like leaders who
&gt;use mysticism, religion, music and propaganda to accomplish this. A person
&gt;can still do very hard organized work for these manipulators and actually
&gt;still not ever think in a non-bicameral or enlightened state of mind. This
&gt;has allowed the world's sadistic, oppressive leaders to screw us for
&gt;1000's of years.</p>

<p>This is nonsense; Jaynes's book says no such thing. Not only does it not
mention the <ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent> or "<ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent>-like leaders," but its thesis is
that the bicamerality of the brain is the ground of true self-consciousness. It is not the case that "non-bicameral" is the equivalent of
"enlightened"--just the opposite, really.</p>

<p>Of course, I'm a lawyer, so feel free to ignore me as I get back to
raping <ent type='NORP'>Amerika</ent>.</p>

<p>--Mike</p>

<p>--
<ent type='PERSON'>Mike Godwin</ent>, (617) 864-0665 |"If the doors of perception were cleansed
mnemonic@eff.org | every thing would appear to man as it is,
<ent type='ORG'>Electronic Frontier</ent> | infinite."
Foundation | --Blake</p>

<p>Article 654 of alt.conspiracy:
Xref: bilver alt.conspiracy:654 rec.arts.books:3018
Path: bilver!tarpit!peora!masscomp!know!news.cs.indiana.edu!att!linac!
uwm.edu!ux1.cso.uiuc.edu!uiucdcs!carroll
From: carroll@cs.uiuc.edu (Alan M. <ent type='ORG'>Carroll</ent>)
Newsgroups: alt.conspiracy,rec.arts.books
Subject: Re: Novus Ordo...(<ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent>=Lawyers=<ent type='NORP'>Amerika</ent>rapers=<ent type='ORG'>cia</ent>/dea/<ent type='ORG'>irs</ent>)
<info type="Message-ID"> 1991Jan10.221553.5811@ux1.cso.uiuc.edu</info>
Date: 10 Jan 91 22:15:53 GMT
References: <special>1991Jan9.185746.9066@isis.cs.du.edu</special>
<special>1991Jan9.231009.13623@eff.org</special>
Sender: news@ux1.cso.uiuc.edu (News)
Reply-To: carroll@cs.uiuc.edu (Alan M. <ent type='ORG'>Carroll</ent>)
Organization: Technophiles Inc. - Engineers with Attitude
Lines: 12</p>

<p>In article <special>1991Jan9.231009.13623@eff.org</special>, mnemonic@eff.org (<ent type='PERSON'>Mike Godwin</ent>)
writes:
&gt;
&gt; Of course, I'm a lawyer, so feel free to ignore me as I get back to
&gt; raping <ent type='NORP'>Amerika</ent>.
&gt; </p>

<p>A lawyer! Ignore you nothin'! Go 'n git the dawgs, boy. We're goin <ent type='PERSON'>huntin</ent>'.</p>

<p>--
Alan M. <ent type='ORG'>Carroll</ent> "It's psychosomatic. You need a lobotomy.
<ent type='ORG'>Epoch Development Team</ent> I'll get a saw."
CS Grad / U of Ill @ Urbana ...{ucbvax,pur-ee,convex}!cs.uiuc.edu!
carroll</p>

<p>Article 643 of alt.conspiracy:
Path: bilver!tarpit!peora!masscomp!know!news.cs.indiana.edu!cica!
sol.ctr.columbia.edu!spool2.mu.edu!uunet!isis!jsanders
From: jsanders@isis.cs.du.edu (<ent type='PERSON'>Jim Sanders</ent>)
Newsgroups: alt.conspiracy
Subject: The <ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent> are an original world "old boy" conspiracy!
<info type="Message-ID"> 1991Jan10.051620.10473@isis.cs.du.edu</info>
Date: 10 Jan 91 05:16:20 GMT
Reply-To: jsanders@isis.<ent type='ORG'>UUCP</ent> (<ent type='PERSON'>Jim Sanders</ent>)
Organization: Math/CS, University of <ent type='GPE'>Denver</ent>
Lines: 77</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Jack</ent>,

I forgot to give you the beta on the <ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent>:

These folks are more secret than <ent type='PERSON'>Moussad</ent>(the <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent>i SS) who is the
undisputed ultimate "secret agent men/women" experts of the world.
Therefore, you will find no reliable sources of information on them.

They like to frequent <ent type='NORP'>Swiss</ent> chalets and spend their loot on good spirits
and women. Oh, they do not have women for members.

Their asso<ent type='ORG'>cia</ent>tes are in international banking and are world leaders of
organized crime. But they are not ever necessarily top world leaders or
top CEO's, but they completely influence the major decisions of most
multinational companies and world leaders.

They are always there but you never see them:

Once, at a coffee shop in an affluent <ent type='GPE'>Denver</ent> 'burb in the foothills, I ran
across a man of this general authority. With a <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> accent, he had told
me that if I were to sit at a table, I was to buy coffee, but he did not
work there. He wore a $2000 <ent type='NORP'>Swiss</ent> pilot's chronometer on one wrist. His
clothes cost at least half of the watch and he wasn't wearing a suit!
We were just waiting for the rain to stop and I could not believe my ears
when he tried to shoo me away from my dry spot under the curbside table's
canvas awning. I thought carefully and then replied something to the likes
of "The <ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent> would always like for me to be recirculating my money
back into their economic system of manipulation."

As soon as I said this, never mind the weather, he took off. He was a
strong 50 year old <ent type='NORP'>Aryan</ent>, about 6'1", 200lbs, to my 5'11", 150lbs
but he looked extremely agitated before he left. I could tell he was not
physically scared of me. In fact, he knew all too well what I was saying
about the globally economic policies of his "asso<ent type='ORG'>cia</ent>tes" in the <ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent>.
You see, they have effectively cut off information about even their
existence, that it will damn near give one of them vapor lock if you call
their hand!
(Notice that Europe houses the ultimate banks next to <ent type='GPE'>Bavaria</ent> on <ent type='NORP'>Swiss</ent>
soil, and note how the <ent type='NORP'>Swiss</ent> are given <ent type='ORG'>International Neutrality</ent> to boot so
that the Secret accounts will be safe and stable! I would wager a month of
<ent type='LOC'>Sundays</ent> that money in a <ent type='NORP'>Swiss</ent> account is backed by real gold too!)

Conclusion:

<ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent> belongs to the "Skull and Crossbones Club" which is the <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n
Equivalent of the <ent type='ORG'>Illuninati</ent>. You have to study at <ent type='ORG'>Yale</ent> and be in a family
that is part of the old boy system and then you might get in. It is highly
secret, but really is much more well known than the <ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent>. It exists
to perpetuate the existence of the old boys in <ent type='NORP'>Amerika</ent>, much as the
<ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent> does the same in Europe.

Amazingly, the only reference to the <ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent> that I have ever seen other
than in a few paper back books on mysticism called the Trilogy which
actually are probably right 50% of the time, was in the Unabridged
Webster's Dictionary, where all it dares say is that they were "the members
of an anticlerical, deistic, republican society founded in 1776 by Adam
Weishaupt, professor of law at <ent type='GPE'>Ingolstadt</ent> in <ent type='GPE'>Bavaria</ent>. It was suppressed by
the <ent type='GPE'>Bavaria</ent>n government in 1785: called also the Order of the <ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent>."

I suppose they had to go deep undercover, much more so than even the <ent type='ORG'>Mafia</ent>.
This might explain the agitation I evoked in the fellow!

It might be fun to know more about these fellow, but you now know all you
need to know, except their names. <ent type='ORG'>Search</ent> and destroy!
---
expose a gangster and save money today!
______________________________________________________________
:-) |
<ent type='PERSON'>jim</ent> oversees the fate of the world from high atop <ent type='GPE'>Boulder</ent> |
|______________________________________________________________|
| | |
Vote em out! | jsanders@isis.cs.du.edu | (<ent type='PERSON'>jim</ent> sanders) |
|______________|___________________________|___________________|
"Don't Tread On Me" ? 177x
"This is Jimmy's road, where <ent type='PERSON'>Jimmy</ent> liked to play." (<ent type='PERSON'>Mark Twain</ent>)
&gt;---------------------------------------------&gt;
Hi Ho Pegasus, and away!&gt;---------------------------------------------&gt;
&gt;---------------------------------------------&gt;</p>

<p>Article 656 of alt.conspiracy:
Path: bilver!tarpit!peora!masscomp!know!zaphod.mps.ohio-state.edu!uwm.edu!
ux1.cso.uiuc.edu!bradley2.bradley.edu!pwh
From: pwh@bradley.bradley.edu (<ent type='PERSON'>Pete Hartman</ent>)
Newsgroups: alt.conspiracy
Subject: Re: The <ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent> are an original world "old boy" conspiracy!
<info type="Message-ID"> 1991Jan10.224545.646@bradley.bradley.edu</info>
Date: 10 Jan 91 22:45:45 GMT
References: <special>1991Jan10.051620.10473@isis.cs.du.edu</special>
Distribution: usa
Organization: Bradley University
Lines: 9</p>

<p>In <special>1991Jan10.051620.10473@isis.cs.du.edu</special> jsanders@isis.cs.du.edu
(<ent type='PERSON'>Jim Sanders</ent>) writes:
&gt;These folks are more secret than <ent type='PERSON'>Moussad</ent>(the <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent>i SS) who is the
&gt;undisputed ultimate "secret agent men/women" experts of the world.
&gt;Therefore, you will find no reliable sources of information on them. </p>

<p>That includes you, I suppose....
--
-----
<ent type='PERSON'>Pete Hartman</ent>pwh@bradley.bradley.eduHaazavaa?</p>

<p>Article 1809 of alt.activism:
Xref: bilver alt.activism:1809 alt.conspiracy:652 talk.politics.misc:7767
Path: bilver!tarpit!peora!masscomp!rpi!zaphod.mps.ohio-state.edu!<ent type='ORG'>samsung</ent>!
uunet!bu.edu!dartvax!cabot!harelb
From: harelb@cabot.dartmouth.edu (<ent type='PERSON'>Harel Barzilai</ent>)
Newsgroups: alt.activism,alt.conspiracy,talk.politics.misc
Subject: The S&amp;L - Contra/drug Connection -- will <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent> investigate?
<info type="Message-ID"> 1991Jan10.051739.22241@dartvax.dartmouth.edu</info>
Date: 10 Jan 91 05:17:39 GMT
Sender: news@dartvax.dartmouth.edu (The News Manager)
Distribution: na
Organization: Dartmouth College
Lines: 105
Followup: alt.conspiracy</p>

<p>HOUSE INTELLIGENCE COMMITTEE BLOCKS S&amp;L INVESTIGATION
=====================================================
<ent type='ORG'>Convergence Magazine</ent>, <ent type='NORP'>Christic</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Institute</ent>, Winter 1991, p. 16</p>

<p>As <ent type='NORP'>Convergence</ent> went to press we learned that the House Intelligence
Committee will refuse to investigate the reported use of failed savings and
loan institutions to launder funds for the Reagan Administration's secret
war in <ent type='GPE'>Nicaragua</ent>.</p>

<p>The last issue of <ent type='NORP'>Convergence</ent> (Fall 1990) reported that an investigation by
<ent type='ORG'>the <ent type='NORP'>Christic</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Institute</ent></ent> had found new evidence that drug traffickers may
have taken advantage of S&amp;L deregulation to launder cocaine profits
destined for the contras. In a separate investigation, <ent type='ORG'>the Houston Post</ent> has
concluded that several failed S&amp;Ls were looted by businessmen connected
with both organized crime and <ent type='ORG'>the Central Intelligence Agency</ent>.</p>

<p>Last summer the <ent type='ORG'>House Banking</ent> subcommittee on finan<ent type='ORG'>cia</ent>l institutions
attempted to investigate the reports, but abandoned the effort when C.I.A.
Director <ent type='PERSON'>William Webster</ent> refused to testify. But the subcommittee's chair,
<ent type='GPE'>Illinois</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Democrat</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Frank Annunzio</ent>, referred the allegations to the House
<ent type='ORG'>Intelligence Committee</ent>, which has jurisdiction over America's spy agencies.</p>

<p>On Nov. 15 <ent type='ORG'>the <ent type='NORP'>Christic</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Institute</ent></ent> delivered 30000 petitions to
Rep. <ent type='PERSON'>Anthony Beilenson</ent>, the <ent type='GPE'>California</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Democrat</ent> who cha<ent type='ORG'>irs</ent> the Intelligence
Committee, asking for a full investigation of the reports. The signatures
were gathered in 22 cities in one day of canvassing by volunteers from the
<ent type='NORP'>Christic</ent> Institute's local action networks and the Citizen/Labor Energy
Coalition.</p>

<p>A spokesman for the intelligence committee said the staff had conducted
dozens of interviews to determine whether the reports should be
investigated. But in November investigative journalist <ent type='PERSON'>Pete Brewton</ent>
reported in <ent type='ORG'>the Houston Post</ent> that "the committee has not attempted to
trace any of the S&amp;L money looted by C.I.A. operatives.''</p>

<p>The committee staff also failed to contact a former C.I.A. contract agent
who told a Federal court in 1988 that the agency used funds from failed
banks and thrift institutions to finance covert operations.</p>

<p>When asked by <ent type='PERSON'>Brewton</ent> why the committee made no attempt to trace any S&amp;L
money to discover if it had been used for covert operations, staff director
<ent type='PERSON'>Dan Childs</ent> said "we have only three attorneys to do this.''</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Childs</ent> was the chief finan<ent type='ORG'>cia</ent>l officer for the C.I.A. during the period
when the alleged transfer of funds occurred.</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>The <ent type='NORP'>Christic</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Institute</ent></ent>'s probe of S&amp;L fraud goes back to 1988, when
<ent type='NORP'>Christic</ent> investigators found evidence that C.I.A.-sponsored drug
traffickers may have used dozens of thrifts in several states to launder
cocaine profits destined for the contra war effort.</p>

<p>"<ent type='ORG'>The <ent type='NORP'>Christic</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Institute</ent></ent> has uncovered evidence that covert operatives and
drug traffickers exploited dozens of S&amp;Ls to launder funds destined for
the illegal contra war,'' said <ent type='PERSON'>Daniel</ent> P. Sheehan, the Institute's general
counsel. "This evidence suggests that the links among S&amp;Ls, covert
operatives and organized crime can be traced to the 'off-the-shelf
enterprise' described by Oliver <ent type='PERSON'>North</ent> before the <ent type='GPE'>Iran</ent>-contra investigating
committees.</p>

<p>"It appears that S&amp;Ls may have made fraudulent loans in order to siphon
money to the contras at a time when <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent> had cut off aid to the
rebels.''</p>

<p>Brewton's investigative series in <ent type='ORG'>Post</ent> has concluded that "at least 27
failed finan<ent type='ORG'>cia</ent>l institutions (25 S&amp;Ls and two banks) had links to C.I.A.
operatives or to organized crime figures with links to the C.I.A..''</p>

<p>"The savings and loan collapse will cost taxpayers over $500 billion,''
said <ent type='PERSON'>Sara Nelson</ent>, the Institute's executive director. "If it is true that
S&amp;L money went to the contras, then the U.S. public was duped into paying
the bill for the contra war after <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent> had outlawed contra aid.
The evidence pointing to a systematic fraud on</p>

<p>"The response to this petition has been enormous,'' said <ent type='PERSON'>Nelson</ent>, "and
shows just how upset people are that <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent> has failed to investigate
the intelligence connection to the S&amp;L collapse. We hope that <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>man
<ent type='PERSON'>Beilenson</ent> will take this message very seriously.''</p>

<p>-----------------------------------------------------------------
Andrew <ent type='PERSON'>Lang</ent> 151251507 <ent type='ORG'>CHRISTIC</ent> telex
<ent type='NORP'>Christic</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Institute</ent> tcn449 <ent type='ORG'>TCN</ent>
<ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, D.C. christic PeaceNet
202-529-0140 BBS uunet!pyramid!<ent type='ORG'>cdp</ent>!christic <ent type='ORG'>UUCP</ent>
202-797-8106 voice <ent type='ORG'>cdp</ent>!christic%labrea@stanford Bitnet
202-462-5138 fax <ent type='ORG'>cdp</ent>!christic@labrea.stanford.edu Internet</p>

<p>##################################################################
###################################################################
# <ent type='PERSON'>Harel Barzilai</ent> for Activists Mailing List (<ent type='ORG'>AML</ent>) #
###################################################################
To join <ent type='ORG'>AML</ent>, just send the message "SUB ACTIV-L <special>your full name</special>" to
the address: LISTSERV@UMCVMB.BITNET; you should then receive a message
confirming that your name has been added to the list. Other addresses
to try (only) if the above fails are: "LISTSERV@UMCVMB.MISSOURI.<ent type='ORG'>EDU</ent>"
or "ucscc!umcvmb.missouri.edu!LISTSERV"]

</p></xml>