<xml><p>Article 11143 of alt.activism:
Xref: bilver alt.activism:11143 alt.conspiracy:5176
Path: bil-ver!tous!peora!masscomp!usenet.coe.montana.edu!rpi!sci.ccny.cuny.edu!psinnt
p!psinntp!sgigate!odin!ratmandu.corp.sgi.com!dave
From: dave@ratmandu.corp.sgi.com (dave "who can do? ratmandu!" ratcliffe)
Newsgroups: alt.activism,alt.conspiracy
Subject: the INSLAW case: more on <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent>
Keywords: Hitler's rise to power succeeded through the use of private ar-mies
<info type="Message-ID"> 1991Oct15.160142.29417@odin.corp.sgi.com</info>
Date: 15 Oct 91 16:01:42 GMT
Sender: news@odin.corp.sgi.com (Net News)
Organization: Silicon Graphics, Inc.
Lines: 180</p>

<p> The <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> Corporation: the maturation of "private" government.</p>

<p> Wackenhut's Director of Special Investigations Service <ent type='PERSON'>Wayne Black</ent>
told the "<ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent> Times"' <ent type='PERSON'>Deanna Hoagin</ent> earlier this year: "We
are similar to a private <ent type='ORG'>FBI</ent>." The company's board of directors
reads like a who's who of the intelligence community.</p>

<p>from "The <ent type='ORG'>First Stone</ent>" column of the Sept. 18-24 1991 issue of "In These
Times":</p>

<p>---------------------------------------------------------------------------
Scandal <ent type='ORG'>Gates</ent>
By Joel Bleifuss</p>

<p> As <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> Director-designate <ent type='PERSON'>Robert Gates</ent> pleads ignorance to knowledge
of <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> misdeeds before the Senate Intelligence Committee this week,
the lawmakers might do well to remember his sworn testimony of March
March 6, 1986. At the time, <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> Director <ent type='PERSON'>William</ent> Casey had
nominated <ent type='ORG'>Gates</ent> for the number-two position at the agency. In an
effort to impress the senators considering his nomination, <ent type='ORG'>Gates</ent>
said: "[Casey] and I have consulted extensively, even in my present
position [as deputy director for intelligence] in all areas of
intelligence policy including not just analysis and estimates but
also organization, budgeting and covert action. I will now have a
formal role in all of these areas."
If <ent type='ORG'>Gates</ent> really had "a formal role in all of these areas"--which
appears likely--he certainly knows more than he has let on. And
someone should ask <ent type='ORG'>Gates</ent> what he knows about the <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent>
Corporation of Coral Gables, <ent type='GPE'>Fla</ent>.
As the <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> letterhead puts in, the company provides
"security systems and services throughout the world." As
Wackenhut's Director of Special Investigations Service <ent type='PERSON'>Wayne Black</ent>
told the "<ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent> Times"' <ent type='PERSON'>Deanna Hoagin</ent> earlier this year: "We
are similar to a private <ent type='ORG'>FBI</ent>." The company's board of directors
reads like a who's who of the intelligence community. In 1984, for
example, former Deputy <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> Director <ent type='PERSON'>Bobby Inman</ent>, currently one of
<ent type='ORG'>Gates</ent>' main boosters in <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, was a director of the company.
And among those on the 1983 board were two former <ent type='ORG'>FBI</ent> special
agents, one retired <ent type='ORG'>Air Force</ent> general, one former commander in chief
of the <ent type='PERSON'>North</ent> <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> Air Defense Command (<ent type='ORG'>NORAD</ent>), one former
director of <ent type='ORG'>the Defense Intelligence Agency</ent>, former <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> Director
<ent type='PERSON'>William</ent> Rabor, <ent type='PERSON'>Nixon</ent>-appointed <ent type='ORG'>FBI</ent> Director <ent type='PERSON'>Clarence Kelly</ent> and
former <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> Deputy Director <ent type='PERSON'>Frank Carlucci</ent> (who would later become
Ronald Reagan's national security adviser). Further, the 1983 board
included <ent type='PERSON'>Robert Chasen</ent>, a former <ent type='ORG'>FBI</ent> special agent who was Carter's
commissioner of customs until 1980, when he became a vice president
of <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent>. Also in 1980, soon-to-be <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> chief <ent type='PERSON'>William</ent> Casey
served as Wackenhut's outside legal counsel--the same year he
managed the Reagan-<ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent> election campaign.</p>

<p> ON THE RESERVATION: It was in 1980 that <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> began working
closely with <ent type='LOC'>Southern California</ent>'s <ent type='PERSON'>Cabazon</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Indians</ent> and their tribal
administrator <ent type='PERSON'>John Philip Nichols</ent>. The "<ent type='ORG'>San Francisco Chronicle</ent>"'s
<ent type='PERSON'>Jonathan Littman</ent> reported this month that <ent type='PERSON'>Nichols</ent>, a white <ent type='NORP'>American</ent>
who spent years in South <ent type='NORP'>American</ent>, has boasted to friends about
working on the attempted assassination of <ent type='PERSON'>Fidel Castro</ent> and the
successful assassination of <ent type='PERSON'>Salvador Allende</ent>.
The <ent type='PERSON'>Cabazon</ent>s hired <ent type='PERSON'>Nichols</ent> as their administrator in 1978.
<ent type='PERSON'>Littman</ent> reports that thanks to <ent type='PERSON'>Nichols</ent>' connections and
grantsmanship, "federal and state agencies are helping to finance
nearly $250 million worth of projects on the 1700-acre reservation"
belonging to the 30-member <ent type='PERSON'>Cabazon</ent> tribe. According to <ent type='PERSON'>Littman</ent>,
these projects include a <ent type='ORG'>HUD</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>mafia</ent>-financed casino, a 1800-unit
housing complex and a $150 million waste incinerator/power plant
that was built with tax-exempt state bonds.
But most intriguing is the <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent>/<ent type='PERSON'>Cabazon</ent> joint venture, which
began in 1980 when the tribe was asked to design a security system
for Crown Prince Fahd's palace in <ent type='GPE'>Tiaf</ent>, Saudi Arabia. This was
followed by <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent>/<ent type='PERSON'>Cabazon</ent> joint venture proposals to develop
biological weapons for the <ent type='ORG'>Pentagon</ent> and assemble night-vision
goggles for the <ent type='NORP'>Guatemalan</ent> and <ent type='NORP'>Jordanian</ent> governments.
Why was a security firm so interested in working with a small
tribe of native <ent type='NORP'>American</ent>s? One good reason can be found in a May
26, 1981, inter-office memo from <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> executive <ent type='PERSON'>Robert Frye</ent> to
the above-mentioned <ent type='PERSON'>Robert Chasen</ent>. <ent type='PERSON'>Frye</ent> described an 11-day
business trip with <ent type='PERSON'>Nichols</ent> "to explore the apparent potential for
the <ent type='PERSON'>Cabazon</ent>-<ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> joint venture." <ent type='PERSON'>Frye</ent> wrote that the
reservation has "several key ingredients necessary" for a weapons
plant, including "lack of opposition by adjacent governing bodies
and 'irate citizens' over the siting of such a facility."
<ent type='PERSON'>John Philip Nichols</ent> is no longer officially running the
reservation. According to <ent type='PERSON'>Littman</ent>, son Mark <ent type='PERSON'>Nichols</ent> is the tribal
administrator while the elder <ent type='PERSON'>Nichols</ent> serves as a "mental-health
counselor to <ent type='PERSON'>Cabazon</ent> reservation employees." <ent type='PERSON'>John Philip Nichols</ent>
lost his job because federal law prohibits convicted felons from
running casinos.
In January, 1985, <ent type='PERSON'>Nichols</ent> was sentenced to four years in prison
for capital solicitation of murder. He served 19 months. No one
was killed in that murder-for-hire scheme. However, in 1981, Alfred
<ent type='PERSON'>Alvarez</ent>, a <ent type='PERSON'>Cabazon</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Indian</ent> tribal vice president, and two non-<ent type='NORP'>Indians</ent>
were murdered execution style. Alvarez's sister Linda Streeter
Dukic says her brother and his friends died because they were about
to expose mismanagement on the <ent type='PERSON'>Cabazon</ent> reservation. <ent type='PERSON'>Mike Kataoka</ent> of
<ent type='ORG'>the Palm Springs</ent> "Press-Enterprise" reports that in 1985, when
<ent type='PERSON'>Nichols</ent> was arrested for hiring the hitman, the U.S. Justice
Department was investigating his possible involvement in those 1981
deaths. No charges were ever filed.</p>

<p> ANOTHER MURDER? The <ent type='PERSON'>Cabazon</ent>/<ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> connection was of particular
interest to <ent type='PERSON'><ent type='PERSON'>Danny</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Casolaro</ent></ent>, the <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>-based journalist who was
found dead in the <ent type='GPE'>Martinsburg</ent>, W. Va., <ent type='ORG'>Sheraton</ent> on August 10 (see
"The <ent type='ORG'>First Stone</ent>," Sept. 4 [an earlier post in this on-line
series]). Casolaro's friends, family and professional associates
fear he was murdered--and that the crime was related to his
investigations into a series of corporate and governmental scandals.
Casolaro's brother, <ent type='PERSON'>Anthony</ent>, told the <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>-based "Corporate
Crime Reporter," "<ent type='PERSON'>Danny</ent> was trying to track monies <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> spent
and what <ent type='PERSON'>Danny</ent> found was that [<ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent>] had ear-marked a half
million dollars for what they call 'research.'"
<ent type='PERSON'>Anthony</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Casolaro</ent> said that the money "ties in <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> with this
<ent type='NORP'>Indian</ent> reservation and organized crime and <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> guys . . . Those
same people showed up with <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> and one of them shows up in the
October Surprise."
The "October Surprise" was the alleged campaign deal between <ent type='GPE'>Iran</ent>
and the 1980 Reagan campaign to delay the release of the U.S.
hostages held in <ent type='GPE'>Tehran</ent> (see "In These Times," June 24, 1987, Oct.
12, 1988 and April 27, 1991).
"<ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> was <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> Inc. of <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent> D.C.--a firm that has
brought suit in federal court, charging that the Reagan Justice
Department stole the company's Promis case-management software
program. Two judges has thus far ruled in the company's favor. The
suit is still in the courts (see "In These Times," May 29, 1991
["Software Pirates," an earlier on-line post in this series]).
Earlier this year, <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> further alleged that the Justice
Department turned the stolen software over to <ent type='PERSON'>Earl Brian</ent>, a friend
of both former President Ronald Reagan and former Attorney General
<ent type='PERSON'>Edwin Meese</ent>. <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> charges that the software was a payback for
Brian's help in arranging the October Surprise. Former <ent type='NORP'>Israeli</ent>
intelligence agent Ari Ben-Menashe alleges that <ent type='PERSON'>Brian</ent>--now the head
of <ent type='ORG'>United Press International</ent>--was directly involved in arranging
the 1980 deal. Ben-Menashe claims that <ent type='PERSON'>Brian</ent> "worked very closely"
on the deal with <ent type='PERSON'>Robert Gates</ent>, who was then a top <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> official.</p>

<p> NO JUSTICE: <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> is also linked to the <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> scandal.
<ent type='PERSON'>Michael Riconosciuto</ent>--a weapons-systems designer and software
specialist--was director of research for the <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent>/<ent type='PERSON'>Cabazon</ent> joint
venture in the early '80s. In a March 1991 affidavit for the <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent>
case, <ent type='ORG'>Riconosciuto</ent> claimed that "in connection with [Riconosciuto's]
work for <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent>," he modified the stolen Promis software for
foreign sales. "Earl W. <ent type='PERSON'>Brian</ent> made [the software program] available
to me through <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> after acquiring it from <ent type='PERSON'>Peter Videnieks</ent>, who
was then a Department of Justice contracting official with
responsibility for the Promis software."
<ent type='PERSON'>Videnieks</ent>, a former Customs Service official under Commissioner
<ent type='PERSON'>Chasen</ent>, served in the Justice Department from 1981 through 1990. In
his affidavit, <ent type='ORG'>Riconosciuto</ent> said <ent type='PERSON'>Videnieks</ent> had threatened to
retaliate against <ent type='ORG'>Riconosciuto</ent> if he cooperated with a House
Judiciary Committee probe of the <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> case. Seven days after
filing the affidavit (which was not, technically, part of the
committee investigation), <ent type='ORG'>Riconosciuto</ent> was arrested on drug-selling
charges. He is now in a <ent type='GPE'>Seattle</ent> jail awaiting trial.</p>

<p> PRIVATE SPIES The 1980s were a decade of privatization. As a for-profit intelligence service, <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> appears to have taken on the
kind of work that in earlier years the <ent type='ORG'>FBI</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> would have done
(and still do), albeit illegally.
On the environmental-crime front, <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> is now the object of
an investigation by <ent type='ORG'>the House Interior Committee</ent>. Early in 1990,
<ent type='ORG'>the Alyeska Pipeline Service</ent> Co., a consortium of seven oil
companies that run the trans-<ent type='GPE'>Alaska</ent> oil pipeline, hired <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> to
spy on environmentalists, whistleblowers and other oil company
critics. <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> tactics included setting up a phoney
environmental organization and having agents pose as reporters. It
is alleged in press reports that the company also monitored Rep.
<ent type='PERSON'>George Miller</ent> (D-CA) whose house subcommittee has been investigating
environmental crimes allegedly committed by the consortium which is
composed of <ent type='ORG'>British Petroleum</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Exxon</ent>, ARCO, <ent type='ORG'>Phillips</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Unocal</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Mobil</ent>
and <ent type='PERSON'>Amerada Hess</ent>.</p>

<p>--
daveus rattus</p>

<p> yer friendly neighborhood ratman</p>

<p> KOYAANISQATSI</p>

<p> ko.yan.nis.qatsi (from <ent type='EVENT'>the Hopi Language</ent>) n. 1. crazy life. 2. life
in turmoil. 3. life out of balance. 4. life disintegrating.
5. a state of life that calls for another way of living.</p>

</xml>