<xml><p>This file is the abstracts or text of 26 articles with references to the
Justice Department's participation in the <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> scandal. There are also
references to <ent type='PERSON'><ent type='PERSON'>Danny</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Casolaro</ent></ent>'s mysterious death (spelled murder). The
articles were published in 1991 and 1992.</p>

<p>I've included some background information about <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> and its products.</p>

<p>Copyrights belong to the corresponding journals.</p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>Journal</ent>: Newsbytes March 5 1992
----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Title: Justice Dept. allegedly blocks <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> investigation.
Author: McCormick, John.
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Descriptors..
Company: INSLAW Inc. (Investigations).
Topic: Legal Issues
Investigations
Government Agency
<ent type='GPE'>United</ent> States. <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> of Justice
Software piracy
Copyright.</p>

<p>-----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Full Text:</p>

<p>****Justice Dept Allegedly Blocks <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> Investigation 03/05/92 <ent type='GPE'>WASHINGTON</ent>,
DC, U.S.A., 1992 MAR 5 (NB) -- According to a <ent type='ORG'>CNN Business</ent> report today, the
U.S. Justice <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> is harassing individuals who talk with investigators
who are looking into the <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> software case. <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent>, a <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent> based
software company, has charged that the Justice <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> made illegal copies
of its <ent type='ORG'>PROMIS</ent> legal case tracking software and sold or gave it to various
countries.</p>

<p>Former Attorney General and defeated <ent type='GPE'>Pennsylvania</ent> candidate for the U.S.
Senate, <ent type='PERSON'><ent type='PERSON'>Richard</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Thornburgh</ent></ent>, fought a futile battle to keep congressional
investigators from obtaining Justice <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> files relating to the case,
and although a spokesperson for <ent type='ORG'>the Department</ent> of Justice is saying that
current head <ent type='PERSON'>William</ent> P. <ent type='PERSON'>Barr</ent> has ordered <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> employees to provide
"full support" to the investigation, <ent type='ORG'>CNN</ent> reports that Judge <ent type='PERSON'>Bua</ent> said he is
aware of the allegations that Justice is harassing people who talk to his
investigators.</p>

<p>Judge <ent type='PERSON'>Bua</ent> was appointed by <ent type='PERSON'>Barr</ent> in November of 1991 to investigate the
allegations against his <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> but there has been some confusion over
just how much authority the retired federal judge has to force cooperation.</p>

<p>The Justice <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> says that the Attorney General's office is not aware
of any allegations of harassment, but <ent type='ORG'>CNN</ent> today carried an interview with
former Justice <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> staffer <ent type='PERSON'>Lois Battastoni</ent> who said that she knows
about such cases and that employees are in fear of losing their jobs if they
talk to the investigators.</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>Courts</ent> have already ruled in favor of <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> on several occasions, but the $8
million award to the small ($6 million gross) company was overturned on a
technicality.</p>

<p>More recently there have been suspicions voiced that the death of <ent type='PERSON'>James</ent> D.
"<ent type='PERSON'>Danny</ent>" <ent type='PERSON'>Casolaro</ent>, a freelance writer who was investigating the <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> case,
was not a suicide as originally reported.</p>

<p>(John McCormick/19920305)</p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>Journal</ent>: Government Computer News Feb 17 1992 v11 n4 p10(1)
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Title: Writing is on the wall for the move to open systems. (U.S. Justice
<ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> Information Resources Management Chief Roger M. <ent type='PERSON'>Cooper</ent>)
(<ent type='ORG'>GCN</ent> Interview) (Interview)
Author: Quindlen, <ent type='PERSON'>Terrey Hatcher</ent>.</p>

<p>Summary: US Justice <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> Information Resources Management (<ent type='ORG'>IRM</ent>) Chief
Roger M. <ent type='PERSON'>Cooper</ent> has guided the department toward embracing open
systems. Currently, the department is putting together a policy
paper that addresses multiuser systems below the level of
mainframes. <ent type='PERSON'>Cooper</ent> would like systems to comply with <ent type='PERSON'>Posix</ent> and to
use <ent type='ORG'>the Government Open Systems Interconnection</ent> Profile. The
local area network standard will be the 10M-bps twisted-pair
Ethernet servers and the word processing standard will be Word
Perfect Corp's WordPerfect 5.1 software package. <ent type='PERSON'>Cooper</ent> and his
staff are looking for ways to procure equipment and supplies, and
he may investigate working with other agencies. He supports the
General Services Administration's policy of leaving 10 percent of
big procurement contracts for other agencies.
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Descriptors..
Topic: MIS
Standards
Open <ent type='ORG'>Systems</ent>
System Conversion
Interview
Office Automation
Government Contracts
Equipment Acquisition
Information resources management
Government Officials
Management of EDP
Trends.
Feature: illustration
photograph.</p>

<p>-----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Full Text:</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>GCN</ent>: You have a reputation for supporting open systems. Have you made any
efforts at the Justice <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> to move toward an open environment?</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>COOPER</ent>: We basically have done a lot of work with the <ent type='ORG'>IRM</ent> directors and the
components in the agencies. We are putting together a policy paper that
covers multiuser systems below the mainframe level, because we've got a lot
of <ent type='ORG'>IBM</ent>-compatible mainframes.</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>Systems</ent> will be <ent type='PERSON'>Posix</ent>-complaint and use the Government Open systems
Interconnection Profile. The department's default for local area network
transmission media will be 10-megabit/<ent type='ORG'>sec</ent>, twisted-pair Ethernet servers.
It's a very flexible way to transmit.</p>

<p>For office automation, since everybody uses WordPerfect, we've said you've
got to use WordPerfect or at least have compatibility. We mostly use Version
5.1.</p>

<p>We're also working at bringing some version of Unix up on the <ent type='ORG'>IBM</ent>-compatible
mainframes.</p>

<p>Justice, like most agencies, is very paperwork-oriented. So we're trying to
come up with standards on how we image documents.</p>

<p>We've got a coordinating group for image standards that's met twice now. The
group focuses on joint procurements because that's a growth industry.</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>GCN</ent>: When you say joint procurements, do you mean with other Justice bureaus
or with other agencies?</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>COOPER</ent>: I mean mostly within Justice. But we're always looking for other
procurement vehicles. I've had lots of discussions with <ent type='PERSON'>Thomas Buckholtz</ent>,
commissioner of <ent type='ORG'>the General Services Administration</ent>'s <ent type='ORG'>IRM</ent> Service, and Frank
McDonough, the assistant commissioner, about using every vehicle. We were
the first people that called on Desktop IV, I think, to see if we could be on
it. That was before it got protested. But that's the way it goes.</p>

<p>I think GSA's proposed policy of leaving 10 percent of certain big
procurements for other agencies is a good idea. We had a very good
experience at <ent type='ORG'>the Farmers Home Administration</ent>. We had some AT&amp;T 3B2
computers we got through a big office automation contract. <ent type='ORG'>The Air Force</ent>'s
AFCAC 251 had a similar set of hardware and software. But there was a big
difference in the prices.</p>

<p>So we wanted the <ent type='ORG'>Agriculture</ent> contractor to change his prices. He wasn't very
responsive until we bought a hundred or so computers from the <ent type='ORG'>Air Force</ent>
contract. Then he got a lot more responsive.</p>

<p>Procurements are so tough that any time you can leverage back and forth, I
think it's a good idea. So I'm glad GSA's doing it.</p>

<p>The down side is if you've got a tightly integrated system and someone picks
out one part of it and says, "Gee, you can buy a PC cheaper here." Certainly
some of the criticism we've had on our Project <ent type='ORG'>Eagle</ent> microcomputers is not
fair. It's all bundled up with software and everything.</p>

<p>You've got to be careful that you're not cream-skimming on the whole thing.
It has to be a judgment call. When the guy priced the thing, maybe he
unloaded part of the development costs in the price of the PC.</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>GCN</ent>: When you came to Justice, the department's <ent type='ORG'>IRM</ent> had been under fire from
many sides, including <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>the General Accounting Office</ent>. What goals
do you have for improving <ent type='ORG'>IRM</ent>?</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>COOPER</ent>: We have had criticism, but I think a lot of it has not been
justified. Certainly we've had some problems. The press Justice has had is
not commensurate with the level of sophistication of the systems or the
people. I was pleasantly surprised at the competence level at Justice.</p>

<p>One area we're going to work on, and I think we probably did need a little
more work on, is computer <ent type='ORG'>sec</ent>urity. We have done a tremendous amount of
training and education, and gotten a lot tougher. It has gotten further up
on the list of things we worry about.</p>

<p>I'm proposing putting together a computer <ent type='ORG'>sec</ent>urity organization reporting
directly to me. We're thinking about it, but I've got union negotiations.</p>

<p>In other areas, we've done some really neat things. On our <ent type='ORG'>Eagle</ent> system,
every morning when you fire up you PC, the local area network server scans
your hard disk to see if there's any viruses. It takes a little longer.
When you turn the thing on, it is not available for about 5 minutes while the
network interrogates the PC.</p>

<p>We have found some viruses here, as everybody else in town has. What's nice
is, when you find it, you know about it instantly. Somebody doesn't have to
remember to turn the virus program on; it's done automatically. If we get a
new change to the virus protection software, it goes on the system.
Eventually, 15000 PCs are going to be interrogated every morning for
viruses.</p>

<p>There's a lot of ways they could be introduced. We probably have had less
viruses than most folks, but I'd say in the nine months I've been here, we've
had at least a half-dozen to a dozen instances. A lot of them I don't even
have to worry about, because the system in many cases fixes them
automatically.</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>GCN</ent>: Last year, <ent type='ORG'>GAO</ent> said the U.S. attorneys' offices were not getting
enough training in <ent type='ORG'>sec</ent>urity procedures. This year <ent type='ORG'>the House Government</ent>
Operations Subcommittee on Government Information, Justice and <ent type='ORG'>Agriculture</ent>
said sensitive data in <ent type='ORG'>the Bureau</ent> of Prisons Sentry system was not getting
adequate protection. Do you think those situations have improved?</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>COOPER</ent>: I don't necessarily agree with their assessment, but we've improved
those situations. In the U.S. attorneys' officers we've done a massive
education process. A couple of months ago, they had a big computer <ent type='ORG'>sec</ent>urity
conference here in <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>. They had, I think, 200 people there. We have
had lots of training and have improved awareness in that organization by two
orders of magnitude.</p>

<p>In addition, we're going to be encrypting all the communications between the
U.S. attorneys' offices. Anytime they do communications outside the
controlled area, we're using some encryption. It's not classified data, but
it's certainly very sensitive.</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>GCN</ent>: How do you respond to the recent criticism of the Project <ent type='ORG'>Eagle</ent> office
automation buy from <ent type='NORP'>Democrats</ent> on <ent type='ORG'>the House</ent> Judiciary Committee?</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>COOPER</ent>: A great many reports have a particular political spin out there.
I've heard the arguments about the particular spin on the thing, but that's
not unusual. There have been some recommendations, and we will address them
back to the regular channels. We're not getting into some kind of dialogue.
Enough has been said about the whole issue.</p>

<p>Sometimes I think we lose sight of what we're doing here. We get hung up on
the process. The question we ultimately should ask is: Is the customer
getting what he wanted? I think with <ent type='ORG'>Eagle</ent>, the answer would be a resounding
yes. A lot of systems in town don't have happy customers.</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>GCN</ent>: How is <ent type='ORG'>Eagle</ent> giving the customers what they want?</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>COOPER</ent>: It's easy to use. It's got great connectivity. It's reasonably
inexpensive. It's modular. It's upgradeable. And it has minimized the use
of proprietary technology. It's been so successful that we've beat our best
projections for installing it. We're talking 12000 workstations installed
in less than two years. Within six months, we'll probably have them all
talking to each other.</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>GCN</ent>: You said it's inexpensive. One of the things <ent type='ORG'>the House</ent> report said is
that you could go out in the stores and get computers cheaper than through
<ent type='ORG'>Eagle</ent>.</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>COOPER</ent>: An analogy would be like saying, "A tank weighs 60 tons and it's made
mostly of steel. I could buy steel at $ 60 a ton."</p>

<p>The federal procurement system says you buy an integrated solution. It
doesn't say you can go out and price the parts individually. That would be
like taking a <ent type='ORG'>lapto</ent>p computer and weighing all the silicon and all the
solder. If you added up a $2000 <ent type='ORG'>lapto</ent> with all the raw materials or
component parts, you would not get the value added in there.</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>GSA</ent> publishers a report on PC prices. The Justice <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> PC prices,
which are mostly <ent type='ORG'>Eagle</ent>, are right in the middle of that. They're not the
lowest and they're not the highest.</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>GCN</ent>: Are you still planning an agencywide case management software buy for
the <ent type='ORG'>Eagle</ent> machines?</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>COOPER</ent>: Well, we didn't get any money, so we're re-evaluating that. We're
taking a look at our options, given no money.</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>GCN</ent>: That's tied in with <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> Inc. and the company's Promis case management
software. Have you met with Judge <ent type='PERSON'>Nicholas</ent> J. <ent type='PERSON'>Bua</ent>, the special counsel the
attorney general appointed to investigate Inslaw's claim that Justice stole
copies of Promis and tried to drive the company into bankruptcy?</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>COOPER</ent>: I have not met him. He has not talked to me. Most of the <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent>
thing happened years and years ago. It has gone to numerous courts. Our
position all along has been that it's a contract dispute that's gotten out of
hand.</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>The Civil Division</ent> is handlign that. The judge will do as the attorney
general wants him to do, and that's fine. I think all of us in the
department would like to get it behind us. It's sort of an albatross.</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>GCN</ent>: What else is Justice doing in <ent type='ORG'>IRM</ent>?</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>COOPER</ent>: We're trying to work the open systems thing. We're not making
everybody run their PC with Unix. We're not making everybody take the
proprietary system and convert it over. What we're saying is, if you buy
something new, this is what you should do. We're trying to get a rational
move to open systems without throwing the baby out with the bathwater.</p>

<p>I've been very pleased with the response. Justice has a heavily
<ent type='ORG'>IBM</ent>-compatible mainframe background, yet I've found great interest in going
to open systems. I think the handwriting is on the wall.</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>Journal</ent>: Government Computer News Jan 20 1992 v11 n2 p4(1)
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Title: <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> owners vow to continue software battle. (<ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> Inc.
battles U.S. Justice <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent>) (Brief Article)
Author: Quindlen, <ent type='PERSON'>Terrey Hatcher</ent>.
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Descriptors..
Company: INSLAW Inc. (Cases).
Topic: Legal Issues
Law Suit
Software Piracy
<ent type='GPE'>United</ent> States. <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> of Justice
Computer software industry.</p>

<p>-----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Full Text:</p>

<p>Even though <ent type='ORG'>the Supreme Court</ent> last week decided not to hear <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> Inc.'s
complaint against the Justice <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent>, the company's owners said they will
not give up their fight over rights to the Promis case management software.</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> owners <ent type='PERSON'>Nancy</ent> B. and <ent type='PERSON'>William</ent> A. <ent type='PERSON'>Hamilton</ent> said they plan to file a new
suit against the Justice <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent>, probably in the U.S. <ent type='ORG'>District Court</ent> for
<ent type='ORG'>the District</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>Columbia</ent>. The <ent type='PERSON'>Hamilton</ent>s have alleged that Justice officials
stole versions of the company's Promis software and tried to force <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent>
into bankruptcy.</p>

<p>"If you don't punish wrongdoing, it's going to come and bite you again,"
<ent type='PERSON'>William</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Hamilton</ent> said last week at a briefing sponsored by Federal Sources
Inc., a consulting firm in McLean, Va.</p>

<p>Justice spokesman <ent type='PERSON'><ent type='PERSON'>Joseph</ent> <ent type='GPE'>Krovisky</ent></ent> said the department had no comment on the
<ent type='ORG'>Supreme Court</ent> decision nor on the prospect of more litigation.</p>

<p>In November, Attorney General <ent type='PERSON'>William</ent> P. <ent type='PERSON'>Barr</ent> appointed <ent type='PERSON'>Nicholas</ent> J. <ent type='PERSON'>Bua</ent>, a
retired judge, to act as a special counsel to investigate the Hamilton's
8-year-old charges of wrongdoing by Justice officials.</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Hamilton</ent> said Justice's primary motivation in stealing Inslaw's software was
money, but surveillance of foreign governments might have been another
motive.</p>

<p>He said he has been told that the <ent type='NORP'>Iraqis</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>the Royal</ent> Canadian Mounted Police
and <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> intelligence have had Promis software installed on their
computers.</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Hamilton</ent> speculated that someone might have sold copies of Promis illegally
to foreign governments. Those copies of the software might have had a hidden
feature that could transmit information to U.S. surveillance systems, he
suggested.</p>

<p>Justice officials have denied these allegations repeatedly.</p>

<p>The <ent type='PERSON'>Hamilton</ent>s' case has been heard in three courts. The U.S. Bankruptcy
Court in 1987 found in Inslaw's favor. The U.S. <ent type='ORG'>District Court</ent> for D.C.
affirmed that ruling in 1988 and awarded <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> $6 million.</p>

<p>Last year, the U.S. Appeals Court for D.C. overturned those rulings, saying
the bankruptcy court did not have the authority to rule on the matter.</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> came out of Chapter 11 bankruptcy in 1988 with a loan from <ent type='ORG'>IBM</ent> Corp.,
<ent type='PERSON'>Nancy</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Hamilton</ent> said. The company still sells Promis to state and local
governments, <ent type='PERSON'>William</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Hamilton</ent> said.</p>

<p>The company also sells software for legal and insurance workload management
as well as Promis.</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>Journal</ent>: Newsbytes Jan 14 1992
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Title: <ent type='ORG'>Supreme Court</ent> denies <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> petition. (court case against US
<ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> of Justice)
Author: McCormick, John.
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Descriptors..
Company: INSLAW Inc. (Cases).
Topic: Government Agency
Legal Issues
Software Publishers
Court Cases
Fraud
<ent type='GPE'>United</ent> States. <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> of Justice.</p>

<p>-----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Full Text:</p>

<p>****<ent type='ORG'>Supreme Court</ent> Denies <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> Petition 01/14/92 <ent type='GPE'>WASHINGTON</ent>, DC, U.S.A.,
1992 JAN 14 (NB) -- The U.S. <ent type='ORG'>Supreme Court</ent> has refused to reinstate the
nearly $8 million fine which <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> had won against the U.S. Justice
<ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> in earlier cases.</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> had charged that during the Reagan administration the Justice
<ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> had stolen the company's legal case-tracking software and sold it
to other agencies in <ent type='ORG'>the United</ent> States and abroad.</p>

<p>The <ent type='ORG'>Supreme Court</ent> had been petitioned to reinstate the $7.8 million fine
which had earlier be overturned because of a procedural error in which the
company had sued and won its case, but in the wrong court.</p>

<p>The ball is now back in Inslaw's court and the company has expressed
confidence that a retrial in the correct court will again result in its
winning a major award against the U.S. government. The Justice <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent>
would not comment on <ent type='ORG'>the Supreme Court</ent>'s decision or Inslaw's statement that
it would continue to pursue the case.</p>

<p>(John McCormick/19920114)</p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>Journal</ent>: Newsbytes Dec 6 1991
----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Title: Suspect <ent type='ORG'>TISOFT</ent> contract given <ent type='ORG'>Eagle</ent>-eye. (<ent type='GPE'>United</ent> States'
<ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> of Justice contract)
Author: McCormick, John.
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Descriptors..
Company: TiSoft Inc. (Contracts).
Topic: Investigations
Government Contracts
Government Agency
Competitive Bidding
Computer industry
<ent type='GPE'>United</ent> States. <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> of Justice.</p>

<p>-----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Full Text:</p>

<p>****Suspect <ent type='ORG'>TISOFT</ent> Contract Given <ent type='ORG'>Eagle</ent>-Eye 12/06/91 <ent type='GPE'>WASHINGTON</ent>, DC, U.S.A.,
1991 <ent type='ORG'>DEC</ent> 6 (NB) -- <ent type='ORG'>Eagle</ent>, a multi-billion dollar computer system being
installed by the U.S. <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> of Justice, was apparently a gold-plated
contract, according to a <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>ional investigation by <ent type='NORP'>Democrat</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Jack Brooks</ent>'
Judiciary Committee. A <ent type='GPE'>Virginia</ent>-based firm, <ent type='ORG'>TISOFT</ent> was awarded the contract
for approximately 15000 workstations despite the fact that it had submitted
not the lowest but the <ent type='ORG'>sec</ent>ond highest bid.</p>

<p>Among the charges investigated by the committee were a possible relationship
between the <ent type='ORG'>Eagle</ent> computer system and INSLAW-like software which was
originally specified for the system. <ent type='ORG'>CNN</ent> reports that investigators contend
<ent type='ORG'>the Department</ent> of Justice gave the winning bidder, <ent type='ORG'>TISOFT</ent>, a $200000 payment
which was allegedly used to pay off losing bidders who would otherwise have
contested the award to <ent type='ORG'>TISOFT</ent>.</p>

<p>The committee is still holding hearings on the possible INSLAW connection but
it has reported that the $200000 payment did take place and that, in its
estimation, Justice paid $18 million too much for the Project <ent type='ORG'>Eagle</ent> system.</p>

<p>In a televised interview seen on Friday's <ent type='ORG'>CNN Business</ent> Morning, <ent type='GPE'>Texas</ent>' 9th
District Representative <ent type='PERSON'>Jack Brooks</ent> stated, "We didn't find them stealing any
money, of course - we found ... neglect. It took the Justice <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> two
and one-half years to award a contract for equipment that was available in
stores."</p>

<p>As for the special payment, Rep. <ent type='ORG'>Brooks</ent> said, "It doesn't sound right that
the Justice <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> of <ent type='ORG'>the United</ent> States gave them (<ent type='ORG'>TISOFT</ent>) $200000 to
pay off these people."</p>

<p>As for the Justice <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent>, spokesmen have pointed out that they did
nothing illegal.</p>

<p>According to <ent type='ORG'>CNN</ent>, Patrick Gallager, president of <ent type='ORG'>TISOFT</ent>, says that Rep.
<ent type='ORG'>Brooks</ent> doesn't understand the difference between buying commodity items off
the shelf and purchasing a complete integrated system. He also reportedly
said that the payoffs were legal.</p>

<p>(John McCormick/19911206/Press Contact: <ent type='PERSON'>Jack Brooks</ent>, 202-225-6565 or fax
202-225-1584)</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>Journal</ent>: Government Computer News Nov 25 1991 v10 n24 p60(1)
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Title: Special counsel appointed to review <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> claims. (Justice
<ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> investigation involving <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> Corp.)
Author: Quindlen, <ent type='PERSON'>Terrey Hatcher</ent>.</p>

<p>Summary: The Justice <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> will investigate allegations by <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> Inc
owners, <ent type='PERSON'>Nancy</ent> B. <ent type='PERSON'>Hamilton</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>William</ent> A. <ent type='PERSON'>Hamilton</ent>, who say that
the Justice <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> stole computer software that belongs to
them and tried to push their company into bankruptcy. <ent type='PERSON'>William</ent> P.
<ent type='PERSON'>Barr</ent>, the newly appointed attorney general, has appointed a
special counsel, <ent type='PERSON'>Nicholas</ent> J. <ent type='PERSON'>Bua</ent>, to look into the <ent type='PERSON'>Hamilton</ent>s'
claims. The <ent type='PERSON'>Hamilton</ent>s are skeptical, saying that an investigator
from outside the Justice <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> is needed. It is not
reasonable to expect, say the <ent type='PERSON'>Hamilton</ent>s, that the Justice
<ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> will do an adequate job if it is investigating itself.
Nevertheless, the <ent type='PERSON'>Hamilton</ent>s are pleased that there is renewed
activity and interest in the matter.
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Descriptors..
Company: INSLAW Inc. (Investigations).
Topic: Investigations
<ent type='GPE'>United</ent> States. <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> of Justice.
Person: <ent type='PERSON'>Hamilton</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>William</ent> A. (Cases); <ent type='PERSON'>Hamilton</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Nancy</ent> B. (Cases).</p>

<p>-----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Full Text:</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> Inc. owners <ent type='PERSON'>Nancy</ent> B. and <ent type='PERSON'>William</ent> A. <ent type='PERSON'>Hamilton</ent> are expecting the worst,
yet hoping for the best out of anew Justice <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> investigation into the
couple's allegations that Justice stole <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> software and attempted to
drive the <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent> company into bankruptcy.</p>

<p>When the newly designated attorney general, <ent type='PERSON'>William</ent> P. <ent type='PERSON'>Barr</ent>, announced this
month that he had appointed a special counsel to check out the <ent type='PERSON'>Hamilton</ent>s'
claims, <ent type='PERSON'>Nancy</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Hamilton</ent> expressed doubts about the outcome of such an
investigation.</p>

<p>A special pro<ent type='ORG'>sec</ent>utor appointed outside the department is sorely needed, she
said. It is unreasonable "to think that <ent type='ORG'>the Department</ent> of Justice could
investigate itself," she said.</p>

<p>For nearly eight years, the <ent type='PERSON'>Hamilton</ent>s have been fighting to get compensation
from Justice for the alleged theft of enhanced versions of the company's case
management software, Promis.</p>

<p>The U.S. <ent type='ORG'>Bankruptcy Court</ent> in 1987 found in Inslaw's favor and said Justice
had tried to force the company into bankruptcy. The following year, the U.S.
<ent type='ORG'>District Court</ent> for <ent type='ORG'>the District</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>Columbia</ent> affirmed the bankruptcy court
ruling and awarded <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> $6 million.</p>

<p>But in May, the U.S. Appeals Court for D.C. threw out those rulings, saying
the bankruptcy court had exceeded its authority.</p>

<p>Now <ent type='PERSON'>Barr</ent> has asked <ent type='PERSON'>Nicholas</ent> J. <ent type='PERSON'>Bua</ent>, a retired federal judge for the <ent type='PERSON'>Northern</ent>
District of <ent type='GPE'>Illinois</ent>, to "review all the information related to the <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent>
case and advise the attorney general of any further action that may be
required," Justice spokesman <ent type='PERSON'><ent type='PERSON'>Joseph</ent> <ent type='GPE'>Krovisky</ent></ent> said.</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Bua</ent>, who will serve as special counsel and assistant U.S. attorney, said he
had "no idea at this time" how long his investigation might take.</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Hamilton</ent> said she was glad for the renewed interest but questioned whether
<ent type='PERSON'>Bua</ent> could accomplish anything. Justice employees who know of wrongdoing will
be reluctant to volunteer information because <ent type='PERSON'>Bua</ent> will report directly to
<ent type='PERSON'>Barr</ent>, she said.</p>

<p>"They are not going to tell someone representing the attorney general of the
criminal misconduct of their superior. It simply won't happen," <ent type='PERSON'>Hamilton</ent>
said.</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Barr</ent> appointed <ent type='PERSON'>Bua</ent> "in an effort to resolve fairly and conclusively the
ongoing litigation," <ent type='GPE'>Krovisky</ent> said. <ent type='PERSON'>Barr</ent> gave <ent type='PERSON'>Bua</ent> carte blanche to gather
any information he seeks, <ent type='GPE'>Krovisky</ent> added.</p>

<p>"We are in the embryonic stage of the matter," <ent type='PERSON'>Bua</ent> said, adding that it was
too early to give a reading on the situation. <ent type='PERSON'>Bua</ent>, a partner in a <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>
law firm, said he plans to begin looking into the charges in <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent> by
early December.</p>

<p>Although the appointment is "a step in the right direction," <ent type='PERSON'>Hamilton</ent> said,
she questioned Bua's ability to bring witnesses forward. "People in law
enforcement know that to uncover official corruption you need subpoena power
and the power of a grand jury," she said.</p>

<p>The special counsel does not have subpoena power now. But if <ent type='PERSON'>Bua</ent> runs into
problems getting the information he needs, he can "lay out what the problem
is and then request subpoena power from the attorney general," <ent type='GPE'>Krovisky</ent> said.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, the <ent type='PERSON'>Hamilton</ent>s have filed a petition asking <ent type='ORG'>the Supreme Court</ent> to
consider their case. "We're hoping that there will be a decision sometime
before the end of the year" on whether <ent type='ORG'>the Supreme Court</ent> will hear the case,
<ent type='PERSON'>Hamilton</ent> said.</p>

<p>On the congressional front, <ent type='ORG'>the House</ent> Judiciary Committee still has the
record open on its <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> investigation. The committee has been seeking
several documents from the department. When Attorney General <ent type='PERSON'>Richard</ent> L.
<ent type='PERSON'>Thornburgh</ent> resigned, several documents relating to <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> had not been turned
over. The committee chairman, Rep. <ent type='PERSON'>Jack Brooks</ent> (D-<ent type='GPE'>Texas</ent>), has not said how
he will proceed.</p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>Journal</ent>: Newsbytes Nov 15 1991
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Title: Special counsel appointed in <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> case. (<ent type='PERSON'>Nicholas</ent> J. <ent type='PERSON'>Bua</ent>)
Author: McCormick, John.
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Descriptors..
Company: INSLAW Inc. (Investigations).
Topic: Investigations
Government Agency
Legal Issues
Computer industry
Fraud
<ent type='GPE'>United</ent> States. <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> of Justice.</p>

<p>-----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Full Text:</p>

<p>Special Counsel Appointed in <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> Case 11/15/91 <ent type='GPE'>WASHINGTON</ent>, DC, U.S.A.,
1991 NOV 15 (NB) -- Just a few days after the White <ent type='ORG'>House</ent> suffered a major
public defeat when its hand-picked Senate candidate for <ent type='GPE'>Pennsylvania</ent>, former
Attorney General <ent type='PERSON'><ent type='PERSON'>Richard</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Thornburgh</ent></ent>, who had blocked all investigations into
the <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent>/Justice <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> scandal, was defeated by <ent type='PERSON'>Harris Wofford</ent>,
President Bush's Attorney General-designate, <ent type='PERSON'>William</ent> P. <ent type='PERSON'>Barr</ent>, has appointed a
special counsel to look into charges that the Justice <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> defrauded
and attempted to bankrupt the <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> company.</p>

<p>Allegations surround <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> and claims that the Justice <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> and
intelligence agencies illegally copied, modified, and sold the law
enforcement-related software <ent type='ORG'>PROMIS</ent>, which was marketed by <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent>. One
prominent claim is that the software was modified to allow U.S. intelligence
agencies to penetrate foreign law-enforcement and intelligence computers
running the software through what is called a trap-door, a <ent type='ORG'>sec</ent>ret way around
the usual password access permission systems used to prevent such access.</p>

<p>Saying during his confirmation hearing testimony before the Senate Judiciary
Committee on Wednesday, "I want to get to the bottom of this," Mr. <ent type='PERSON'>Barr</ent> went
on to tell the Senate that he had appointed retired U.S. District judge
<ent type='PERSON'>Nicholas</ent> J. <ent type='PERSON'>Bua</ent> (<ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>) to investigate the situation which goes back to
1984. Judge <ent type='PERSON'>Bua</ent> was a <ent type='NORP'>Democrat</ent>ic appointee to the bench.</p>

<p>The U.S. <ent type='ORG'>House</ent> of Representatives tried to investigate the <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> case last
year when <ent type='ORG'>House</ent> Judiciary Committee Chairman <ent type='PERSON'>Jack Brooks</ent> (D-Tex.) subpoenaed
Justice <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> documents which former Attorney General <ent type='PERSON'>Thornburgh</ent> only
grudgingly released early this year.</p>

<p>A court had earlier found the Justice <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> guilty of "fraud, deceit,
and trickery" and awarded <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> $8 million in damages, but that ruling was
overturned on a minor technicality by another court and the case is now being
put before <ent type='ORG'>the Supreme Court</ent>.</p>

<p>(John McCormick/19911115)</p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>Journal</ent>: Newsbytes Sept 24 1991
* Full Text COPYRIGHT Newsbytes Inc. 1991.
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Title: <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> denies <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> connection.
Author: McMullen, <ent type='PERSON'>Barbara</ent> E.; McMullen, John F.
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Descriptors..
Company: <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> Corp. (Investigations)
INSLAW Inc. (Products).
Topic: Investigations
Legal Issues
Software piracy
<ent type='GPE'>United</ent> States. <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> of Justice
Government Agency
Court Cases.
Person: Riconosciuto, Michael (Investigations).</p>

<p>-----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Full Text:</p>

<p>****<ent type='ORG'>WACKENHUT</ent> DENIES INSLAW CONNECTION 09/24/91 CORAL <ent type='ORG'>GABLES</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>FLORIDA</ent>,
U.S.A., 1991 SEP 24 (NB) -- <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> Corp.'s director of publications,
<ent type='PERSON'>Patrick Cannan</ent>, in a conversation with Newsbytes, has denied any connection
between <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> and the so-called "<ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> case."</p>

<p>Wackenhut's name has come up consistently in relation to claims made by
<ent type='PERSON'>Michael Riconosciuto</ent> that he, while a research director for a joint venture
between <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> and the <ent type='ORG'>Cabazon</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Indians</ent>, modified a stolen copy of Inslaw's
Promis software for sale by <ent type='PERSON'>Earl Brian</ent> to the Canadian government. These
claims, which surfaced most recently in a <ent type='ORG'>Village Voice</ent> article by <ent type='PERSON'>James</ent>
Ridgeway ("Software To Die For", <ent type='ORG'>Village Voice</ent>, September 24th), also portray
the joint venture as one which manufactured weapons (including biological and
chemical) for foreign governments, including the "contras."</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Cannan</ent> told Newsbytes: "When these claims first came up, we did an extensive
check of our records on Riconosciuto and can say, without fear of
contradiction, that he was never an employee of <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent>. I believe that he
did make some proposals to the management of the joint venture and, if they
had been accepted, he would have played a role in the project. Things like
this are common in this type of business but his proposals were never
accepted."</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Cannan</ent>, continued, commenting on the relationship of <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> and the
<ent type='ORG'>Cabazon</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Indians</ent>, saying: "We were involved in a joint venture in the early
1980s. The purpose of the venture was to attempt to obtain contracts in our
base business - the <ent type='ORG'>sec</ent>urity business. The <ent type='NORP'>Indians</ent>, I guess because of their
minority status, were believed to have good opportunities of obtaining this
type of contract. It turned out that we never got any contracts and, after
two years, the venture was cancelled."</p>

<p>The <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> case involves the alleged theft of software by the Justice
Deptartment from the <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> Corp. and, has grown from a tile and bankruptcy
case to one that includes allegations of sales of the software to foreign
governments (such as <ent type='GPE'>Canada</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Iraq</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>South Korea</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Libya</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent>) by such
<ent type='EVENT'>Watergate</ent> figures as <ent type='PERSON'>Robert</ent> McFarlane and <ent type='PERSON'>Richard</ent> Secord.</p>

<p>The case attracted more public attention following the apparent suicide death
of journalist <ent type='PERSON'>Joseph</ent> D. "<ent type='PERSON'>Danny</ent>" <ent type='PERSON'>Casolaro</ent> on mid-August in a <ent type='GPE'>Martinsburg</ent> motel
room. <ent type='PERSON'>Casolaro</ent> had told friends that he had made connections between <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent>,
<ent type='GPE'>Iran</ent>Contra and the so-called "October Surprise" (allegations that
representatives of the Reagan-<ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent> campaign team had convinced the <ent type='NORP'>Iranian</ent>
government to delay release of <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> hostages until after the 1980 U.S.
elections).</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Casolaro</ent> also allegedly told his brother, that, if he reportedly had an
accident, it was not to be believed. Former US Attorney General Elliot
<ent type='PERSON'>Richard</ent>son, now attorney for <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent>, has demanded a federal investigation of
Casolaro's death and has been quoted that <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> "is far worse than
<ent type='EVENT'>Watergate</ent>."</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Cannan</ent> also responded to Newsbytes questions concerning rumors that <ent type='PERSON'>William</ent>
Casey, ex-<ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> Director often named in the "October Surprise" allegations was
legal counsel to <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> before joining the government and that former <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>
officials <ent type='PERSON'>Frank Carlucci</ent> and Admiral <ent type='PERSON'>Bobby Ray Inman</ent> were <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent>
directors. <ent type='PERSON'>Cannan</ent> said: "Although Casey's law firm represented <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent>,
Casey himself never had any connection with us. <ent type='PERSON'>Carlucci</ent> was a director of
the firm -- he is no longer -- but <ent type='ORG'>Inman</ent> was not. We did have another
director with a similar background to <ent type='ORG'>Inman</ent>, an admiral who was chief of
naval operations, and that might have lead to the incorrect rumor."</p>

<p>The <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> Corp. is listed on <ent type='ORG'>the New York Stock Exchange</ent> (ticker symbol -
WAK) and is a conglomerate with subsidiaries throughout the world, including
<ent type='GPE'>Canada</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Liberia</ent>, El Salvador, <ent type='GPE'>Paraguay</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Costa Rica</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Australia</ent>, and Central
Europe. Its enterprises include the providing of <ent type='ORG'>sec</ent>urity and investigative
services to business, management of correctional facilities, nuclear material
auditing, training of <ent type='ORG'>sec</ent>urity and fire and crash rescue personnel, and the
sale of electronic <ent type='ORG'>sec</ent>urity systems. It also owns a casualty reinsurance
firm, a travel service and an airline services company.</p>

<p>(<ent type='PERSON'>Barbara</ent> E. McMullen &amp; John F. McMullen/19910924)</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>Journal</ent>: <ent type='ORG'>The New York</ent> Times Sept 3 1991 v140 pA17(N) pD12(L) 27 col in.
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Title: As U.S. battles computer company, writer takes vision of evil to
grave. (the <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> case)(<ent type='PERSON'><ent type='PERSON'>Danny</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Casolaro</ent></ent>)
Author: Ayres, B. Drummond, Jr.</p>

<p>Summary: The mysterious death of <ent type='PERSON'><ent type='PERSON'>Danny</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Casolaro</ent></ent>, a novelist and magazine
writer, generates attention to the long-running Justice <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent>
vs <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> Inc court case. <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent>, a small <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent> DC-based
software company, has accused Justice <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> officials of
fraud and theft. Officials allegedly schemed to steal Inslaw's
software that was developed for tracking the government's record
of criminal cases, and withheld payments on the pretext of
contract violations, thereby driving <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> to insolvency. The
Justice <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> denies the allegations. <ent type='PERSON'>Casolaro</ent>, who was
openly investigating the case, reportedly believed the <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> case
was part of a government-wide scandal involving Reagan
administration officials. Inslaw's lawyer, Elliot L. <ent type='PERSON'>Richard</ent>son,
has called for an investigation on Casolaro's death and the <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent>
case.
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Descriptors..
Company: INSLAW Inc. (Cases).
Topic: Court Cases
Software Publishers
Investigations
<ent type='GPE'>United</ent> States. <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> of Justice
Fraud.
Person: <ent type='PERSON'>Casolaro</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Joseph</ent> D. (Biography).</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>Journal</ent>: Newsbytes August 27 1991
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Title: <ent type='PERSON'>Casolaro</ent> source charges gov't procurement scandal. (<ent type='PERSON'>William</ent>
<ent type='PERSON'>Turner</ent>; <ent type='PERSON'>James</ent> D. <ent type='PERSON'>Casolaro</ent> died while investigating charges of
government involvement in <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> Inc.)
Author: McMullen, <ent type='PERSON'>Barbara</ent> E.; McMullen, John F.
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Descriptors..
Company: INSLAW Inc. (Cases).
Topic: Government Agency
Investigations
Legal Issues
Theft of Equipment
Software Publishers
<ent type='GPE'>United</ent> States. <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> of Justice
Court Cases.
Person: <ent type='PERSON'>Casolaro</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>James</ent> D. (Biography); <ent type='PERSON'>Turner</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>William</ent> (Investigations).</p>

<p>-----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Full Text:</p>

<p>****CASOLARO SOURCE CHARGES GOV'T PROCUREMENT SCANDAL 08/27/91 <ent type='GPE'>WASHINGTON</ent>,
D.C., U.S.A., 1991 AUG 27 (NB) -- "<ent type='PERSON'>Bill</ent>," the mysterious Newsbytes source who
met with investigative journalist <ent type='PERSON'>James</ent> D. "<ent type='PERSON'>Danny</ent>" <ent type='PERSON'>Casolaro</ent> on the night
before Casolaro's death in a <ent type='GPE'>Martinsburg</ent>, W. VA motel, has come forward on
the August 26th "Inside Edition" television show and discussed his meeting
with <ent type='PERSON'>Casolaro</ent>.</p>

<p>By coming forward, "<ent type='PERSON'>Bill</ent>" identified himself as <ent type='PERSON'>William</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Turner</ent>, a former
quality assurance manager for <ent type='ORG'>Hughes Aircraft</ent>. In Turner's previous
interviews with Newsbytes, he had requested anonymity because of both a
commitment to Inside Edition and what he said was the advice of counsel.
<ent type='PERSON'>Turner</ent> has alleged that <ent type='ORG'>Hughes Aircraft</ent>, with the assistance of U.S.
government personnel, has covered up the deliverance of systems for military
use that were below the procurement specifications.</p>

<p>While Turner's participation on the television broadcast dealt almost
exclusively with his meeting with <ent type='PERSON'>Casolaro</ent>, he told Newsbytes that he had
over three hours of discussion with the show's interviewers on all aspects of
his charges. <ent type='PERSON'>Casolaro</ent> has told Newsbytes that his attempts to call public
attention to what he calls a "procurement scandal" have resulted in his
harassment by the government. He claims that "all of a sudden <ent type='ORG'>the Veteran</ent>'s
Administration found that it had been overpaying my pension. Even after I
agreed with them on a schedule for me to make installment repayment of the
overage, I was sued for the entire amount."</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Turner</ent> also told Newsbytes that threats have been made against him
personally, resulting in his obtaining of police protection. He said that,
prior to the police protection, his house had been under obvious surveillance
from autos parked near his home. He said that his phone frequently rings
and, when he picks it up, there is an audible "hang-up" from the other end.
He also alleges that his telephone is "tapped" and that his conversations are
often interrupted by clicks and that conversations are terminated.</p>

<p>During his conversation with Newsbytes, at a point when he was discussing the
details of the alleged procurement scandal, a click similar to that of an
extension being picked up was clearly heard and our conversation was cut off.
When Newsbytes called back, <ent type='PERSON'>Turner</ent> said that the interruption had become an
"on-going thing" and that he was "sure that it related to his phone being
tapped."</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Turner</ent> said that he has had contact with ex-U.S. Attorney General Elliott
<ent type='PERSON'>Richard</ent>son's law firm, which is also representing <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> Inc., the firm whose
charges against the Justice Dept. has been a major subject of Casolaro's
investigation. According to <ent type='PERSON'>Turner</ent>, the law firm has advised him to refuse
to discuss the <ent type='PERSON'>Casolaro</ent> death with the <ent type='GPE'>Martinsburg</ent>, W. VA police who have
been trying to contact him. <ent type='PERSON'>Turner</ent>, who criticized the police investigation
of the death, said that he will discuss his meeting with <ent type='PERSON'>Casolaro</ent> with the
police when his attorneys are present.</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Turner</ent> told Newsbytes that on the day before <ent type='PERSON'>Casolaro</ent> was found dead of an
apparent suicide, he had met with him and turned over papers documenting his
charges about the <ent type='PERSON'>Hughes</ent> cover-up. He said that he was shown other material
that <ent type='PERSON'>Casolaro</ent> had received -- material that <ent type='PERSON'>Casolaro</ent> felt would substantiate
"Octopus" theory. (According to friends of <ent type='PERSON'>Casolaro</ent>, "octopus" referred to
his belief that there was a connection between the various cases, or
"tentacles," that he was investigating: <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent>, government procurement,
<ent type='GPE'>Iran</ent>Contra, "October Surprise.")</p>

<p>Reports from the <ent type='GPE'>Martinsburg</ent> death scene did not report the finding of papers
mentioned by <ent type='PERSON'>Turner</ent> and their absence has led to charges that <ent type='PERSON'>Casolaro</ent> met
with foul play. <ent type='PERSON'>Richard</ent>son has called for a federal investigation of the
death, as has Casolaro's brother, a <ent type='GPE'>Virginia</ent> physician.</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Turner</ent> also told Newsbytes that he has additional copies of the documentation
supporting his charges <ent type='ORG'>sec</ent>ure in a safe place and that the "truth will come
out even if something happens to me."</p>

<p>The so-called "<ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> Case" involves charges by <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent>, Inc. that the Justice
<ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> purposely drove it into bankruptcy so that it could steal Inslaw's
Promis software. While bankruptcy counts on two decisions found the
allegations to be factual and fined the Justice Dept., saying that the
government agency had practiced "trickery, fraud and deceit," the U.S. Court
of Appeals on May 7, 1991 overturned the award, saying that the courts had
overstepped their jurisdiction. The appeals court said, at the time, that
<ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> CEO <ent type='PERSON'>William</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Hamilton</ent> was free to pursue his claims in the proper
federal court and that the Justice Department's "conduct, if it occurred, is
inexcusable."</p>

<p>During the appeal process, <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> broadened its charges to claim that <ent type='GPE'>Iran</ent>
Contra figures <ent type='PERSON'>Robert</ent> McFarlane and <ent type='PERSON'>Richard</ent> Secord had played a role is
disseminating the software to intelligence agencies of <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Libya</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Iraq</ent>,
<ent type='GPE'>South Korea</ent>, and <ent type='GPE'>Canada</ent>. These charges, substantiated by Ari Ben-Menashe,
who claims to be a former <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent>i intelligence officer, <ent type='NORP'>Iranian</ent> arms dealer
<ent type='PERSON'>Richard</ent> Babayan, and <ent type='PERSON'>Michael Riconosciuto</ent>, who said that he was hired to
modify the software for use in law enforcement and intelligence agencies
worldwide, led to a investigation of the case by <ent type='ORG'>the House</ent> Judiciary
Committee and a confrontation between committee chairman <ent type='PERSON'>Jack Brooks</ent> and
Attorney General <ent type='PERSON'><ent type='PERSON'>Richard</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Thornburgh</ent></ent> over the release to the committee of
material relating to the case. The investigation continues at this time.</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Turner</ent> told Newsbytes that he has confidence in Casolaro's theory of a
connection between <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> and his charges concerning <ent type='PERSON'>Hughes</ent>.</p>

<p>(<ent type='PERSON'>Barbara</ent> E. McMullen &amp; John F. McMullen/19910827)</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>Journal</ent>: Newsbytes August 22 1991
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Title: <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> "source" speaks to Newsbytes.
Author: McMullen, <ent type='PERSON'>Barbara</ent> E.; McMullen, John F.
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Descriptors..
Company: INSLAW Inc. (Cases).
Topic: Court Cases
Government
Purchases
Software packages
Investigations.
Person: <ent type='PERSON'>Casolaro</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>James</ent> D. (Crimes against).</p>

<p>-----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Full Text:</p>

<p>INSLAW "SOURCE" SPEAKS TO <ent type='ORG'>NEWSBYTES</ent> 08/22/91 <ent type='GPE'>WASHINGTON</ent>, D.C., U.S.A., 1991
AUG 22 (NB) -- "<ent type='PERSON'>Bill</ent>," the person who reportedly met with journalist <ent type='PERSON'>James</ent> D.
"<ent type='PERSON'>Danny</ent>" <ent type='PERSON'>Casolaro</ent> on the night before Casolaro's death in a <ent type='GPE'>Martinsburg</ent>, W. VA
motel, has confirmed to Newsbytes that he provided <ent type='PERSON'>Casolaro</ent> with evidence of
U.S. government malfeasance in the procurement of technology.</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Bill</ent>, speaking to Newsbytes under the promise of anonymity, said that
<ent type='PERSON'>Casolaro</ent> found this information to be related to Casolaro's year-long
investigation of accusations made by the <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent>, Inc. against <ent type='ORG'>the United</ent>
States <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> of Justice. <ent type='PERSON'>Casolaro</ent> had told friends shortly before his
death that he had taken to calling the investigation the "Octopus" because of
connections that he had allegedly found between the <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> case and such
things as "<ent type='GPE'>Iran</ent>Contra," the "October Surprise," investigation and Bill's
charges.</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Bill</ent>, who is now scheduled to "go public" with his charges in an appearance
on the television show "Inside Edition" on Monday, August 26th, told
Newsbytes that he had promised the producers of the show that he would make
no statements to the media on these matters until Tuesday, August 27th. He
additionally said that he had discussed this commitment with <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent>, Inc.
attorney Elliot <ent type='PERSON'>Richard</ent>son who also advised him to make no public statements
until that date.</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Bill</ent> further told Newsbytes that the <ent type='GPE'>Martinsburg</ent> police investigators are
aware of his identity and have attempted to interrogate him concerning his
conversations with <ent type='PERSON'>Casolaro</ent>. He, to this date, has refused to meet with them
and stated that this decision was also made in consultation with <ent type='PERSON'>Richard</ent>son's
firm. He also told Newsbytes that he has reason to believe that he is under
surveillance, saying, "There are many more cars on my street than usual and I
am sure that my phone is tapped. I'm getting calls at all hours of the night
and, when I pick up the phone, the caller hangs up. They are not only
watching me but are trying to scare me off. They won't succeed, however; I
will get the truth out. I have copies of the documentation in a safe place
and it will come out even if something happens to me."</p>

<p>Another <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent>-related allegation came to light when a Newsbytes source said
that <ent type='PERSON'>Casolaro</ent> had told her/him that a person that was about to furnish him
with important documentation had been murdered last January 31st. According
to the source, <ent type='PERSON'>Casolaro</ent> had identified ex-<ent type='ORG'>National Security Agency</ent> (<ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent>)
employee <ent type='PERSON'>Alan David Standoff</ent>, found at <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent> National Airport in a car,
as a contact tied to the case. According to investigators, <ent type='ORG'>Standoff</ent> had been
murdered by beating with a blunt instrument at some other location and then
transported to the airport. He, according to the Newsbytes source, had
resigned from the <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent> on December 19th (effective 01/14/91) because of his
call-up by his <ent type='ORG'>National Guard</ent> unit.</p>

<p>Casolaro's death, initially ruled a suicide, has been referred to as possibly
a murder by friends and relatives as well as by <ent type='PERSON'>Richard</ent>son who has called for
a federal inquiry. The so-called "<ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> Case" involves charges by <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent>,
Inc., that the Justice <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> purposely drove it into bankruptcy so that
it could steal Inslaw's Promis software. While bankruptcy counts on two
decisions found the allegations to be factual and fined the Justice Dept.,
saying that the government agency had practiced "trickery, fraud and deceit."
The U.S. Court of Appeals on May 7, 1991 overturned the award, saying that
the courts had overstepped their jurisdiction. The appeals court said, at
the time, that <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> CEO <ent type='PERSON'>William</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Hamilton</ent> was free to pursue his claims in
the proper federal court and that the Justice Department's "conduct, if it
occurred, is inexcusable."</p>

<p>During the appeal process, <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> broadened its charges to claim that <ent type='GPE'>Iran</ent>
Contra figures <ent type='PERSON'>Robert</ent> McFarlane and <ent type='PERSON'>Richard</ent> Secord had played a role is
disseminating the software to intelligence agencies of <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Libya</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Iraq</ent>,
<ent type='GPE'>South Korea</ent>, and <ent type='GPE'>Canada</ent>. These charges, substantiated by Ari Ben-Menashe,
who claims to be a former <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent>i intelligence officer, <ent type='NORP'>Iranian</ent> arms dealer
<ent type='PERSON'>Richard</ent> Babayan, and <ent type='PERSON'>Michael Riconosciuto</ent>, who said that he was hired to
modify the software for use in law enforcement and intelligence agencies
worldwide, led to a investigation of the case by <ent type='ORG'>the House</ent> Judiciary
Committee and a confrontation between committee chairman <ent type='PERSON'>Jack Brooks</ent> and
Attorney General <ent type='PERSON'><ent type='PERSON'>Richard</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Thornburgh</ent></ent> over the release to the committee of
material relating to the case. The investigation continues at this time.</p>

<p>(<ent type='PERSON'>Barbara</ent> E. McMullen &amp; John F. McMullen/1991082)</p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>Journal</ent>: Newsbytes August 19 1991
----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Title: <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> death investigation continues. (death of reporter <ent type='PERSON'>Joseph</ent> D.
<ent type='PERSON'>Casolaro</ent> investigating <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> Inc.'s suit against government)
Author: McMullen, <ent type='PERSON'>Barbara</ent> E.; McMullen, John F.
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Descriptors..
Company: INSLAW Inc. (Cases).
Product: Promis (Office automation software) (Cases).
Topic: Government Agency
Investigations
<ent type='GPE'>United</ent> States. <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> of Justice.
Person: <ent type='PERSON'>Casolaro</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Joseph</ent> D. (Biography).</p>

<p>-----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Full Text:</p>

<p>****INSLAW DEATH INVESTIGATION CONTINUES 08/19/91 MARTINSBURG, <ent type='GPE'>WEST VIRGINIA</ent>,
U.S.A., AUG 19 (NB) -- The <ent type='ORG'>Sheraton</ent> Inn in <ent type='GPE'>Martinsburg</ent>, West <ent type='GPE'>Virginia</ent>, the
scene of the death of <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, D.C. journalist <ent type='PERSON'>Joseph</ent> D. "<ent type='PERSON'>Danny</ent>"
<ent type='PERSON'>Casolaro</ent>, has received more press attention than ever before in its history
as reporters from <ent type='ORG'>ABC</ent>-TV, Newsbytes News Network, and the <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Post</ent>
roamed the halls interrogating bell-hops, waitresses, and desk clerks for
information regarding the death of <ent type='PERSON'>Casolaro</ent>.</p>

<p>Employees, supposedly under the cloak of <ent type='ORG'>Sheraton</ent>-forced silence, told
Newsbytes that, while some prospective guests have specifically requested the
room in which <ent type='PERSON'>Casolaro</ent> died, their instructions have been to leave the room
vacant for an unspecified time.</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Casolaro</ent>, 44, had been investigating the "<ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent>" case, a rather tangled web
of allegations relating to the charges brought by <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> Inc., that the
Justice <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> had first stolen its software product, "Promis," and then
driven the firm into bankruptcy. <ent type='PERSON'>Casolaro</ent> had told friends and family that
he was about to receive material that would provide him with documentation
linking <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> to other alleged incidents of Reagan-<ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent> administration
wrong-doing. <ent type='PERSON'>Casolaro</ent> was said to have referred to the alleged conspiracy as
the "Octopus" and stated that there were links between the <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> theft, the
"October Surprise," and <ent type='GPE'>Iran</ent>-Contra allegations.</p>

<p>The "October surprise" refers to allegations that representatives of the
Reagan-<ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent> campaign team, through meetings with <ent type='NORP'>Iranian</ent> representatives,
delayed the release of the hostages in <ent type='GPE'>Iran</ent> until after the 1980 elections.
These charges are currently being investigated by <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>ional committee.</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Casolaro</ent> was found dead, an apparent suicide, in Room 517 of the <ent type='ORG'>Sheraton</ent> on
Saturday, August 10th, two days after his arrival in <ent type='GPE'>Martinsburg</ent>. He was
found in the bathtub at approximately 1:00 pm with both wrists slashed. His
body was released within three hours to a local funeral parlor for embalming,
an action that <ent type='GPE'>Berkeley County</ent> Medical Examiner <ent type='PERSON'>Sandra Brining</ent> was quoted as
saying was normal in the case of a suicide. "Everything was consistent with
a self-inflicted wound."</p>

<p>When Casolaro's family became aware of his death on Monday, August 14th, it
immediately called for an expanded investigation and his brother, Dr. Anthony
<ent type='PERSON'>Casolaro</ent>, an <ent type='GPE'>Arlington</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Virginia</ent> physician, was quoted as saying, "In my
heart I remember <ent type='PERSON'>Danny</ent> telling us that in case of an accident, don't believe
it." Dr. <ent type='PERSON'>Casolaro</ent> also discounted statements made by his brother in a letter
to a publisher in which he seemed financially strapped and despondent. Dr.
<ent type='PERSON'>Casolaro</ent> attributed Casolaro's remarks to a desire to convince the would-be
publisher of the importance of extending a book contract to him. <ent type='PERSON'>Casolaro</ent>
had been immersed in the <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> case for over a year and had been
unsuccessful in two proposals to the publishing firm of Little, Brown &amp; Co.</p>

<p>The clamor for a fuller investigation caused an autopsy to be subsequently
performed on <ent type='PERSON'>Casolaro</ent>, an action that Assistant <ent type='GPE'>Berkeley County</ent> pro<ent type='ORG'>sec</ent>utor
<ent type='PERSON'>Cynthia Gaither</ent> said was not hindered by the previous embalming.</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Casolaro</ent> was buried on Friday, October 16th after a funeral service at St.
Ann's Catholic Church in <ent type='GPE'>Arlington</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Virginia</ent> attended by over 100 people.</p>

<p>At a press conference held on Thursday, August 15th, Dr. <ent type='PERSON'>James</ent> Frost,
assistant West <ent type='GPE'>Virginia</ent> medical <ent type='ORG'>examiner</ent>, said that, while the results of the
examination bore out the preliminary findings of suicide, the investigation
would be continued. Brining and <ent type='PERSON'>Gaither</ent> also participated in the hour-long
press conference held in the meeting room of the <ent type='GPE'>Martinsburg</ent> City Council.</p>

<p>Newsbytes has obtained conflicting reports on the state of Casolaro's mental
condition. A <ent type='GPE'>California</ent> free-lance journalist, <ent type='GPE'>Virginia</ent> McCullough, with
whom <ent type='PERSON'>Casolaro</ent> had allegedly shared information, told Newsbytes, "It is
ludicrous to think that <ent type='PERSON'>Danny</ent> took his life. He was excited about his new
contact and said that 'For the first time I really believe that the
government was involved.'" McCullough, herself, claims to be the victim of a
government action that drove her electronics firm into bankruptcy and she is
presently writing a book on her case and other similar cases, including
<ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent>.</p>

<p>McCullough's comments on the unlikelihood of a <ent type='PERSON'>Casolaro</ent> suicide were echoed
in quotes from <ent type='PERSON'>Pat Clawson</ent>, president of <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>-based Metrowest
Broadcasting Co., and <ent type='PERSON'>Richard</ent> O'Connell, editor of the <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent> Crime News,
a newsletter published in <ent type='GPE'>Arlington</ent>, VA. <ent type='PERSON'>Nancy</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Hamilton</ent>, vice president of
<ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent>, also took issue with the suicide finding telling the <ent type='GPE'>Martinsburg</ent>
Morning <ent type='ORG'>Journal</ent>, "We don't accept that. They are saying that here is a man,
totally sober, mutilating himself."</p>

<p><ent type='GPE'>Martinsburg</ent> residents interviewed by Newsbytes paint a slightly different
picture and depict <ent type='PERSON'>Casolaro</ent> as seemingly depressed and drinking pitchers of
beer by himself in a local <ent type='ORG'>Pizza Hut</ent> on the Thursday evening before his death
(although a wine bottle was found in his room, there was no evidence of
alcohol found in the body by the autopsy). Additionally, a <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Post</ent>
piece of Saturday, August 17th by <ent type='PERSON'>Gary Lee</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Robert</ent> O'Harrow, Jr., shows
<ent type='PERSON'>Casolaro</ent> to be debt-ridden and despondent. According to the <ent type='ORG'>Post</ent> report,
"<ent type='PERSON'>Casolaro</ent> had no independent means of income and had invested heavily in the
book project for at least eight months, financing several trips to the West
Coast and long-distance telephone calls."</p>

<p>The <ent type='ORG'>Post</ent> article also revealed that Casolaro's sister had committed suicide
in <ent type='GPE'>California</ent> 20 years ago. While confirming the sister's suicide and his
brother's financial difficulties, Dr. <ent type='PERSON'>Casolaro</ent> said that these facts still
did not support a conclusion of suicide for his brother. He told the <ent type='ORG'>Post</ent>,
"<ent type='PERSON'>Danny</ent> was the sort of guy who was always broke but he knew that he had a lot
of resources for money in the family if he needed it."</p>

<p>Dr. <ent type='PERSON'>Casolaro</ent> also told the <ent type='ORG'>Post</ent> that he had received a call from a man who
purported to have met with <ent type='PERSON'>Casolaro</ent> in <ent type='GPE'>Martinsburg</ent> on the day before the
death and turned over documents relating to computer hardware thefts. Dr.
<ent type='PERSON'>Casolaro</ent> said that the man was willing to meet with investigators under the
cloak of anonymity. Newsbytes has confirmed, from multiple sources, the
existence of the contact, a man called "<ent type='PERSON'>Bill</ent>," but has not yet obtained
information concerning the content or the validity of the purported
documentation.</p>

<p>The so-called "<ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> Case" began in 1982 when <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> signed a $10 million
contract to provide an enhanced version of its case tracking software to the
U.S. <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> of Justice. According to <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent>, shortly after it rebuffed
attempts by a company owned by <ent type='PERSON'>Earl Brian</ent>, a close friend of former US.
Attorney General <ent type='PERSON'>Edwin Meese</ent>, to buy <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent>, the government stopped its
contract payments and eventually forced the firm into bankruptcy. In January
1988, a federal bankruptcy judge upheld the claims of <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> President
<ent type='PERSON'>William</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Hamilton</ent> and awarded <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> damages of $6.8 million, saying that the
Justice <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> has stolen the Promis software by "trickery, fraud and
deceit." A <ent type='ORG'>sec</ent>ond federal judge later upheld the ruling.</p>

<p>The Justice Dept. continued to appeal the verdicts and, on May 7, 1991, was
successful when the U.S. Court of Appeals ruled that the bankruptcy court
had claimed extraordinary and improper jurisdiction in the case. The court
said that <ent type='PERSON'>Hamilton</ent> was free to pursue his claims in the proper federal court
and that the Justice Department's "conduct, if it occurred, is inexcusable."</p>

<p>During the appeal process, <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> broadened its charges to claim that <ent type='GPE'>Iran</ent>
Contra figures <ent type='PERSON'>Robert</ent> McFarlane and <ent type='PERSON'>Richard</ent> Secord had played a role is
disseminating the software to intelligence agencies of <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Libya</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Iraq</ent>,
<ent type='GPE'>South Korea</ent>, and <ent type='GPE'>Canada</ent>. These charges were substantiated by Ari
Ben-Menashe, who claims to be a former <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent>i intelligence officer, <ent type='NORP'>Iranian</ent>
arms dealer <ent type='PERSON'>Richard</ent> Babayan, and <ent type='PERSON'>Michael Riconosciuto</ent>, who said that he was
hired to modify the software for use in law enforcement and intelligence
agencies worldwide.</p>

<p>Riconosciuto, who was arrested in March of this year and is being held in the
state of <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, also claimed to be involved in a now-defunct joint
venture between <ent type='ORG'>the Wachenhut Corp</ent>. of <ent type='ORG'>Coral Gables</ent>, FL and the <ent type='NORP'>Southern</ent>
<ent type='GPE'>California</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Cabazon</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Indian</ent> tribe. According to Riconosciuto's affidavit, the
joint venture developed sophisticated weapons for the <ent type='NORP'>Contras</ent>. McFarlane and
<ent type='PERSON'>Brian</ent> have denied all charges.</p>

<p>There have also been reports that the software, allegedly used by the foreign
intelligence services for maintaining dissidents, contained a "Trojan horse"
that would allow U.S. <ent type='ORG'>sec</ent>urity agencies to have undetected access to the
computer system of the foreign agency. It was also revealed during this time
that <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> President <ent type='PERSON'>Hamilton</ent> is a former employee of the National Security
Agency (<ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent>).</p>

<p>As the long appeal process continued, <ent type='ORG'>the House</ent> Judiciary Committee under
Chairman <ent type='PERSON'>Jack Brooks</ent> (D-Tex.) began its own investigation of the case and
became embroiled in a year-long battle with then Attorney General <ent type='PERSON'>Richard</ent>
<ent type='PERSON'>Thornburgh</ent> who refused to turn over Justice <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> documents to the
committee. Shortly before Thornburgh's departure to run for the Senate from
<ent type='GPE'>Pennsylvania</ent>, an agreement was reached between the committee and the Justice
<ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> on the release of certain documents and the investigation is now
continuing. During the controversy, another former U.S. Attorney General,
Elliot <ent type='PERSON'>Richard</ent>son, now serving as counsel for <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent>, said, "Evidence of the
widespread ramifications of the <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> case comes from many sources and keeps
accumulating. It remains inexplicable why the Justice <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> refuses to
pursue this evidence and resists cooperation with the Judiciary Committee of
<ent type='ORG'>the House</ent> of Representatives."</p>

<p>On Wednesday, August 14th, <ent type='PERSON'>Richard</ent>son called for a federal investigation of
Casolaro's death and was quoted as suspecting murder in the case.</p>

<p>In an interview with Newsbytes, an investigative reporter who has been
tracking <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> and related cases for a few years said that he had met with
<ent type='PERSON'>Casolaro</ent> within the last six months and that <ent type='PERSON'>Casolaro</ent> had no material at that
time that the investigative reporter deemed as new. The reporter, speaking
to Newsbytes under the promise of non-attribution, also said, "I believe that
the Justice <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> stole Inslaw's software. I have not seen, however,
compelling evidence to support the charges that it was linked to the
so-called 'October Surprise.'"</p>

<p>(<ent type='PERSON'>Barbara</ent> E. McMullen &amp; John F. McMullen/19910819)</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>Journal</ent>: Computergram International August 16 1991 n1742
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Title: Minigrams.
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Descriptors..</p>

<p>-----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Full Text:</p>

<p>Remember the InsLaw Inc case - well it looks set to blow up into a high
profile and potentially far-reaching scandal: InsLaw is a tiny <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent> DC
company that was awarded a $10m contract with the US Justice <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> for
software designed to make it easier for the police and the authorities to
track cases and keep tabs on dissidents, and in 1983, it sued Justice
claiming that theer ain't no such thing and that <ent type='ORG'>the Department</ent> had stolen
its software; a <ent type='ORG'>House</ent> of Representatives judiciary subcommittee is still
investigating the case, but meantime <ent type='PERSON'>Joseph</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Casolaro</ent>, an investigative
reporter of <ent type='GPE'>Fairfax</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Virginia</ent> who had been working for a year researching a
book on the InsLaw case, was found in a hotel bathtub with both wrists
slashed; a suicide note was found nearby, but an autopsy has been ordered
after suspicions were aroused that the death was a murder disguised to look
like suicide after the family told police he had no reason to kill himself.</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>Journal</ent>: Newsbytes August 15 1991
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Title: "Suicide" of <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> reporter questioned. (<ent type='PERSON'>Joseph</ent> D. '<ent type='PERSON'>Danny</ent>'
<ent type='PERSON'>Casolaro</ent> may have been murdered during investigation of <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent>
suit against U.S. Justice Dept.)
Author: McMullen, <ent type='PERSON'>Barbara</ent> E.; McMullen, John F.
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Descriptors..
Company: INSLAW Inc. (Cases).
Topic: Legal Issues
Law Suit
<ent type='GPE'>United</ent> States. <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> of Justice
Investigations
Computer Crimes.
Person: <ent type='PERSON'>Casolaro</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Joseph</ent> D. (Investigations).</p>

<p>-----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Full Text:</p>

<p>"SUICIDE" OF INSLAW REPORTER QUESTIONED 08/15/91 <ent type='ORG'>SUNOL</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>CALIFORNIA</ent>, U.S.A.,
1991 AUG 15 (NB) -- The verdict of suicide in the death of reporter <ent type='PERSON'>Joseph</ent> D.
"<ent type='PERSON'>Danny</ent>" <ent type='PERSON'>Casolaro</ent> on Saturday, August 10th has been challenged by friends and
relatives.</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Casolaro</ent>, 44, of <ent type='GPE'>Fairfax</ent>, Va., had been, according to reports, involved in an
investigation of the allegations surrounding government activities in the
<ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> software case.</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Casolaro</ent> was, according to reports, found dead in the bathtub of his
<ent type='GPE'>Martinsburg</ent>, West <ent type='GPE'>Virginia</ent> hotel room Saturday with his wrists cut. Dr.
<ent type='PERSON'>James</ent> Frost, an assistant state medical <ent type='ORG'>examiner</ent> was quoted as saying: "The
wounds are consistent with being self-inflicted, but that doesn't mean that
someone else couldn't have done this if he were not able to defend himself."</p>

<p><ent type='GPE'>Virginia</ent> McCullough, a freelance journalist and friend of <ent type='PERSON'>Casolaro</ent>, told
Newsbytes that <ent type='PERSON'>Casolaro</ent> was working for over a year on a book concerning the
allegations by <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> president <ent type='PERSON'>William</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Hamilton</ent> that the Justice <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent>
first broke a $10 million contract with his firm, then stole the firm's
software and subsequently sold and donated it to foreign intelligence
agencies.</p>

<p>McCullough said: "It is ludicrous to think that <ent type='PERSON'>Danny</ent> would kill himself. He
had recently told me that he was looking forward to a trip that would give
him the documentation to prove the Justice Department's involvement. He
said: 'For the first time, I've become a real believer that the government
was involved in these things.'"</p>

<p>McCullough went on to say that <ent type='PERSON'>Casolaro</ent> was never depressed in his
conversations with her and that they often spoke, sharing information in
relation to the case. McCullough, herself involved with a company that she
says had very similar experiences to <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent>, is currently writing a book
detailing what she says have been questionable acts by government agencies in
the use of bankruptcy proceedings to stifle the development of technology.</p>

<p>Casolaro's brother, Dr. M. Anthony <ent type='PERSON'>Casolaro</ent>, was quoted by news services as
also doubting the suicide reports. He said that police told him a
handwritten note saying: "I'm sorry, especially to my son," was found at the
scene.</p>

<p>The <ent type='ORG'>House</ent> Judiciary Committee is presently investigating the <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> charges
and had announced in April of this year that the Justice <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent>, after
long delays, has agreed to turn over documentation relating to the case.</p>

<p>The case began in 1985 when <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> filed for bankruptcy claiming that the
Justice Dept. had stopped payment on a 1982 contract for the installation of
Inslaw's legal case management software, "Promis" into 97 U.S. Attorney's
offices. <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> claimed that the government contract represented 70 percent
of Inslaw's income and that the government action forced it into bankruptcy.</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> was successful and a bankruptcy judge found that the department "took,
converted and stole" the company's property "by trickery, fraud and deceit"
and further said that the government's conduct demonstrated "bad faith,
vexatiousness, wantonness and oppressiveness."</p>

<p>The Justice <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> appealed the ruling and, in 1989, U.S. <ent type='ORG'>District Court</ent>
Judge <ent type='PERSON'>William</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Bryant</ent> upheld the decision and ordered the government to pay
<ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> $8 million plus attorney's fees.</p>

<p>The Justice <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> continued to appeal the case and, on May 7, 1991, was
successful when the U.S. Court of Appeals for <ent type='ORG'>the District</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>Columbia</ent>
reversed the bankruptcy rulings saying that the bankruptcy court's rulings
were too broad and inappropriate for a bankruptcy ruling.</p>

<p>The court said that, while <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> is entitled to go to another court to press
its claim,. the U.S. <ent type='ORG'>Bankruptcy Court</ent> lacked jurisdiction. Commenting on
Inslaw's allegations of misbehavior, the court said: "Such conduct, if it
occurred, is inexcusable."</p>

<p>During the appeals, stories of illegal sales of the allegedly stolen software
to foreign governments including <ent type='GPE'>Iraq</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Libya</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>South Korea</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Canada</ent>,
and involvement of Reagan <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>California</ent> appointees <ent type='PERSON'>Earl Brian</ent>,
<ent type='PERSON'>Robert</ent> McFarlane and <ent type='PERSON'>Richard</ent> Secord in the transactions have caused <ent type='ORG'>the House</ent>
Judiciary Committee to seek involvement -- an involvement that the Justice
<ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> has resisted.</p>

<p>Elliot <ent type='PERSON'>Richard</ent>son, former <ent type='GPE'>United</ent> States Attorney General who now represents
<ent type='PERSON'>Hamilton</ent>, was quoted during the appeal process as saying: "Evidence of the
widespread ramifications of the <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> case comes from many sources and keeps
accumulating."</p>

<p>"It remains inexplicable why the Justice <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> consistently refuses to
pursue this evidence and resists co-operation with the Judiciary Committee of
<ent type='ORG'>the House</ent> of Representatives," he added.</p>

<p>The case took still another turn when witness Ari Ben-Menashe reportedly
testified that the owner of <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>William</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Hamilton</ent>, is a former employee of
the <ent type='ORG'>National Security Agency</ent> (<ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent>) and that the software was modified into a
"Trojan Horse" in order to allow the <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent> and the <ent type='ORG'>Mossad</ent> to listen in on the
transactions of other intelligence services.</p>

<p>The attraction of the case management software to these intelligence agencies
was, according to witnesses, that, rather than its intended use of tracking
case witnesses and legal opinions, it lent itself to the tracking of
dissidents and foreign agents.</p>

<p>(<ent type='PERSON'>Barbara</ent> E. McMullen &amp; John F. McMullen/19910815)</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>Journal</ent>: Government Computer News August 5 1991 v10 n16 p1(2)
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Title: <ent type='PERSON'>Thornburgh</ent> bows on <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> papers. (Attorney General <ent type='PERSON'>Richard</ent>
<ent type='PERSON'>Thornburgh</ent> turns over to <ent type='ORG'>House</ent> Judiciary Committee documents on
the Justice Department's dealings with <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> Inc.)
Author: <ent type='ORG'>Seaborn</ent>, Margaret M.</p>

<p>Summary: Attorney General <ent type='PERSON'><ent type='PERSON'>Richard</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Thornburgh</ent></ent> submitted to <ent type='ORG'>the House</ent>
Judiciary most of the 456 subpoenaed documents concerning the
Justice Department's dealings with <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> Inc, a software
publisher. <ent type='PERSON'>Thornburgh</ent> had been threatened with a
contempt-of-<ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent> charge if he did not turn over the documents.
<ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> and the Justice <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> have been locked in lawsuits
over Inslaw's case management software, Promis. Justice has been
accused of stealing later versions of the software and attempting
to force the company into bankruptcy. The <ent type='ORG'>House</ent> committee,
chaired by <ent type='PERSON'>Rep John Brooks</ent>, has been investigating the case for
two years but <ent type='ORG'>Brooks</ent> said that <ent type='PERSON'>Thornburgh</ent> has stalled its progress
by withholding documents. Justice officials have declared 51
documents lost but have reconstructed most of them.
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Descriptors..
Company: INSLAW Inc. (Cases).
Product: Promis (Office automation software) (Cases).
Topic: <ent type='GPE'>United</ent> States. <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> of Justice
<ent type='GPE'>United</ent> States. <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>. <ent type='ORG'>House</ent>
Software Piracy
Court Cases
Investigations.
Person: <ent type='PERSON'>Thornburgh</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Richard</ent> L. (Cases).</p>

<p>-----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Full Text:</p>

<p>Threatened with a contempt-of-<ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent> charge, Attorney General <ent type='PERSON'>Richard</ent>
<ent type='PERSON'>Thornburgh</ent> last week turned over to <ent type='ORG'>House</ent> investigators several hundred
subpoenaed documents concerning the Justice Department's dealings with <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent>
Inc.</p>

<p>Last Tuesday night, <ent type='PERSON'>Thornburgh</ent> handed over most but not all of the 456
documents. Rep. <ent type='PERSON'>Jack Brooks</ent> (D-<ent type='GPE'>Texas</ent>), chairman of <ent type='ORG'>the House</ent> Judiciary
Committee, had warned that if the department failed to hand over the
documents by Wednesday, he would ask <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent> to act to hold <ent type='PERSON'>Thornburgh</ent> in
contempt.</p>

<p>After the partial delivery, <ent type='ORG'>Brooks</ent> said the contempt proceedings were "merely
suspended." He said he expects <ent type='PERSON'>Thornburgh</ent> to turn over the remaining
documents by Sept. 11, when <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent> reconvenes after its summer holiday.</p>

<p>The missing documents are from one file of the chief litigating attorney in
the <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> case. Justice officials have been telling the committee since May
that the department had misplaced 51 of that attorney's documents.</p>

<p>Justice reconstructed most of these documents, but at least 12 still are
missing, <ent type='ORG'>Brooks</ent> said, adding that the committee has not been able to assess
the thoroughness of the reconstructed material. Also, <ent type='ORG'>Brooks</ent> said, at least
another 40 documents submitted last week are incomplete.</p>

<p>Justice said in a letter that it had searched "meticulously" for the missing
documents. <ent type='ORG'>Brooks</ent> said the department has been unable to explain to the
committee how the records were misplaced.</p>

<p>"By the department's own admission, these documents are highly sensitive. I
hope they are not lost somewhere," he said last week. "I remain concerned
that no action has been taken [by the department] to investigate the
possibility that this material was destroyed, stolen or shredded in order to
obstruct the committee's investigation."</p>

<p>For the past several years, Justice and <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent>, a small <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent> software
company, have been battling in courts over the company's case management
software, Promis. <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> first provided its software to Justice through a
1982 contract.</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>Brooks</ent>' committee has been investigating allegations that Justice stole later
versions of the software and tried to force the company into bankruptcy. But
<ent type='ORG'>Brooks</ent> said <ent type='PERSON'>Thornburgh</ent> has stalled Judiciary's two-year investigation by
denying committee investigators access to documents.</p>

<p>Finally, late last month, the Judiciary Subcommittee on Economic and
Commercial Law voted 10 to 6 to subpoena the <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> files from <ent type='PERSON'>Thornburgh</ent>.</p>

<p>Although the department had promised repeatedly to supply the missing
documents, <ent type='ORG'>Brooks</ent> said, the subpoena was necessary because Justice had
reneged at least three times.</p>

<p>"At this rate, the investigation could drag on for another two years," <ent type='ORG'>Brooks</ent>
said. "I simply cannot permit legitimate oversight to be forestalled by
dilatory or evasive steps."</p>

<p>To hold <ent type='PERSON'>Thornburgh</ent> in contempt of <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Brooks</ent> would have to gain the
votes of a majority of the full <ent type='ORG'>House</ent>. If <ent type='ORG'>the House</ent> were to approve such a
charge, theoretically the sergeant-at-arms would be empowered to arrest the
attorney general and hold him in a one-room cell in the Capitol.</p>

<p>Justice officials tried to avoid the subpoena by making an 11th-hour promise
last month to provide the documents. <ent type='ORG'>Brooks</ent> said <ent type='PERSON'>Thornburgh</ent> had assured him
on six occasions that the department would cooperate. But <ent type='ORG'>Brooks</ent> said he no
longer would accept such assurances, and the subcommittee went ahead with the
subpoena.</p>

<p>The Judiciary Committee's relationship with <ent type='PERSON'>Thornburgh</ent> has grown increasingly
testly during the past few weeks, culminating with the <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> subpoena.</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Thornburgh</ent> refused to appear at an earlier committee hearing concerning
Justice's 1992 budget request [<ent type='ORG'>GCN</ent>, July 22]. <ent type='ORG'>Brooks</ent> has said the committee
may cut finding for several Justice programs, including its massive Project
<ent type='ORG'>Eagle</ent> office automation initiative, if that is what is necessary to get the
department's attention.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, the U.S. Court of Appeals for <ent type='ORG'>the District</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>Columbia</ent> has denied
Inslaw's petition for a rehearing by the 11-judge bench.</p>

<p>An appeals court panel in May ruled that the U.S. <ent type='ORG'>Bankruptcy Court</ent> did not
have jurisdiction in 1988 when it concluded that Justice attempted to drive
<ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> out of business.</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Nancy</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Hamilton</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> vice president, said the company plans to petition the
<ent type='ORG'>Supreme Court</ent> to hear its case.</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>Journal</ent>: Computerworld July 29 1991 v25 n30 p12(1).
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Title: <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> papers subpoenaed. (Judiciary Committee of the U.S. <ent type='ORG'>House</ent>
of Representatives issues subpoena to access records thought to be
important in case between <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> Inc. and the U.S. <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> of
Justice)
Author: Anthes, Gary H.</p>

<p>Summary: The US <ent type='ORG'>House</ent> of Representatives Judiciary Committee issued a
subpoena to the US Justice <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> to turn over records thought
to be relevant to the on-going dispute initiated in 1983 between
the Justice <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> Inc. The Judiciary Committee is
investigating charges that the US Justice <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> stole
software and tried to force <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> out of business. The subpoena
asked Attorney General <ent type='PERSON'><ent type='PERSON'>Richard</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Thornburgh</ent></ent> to release 456 documents
thought to be connected to the case. <ent type='PERSON'>Thornburgh</ent> has promised to
release the documents on several occasions, but he has not done
so. The Justice <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> now claims that several of the
requested documents are missing, and no explanation has been
offered to explain their absence.
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Descriptors..
Company: INSLAW Inc. (Cases).
Topic: Legal Issues
<ent type='GPE'>United</ent> States. <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> of Justice
<ent type='GPE'>United</ent> States. <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>. <ent type='ORG'>House</ent>. Committee on the Judiciary
Law Suit
Bankruptcy
Government Agency
Investigations.</p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>Journal</ent>: Government Computer News July 22 1991 v10 n15 p76(1)
----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Title: <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> asks court to reinstate $6M judgement against Justice.
(<ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> Inc., U.S. Court of Appeals for <ent type='ORG'>the District</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>Columbia</ent>,
<ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> of Justice)
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Descriptors..
Company: INSLAW Inc. (Cases).
Topic: <ent type='GPE'>United</ent> States. <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> of Justice
<ent type='GPE'>United</ent> States. Court of Appeals for <ent type='ORG'>the District</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>Columbia</ent>
Circuit
Court Cases
Bankruptcy.</p>

<p>-----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Full Text:</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> Inc. has asked the 11-judge bench of the U.S. Court of Appeals for
<ent type='ORG'>the District</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>Columbia</ent> to reinstate a lower court's decision to award
<ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> $6 million in damages from the Justice <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent>.</p>

<p>For several years, the small <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent> software company has alleged that
following a dispute over a 1982 contract, Justice officials tried to force
<ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> into bankruptcy and to steal enhanced versions of the company's case
management software, Promis.</p>

<p>In 1987, the U.S. <ent type='ORG'>Bankruptcy Court</ent> substantially upheld these arguments.
The U.S. <ent type='ORG'>District Court</ent> in <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent> then affirmed the bankruptcy court's
ruling and awarded <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> more than $6 million in damages, which Justice
never paid.</p>

<p>An appeals court panel in May said the bankruptcy court had no jurisdiction
to rule that Justice used "trickery, fraud and deceit" to drive <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> out of
business.</p>

<p>Inslaw's petition for reconsideration said the appeals court decision
"rejects the well-accepted authority of a bankruptcy court to hear actions
that directly affect the administration of a bankruptcy estate."</p>

<p>In reversing the ruling, the appeals court said it was not ruling on the
validity of Inslaw's allegations and suggested the company file its
complaints anew in a court other than bankruptcy court.</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>Journal</ent>: PC Week June 10 1991 v8 n23 p130(1)
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Title: The verdict on <ent type='PERSON'>Cal</ent>? he's 'a nice fellow,' but the jury's still
out. (<ent type='ORG'>Rumor Central</ent>) (column)
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Descriptors..</p>

<p>-----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Text:</p>

<p>As the Furry One maneuvered his <ent type='PERSON'>Winnebago</ent> into a rest area off I-95, <ent type='PERSON'>Cal</ent>
pulled out a copy of In These Times, which last month told of alleged
injustices by the U.S. Justice <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent>. As the story goes, the <ent type='ORG'>Feds</ent>
asked a company called <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> to develop a case-tracking database called
Promis, which <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> then developed. The <ent type='ORG'>Feds</ent> rejected the package on
technical grounds --but then used it anyway, selling it to several foreign
nations without cutting the vendor in on the profits.</p>

<p>"I don't believe a word of it," <ent type='PERSON'>Spencer</ent> harrumphed. "It's a matter of public
record. Look it up," responded <ent type='PERSON'>Cal</ent>.</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>Journal</ent>: Government Computer News May 13 1991 v10 n10 p3(2)
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Title: Appeals Court tosses finding that Justice stole from <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent>.
(<ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> of Justice)
Author: <ent type='ORG'>Seaborn</ent>, Margaret M.</p>

<p>Summary: A federal appeals court has dismissed the ruling of a lower court
that <ent type='ORG'>the Department</ent> of Justice stole case management software from
<ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> Inc. <ent type='ORG'>The District</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>Columbia</ent> US Court of Appeals ruled
that the federal <ent type='ORG'>Bankruptcy Court</ent> overstepped its jurisdiction in
1987 when it ruled that the Justice <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> used fraud,
trickery and deceit to force the <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>-based software company
out of business. The US District court affirmed the bankruptcy
ruling and awarded <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> a $6 million judgement which the Justice
<ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> never paid. The appeals court suggested that <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent>
start over in the federal court system after five years of legal
actions stemming from a contract awarded by Justice to <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> for
the development of case management software. The court's decision
said the Justice <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> was brought into the Bankruptcy court
because <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> filed for bankruptcy and the company succeeded in
convincing the court to adjudicate the contract, though the court
had no jurisdiction to do so. The court did not rule on the
validity of the charges and criticized the bankruptcy court for
its ruling.
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Descriptors..
Company: INSLAW Inc. (Cases).
Topic: <ent type='GPE'>United</ent> States. <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> of Justice
Legal Applications
Software Packages
Bankruptcy
Court Cases
Legal Issues
Copyright
National Government.</p>

<p>-----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Full Text:</p>

<p>A federal appeals court last week threw out a lower court's findings that the
Justice <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> had stolen case management software from <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> Inc.</p>

<p>The U.S. Court of Appeals for <ent type='ORG'>the District</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>Columbia</ent> found that the U.S.
<ent type='ORG'>Bankruptcy Court</ent> had overstepped its jurisdiction in 1987 when it ruled
Justice used "trickery, fraud and deceit" to drive the small <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>
software company out of business.</p>

<p>A U.S. <ent type='ORG'>District Court</ent> later affirmed the bankruptcy ruling and awarded
<ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> $6 million. Justice never paid the money.</p>

<p>After five years of legal actions stemming from a contract Justice awarded to
<ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> in 1982 for development of case management software, the appeals court
suggested that <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> start over in the federal court system.</p>

<p>The appeals court's decision said Justice was "hauled in front of the
bankruptcy court simply because <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> filed for bankruptcy, and <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> has
succeeded in convincing the bankruptcy court to adjudicate its contract . .
. disputes although the court had no basis to do so."</p>

<p>The court did not rule on the validity of the <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> charges and criticized
the bankruptcy court for its "extraordinary" ruling. "Such conduct, if it
occurred, is inexcusable," the appeals court said of Inslaw's complaints
against Justice. But, "offensive as lawless conduct by one branch of
government may be, however, it does not justify another's lawlessness."</p>

<p>The reversal also means Justice need not comply with a discovery ruling last
month in which an appeals court judge ordered Justice to turn over
information about whether the software, Promis, was being used at several
Justice bureaus.</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> vice president <ent type='PERSON'>Nancy</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Hamilton</ent> said the company "will fight to the
end." She said <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> either will file a new suit or appeal the decision.
The company has gathered more evidence against Justice since it filed the
original suit, she said.</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Stuart</ent> M. <ent type='PERSON'>Gerson</ent>, assistant attorney general in charge of Justice's Civil
Division, said the department was "gratified" by the court's dismissal of
Inslaw's complaint.</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Gerson</ent> said it "vindicates the position the government has taken from the
outset -- that notwithstanding the intensity of the underlying dispute
between <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> and the department, this is fundamentally a . . .
contractual disagreement."</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> president <ent type='PERSON'>William</ent> A. <ent type='PERSON'>Hamilton</ent> said, "The Justice <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> has
consistently hidden behind technical defenses to avoid its duty to enforce
the laws in regard to the misconduct of its own officials against <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent>."</p>

<p>Meanwhile, a congressional investigation of the <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent>-Justice dispute is
continuing. After months of stalling, Attorney General <ent type='PERSON'><ent type='PERSON'>Richard</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Thornburgh</ent></ent>
has agreed to make several hundred documents about the department's dealings
with <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> available to <ent type='ORG'>House</ent> Judiciary Committee investigators.</p>

<p>The committee was allowed access to the materials only after agreeing to
several stipulations <ent type='PERSON'>Thornburgh</ent> laid out last month in a letter to the
committee chairman, Rep. <ent type='PERSON'>Jack Brooks</ent> (D-<ent type='GPE'>Texas</ent>).</p>

<p>Judiciary investigators agreed to review the documents on Justice's premises,
formally request copies and, at least initially, withhold the documents from
the public.</p>

<p>Since last July, <ent type='ORG'>Brooks</ent> had been trying to obtain some 200 department
documents his committee investigators said pertained to the legal dispute.</p>

<p>It now appears the committee will examine many more than 200 documents. The
first of 15 sets of documents, which investigators began reviewing May 1,
alone contained 193 items.</p>

<p>The committee considers access to the documents a major breakthrough in its
investigation.</p>

<p>The issue of access to the documents came to a head late last year. <ent type='ORG'>Brooks</ent>,
frustrated by Justice's continual delays in providing the materials to his
committee, threatened to issue subpoenas and said he would use whatever means
necessary to force Justice to turn over the documents.</p>

<p>Subsequently, <ent type='PERSON'>Thornburgh</ent> assured <ent type='ORG'>Brooks</ent> he would give him the documents and
the department would cooperate fully.</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>Journal</ent>: Federal Computer Week May 6 1991 v5 n12 p4(1).
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Title: Justice screens <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> document release. (<ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> of Justice
limits access to documents in conspiracy case)
Author: Sweeney, Shahida.</p>

<p>Summary: The <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> of Justice limits <ent type='ORG'>House</ent> Judiciary Committee access
to papers relating to an investigation of government conspiracy
against software developer INSLAW. The Justice <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> claims
that releasing all documents would jeopardize its appeal against
INSLAW. The <ent type='ORG'>House</ent> Judiciary Committee is investigating the
Justice Department's award of a $212 million office automation
contract to TiSoft Inc. <ent type='ORG'>House</ent> investigators are being allowed by
the Justice <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> to view relating papers, but may only take
notes from them for future reference or permission to obtain
copies. INSLAW is granted permission to examine <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> of
Justice tapes in order to ascertain if the agency is illegally
using copies if INSLAW's Promise office automation software.
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Descriptors..
Company: INSLAW Inc. (Investigations)
TiSoft Inc. (Contracts).
Product: Promis (Office automation software) (Investigations).
Topic: Software Piracy
Investigations
Office Automation
Legal Applications
<ent type='GPE'>United</ent> States. <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> of Justice
<ent type='GPE'>United</ent> States. <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>. <ent type='ORG'>House</ent>. Committee on the Judiciary
Court Cases.</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>Journal</ent>: Newsbytes April 29 1991
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Title: <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Post</ent> calls for <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> progress. (software publisher's
case against the justice <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent>)
Author: McMullen, <ent type='PERSON'>Barbara</ent> E.; McMullen, John F.
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Descriptors..
Company: INSLAW Inc. (Cases).
Topic: <ent type='GPE'>United</ent> States. <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> of Justice
Legal Issues
Court Cases
Government Agency
Software Publishers
Theft of Equipment
Government Contracts.</p>

<p>-----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Full Text:</p>

<p><ent type='GPE'>WASHINGTON</ent> POST CALLS FOR INSLAW PROGRESS 04/29/91 <ent type='GPE'>WASHINGTON</ent>, DC, U.S.A.,
1991 APR 29 (NB) -- The <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Post</ent>, in an April 27th editorial, has
criticized the Justice <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> for the lengthy lack of progress in
cooperation with <ent type='ORG'>the House</ent> Judiciary Committee's investigation of the <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent>
case.</p>

<p>Recalling that it had editorially praised Attorney General Dick <ent type='PERSON'>Thornburgh</ent> a
year ago for agreeing to cooperate, the <ent type='ORG'>Post</ent> said, "We wrote too soon. The
department continued to resist the committee's request for some documents,
and the investigation has been hamstrung while lawyers argued over what
should be shared and what should remain <ent type='ORG'>sec</ent>ret. This week agreement was
finally achieved - or so we think - and after seven years of stonewalling the
department has pledged full cooperation."</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent>, a small computer software firm signed a contract in 1982 to supply
all 94 U.S. attorney's offices with "Promis" software it had developed to
track the progress of cases and compile information about caseloads.
According to the <ent type='ORG'>Post</ent> story, the government contract accounted for 70% of
Inslaw's business and, when the Justice Dept. stopped payment and terminated
the contract in 1984, the firm went into bankruptcy.</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>William</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Hamilton</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> owner, brought suit against the Justice Dept.,
claiming that it had stolen the firm's software and willfully driven the firm
into bankruptcy. <ent type='PERSON'>Hamilton</ent> was successful in his suit and a judge in the
initial case found that the department "took, converted and stole" the
company's property "by trickery, fraud and deceit" and further said that the
government's conduct demonstrated "bad faith, vexatiousness, wantonness and
oppressiveness."</p>

<p>The Justice Dept. appealed the ruling and, in 1989, U.S. <ent type='ORG'>District Court</ent>
Judge <ent type='PERSON'>William</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Bryant</ent> upheld the decision and ordered the government to pay
<ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> $8 million plus attorney's fees. Bryant's decision has since been
appealed.</p>

<p>During the appeals, stories of illegal sales of the allegedly stolen software
to foreign governments including <ent type='GPE'>Iraq</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Libya</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>South Korea</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Canada</ent>,
and involvement of Reagan <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>California</ent> appointees <ent type='PERSON'>Earl Brian</ent>,
<ent type='PERSON'>Robert</ent> McFarlane and <ent type='PERSON'>Richard</ent> Secord in the transactions have caused <ent type='ORG'>the House</ent>
Judiciary Committee to seek involvement -- an involvement that the Justice
Dept. has resisted. Elliot <ent type='PERSON'>Richard</ent>son, former <ent type='GPE'>United</ent> States Attorney
General who now represents <ent type='PERSON'>Hamilton</ent>, was quoted recently as saying, "Evidence
of the widespread ramifications of the <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> case comes from many sources
and keeps accumulating. It remains inexplicable why the Justice <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent>
consistently refuses to pursue this evidence and resists cooperation with the
Judiciary Committee of <ent type='ORG'>the House</ent> of Representatives."</p>

<p>The <ent type='ORG'>Post</ent> editorial concludes, "The <ent type='ORG'>House</ent> Judiciary Committee has been more
insistent, and now Chairman <ent type='PERSON'>Jack Brooks</ent>' (D-Tex.) persistence has paid off.
The attorney general will let committee investigators see every document,
though it is understood that some material sensitive to the litigation will
be treated in confidence. This simple arrangement should not have taken
nearly so long. The breakthrough is welcome. We hope it is for real this
time."</p>

<p>(<ent type='PERSON'>Barbara</ent> E. McMullen &amp; John F. McMullen//19910429)</p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>Journal</ent>: Government Computer News April 15 1991 v10 n8 p6(1)
----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Title: Panel questions Justice Dept. on <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent>. (<ent type='ORG'>House</ent> Judiciary
Committee investigates <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> Inc. accusation that Justice Dept.
illegally used and distributed Promis case management system)
Author: <ent type='ORG'>Seaborn</ent>, Margaret M.
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Descriptors..
Company: INSLAW Inc. (Cases).
Product: Promis (Office automation software) (Usage).
Topic: Law Suit
Licensing
Copyright
Investigations
<ent type='GPE'>United</ent> States. <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> of Justice
<ent type='GPE'>United</ent> States. <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>. <ent type='ORG'>House</ent>. Committee on the Judiciary.</p>

<p>-----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Full Text:</p>

<p>Panel Questions Justice Dept. on <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent></p>

<p>Despite the Justice Department's recent appointment of an <ent type='ORG'>IRM</ent> chief, the
<ent type='ORG'>House</ent> Judiciary Committee continues to question the department's ability to
keep its <ent type='ORG'>ADP</ent> house in order, especially where it concerns <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> and Project
<ent type='ORG'>Eagle</ent>.</p>

<p>Next month Judiciary Chairman <ent type='PERSON'>Jack Brooks</ent> (D-<ent type='GPE'>Texas</ent>) intends to ask Justice
officials in a hearing to justify their $35.2 million fiscal 1992 request for
<ent type='ORG'>Eagle</ent>. The committee first raised questions about the office automation
project last year and voiced concerns about general <ent type='ORG'>ADP</ent> oversight.</p>

<p>Justice last month took steps to address some of these management issues when
it named longtime <ent type='ORG'>IRM</ent> veteran Roger M. <ent type='PERSON'>Cooper</ent> as the first deputy assistant
attorney general for <ent type='ORG'>IRM</ent>. But <ent type='PERSON'>Cooper</ent> has said he needs some time on the job
before outlining his priorities.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, committee investigators are continuing to prod Justice to provide
them with information for their continuing review of the <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> case, in
which Justice is accused of using proprietary software without a license.
Recently the department also has been accused of distributing the product to
other organizations.</p>

<p>Although <ent type='ORG'>Brooks</ent> has threatened to issue subpoenas, investigators might
piggyback on the subpoena power recently won by <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> Inc. president <ent type='PERSON'>William</ent>
A. <ent type='PERSON'>Hamilton</ent>.</p>

<p>The committee's investigation has been hamstrung by Justice's unwillingness
to turn over some 200 documents concerning Promis, the case management system
<ent type='PERSON'>Hamilton</ent> alleges Justice officials stole from his company. The committee
anticipates these documents will raise more questions and will point to its
next move, a congressional staff member said.</p>

<p>The committee is conducting its investigation independent of information
<ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> uncovers, but if the company's discovery process turns up evidence
that would be useful, "we will certainly look at it," he said.</p>

<p>Chief Judge <ent type='PERSON'>Aubrey</ent> E. <ent type='PERSON'>Robinson</ent> of the U.S. <ent type='ORG'>District Court</ent> granted <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent>
limited discovery authority this month. It will allow the small <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>
software company to subpoena information from certain Justice bureaus to
determine whether the department illegally distributed Promis.</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Robinson</ent> gave Justice 30 days to respond to the subpoenas.</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> will subpoena information from the Drug Enforcement Administration,
the U.S. Marshals Service, the <ent type='ORG'>FBI</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>the Bureau</ent> of Prisons, the Immigration
and Naturalization Service and the Justice Management Division, <ent type='PERSON'>Hamilton</ent>
said.</p>

<p>Before granting the motion, <ent type='PERSON'>Robinson</ent> said, "This case has had so many
skirmishes, I don't know whether you will ever get to the major battle." He
also said the court should not have to monitor Justice continuously to ensure
it obeys the law.</p>

<p>At Hamilton's request, <ent type='PERSON'>Robinson</ent> last month agreed to take over the case from
the U.S. <ent type='ORG'>Bankruptcy Court</ent>. <ent type='PERSON'>Hamilton</ent> said <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> may request more subpoenas
if the discovery process shows that Justice violated a court injunction
against distributing Promis beyond the 44 copies to which it is entitled
under a 1982 contract.</p>

<p>Justice officials continually have denied Inslaw's allegations of wrongdoing.</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Robinson</ent> noted Justice's argument that some of Inslaw's affidavits include
"<ent type='ORG'>sec</ent>ond-or third-hand hearsay."</p>

<p>But <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> attorney <ent type='PERSON'>Charles Work</ent> said, "I've got a lot of proof that
something is going on. I don't have linkage, but if I did I wouldn't be
asking for discovery."</p>

<p>Although <ent type='ORG'>Brooks</ent> has not resorted to subpoenaing Justice officials, he made it
clear in December that he would force Justice to produce the documents he
seeks. <ent type='ORG'>Brooks</ent> has threatened Justice with subpoenas as well as <ent type='ORG'>ADP</ent> funding
cuts.</p>

<p>Last year, <ent type='ORG'>Brooks</ent> recommended that Eagle's fiscal 1991 funding be cut back to
the previous year's spending level. Instead, <ent type='ORG'>the House</ent> Appropriations
Committee restricted <ent type='ORG'>Eagle</ent> installations to management and litigating
agencies and cut funding by $6.1 million to $16.9 million.</p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>Journal</ent>: Computerworld April 1 1991 v25 n13 p1(2).
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Title: <ent type='ORG'>Spies</ent> linked to software scam. (former national <ent type='ORG'>sec</ent>urity adviser
<ent type='PERSON'>Robert</ent> C. McFarlane implicated)
Author: Anthes, Gary H.</p>

<p>Summary: Small software developer <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> Inc has been fighting since 1983
to prove that the US <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> of Justice misappropriated its
product, but the case has taken a new twist with the revelation
that former national <ent type='ORG'>sec</ent>urity adviser <ent type='PERSON'>Robert</ent> C. McFarlane might be
linked to case-tracking software allegedly fraudulently obtained
from <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent>. A former <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent>i intelligence officer has alleged in
a sworn statement filed in the US <ent type='ORG'>Bankruptcy Court</ent> that McFarlane
gave the software to the <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent>i government. <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> claims
officials of the Justice <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> and their friends stole its
Promis law-enforcement case-tracking software for use in a complex
series of business arrangements. Federal bankruptcy judge George
Bason Jr ruled in favor of <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> in 1987, but the Justice
<ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> has filed a series of appeals in the intervening years.
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Descriptors..
Company: INSLAW Inc. (Cases).
Topic: Software Piracy
Government Officials
<ent type='GPE'>United</ent> States. <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> of Justice
Fraud.</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>Journal</ent>: Government Computer News April 1 1991 v10 n7 p66(2)
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Title: <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> head says software passed like a hot potato. (<ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> of
Justice accused of stealing software)
Author: <ent type='ORG'>Seaborn</ent>, Margaret M.
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Descriptors..
Company: INSLAW Inc. (Cases).
Topic: Legal Issues
Court Cases
Bankruptcy
<ent type='GPE'>United</ent> States. <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> of Justice
Government Agency
Theft of Equipment
Software Publishers.</p>

<p>-----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Full Text:</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> Head Says Software Passed Like a Hot Potato</p>

<p>Saying four federal judges have passed its Promis software case around like a
"hot potato," <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> Inc. has persuaded the U.S. <ent type='ORG'>Bankruptcy Court</ent> to allow
the U.S. <ent type='ORG'>District Court</ent> to consider an unsettled discovery motion.</p>

<p>The small <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent> company had wanted senior <ent type='ORG'>District Court</ent> Judge <ent type='PERSON'>William</ent>
B. <ent type='PERSON'>Bryant</ent> to decide a discovery motion filed last September. In 1989, <ent type='PERSON'>Bryant</ent>
agreed with a 1987 bankruptcy court ruling that Justice <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> officials
stole 44 copies of enhanced Promis from <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent>.</p>

<p>In February, Judge <ent type='PERSON'>James</ent> F. <ent type='PERSON'>Schneider</ent>, the bankruptcy judge who had handled
the case for the past two and a half years, recused himself from the case
citing potential conflicts of interest.</p>

<p>"Now some six months after <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> initially asked for limited discovery to
determine whether the injunction had been violated... <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> still has had
no ruling on its motion, and worse still, has no judge to hear it," <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent>
said in an emergency motion filed last month.</p>

<p>If a court granted Inslaw's motion for discovery, the company could subpoena
information to determine whether Justice had violated an injunction against
distributing copies of Promis beyond what the department acquired through a
1982 contract.</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> officials said they want to withdraw the motion from the bankruptcy
court and resubmit it to the district court because the discovery request is
not a bankruptcy question.</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> president <ent type='PERSON'>William</ent> A. <ent type='PERSON'>Hamilton</ent> said he now believes Promis has been
illegally distributed to <ent type='ORG'>the Central Intelligence Agency</ent>, the Defense
Intelligence Agency, the <ent type='ORG'>National Security Agency</ent> and the <ent type='ORG'>FBI</ent>.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> has submitted to the bankruptcy court an affidavit from
regional sales manager Patricia <ent type='PERSON'>Hamilton</ent> that claims Canadian government
officials told her their government was using pirated copies of Promis in as
many as 905 locations. <ent type='ORG'>The Royal</ent> Canadian Mounted Police could be using
Promis in 900 of those locations, she said.</p>

<p>A former <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent>i intelligence officer alleged in a <ent type='ORG'>sec</ent>ond affidavit that Earl
W. <ent type='PERSON'>Brian</ent>, a friend of former Attorney General <ent type='PERSON'>Edwin Meese</ent>, told him that U.S.
and <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent>i intelligence agencies were using Promis. The <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent>i, Ari
Ben-Menashe, also said in the affidavit he had learned that <ent type='PERSON'>Brian</ent> sold Promis
to <ent type='GPE'>Iraq</ent>i military intelligence.</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Brian</ent> has denied these allegations.</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Schneider</ent> is the third judge to recuse himself from the case, which has been
pending almost five years. A fourth judge and the first to hear the case,
Judge George F. Bason Jr., "has come to believe that his failure to be
reappointed to the bench was due to the opinions he rendered in this case,"
<ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> said.</p>

<p>The emergency motion said, "Judge <ent type='PERSON'>Bryant</ent> remains the only sitting judge who
has not removed himself and has knowledge of the facts of the case."</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Bryant</ent> awarded <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> more than $6 million in 1988. Justice is appealing the
U.S. <ent type='ORG'>District Court</ent> judge's 1989 affirmation of the bankruptcy court's
ruling and has not paid <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> any of the awarded money.</p>

<p> Product: Docketrac
----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Company: INSLAW, Inc.
Address: 1125 15th St., NW, Ste. 300
<ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, DC 20005
800-221-3187; 202-828-8600
FAX: 202-659-0755
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Category: Software, Applications
Legal Services</p>

<p>Specs: Pricing: $40000-$150000
Number sold: 18
Release date: 1983
Application: Legal Services-Docket Scheduling
Compatible with: <ent type='ORG'>IBM</ent> 9370, 30XX, 43XX/DOS, OS, <ent type='ORG'>MVS</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>CICS</ent>; <ent type='ORG'>DEC</ent>
VAX/ULTRIX; Wang/VS; <ent type='ORG'>Unisys</ent>; AT&amp;T 3B/UNIX System V; HP/HP-UX
Minimum RAM required: 2 MB
Source language: COBOL
Customer support: Maint. fee 12% of licensing fee per yr.
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Summary: On-line docketing and calendaring. Trial court information
system. Tracks cases, litigants, case parties, causes of action
and charges from filing to disposition. Debt Collection module.</p>

<p>Descriptors: scheduling</p>

<p> Product: Jailtrac
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Company: INSLAW, Inc.
Address: 1125 15th St., NW, Ste. 300
<ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, DC 20005
800-221-3187; 202-828-8600
FAX: 202-659-0755
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Category: Software, Applications
Government/Public Administration</p>

<p>Specs: Pricing: $30000-$125000
Number sold: 14
Release date: 1982
Application: Law Enforcement/Emergency Services
Compatible with: <ent type='ORG'>IBM</ent> 9370, 30XX, 43XX/DOS, OS, <ent type='ORG'>MVS</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>CICS</ent>; <ent type='ORG'>DEC</ent>
VAX/ULTRIX; Wang/VS; <ent type='ORG'>Unisys</ent>; AT&amp;T 3B/UNIX System V; HP/HP-UX
Minimum RAM required: 2 MB
Source language: COBOL
Customer support: Maint. fee 12% of licensing fee per yr.
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Summary: Arrest booking and jail management. Tracks arrestees, inmates and
cases. On-line data entry, updating and retrieval. Produces
user-defined forms. Includes inmate tracking, cell assignment,
property, inmate accounting, visitor control, scheduling, inmate
history, medical information and release date calculation.
Tailorable.</p>

<p>Descriptors: scheduling</p>

<p>Product: <ent type='ORG'>Modulaw Corporate</ent>/Lawfirm Public
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Company: INSLAW, Inc.
Address: 1125 15th St., NW, Ste. 300
<ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, DC 20005
800-221-3187; 202-828-8600
FAX: 202-659-0755
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Category: Software, Applications
Legal Services</p>

<p>Specs: Pricing: $30000-$125000
Number sold: 15
Release date: 1983
Application: Legal Services-Practice Management
Compatible with: <ent type='ORG'>IBM</ent> 9370, 30XX, 43XX/DOS, OS, <ent type='ORG'>MVS</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>CICS</ent>; <ent type='ORG'>DEC</ent>
VAX/ULTRIX; Wang/VS; <ent type='ORG'>Unisys</ent>; AT&amp;T 3B/UNIX System V; HP/HP-UX
Minimum RAM required: 2 MB
Source language: COBOL
Customer support: Maint. fee 12% of licensing fee per yr.
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Summary: Performs claims/matter tracking, attorney timekeeping, outside
counsel tracking, work product retrieval, docket control and
calendaring, corporate <ent type='ORG'>sec</ent>retary management, person/organization
tracking, law library management, legislation tracking, loan
recovery and records management. User designed screens, forms and
reports.</p>

<p>Descriptors: scheduling; personnel; office automation; professional time
accounting</p>

<p>Product: Modulaw Insurance
----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Company: INSLAW, Inc.
Address: 1125 15th St., NW, Ste. 300
<ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, DC 20005
800-221-3187; 202-828-8600
FAX: 202-659-0755
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Category: Software, Applications
Legal Services</p>

<p>Specs: Pricing: $30000-$125000 per office
Number sold: 13
Release date: 1986
Application: Legal Services
Compatible with: <ent type='ORG'>IBM</ent> 9370, 30XX, 43XX/DOS, OS, <ent type='ORG'>MVS</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>CICS</ent>; <ent type='ORG'>DEC</ent>
VAX/ULTRIX; Wang/VS; <ent type='ORG'>Unisys</ent>; AT&amp;T 3B/UNIX System V; HP/HP-UX
Minimum RAM required: 2 MB
Source language: COBOL
Customer support: Maint. fee 12% of licensing fee per yr.
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Summary: On-line information system. Supports claims litigation tracking,
claims evaluation, reserve tracking, party and expert witness
cross referencing, outside counsel management, docket control and
scheduling, staff workload management, staff timekeeping and
document and issue indexing.</p>

<p>Descriptors: scheduling; professional time accounting</p>

<p>Product: Promis
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Company: INSLAW, Inc.
Address: 1125 15th St., NW, Ste. 300
<ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, DC 20005
800-221-3187; 202-828-8600
FAX: 202-659-0755
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Category: Software, Applications
Government/Public Administration</p>

<p>Specs: Pricing: $30000-$125000
Number sold: 75
Release date: 1980
Application: Law Enforcement/Emergency Services
Compatible with: <ent type='ORG'>IBM</ent> 9370, 30XX, 43XX/DOS, OS, <ent type='ORG'>MVS</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>CICS</ent>; <ent type='ORG'>DEC</ent>
VAX/ULTRIX; Wang/VS; <ent type='ORG'>Unisys</ent>; AT&amp;T 3B/UNIX System V; HP/HP-UX
Minimum RAM required: 2 MB
Source language: COBOL
Customer support: Maint. fee 12% of licensing fee per yr.
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Summary: Tracks cases, defendants and charges in public pro<ent type='ORG'>sec</ent>utor's
office. <ent type='ORG'>Data</ent> entry, updating and retrieval. Produces
user-defined forms. Defines reports for ad hoc or periodic
production.

Company: INSLAW, Inc.
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Address: 1125 15th St., NW, Ste. 300
<ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, DC 20005
800-221-3187; 202-828-8600
FAX: 202-659-0755
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Summary: Gross annual sales: $6000000
No. of employees: 55
Year established: 1972
Chairman/CEO/President: <ent type='PERSON'>William</ent> A. <ent type='PERSON'>Hamilton</ent>
Controller: Bellie Ling
Marketing Dir.: Edward M. Durham
Personnel Dir.: Elizabeth Davis
Marketing/Comm. Mgr.: Evelyn L. <ent type='ORG'>Millhouse</ent>
VP Product Development: <ent type='PERSON'>Marian Holton</ent>
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------
Category: Software, Applications
Government/Public Administration
Legal Services
</p></xml>