<xml><p>FILENAME: INTRO-A</p>

<p> An INTRODUCTION to

************************* HYPERSPACE **************************
in
Your Everyday Life</p>

<p> WHERE IS HYPERSPACE?
------ and ------
HOW DO WE GET THERE FROM HERE?
----------------------------- </p>

<p> THE Ancients imagined a timeless space beyond human </p>

<p>comprehension that they called Heaven, Hades, Valhalla, <ent type='GPE'>Gehenna</ent>,
------ ----- -------- -------
Limbo, <ent type='PERSON'>Elysian Fields</ent>, Happy Hunting Grounds, each in his own
----- -------------- ---------------------
language. The mysterious supernal and infernal regions were </p>

<p>populated with gods and goddesses, devils and demons, angels and </p>

<p>fairies, ghosts and goblins, <ent type='ORG'>chimerae</ent> of every conception. On an </p>

<p>Olympian stage, the immortal spirits acted out the universal </p>

<p>human drama in myths teaching the meanings of life and death, </p>

<p>good and evil, morality and nemesis, until the advent of modern </p>

<p>science brought discredit to intangible realities.</p>

<p> Man does not live without myth. As the traditional morality </p>

<p>plays lose their power to rule men's minds, lively new myths are </p>

<p>composed to replace the dead. If the modern priests of science </p>

<p>refuse to address the problems of the human soul, the modern </p>

<p>poets of science-fiction will use the ken and cant of science to </p>

<p>answer spiritual needs for intangible ideals. Mentor and Merlin </p>

<p>are reincarnated as <ent type='PERSON'>Obi Wan Kenobi</ent> and Yoda; as the last of the </p>

<p>Jedi Knights of a Round Table on some planetary Camelot, Luke </p>

<p>Skywalker draws a laser <ent type='ORG'>Excalibur</ent> from the <ent type='PERSON'>Stone</ent> to wield The </p>

<p>Force on a cosmic odyssey. After running for centuries at </p>

<p>Olympus, followed by a century of full houses at <ent type='GPE'>Dodge City</ent>, the </p>

<p>spiritual epics are now playing in hyperspace.
----------</p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>Hyperspace</ent> is known to science only as a calculation of </p>

<p>pure, abstract mathematics. Physicists are unaware that they </p>

<p>are actually charting the tangible landmarks of hyperspace while </p>

<p>they plot the PSI factors defining the virtual state of the
------------------------
quantum field. Like Moliere's <ent type='PERSON'>BOURGEOIS GENTILHOMME</ent>, everyone
-------------
lives in The Twilight Zone without knowing it. After reading
-----------------
this book, you will be able to recognize the landscape of </p>

<p>hyperspace in your everyday life. The immortal spirits are very </p>

<p>real entities, and God is alive and well on the street where you </p>

<p>live. </p>

<p> __________________________
I I
I Creatures that drift I
I in the depths of the sea I
I are the very last I
I to discover the water. I
I__________________________I</p>

<p> THIS thesis has grown over twenty-five years since I noticed </p>

<p>that the ceremonial <ent type='ORG'>KATAS</ent> of the ZEN martial arts express the </p>

<p>very same energy equations that physicists write in mathematical </p>

<p>notation. (SIDE-1) Once I discovered this key, I realized that </p>

<p>all forms of art are mathematical equations expressing </p>

<p>transformations of energy more subtle than brute strength. Works </p>

<p>of art are a special kind of physical machinery that projects </p>

<p>higher-dimensional structures into lower-dimensional spaces for </p>

<p>some convenience of perceiving. You can see the way art performs </p>

<p>this function by applying the rules of optical perspective to </p>

<p>represent a three-dimensional structure on a plane surface. </p>

<p> The most familiar kind of pictorial perspective presents the </p>

<p>appearance of its subject from but a single viewpoint. In order </p>

<p>to comprehend a solid structure in its entirety, it is necessary </p>

<p>to render it from as many aspects as are required to reveal all </p>

<p>of its structural details in their correct relationships to each </p>

<p>other; many tridimensional perspectives must be studied in order </p>

<p>to construct a conception of a hyperspacial entity. </p>

<p> The art of mathematics presents alternative aspects in the </p>

<p>form of tautological equations, each expressing the view from a </p>

<p>different frame of reference, such as a=lw, l=a/w, and w=a/l to </p>

<p>describe the two-dimensional structure of a square by one-</p>

<p>dimensional semantics. All the codices of mathematical equations </p>

<p>express different views of the single hyperspacial entity known </p>

<p>as the universe; our comprehension of the universal structure
--------
is far from complete.</p>

<p> Artists have a vocation to express their perceptions of </p>

<p>hyperspacial realities from every point of view that man can </p>

<p>reach, at every different time that man can live in, to provide </p>

<p>us with handles on universal truths. All the myths and all the </p>

<p>religions present us with different pictures of the same </p>

<p>hyperspacial entity, and that entity is ourselves. </p>

<p> CLOSE THIS FILE</p>

<p> OPEN FILE "INTRO-C"</p>

<div>================================================================</div>

<p>SIDE-1</p>

<p> Most lovers of literature know that "Gulliver's </p>

<p> Travels is a satire on the politics of Jonathan </p>

<p> Swift's time and place but did you realize that </p>

<p> "<ent type='PERSON'>Alice</ent> In <ent type='GPE'>Wonderland</ent>" and "Through The Looking </p>

<p> Glass" are cryptic explorations of hyperspace? </p>

<p> Alice's adventures are a comic dramatization of the </p>

<p> very same protean confusions, instabilities, </p>

<p> fantasies, whimsies, cruelties, and self-</p>

<p> contradictions of the virtual state of the quantum </p>

<p> field that you are about to tour by way of a more </p>

<p> mathematical direction.</p>

<p> <ent type='PERSON'>Lewis Carroll</ent> is the pen name of the Reverend </p>

<p> Charles Dodgson, a mathematician more competent </p>

<p> than he dared to reveal to his contemporaries, so </p>

<p> he became better known under his real name for </p>

<p> making sensitive photographs of pretty little girls </p>

<p> all bare naked with no clothes on. </p>

<p> ___________________________________
I I
I Scientists and artists I
I are both mystics I
I competing in the myth business. I
I I
I The differences between them I
I are mainly a matter I
I of professional jargon. I
I___________________________________I</p>

<p> YOU are able to perceive voluminous space only because your </p>

<p>mind fuses the two different perspectives received by your two </p>

<p>eyes. *1</p>

<p> From one point of view, your inner eye sees merely plane </p>

<p>images. In order to perceive solid structures in voluminous </p>

<p>space, you must move around the subject under observation and </p>

<p>fuse an indefinite number of aspects from all sides. A cone, </p>

<p>for illustration, is seen as a circle in plan view, a triangle in </p>

<p>elevation, and various angles subtended by various arcs in all </p>

<p>other views. The solid structure of a cone is conceived only </p>

<p>after fusing all images in the mind. If your mind were not able </p>

<p>to construct this gestalt, you would be unable to recognize the
-------
triangular aspect of the cone as having the same identity as the </p>

<p>circular aspect. (SIDE-1)</p>

<p> The ability to fuse an indefinite number of plane images </p>

<p>into a solid image in the mind is usually achieved during </p>

<p>childhood as we master language, so no one is aware of common </p>

<p>aberrations. As an example, few people saw the view from the top </p>

<p>until everyone trav<ent type='LOC'>elle</ent>d by air. Without flight experience, you </p>

<p>don't learn to fuse plan views of the landscape with the familiar </p>

<p>elevations; therefore, aerial photographs remain unintelligible </p>

<p>to most people. You would be surprised by the number of people </p>

<p>who cannot read blueprints because of their inability to fuse all </p>

<p>sectional drawings into a dynamic tridimensional gestalt. Cubism </p>

<p>is four-dimensional perspective; the art of Cubism makes no sense </p>

<p>to people who cannot analyze plural perspectives and recombine </p>

<p>them mentally to form a hyperspacial image of the pictorial </p>

<p>subject.</p>

<p> Since <ent type='PERSON'>George Eastman</ent> provided everyone with a camera, we find </p>

<p>that most snapshots, like driver's IDs, can't be recognized by the </p>

<p>subject's mother. How is it possible for the camera (that cannot </p>

<p>lie) to produce unrecognizable portraits? From the infinite number </p>

<p>of views you see of your nearest and dearest, only a certain number </p>

<p>are selected for fusion into the mental image of the person you </p>

<p>identify. The zillions of other views are occulted from the visual </p>

<p>consciousness because they are insignificant or because the </p>

<p>differences are great enough to produce the painful condition of </p>

<p>cognitive dissonance that prevents fusion of disparate ideas.
--------------------</p>

<p> Cognitive dissonance is produced by harmonic discord among </p>

<p>the vibrations defining ideas, images, and sounds. All </p>

<p>differences produce cognitive dissonance until discordant phases </p>

<p>are canc<ent type='LOC'>elle</ent>d and the remaining vibrations are resolved into a </p>

<p>harmonically integrated gestalt in a higher dimension, like a </p>

<p>musical chord. Wave cancellation is the physical basis of the </p>

<p>concept of psychological repression established by Freud; these </p>

<p>wave mechanics also produce <ent type='EVENT'>KARMA</ent>. (*2)</p>

<p> Interference between (mental) waves transforms them into </p>

<p>other frequencies so that objects are not perceived as they </p>

<p>really are, if they are not rendered altogether invisible as a </p>

<p>consequence of cognitive dissonance. Therefore, each person sees </p>

<p>and hears truly only those signals that are congruent with the </p>

<p>conceptual patterns already defining one's own mental structure; </p>

<p>all other perceptions are distorted and repressed, occulted </p>

<p>behind the Veils of <ent type='PERSON'>Maja</ent>. (SIDE-2) At the bottom line, </p>

<p>intereference produces a pair of predominant patterns separated </p>

<p>by 180o of phase. As a result, reality is perceived to be </p>

<p>polarized between good and evil, black and white, strong and </p>

<p>weak, male and female, etc. </p>

<p> Just as only one side of a solid structure can be seen at a </p>

<p>time, without a mirror, only one phase of a hyperspacial </p>

<p>structure can be perceived directly at one time. It is natural, </p>

<p>therefore, to assign a unique identity to different phases that </p>

<p>exceed the observer's capacity for resolution into a single </p>

<p>gestalt. Virtue is not recognized as the front of vice, no light </p>

<p>is seen in darkness, and you have to know your <ent type='PERSON'>TAO</ent> to find </p>

<p>strength in compliance. <ent type='ORG'>Union</ent> of complementary opposites </p>

<p>transforms them both into a structure of higher dimension. The </p>

<p>degree to which you can resolve polar opposites establishes the </p>

<p>dimensional scope of your <ent type='ORG'>Consciousness</ent>. An understanding of </p>

<p>hyperspace enables you to answer problems that defy all </p>

<p>philosophers limited to three-dimensional concepts; given </p>

<p>sufficient scope, you will even understand the opposite sex. (*3)</p>

<p> CLOSE THIS FILE</p>

<p> OPEN FILE "INTRO-D"</p>

<div>===============================================================</div>

<p>SIDE-1
Assigning different identities to </p>

<p> different aspects of the same structure is </p>

<p> most commonly experienced in interpersonal </p>

<p> relationships. During the initial rush of </p>

<p> love, all perceptions that trouble the purity </p>

<p> of the relationship is repressed. Admonitions </p>

<p> from friends and family to watch where you are </p>

<p> giving your heart are ignored as utterly </p>

<p> irrelevant to the paragon identified with all </p>

<p> the virtues of true love, and none of the </p>

<p> vices. When dissonant aspects of the loved one </p>

<p> appear from behind the Veils of <ent type='PERSON'>Maja</ent>, they are </p>

<p> perceived to belong to another person, a </p>

<p> stranger in your home and a devil in your bed. </p>

<p>
Unable to conceive that pleasure and pain </p>

<p> can come from the same parent, infants </p>

<p> perceive a good true-parent and a wicked step-</p>

<p> parent. Most people still cannot identify God </p>

<p> with the devil, nor can they perceive that </p>

<p> Heaven and hell are complementary aspects of </p>

<p> one real world. </p>

<div> =============================================</div>

<p>SIDE-2
The <ent type='NORP'>Latin</ent> mind has no imprinted concept </p>

<p> of the English SCHWA sound. Without the mental </p>

<p> concept, the <ent type='NORP'>Latin</ent> ear cannot distinguish </p>

<p> between his and <ent type='ORG'>hees</ent>. The sound of big
--- ---- ---
activates the concept of <ent type='ORG'>beeg</ent>, and <ent type='ORG'>beeg</ent> is
---- ----
what the <ent type='NORP'>Latin</ent> mind hears. Likewise, the </p>

<p> <ent type='NORP'>Japanese</ent> mind has no imprint for the ell
---
sound; in the <ent type='NORP'>Japanese</ent> mind, the <ent type='LOC'>elle</ent> sound is
----
heard as arr.
--- </p>

<p> Male and female mentalities are </p>

<p> imprinted with different concepts making it </p>

<p> physically impossible for the opposite sex to </p>

<p> receive the same message thatis sent. </p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>Communication</ent> between sexes is like </p>

<p> communication between different species. No </p>

<p> matter how many times arguments are settled, </p>

<p> the very next argument is the very same </p>

<p> argument. <ent type='ORG'>Acquiescence</ent> is not agreement, but </p>

<p> resignation and tolerance of the </p>

<p> incomprehensible. </p>

<div>---------------------------------------------------------------</div>

<p>*1 If your mind is unable to fuse plural images, the brain
is confused, and all images but one are erased from your visual
<ent type='ORG'>Consciousness</ent>. The eye transmitting the voided image loses its
functional capacity. It may be speculated that other sense
organs also lose their function when their information is voided.</p>

<div>---------------------------------------------------------------</div>

<p>*2 If Freud studied physics before medicine, he wouldn't
have invented a square wheel in his theory of sexual
determinism. Psychology and psychiatry would be radically
different if a grounding in elementary physics were prerequisite.
These professions will soon be demolished and reconstructed by
the hard science of artificial intelligence.</p>

<p> The soft sciences are not soft by their very nature, but
because soft ideas attract people incapable of comprehending
hard, mathematical concepts, and once soft-heads populate a
profession, hard-heads move out of the neighbourhood. As a
consequence, the soft sciences degenerate into nonsense until
they become too impractical to hold their customers. If astrology
were not so soft-headed, actuaries would be calculating horoscopes
instead of statistics.</p>

<p> The essential difference between the hard-head and the soft-head is concentration of mental focus. Whereas the hard-head
defines particulars, the soft-head senses the overview. Both
heads are half-wits if they cannot vary the scope of their focus
to integrate particulars with wholes to comprehend both at once
in a higher dimension of <ent type='ORG'>Consciousness</ent>.</p>

<div>---------------------------------------------------------------</div>

<p>*3</p>

<p> OOOOOOOOOOOOO\ The confusion prodiced by the
O\ O \ Necker cube is due to seeing the
O \OOOOOOOOOOOOO inside and the outside of a box
O O O O at the same time. When seen as a
O O O O plane image, a transparent cube
O O O O presents a different structure
OOOOOOOOOOOOO O from every point of view, and
\ O \ O except when seen in a plan or
\OOOOOOOOOOOOO elevation, no aspect resembles
the shape of an opaque box.
This is an object lesson in the difference between the structure
of an entity in hyperspace and the form it presents in a lower
dimensional space. </p>

<p> Since God is an Entity of utmost dimensional extent,
no man can look at a complete image of It in this lifetime ---
and that is the reason for the religious prohibition against
graven images. In order to preclude any manifestation of The God
That Is All That Is from being worshipped as the One Big I, The
First Commandment is engraved, "Thou shalt not hold any god
before Me." Anything less than God is the very devil, and the
devil grows more diabolical as it grows more Godly; the devil is
<ent type='PERSON'>the Brightest Angel</ent> of them all. </p>

<p> The worship of anything less than God, no matter how Godly,
is <ent type='PERSON'>Satan</ent>ism; the good people of this world are far more
dangerous than the bad. You see, the only difference between bad
people and good people is that bad people say that all wars are
good, whereas good people say that some wars are good; both
sides agree that no war is bad unless it is lost. As the child
prays, "Dear God, please make all the bad people good and the
good people nice." </p>



<p> THE mind is able to fuse two visual images only when </p>

<p>there is practically no difference between them. Fusion of visual </p>

<p>images into a stereo gestalt becomes impossible if the two </p>

<p>perspectives differ by more than the interocular distance. In </p>

<p>other words, there is a limit to the amount of difference that </p>

<p>can be resolved without producing an identity crisis. (SIDE-1)</p>

<p>
To illustrate, if your views of a cone were limited to the </p>

<p>extremes of plan and elevation, only extraordinary conditions and </p>

<p>mathematical calculation would enable you to realize that the two </p>

<p>mutually incommensurable figures were aspects of the same </p>

<p>identity in a higher dimension of space. Ordinarily, you are able </p>

<p>to relate one extreme view to the other extreme by innumerable

other viewing angles revealing the gradual transformation of the </p>

<p>circle into the triangle. Even after identifying the circle as </p>

<p>an allotropic aspect of the triangle, you would still be unable </p>

<p>to form the concept of a solid cone unless your mental space </p>

<p>were large enough to comprehend three dimensions; you would </p>

<p>believe that the conical structure alternates between a </p>

<p>circle and a triangle according to the viewing angle; it would </p>

<p>be the wave-particle paradox all over again.</p>

<p> On the atomic scale, hyperspacial rotations occur at such </p>

<p>speed that transition phases between extreme views cannot be </p>

<p>resolved within the temporal precision of the experiment. The </p>

<p>wave-particle dichotomy is refractory to scientific </p>

<p>comprehension not only because an electron flips between its two </p>

<p>phases faster than the instruments can follow, but also because </p>

<p>both wave packets and particles are three-dimensional concepts. </p>

<p>Mentally unable to comprehend ultratridimensional entities, </p>

<p>physicists identify different projections of one subatomic </p>

<p>particle as several new discoveries, and that is why there is no </p>

<p>end to the number of elementary particles.</p>

<p> At least four dimensions of space are required to fuse </p>

<p>several three-dimensional structures into a single identity in </p>

<p>the same place at the same time. The most highly respected </p>

<p>scientific authorities aver that it is impossible for any human </p>

<p>int<ent type='LOC'>elle</ent>ct to visualize space extending in more than three </p>

<p>dimensions. Nevertheless, your mind reveals the mathematical </p>

<p>parameters of four-dimensional hyperspace every time you fuse </p>

<p>more than one three-dimensional image into a gestalt. Look at </p>

<p>that, would you; like the atom, the inner space of your mind is
-------------------------------
hyper! <ent type='ORG'>Hyperspace</ent> is as familiar to you as your own mental
-----
concepts. How 'bout that, Dr. Einstein? </p>

<p> The science of physics is actually the physics of </p>

<p>perception. Your mind is a house of many mansions. Most people </p>

<p>never see the doors in the walls of their nurseries; they spend </p>

<p>their entire spiritual lives confined in the crib where they </p>

<p>were born, while they can only wonder about the sounds of family </p>

<p>activity that transpire dimly into their windowless </p>

<p>compartments. In these pages, you will read the construction </p>

<p>plans of your spiritual palace. Once you realize that the </p>

<p>barriers limiting your experience are merely partitions, you </p>

<p>will open the doors of your mind to explore the manifold halls </p>

<p>of self-knowledge. You may even leave your father's house to </p>

<p>make your way as a grown person in the big hyperworld outside. </p>

<p>Of course, it is dangerous out there, and not all who venture </p>

<p>return sound and successful, but that is what real life is all </p>

<p>about when play school is left behind. The physics of </p>

<p>consciousness is what this book is all about.</p>

<p> CLOSE THIS FILE</p>

<p> OPEN FILE "INTRO-E"</p>

<div> ===========================================</div>

<p>SIDE-1 </p>

<p> The limits of identity provide a </p>

<p> universally practical principle for getting </p>

<p> what you want out of life -- especially if you </p>

<p> have to get what you want out of other people. </p>

<p> To wit, it is impossible to change anyone's </p>

<p> mind except by nicely graduated argument that </p>

<p> slowly turns the other's point of view to your </p>

<p> direction; if you argue too strongly, you only </p>

<p> provoke rage, denial, and repression of </p>

<p> everything you say. The <ent type='PERSON'>TAO</ent> teaches that the </p>

<p> battle does not go to the strong, nor the race </p>

<p> to the swift, but to the gentle and the </p>

<p> patient; this is the true meaning of <ent type='PERSON'>Jesus</ent>' </p>

<p> promise that the meek will inherit the Earth. </p>

<p> Beggars, flatterers, and cheaters take more </p>

<p> than workers, racers, and robbers. </p>

<p> ___________________________
I I
I It is not in our stars I
I that our troubles arise, I
I my dear reader, I
I but in our telescopes. I
I___________________________I</p>

<p> FUSING disparate images depends upon the development of a </p>

<p>faculty for ignoring differences. The mind learns to ignore </p>

<p>differences by subsuming them to a common feature, such as </p>

<p>association of time, place, utility, or physical property. The </p>

<p>subsumption of ideas into abstract classifications is produced </p>

<p>by wave interference; and so, particular, individual differences </p>

<p>are repressed to the Unconscious as the mind grows from </p>

<p>perceptions limited to tangible sense data to comprehend </p>

<p>abstract concepts. (SIDE-1)</p>

<p> <ent type='PERSON'>Plato</ent> wrote the original hyperspacial theory explaining </p>

<p>that each of the material bodies in this world is a </p>

<p>manifestation of an <ent type='ORG'>Ideal</ent> Form in Heaven. In modern mathematical </p>

<p>terms, <ent type='PERSON'>Plato</ent> can be paraphrased to say that each individual </p>

<p>structure is a unique cross-section (or projection) of an </p>

<p>entity existing in a space of more than three dimensions, </p>

<p>intersecting with our tridimensional world. <ent type='PERSON'>Plato</ent> conceived his </p>

<p>concept of Universal Form by the mental process of verbal </p>

<p>abstraction, and then with true philosophic backasswardness he </p>

<p>declared that the particular is derived from the abstract, </p>

<p>instead of the other way 'round; nevertheless, <ent type='PERSON'>Plato</ent> is right.</p>

<p> Since <ent type='PERSON'>Plato</ent> explained that all individual differences are </p>

<p>unique aspects of the ideal, and since wave interference is </p>

<p>proven to be the physical mechanism that subsumes differences </p>

<p>within the gestalt, the technical means for revealing a tangible </p>

<p>manifestation of the <ent type='ORG'>Ideal</ent> Form is self-evident. By </p>

<p>superimposing an indefinitely large number of individual images </p>

<p>of the same class of tangible manifestations, the individual
-----
wave-forms arrange themselves according to the principle of the </p>

<p>Conservation of Energy into a single, harmonically integrated </p>

<p>structure. Photographers will recognize this process as the way </p>

<p>to make a hologram. A hologram, therefore, is a tangible
--------
hyperspacial structure. How 'bout that, Dr. <ent type='ORG'>Gamow</ent>? </p>

<p> A hologram looks like nothing so much as a compounded </p>

<p>vortex. A compound vortex is what a hyperspacial entity looks </p>

<p>like when it becomes manifest in its entirety as a tridimensional </p>

<p>form. When Cecil B. DeMille represented the God of <ent type='PERSON'>Moses</ent> as a </p>

<p>vortex of light, he was revealing his Unconscious knowledge of </p>

<p>the platonic <ent type='ORG'>Ideal</ent>. (SIDE-2)</p>

<p> _____________________
I I
I Beauty is the Beast I
I_____________________I</p>

<p> CLOSE THIS FILE</p>

<p> OPEN FILE "INTRO-F"</p>

<div> ==============================================</div>

<p>SIDE-1

Children notice microscopic differences; </p>

<p> they inspect details minutely, and object to </p>

<p> the slightest change in their environment ---</p>

<p> especially food. Children lose their </p>

<p> preternatural discrimination of tangible </p>

<p> reality as they learn to speak, and everyone </p>

<p> spends the rest of his life trying to find the </p>

<p> original reality of the child, by way of </p>

<p> sensory excitement, philosophizing, religious </p>

<p> disciplines, and chemical keys to the <ent type='GPE'>Kingdom</ent>.</p>

<p> Childish minds that grow big without </p>

<p> growing up make a profession of details </p>

<p> without being able to realize their meaning in </p>

<p> a universal gestalt; they are favoured to </p>

<p> become scholars and authorities. Sw<ent type='LOC'>elle</ent>d heads </p>

<p> are illustrated by the learned philosophers </p>

<p> who argued about Adam's navel while remaining </p>

<p> incapable of questioning Adam's rib. But </p>

<p> however narrow their perspective, scholars </p>

<p> are broadminded enough to realize that it does </p>

<p> not profiteth a man in this life to gain the </p>

<p> whole world in one vision. </p>

<p> The joys of youth, and its bellicosity, </p>

<p> are the intense excitement produced by the </p>

<p> perception of differences. Conversely, most </p>

<p> of the normal depression which grows with age </p>

<p> is the result of losing discrimination so </p>

<p> that nothing new is perceived under the <ent type='LOC'>Sun</ent>. </p>

<p> The conventional wisdom believes that the </p>

<p> senses atrophy along with the thymus gland, </p>

<p> the gonads, and the digestive organs, to </p>

<p> produce ennui from lack of excitement. </p>

<p> Actually, the sense organs atrophy as </p>

<p> interest in differences is lost because of </p>

<p> terminal classificationosis. Your tour of duty </p>

<p> on this planet is done when you no longer find </p>

<p> any difference between one day and the next, </p>

<p> one season and the next, one person and </p>

<p> another, one sex and the other. VIVE LES </p>

<p> DIFFERENCES! </p>

<div> =========================================</div>

<p>SIDE-2</p>

<p> Christ is the God of Man, variously </p>

<p> called The Son of God and The Son of Man. The </p>

<p> epithets of Christ mean that He is the </p>

<p> platonic <ent type='ORG'>Ideal</ent> of the human species, and each </p>

<p> of us is a unique manifestation of this </p>

<p> Universal <ent type='ORG'>Ideal</ent> Human Being.</p>

<p> A special kind of holographic portrait </p>

<p> of the Christ can be produced by superimposing </p>

<p> an indefinite number of life-size photographs </p>

<p> of people. This technical photography has </p>

<p> actually been done. In this process, the </p>

<p> superimposed waves do not produce a vortex; </p>

<p> instead, the wave interference pattern is </p>

<p> manifest like the superimposition of musical </p>

<p> notes to produce a predominant key tone. The </p>

<p> image resulting from this extraordinary </p>

<p> holographic process reveals an ineffably </p>

<p> beautiful human body of exquisitely perfect </p>

<p> proportions. Christ is quite simply the One </p>

<p> Perfect Human Being from Whom all mortals are </p>

<p> imperfectly projected.</p>

<p>
Individuals possessing features </p>

<p> approximating the human average manifest some </p>

<p> of Christ's Divine Beauty, and that is why all </p>

<p> us mortals who deviate from the average are </p>

<p> moved to adore these paragons of pulchritude. </p>

<p> Unhappily, the instinct to deify the norm has </p>

<p> the necessary consequence of abhorring </p>

<p> deviation as the very devil. </p>

<p> The great truth revealed by this </p>

<p> photographic demonstration is not that good </p>

<p> looks are as good as God; the image of the </p>

<p> Perfect Human Being is composed of every one </p>

<p> of the ugliest and most deviant among us, as </p>

<p> well as the most beautiful freaks. Beauty </p>

<p> without ugliness is less than the whole </p>

<p> platonic Human Being, and anything less than </p>

<p> perfect is diabolical to the degree that </p>

<p> wholeness is lacking. </p>

<p>
The youthful, female form divine tends </p>

<p> toward the average human proportions; the </p>

<p> elderly, male form is the ugly deviant. </p>

<p> Mortals who have seen the Christ Spirit </p>

<p> testify that His counten-nance is like an </p>

<p> unmarked youth with compassion that is learned </p>

<p> only through eons of suffering; His ugliness </p>

<p> radiates beauty.</p>

<p> The closer a nearly holy creature </p>

<p> approaches perfection, the <ent type='ORG'>greateris</ent> its power </p>

<p> for evil, and that is why <ent type='PERSON'>Satan</ent> is the </p>

<p> Brightest Angel of them all, second only to </p>

<p> the Creator, Itself; the buck private's </p>

<p> mistakes will kill him, but the general's </p>

<p> mistakes kill everyone. Before damning the </p>

<p> practically good, execrating the almost true, </p>

<p> and abominating the compellingly beautiful as </p>

<p> Temptation, always remember and bear in mind </p>

<p> that Money is not Evil; it is the worship
-------
of Money that possesses one's soul. We are </p>

<p> given beauty to enjoy while it lasts; the </p>

<p> mortal sin is worshipping beauty --- or any </p>

<p> other god that does not incorporate its </p>

<p> proper devil.</p>



<p> WORDS are ultraspacial structures created by abstracting </p>

<p>common features of significance while ignoring unique features. </p>

<p>Words amplify similarities and eliminate differences by wave </p>

<p>interference. Words are the product of fusing all the unique </p>

<p>images of several structures into an ultraspacial gestalt. </p>

<p> The gestalt represented by its abstract noun is not visible </p>

<p>to the material eye because it is a ultratridimensional physical </p>

<p>structure that is manifest to our <ent type='ORG'>Consciousness</ent> only as a form </p>

<p>of what we conceive to be mental energy, more rarified than </p>

<p>electromagnetic substance. A word is an image of an ultraspatial </p>

<p>mental Form; words are the very Ideas that <ent type='PERSON'>Plato</ent> talked about.</p>

<p> The tridimensional material eye can see only a unique, </p>

<p>material example of the gestalt at any one time. In other words, </p>

<p>a gestalt exists as an extension of its material manifestations </p>

<p>in the form of a trajectory through time and space; to wit, a
---------- ----
mental concept extends through no fewer than four dimensions. </p>

<p>(SIDE-1) The minds comprehends the dimensions of time; this is </p>

<p>why intelligence is identified with the sense of time. Abstract </p>

<p>verbal concepts are understood only as they can be comprehended </p>

<p>within the temporal dimensions of one's mind; a mind is perceived </p>

<p>to grow to the extent that it perceives precedents and </p>

<p>consequences. <ent type='ORG'>Athena</ent> is merely the god of int<ent type='LOC'>elle</ent>ct; the ruler of </p>

<p>consciousness is Kronus, <ent type='ORG'>the Overlord</ent> of Time and Change.</p>

<p> The nemesis of abstraction, as <ent type='PERSON'>Korzybski</ent> pointed out, is </p>

<p>that the symbol becomes the reality, and the individual </p>

<p>differences in the real world are occulted behind the Veils of </p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Maja</ent>. As the focus of the mind shifts from the immediately </p>

<p>tangible world to verbal concepts, the mind becomes separated </p>

<p>from the body and both lose their health. Paradise is a myth </p>

<p>about a preverbal <ent type='ORG'>Consciousness</ent>, before men created words and </p>

<p>subsequently mistook the symbol (idol) for reality (God); the </p>

<p>Fall of Man and his <ent type='ORG'>Expulsion</ent> is the consequence of worshipping </p>

<p>verbally fashioned images. Philosophers pretend to lead us back </p>

<p>to reality on ways paved with more words of higher abstraction, </p>

<p>like devils promising to lead us to Heaven. If the devil is the </p>

<p>Father of Lies, words are surely the Mother.</p>

<p> Conscious mind is a creation of words. Therefore, no one in </p>

<p>his socially defined, right-thinking, right-handed mind can </p>

<p>perceive anything not previously defined by words. Experiments </p>

<p>have found that people lacking the words to describe subtle </p>

<p>colours are also unable to distinguish fine differences in hues, </p>

<p>but as soon as they are given the words to define the </p>

<p>differences between crimson, scarlet, and vermillion, for </p>

<p>example, they no longer see all reds as red. Poets expand the </p>

<p>common <ent type='ORG'>Consciousness</ent> by giving new meanings to old words and by </p>

<p>coining new words. </p>

<p> Words referring to abstract concepts are projections of </p>

<p>spiritual structures from hyperspace into our mental space. </p>

<p>We are unable to know the higher dimensions of the hyperspacial </p>

<p>universe we live in because our culture lacks the verbal </p>

<p>concepts for our minds to perceive what our eyes plainly see. </p>

<p>Although there is no way that you can learn to swim without </p>

<p>getting wet, reading is the most efficient way for you to </p>

<p>acquire the vocabulary of hyperspace that you need for your eyes
----------
to open on <ent type='EVENT'>the New Heaven</ent> and <ent type='LOC'>New Earth</ent> of hyperspace. </p>

<p>Hyperspacial vocabulary is what this book is all about.</p>

<p> Scientific knowledge is nothing but verbal knowledge, and </p>

<p>knowledge is the key to power; humanity is ruled by words. The </p>

<p>physical and mathematical principles that explain the material </p>

<p>world of three dimensions also control the manifestations of </p>

<p>hyperspacial energies; e.g., e=mc^2 opens the way to the high-</p>

<p>dimensional energies of the atom. Furthermore, the very forms in </p>

<p>which higher-dimensional energies are represented serve as a </p>

<p>handle for wielding the power. This is what magic, idols, </p>

<p>charms, amulets, spells, incantations, hexes, and prayers are </p>

<p>all about. (*1)</p>

<p> Artists, scientists, and mystics who glimpse spirits dimly </p>

<p>through the Veils of <ent type='PERSON'>Maja</ent> limn a projection of the eternal </p>

<p>entities into the human dimensions of literature, theatre, </p>

<p>music, dance, architecture, engineering, philosophy, </p>

<p>mathematics, justice, politics, morality --- in a word, culture.
-------
Like pictorial art, all cultural artifacts compress hyperspacial </p>

<p>structures into fewer dimensions so that ideas are represented </p>

<p>in more or less tangible forms. The form is the specialized </p>

<p>language of its poet and the meaning of the form is the essence </p>

<p>of the myth. </p>

<p> The difference between science and religion is the </p>

<p>difference between the quantified equations of mathematics and </p>

<p>the unquantified equations of metaphore. Those who cannot focus </p>

<p>their mental scope with sufficient precision to count must </p>

<p>guesstimate relationships by comparing superficial attributes to </p>

<p>derive meanings from their experiences. The errors of both </p>

<p>science and religion are produced by logical deductions made </p>

<p>from inherently faulty language, but the errors cannot be </p>

<p>perceived by people who mistake their words for real things and </p>

<p>their language for a real map. <ent type='ORG'>Philosophic</ent> disputes are word </p>

<p>wars; those who live by their words also die by their words.</p>

<p> The highest energies are manifest in the power of pure </p>

<p>thought, which mortals call God. Words are the coins of thought, </p>

<p>like money is minted power. It is the extraspacial power of the </p>

<p>human God expressed through the words of men that vouchsafes our </p>

<p>articulate species dominion over all the dumb beasts of the </p>

<p>field, and word power is the very Divine soul deficient in all </p>

<p>other planetary life. The extraspacial power of God expressed </p>

<p>through the word is attested in <ent type='PERSON'>John</ent> 1:1, IN THE BEGINNING WAS </p>

<p>THE WORD AND THE WORD WAS WITH GOD, AND THE WORD WAS GOD.
---- ---- --- ---
Parsing the language of hyperspace reveals the very diction, </p>

<p>syntax, and grammar of Creation, Itself. </p>

<p> CLOSE THIS FILE</p>

<p> OPEN FILE "INTRO-G"</p>

<div> ============================================</div>

<p>SIDE-1</p>

<p> A trajectory is a mathematical and </p>

<p> physical reality that lacks tangible </p>

<p> substance, confounding all scientific </p>

<p> philosophers. A trajectory is a commonplace </p>

<p> example of a pure, objective thought form. A
------------
compound vortex is an infinite trajectory </p>

<p> compressed in time until its entire extension </p>

<p> can be comprehended within a single view. </p>

<div>---------------------------------------------------------------</div>

<p>*1 The automobile is actually a mathematical idea
expressed in a material form, like an idol, that enables us to
use the power of gasoline for propulsion. No other idol possesses
its devotees so compellingly as the automobile, nor does any
other god demand such human sacrifice, not even Ares; the apple
of our modern <ent type='LOC'>Eden</ent> is a red sports car.</p>



<p> ________________________________
I I
I The sound of one hand clapping I
I is the echo I
I of your own praise I
I for your own beliefs I
I reflected from the wall I
I of an indifferent world, I
I and heard only by yourself. I
I________________________________I</p>

<p> AS modern physics becomes mystical, "the ZEN of science" has </p>

<p>become a parlour cliche among the scientifically literate. ZEN </p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>Masters</ent> penetrate the Veils of <ent type='PERSON'>Maja</ent> cast by verbal logic to </p>

<p>apprehend reality by direct experience. (SIDE-1) Since they </p>

<p>eschew words, <ent type='ORG'>ZEN Masters</ent> write no books and preach no sermons. </p>

<p>ZEN disparages texts because no mathematical terminology existed </p>

<p>in its high and far-off times when the YOGAs were developed </p>

<p>empirically. (*2) Nevertheless the <ent type='ORG'>Masters</ent> knew a mathematical </p>

<p>language, and they used it to express their knowledge of </p>

<p>hyperspace. They composed their KATAs as mathematical equations </p>

<p>in the languages of art, music, chanting, dancing, theatre, </p>

<p>graphics, and architecture. The arts inspired with ZEN are </p>

<p>exquisitely measured. The <ent type='ORG'>Hyperspace</ent> Trilogy is a Rosetta <ent type='PERSON'>Stone</ent> </p>

<p>translating the language of the ZEN arts into the language of </p>

<p>modern science. This book could be called <ent type='ORG'>The Physics</ent> of <ent type='PERSON'>TAO</ent>. </p>

<p> The sage says, "Seek and ye will find. Ask and it will be </p>

<p>answered unto you." Scientists are fond of saying that their </p>

<p>business is discovering the right questions to ask. If </p>

<p>scientists weren't so cocksure that they knew everything there </p>

<p>is to know about their business, any lawyer could tell them how </p>

<p>to discover the right questions. The correct question is the
---------------------------
question to which you already know the answer. If you don't have
---------------------------------------------
an immediate answer, you must know where to find it. No other </p>

<p>questions are of any use in the enterprise of deducing Nature's </p>

<p>secrets. </p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>ZEN Masters</ent> are fond of answering disciples asking for </p>

<p>wisdom by a question called a <ent type='ORG'>KOAN</ent>. <ent type='ORG'>KOAN</ent>s are believed to be </p>

<p>nonsense intended to confuse one's mind until a critical tension </p>

<p>precipitates a mystical insight. <ent type='ORG'>KOAN</ent>s are not nonsense; they </p>

<p>are a special kind of question to which you already know the </p>

<p>answer, but you don't want to know you know because such </p>

<p>knowledge is self-knowledge; the most heinous crime of this </p>

<p>civilization is to be caught in possession of self-knowledge. </p>

<p>Self-knowledge, you see, is the special kind of knowledge that </p>

<p>releases a person from the <ent type='PERSON'>KARMIC</ent> wheel of life and the rule of </p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Satan</ent>, however you conceive your devil. As soon as you answer </p>

<p>the <ent type='ORG'>KOAN</ent>, you are exp<ent type='LOC'>elle</ent>d from Plato's cave, and the game of </p>

<p>darkness is over. The Laughing Buddha in the heart of your </p>

<p>personal <ent type='ORG'>Lotus</ent> Blossum isn't ready to cash your chips because of </p>

<p>Enlightenment until damn good and ready. The mental crisis of </p>

<p>the <ent type='ORG'>KOAN</ent> is resolved by formulating a plausible answer that </p>

<p>satisfies the curiosity without actually taking the terminal </p>

<p>gaze into the brilliant Face of God. Psychoanalysts get </p>

<p>plausible answers from all their patients; the trouble with </p>

<p>psychoanalysis is that the entire science is nothing but a </p>

<p>plausible answer to estop its advertised purpose of self-</p>

<p>discovery.</p>

<p> All those posing unanswerable questions, or declaring that </p>

<p>their questions can't be answered are not in the business of </p>

<p>creating science, nor do they have any intention of informing </p>

<p>the public; their real purpose is obscuring knowledge and </p>

<p>confusing you in order that they may gain and hold their </p>

<p>advantage over you. Rhetorical questions take many forms, and </p>

<p>none are so beguiling as the scientific poser. Rhetoric </p>

<p>manipulates automatic psychological reflexes so as to make the </p>

<p>audience believe that the authority who cannot answer his own </p>

<p>questions knows something that his audience doesn't know. The </p>

<p>only thing he knows that you don't know is how to get well paid </p>

<p>for knowing nothing you don't know --- and telling you to your </p>

<p>face.</p>

<p> CLOSE THIS FILE</p>

<p> OPEN FILE "INTRO-H"</p>

<div> ==================================================</div>

<p>SIDE-1</p>

<p> ZEN defies comprehension by Europeans </p>

<p> for reasons similar to the incomprehensibility </p>

<p> of mathematics by broadly focussed minds. It </p>

<p> is simply impossible to describe the </p>

<p> essentially hard-headed precision of ZEN </p>

<p> practise by soft-headed language, and it is </p>

<p> just the softest of <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> heads that are </p>

<p> attracted to ZEN as an escape from </p>

<p> responsibility, rather than for love of </p>

<p> order. Like a symphony and a cathedral, ZEN </p>

<p> is pure mathematics with out words. ZEN is </p>

<p> the essence of art. (*1) </p>

<div>---------------------------------------------------------------</div>

<p>*1 I used to tease waitresses by ordering two fried
eggs, the first egg fried on one side and the second fried on the
other. Eventually I met a serving maid who gave me exactly what I
asked for. She sure shut my mouth. I wonder what she is doing,
now?</p>

<p> I've never met a ZEN freak who used <ent type='ORG'>KOAN</ent>s to blow his mind.
They were all playing one upmanship on me, in the curious belief
that posing an unanswerable question made them superior. They
invested all their faith in the conviction that the <ent type='ORG'>KOAN</ent> can't be
answered logically, so they have something greater than reason
going for them. Children delight in playing with words to create
statements that are self-contradictory and impossible to realize;
it is a childish mind that believes unanswerable questions are
more significant than answers. When the <ent type='ORG'>KOAN</ent> is answered, like
drawing the Sword from the <ent type='PERSON'>Stone</ent>, they not only lose their game,
but they also lose their faith. It satisfies their competitive
humility to proclaim they are stupid, but no one can be smarter
than their <ent type='ORG'>GURU</ent>, so they are wiped out when their GURU's bluff is
called.</p>

<div>--------------------------------------------------------</div>

<p>*2 Every arcane study has devotees of vastly different degrees
of competence. <ent type='ORG'>Groupies</ent> preserve and preach all precepts
indiscriminately, because they don't know the difference between
genius and learned fools.</p>

<p> The moral is that everyone who believes he knows what's what
should write his solutions for world salvation. Sooner or later,
people will regard every recorded folly as inspired wisdom; it
could be yours.</p>

<p>30
FILENAME: INTRO-H</p>

<p> ____________________________________________________
I I
I Like proverbs and all other legislation, I
I every scientific law and mathematical equation I
I is contradicted I
I by another scientific law and mathematical proof. I
I I
I Wisdom is a matter I
I of choosing the law I
I which satisfies your purpose. I
I____________________________________________________I</p>

<p> YOU will find nothing of theoretical importance in this </p>

<p>book that you don't already know; all you will find in this book </p>

<p>is innumerable different views of what you already know and </p>

<p>believe in different contexts. Since the <ent type='PERSON'>TAO</ent> of "phasics" turns </p>

<p>everything into its opposite, you will find that everything you </p>

<p>believe is self-contradictory; nevertheless, PLUS CA CHANGE and </p>

<p>all that. How much of this book you will understand and believe </p>

<p>depends entirely on your ability to maintain mental focus on the </p>

<p>structural points of the subject so that you can hold its </p>

<p>identity as I change the perspective. By the time you finish </p>

<p>this book, you will realize that the entire universe is your own </p>

<p>self, turned around every which way and inside out. </p>

<p> This is not a scholarly thesis; it is not the product of </p>

<p>laboratory experiments, abstruse calculations, nor of library </p>

<p>research. Everything you will read in this book is derived from </p>

<p>observation of everyday, ordinary life. I shall introduce </p>

<p>cardinal cases with commonplace observations or some commonplace </p>

<p>facts and see what comes by way of some commonplace logic. As </p>

<p>you follow my line of reason, you will see that your common </p>

<p>sense leads to insights that are ignored and denied by </p>

<p>authorized versions of truth. Now, what do you do? Do you deny </p>

<p>your own senses and let authorities tell you what your life is </p>

<p>all about, or do you decide for yourself the basis of your facts </p>

<p>and take responsibility for making up your own mind? </p>

<p>Professional authorities are convinced that the public is too </p>

<p>stupid and ignorant to understand science, health, religion, and </p>

<p>politics, not to mention teaching your children. The authorities </p>

<p>have always condemned the <ent type='NORP'>Socratic</ent> dialogue as a corruption of </p>

<p>youth. You won't think you are so stupid and ignorant by the </p>

<p>time you finish reading this book. </p>

<p> It is just because this thesis is based on common </p>

<p>experience that you can satisfy yourself of its truth. If you do </p>

<p>not agree with me after checking my observations and facts </p>

<p>against your own, tell me about it. You may be right; we may </p>

<p>both be right from our respective points of view and frames of </p>

<p>reference. If you find me mistaken, this book will have served a </p>

<p>worthwhile purpose as an object lesson illustrating the ways </p>

<p>that observations are susceptible to misperceptions, common </p>

<p>facts are liable to be mistaken, and common sense can lead to </p>

<p>common delusion. You need only look at the continual revisions </p>

<p>of established scientific facts to see that the most highly </p>

<p>qualified experts are just as subject to changing views as the </p>

<p>rest of us --- which is why they should not be believed with </p>

<p>less question than you are expected to direct at this book. (*1)</p>

<p>The best advice your medical doctor will ever give you is </p>

<p>"seek a second opinion"; the advice is just as wise when you </p>

<p>attend doctors of philosophy.</p>

<p> During earlier years of my life while my livelihood </p>

<p>depended on orthodox beliefs, I refused to give a thought to any </p>

<p>of the ideas I am able to entertain now that my employer doesn't </p>

<p>care what science I believe, as long as I don't bad mouth his </p>

<p>politics (I work for the government, now). So do not suppose </p>

<p>that I have no sympathy for the authorities; I have believed </p>

<p>their doctrine for the same reasons they maintain their faith. I </p>

<p>use satire only to reduce the awe of authority that stultifies </p>

<p>people under oppressive doctrines. As you know, no one hates </p>

<p>smokers more than a quitter --- who longs for a drag.</p>

<p> The critical word in the previous sentence is oppressive.
----------
As long as a doctrine is bigger than its believers, it opens </p>

<p>their minds to explore the vastness of its comprehension; no </p>

<p>believer is going to give up that space --- nor should anyone. </p>

<p>But when its believers outgrow their doctrine, it becomes </p>

<p>spiritually oppressive, and they seek a greater freedom. And so, </p>

<p>you see, no doctrine is inherently true or false; its truth </p>

<p>depends upon how well it fits the vital needs and the mental </p>

<p>stature of the people who believe it. Try this book on for size. </p>

<p>If it fits your head, give it a test run on your road of life; </p>

<p>if it cramps your style or rattles your chassis, you should have </p>

<p>learned by now that we have to kiss a lot of frogs before we </p>

<p>find our princes, and lick a lot of muddy feet before we find a </p>

<p>God that repays our belief with as much support as we give.</p>

<p> My comments on religions are not informed by scholarship </p>

<p>but merely reflect generally held conceptions that outsiders </p>

<p>entertain about creeds other than their own, like ethnic jokes </p>

<p>express one's perspective on foreigners. Outsiders perceive </p>

<p>meanings quite different from insiders. Confession, for example,
----------
has an entirely different meaning for <ent type='NORP'>Romans</ent> than for other </p>

<p>people; you have to be a <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> to experience it. Which is the </p>

<p>true meaning? It depends on whether you are looking from the </p>

<p>inside or the outside, doesn't it? Nevertheless, ethnic jokes </p>

<p>express human identities, values, and follies more acutely than </p>

<p>anthropological studies --- especially the identity, the values, </p>

<p>and the follies of the t<ent type='LOC'>elle</ent>r. Some pious people may not be able </p>

<p>to tolerate the respect I have for any church but theirs, nor </p>

<p>can they tolerate any mention of their obvious follies. I ask </p>

<p>you --- is a sense of humour and appreciation of the ludicrous a </p>

<p>gift of the devil? No soul could abide in a Heaven without </p>

<p>humour if hell holds all the fun. If I failed to offend anyone, </p>

<p>let me know and the next edition will treat you the same as </p>

<p>everyone else. </p>

<p> If you find this book intolerable, it is mainly because you </p>

<p>have not been exposed to this kind of ideas before. You will be </p>

<p>surprised at how inoffensive they will be the next time you have </p>

<p>an encounter of this challenging kind. The initial denial, </p>

<p>ridicule, and scepticism of Flying Saucer sightings gradually </p>

<p>changed to belief for no reason other than the persistence of </p>

<p>the reports for forty years; it doesn't matter that most of the </p>

<p>reports are not true, and <ent type='EVENT'>UFO</ent> hysteria was composed by the media </p>

<p>to supply popular demand. If you haven't come here from </p>

<p>Buckminster <ent type='PERSON'>Fuller</ent>, see how his "Synergetics 1 &amp; 2" grab you when </p>

<p>you go there from here.</p>

<p> Most people expect to understand a book on one reading; a </p>

<p>book baffling at first sight can't get a literary review. I </p>

<p>expect many readers to appreciate the insights into their </p>

<p>special interest and competence, but be lost through the pages </p>

<p>referring to other kinds of knowledge. You must realize, </p>

<p>however, that this book would have no reason for its existence </p>

<p>if it explained hyperspace from the mathematical view, alone --- </p>

<p>as all other books on this subject do. This is a synthesis of </p>

<p>many disciplines and philosophies; your mind must be capable of </p>

<p>fusing the concepts and languages of many arts, crafts, sports, </p>

<p>and sciences into a single gestalt in order to understand the </p>

<p>physical structure and manifestations of hyperspace in your
----
everyday life; this book is a holy scripture for the working
-------------
days of the week. Mathematics and metaphore, high philosophy and </p>

<p>vulgarity, are combined in the same paragraph, if not in the </p>

<p>same sentence, so that you may realize that all languages </p>

<p>express the very same truths. Thus, the believers of every faith </p>

<p>will find scientific substantiation of their religion in the </p>

<p>structure of hyperspace, and artists will find their common </p>

<p>identity with scientists in politics' strangest bed. </p>

<p>Mathematics, science, art, philosophy and religion cannot be </p>

<p>experienced in everyday life unless they are expressed as </p>

<p>everyday ideas in everyday language.</p>

<p> This book is as paradoxical as its subject. It is clear and </p>

<p>confused, profound and superficial, comic and tragic, ludicrous </p>

<p>and reverent, it has no single thread of reason but spreads a </p>

<p>tapestry, it is incoherent but an indivisible whole, it is fact </p>

<p>and fantasy --- with more truth in the fantasy than in the fact. </p>

<p>Writing it has been my <ent type='ORG'>KOAN</ent>; I composed it to be your <ent type='ORG'>KOAN</ent>. </p>

<p>There is at least one epiphany for every reader, but, like a </p>

<p>joke, you must be baffled to get it. This is a book for reading </p>

<p>many times between reflections on life because it yields </p>

<p>different meanings as you learn your living. Read it like a </p>

<p>Bible that can be understood only in parts, according to your </p>

<p>experience, intelligence, and wisdom --- and the number of </p>

<p>children you have raised --- especially the little darlings who </p>

<p>came with your second spouse.</p>

<p> Understanding hyperspace is nothing but the ability to </p>

<p>comprehend plural concepts, including polar opposites, within </p>

<p>the same gestalt. Not only have I written the text to reflect </p>

<p>the confusion of hyperspace, but I have also composed the format </p>

<p>to serve as your object lesson in comprehending multiple views </p>

<p>simultaneously. A magazine style should present no difficulty to </p>

<p>a generation brought up on split-screen movies, multi-media </p>

<p>light shows, and studying for academic exams while watching </p>

<p>television with a friendly friend of the opposite sex. After </p>

<p>reading the sidenotes to get the relevance, the logic is woven </p>

<p>by the continuous text. On the third run through, you may read </p>

<p>the footnotes without feeling interrupted. </p>

<p> Reading this book is somewhat like listening to a symphony; </p>

<p>on first hearing, it is noise. It is only after the structure </p>

<p>and the details have imprinted a gestalt in one's mind that </p>

<p>melodies and counterpoint can be heard as musical architecture. </p>

<p>The meaning of music is the gestalt; otherwise it is only notes; </p>

<p>the beautiful sensation of music is produced by experiencing the </p>

<p>energy of the gestalt amplified by harmonic resonance with each </p>

<p>note. Likewise, the meaning of this book is in its gestalt, a </p>

<p>synthesis of all its disparate parts in a higher dimension of </p>

<p>consciousness. Nevertheless, each page can also be fruitful </p>

<p>without further reference; this book offers something for </p>

<p>everyone at any time.</p>

<p> Once you are informed that lw=a, no further instruction is </p>

<p>required for you to realize that a/l=w and a/w=l; the three </p>

<p>equations express the very same structure. If you can only </p>

<p>memorize equations, however, they will always seem mutually </p>

<p>contradictory to you; lacking any intuitive understanding of why </p>

<p>lw=a, the only proof you have of its truth is that the wallpaper </p>

<p>fits the wall. As a consequence, <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> was adequately trained </p>

<p>to cut wall paper, but his groupies are unable to calculate the </p>

<p>cost of deceptive packaging. </p>

<p> There is nothing in this book that is not self-evident from </p>

<p>elementary equations known to everyone before entering high </p>

<p>school. The only reason this book can be considered necessary </p>

<p>reading is to clear your mind of the rote thinking inculcated by </p>

<p>formal schooling. Formal education is determined to prohibit </p>

<p>everyone from relating facts into a whole body of knowledge that </p>

<p>inspires wisdom. Deprived of faculties for judgement, the public </p>

<p>is unable to understand what is really being done to them; thus, </p>

<p>everyone is forced to pay the professional establishment </p>

<p>exhorbitant fees for simple services everyone can do for himself </p>

<p>--- like filing divorce papers --- and rendered susceptible to </p>

<p>believing everything one is told, like perennial children. </p>

<p>Liberated women know exactly what I mean.</p>

<p> You don't learn about hyperspace so much as you grow into
----- ----
understanding as a consequence of mental/physical/spiritual </p>

<p>evolution, like you grow into walking, talking, and sexual </p>

<p>consciousness. Always remember and bear in mind that hyperspace </p>

<p>extends through more than three dimensions, so you must be able </p>

<p>to read construction plans easily before you can make sense of </p>

<p>this book. In short, hyperspace is not difficult to understand; </p>

<p>if its meaning does not develop like music after some </p>

<p>rumination, comprehension is simply impossible, so don't sweat it. </p>

<p> CLOSE THIS FILE</p>

<p> OPEN FILE "INTRO-I"</p>

<div>----------------------------------------------------------------</div>

<p>* I am impressed that the speakers at conferences are
determined to persuade their audiences to believe, not
criticize, and the audiences are seeking something to believe
rather than a mandate to exercise their judgement. Thus, both
parties waste the opportunty to learn something --- like, maybe
they are mistaken.</p>

<p> 30
FILENAME: INTRO-I</p>

<p> ________________________
I I
I The <ent type='ORG'>Hyperspace</ent> Trilogy I
I is a universal theory. I
I________________________I</p>

<p> "<ent type='ORG'>TIME</ent> TRAVEL --- <ent type='ORG'>The Secret Science</ent> of The <ent type='EVENT'>UFO</ent>s " is the </p>

<p>first volume of a trilogy. This First Book puts you on The Yellow </p>

<p>Brick Road by way by studying some simple models illustrating how </p>

<p>familiar space is converted into familiar time by increasingly
----- ----
fine division and increasingly accelerated velocity. Once you </p>

<p>arrive in <ent type='GPE'>The Emerald City</ent> of hyperspace, you will learn how </p>

<p>higher dimensions are defined by the familiar measurements of </p>

<p>energy; i.e., frequency, phase, and amplitude. You will see how </p>

<p>the familiar physical fields of force known as nuclear, </p>

<p>electromagnetic, gravitic, sonic, and even life and mental </p>

<p>forces, constitute a scale of successively rarified hyperspacial </p>

<p>worlds manifest to our senses as pure energy. <ent type='ORG'>Hyperspace</ent> is </p>

<p>nothing but energy, and the geometry of hyperspace is nothing but </p>

<p>a mathematical plotting of the laws governing transformations of </p>

<p>energy. </p>

<p> "<ent type='ORG'>TIME</ent> TRAVEL --- <ent type='ORG'>THe Secret Science</ent> of The <ent type='EVENT'>UFO</ent>s"</p>

<p>presents a graphic solution to <ent type='ORG'>the Unified Field Equations</ent> that </p>

<p>has defied the entire scientific world for a century. Unlike </p>

<p>e=mc^2, which could not be implemented without an army of the </p>

<p>world's most creative engineers funded by national treasuries, </p>

<p>e=mc^3 is within the economic capacity of a home workshop, </p>

<p>enabling free-enterprising <ent type='GPE'>Yankee</ent> know-how to open a new era of </p>

<p>peace and prosperity like the palmy days of Edison, <ent type='ORG'>Ford</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent>, </p>

<p>the <ent type='ORG'>Wright Brothers</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Tim Leary</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Hugh Hefner</ent>. To the degree </p>

<p>that the experiments of <ent type='PERSON'>Henry Moray</ent>, Thomas Townsend-Brown, </p>

<p>Bruce de Palma, and <ent type='PERSON'>Pat Flanagan</ent> are as successful as they </p>

<p>claim, the first lights are already shining into the New Age. </p>

<p>Professional engineers will develop <ent type='EVENT'>this Unified Field Theory</ent> to </p>

<p>technical details beyond the scope of this book --- not to </p>

<p>mention the competence of this author. After giving a </p>

<p>ringful of keys to several adventurers who would be kings, the rest </p>

<p>of this book will speculate on the probable design and </p>

<p>engineering of the <ent type='ORG'>Flying Saucers</ent>. Once we have some practicable </p>

<p>idea of how the <ent type='ORG'>Saucers</ent> operate, the possibilities of who builds
--- ---
them, where they come from, and what they are doing here are
----- ----
reduced to a practical argument.</p>

<p> The Second Book of <ent type='ORG'>Hyperspace</ent>, titled "LIVING CRYSTAL --- </p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>The Philosopher</ent>'s <ent type='PERSON'>Stone</ent>", explains the theorems of hypergeometry, </p>

<p>providing inventive explorers with a mathematical foundation to </p>

<p>create new engines, sciences, and arts. The discovery of the New </p>

<p>World of <ent type='ORG'>Hyperspace</ent> will transform our civilization more </p>

<p>radically than the discovery of <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>. Like the early </p>

<p>explorers of this world found wealth, power, and fame, the </p>

<p>explorers of the New Reality on the other side of the universal </p>

<p>Klein Bottle will also found their empires and fortunes --- if </p>

<p>they manage to avoid the savage cannibals prowling the </p>

<p>hyperspacial jungles and the jealousy of the nobility when they </p>

<p>return with their finds to civilization --- you are better off </p>

<p>with the savages. <ent type='ORG'>Success</ent> could be yours, if you are young, </p>

<p>energetic, enterprising --- and if your spouse will support you </p>

<p>while you get your act together.</p>

<p> The theorems of hypergeometry actually describe the </p>

<p>properties of crystals, the quintessence of solid state physics.
--------
Crystals provide the means for tapping the titanic energies of </p>

<p>hyperspace for human industry. By the time you read The Second </p>

<p>Book of <ent type='ORG'>Hyperspace</ent>, you will realize that the human body is </p>

<p>actually a living crystal, the most highly evolved crystal in </p>

<p>this world. Miracles are worked by holy men, such as <ent type='PERSON'>Jesus</ent>, </p>

<p>when they learn to alter the crystal parameters of their bodies. </p>

<p>The Rock on which Christ built His Church is the very
----
Philosopher's <ent type='PERSON'>Stone</ent> sought by alchemists throughout history;
-------------------
like the Riddle of The Sphynx, <ent type='PERSON'>Peter</ent> is the human body. The very
-----------------------
fact that the Philosopher King Arthur's <ent type='PERSON'>Stone</ent> is sought indicates </p>

<p>that this hyperscience was known by prehistoric cabals; they are </p>

<p>probably still alive and herding the human livestock on this </p>

<p>lively little planet for their own benefit more than ours. Anyone </p>

<p>who trusts the shepherd when he comes bearing gifts has got to be </p>

<p>some kind of sheep.</p>

<p> "<ent type='EVENT'>KARMA</ent> --- <ent type='ORG'>The Birth</ent>, Life, and Death of YOUR SOUL"</p>

<p>completes this trilogy. You will learn why some people are </p>

<p>healthy, wealthy, and wise, while others suffer various </p>

<p>deficiency diseases. Even love, marriage, and happiness are </p>

<p>determined by each person's position in hyperspace, commonly </p>

<p>plotted by astrologists. Just as modern science has already </p>

<p>opened hyperspace for trade and commerce without knowing what </p>

<p>they hath wrought, the spiritual dimensions of hyperspace are </p>

<p>all described in the world's religions without anyone knowing </p>

<p>what the great Teachers were really talking about. You will </p>

<p>realize the meaning of your life and your eternal soul by the </p>

<p>time you complete The <ent type='ORG'>Hyperspace</ent> Trilogy. (*1)</p>

<p> If I live long enough, the story of how I made all these </p>

<p>discoveries in the ZEN martial arts will be told when I finish </p>

<p>writing the first book I began, "FIERCE LOVE --- The Secret </p>

<p>of Spiritual Power in The ZEN MARTIAL ARTS".</p>

<p> The Flying Saucer is a challenge to science and politics. As </p>

<p>far as the millions of <ent type='ORG'>wonderersare</ent> concerned, however, the <ent type='EVENT'>UFO</ent> </p>

<p>phenomenon is an essentially religious excitement, the secular </p>

<p>apotheosis of the Messiah. Unlike any other study, The <ent type='ORG'>Hyperspace</ent> </p>

<p>Trilogy responds to all public concerns by explaining the </p>

<p>technological, the political, and the religious mysteries </p>

<p>concurrently. This book is the beginning of a literary work </p>

<p>destined to be a seminal classic of the New Age, a text for </p>

<p>researchers, inventors, engineers, farmers and gardeners, </p>

<p>psychologists and psychiatrists, religious disciples, medical </p>

<p>doctors and interminably ill patients, politicians, advertisers, </p>

<p>artists, architects, athletes, science-fiction writers and </p>

<p>everyone who wants to know why people are such problems, </p>

<p>especially the people we love. You are not starting to read a </p>

<p>book but beginning a graduate university course of studies that </p>

<p>will change your perception more drastically than an O.D. ticket </p>

<p>on the SugarCube Express. The <ent type='ORG'>Hyperspace</ent> Trilogy is the kind of </p>

<p>study that enables its readers to fullfill their vocations to </p>

<p>become holistic teachers needed to lead people into the New Age.</p>

<p> CLOSE THIS FILE</p>

<p> OPEN FILE "INTRO-J"</p>

<div>---------------------------------------------------------------</div>

<p>*1 Everyone prays that "Thy will be done", and then prays that
"My will be done". We'll get one or the other, shan't we.</p>

<p> 30
FILENAME: INTRO-J</p>

<p> __________________________________________________
I I
I Curiosity about hyperspace I
I is the mental forerunner I
I of our metamorphosis I
I into the <ent type='GPE'>Kingdom</ent> of Christ, I
I like curiosity about sex I
I is the forerunner I
I of sexual maturation. I
I People with no curiosity I
I about the higher dimensions of ther existence I
I are not yet ready for their Salvation. I
I I
I The direct perception I
I of our Divine Entity in hyperspace I
I is the spiritual destiny of every soul, I
I like parenthood is the destiny of most mortals. I
I__________________________________________________I</p>

<p> EVERY creature is born into this world instinct with all the </p>

<p>knowledge it needs to understand the meaning of its own life and </p>

<p>solve its problems without consulting professional authorities. </p>

<p>Rather than seek a teacher, you are better advised to find your </p>

<p>instincts; your Christ <ent type='ORG'>Consciousness</ent> is nothing but your higher </p>

<p>instincts. The little child sent to lead us is a symbol of our
------------
instincts. The child will show you your way by the following </p>

<p>pentalogue. A real little blind child led me --- which just goes </p>

<p>to show that the blind can lead.</p>

<p>1. The <ent type='ORG'>Universe</ent> does not hide from Her Children.</p>

<p> The <ent type='ORG'>Truth</ent> is always in plain sight.</p>

<p> But the <ent type='ORG'>Truth</ent> is always subtle.</p>

<p> The Child must be perceptive.</p>

<p>2. The <ent type='ORG'>Universe</ent> does not deceive Her Children.</p>

<p> The <ent type='ORG'>Truth</ent> is always simple.</p>

<p> But the <ent type='ORG'>Truth</ent> is always comprehensive.</p>

<p> The Child must be responsible.</p>

<p>3. The <ent type='ORG'>Universe</ent> wants Her Children to know Right from Wrong.</p>

<p> The <ent type='ORG'>Truth</ent> always works.</p>

<p> The <ent type='ORG'>Truth</ent> works immediately.</p>

<p> The <ent type='ORG'>Truth</ent> works without effort.</p>

<p> The <ent type='ORG'>Truth</ent> is always gentle.</p>

<p> The Child must be practical.</p>

<p>4. The <ent type='ORG'>Universe</ent> wants Her Children to love life.</p>

<p> The <ent type='ORG'>Truth</ent> is always joyous.</p>

<p> But the <ent type='ORG'>Truth</ent> is always changing.</p>

<p> The Child must be reborn each day.</p>

<p> Rebirth is the other side of death's door.</p>

<p>5. The <ent type='ORG'>Universe</ent> is an Equal Opportunity Teacher.</p>

<p> She answers all who ask in commitment to the answer.</p>

<p> It's a wise Child that knows when to stop asking </p>

<p> questions. </p>

<p> It is a wiser parent that knows when to stop answering </p>

<p> them. </p>

<p> END OF INTRODUCTION GO TO CHAPTER 1</p>

</xml>