<xml><p>
<ent type='GPE'>FILE</ent> FROM <ent type='ORG'>FYEO</ent> 241
COPYRIGHT (c) 1990 TIGER PUBLICATIONS
POST OFFICE BOX 8759 AMARILLO TX 79114
SUBSCRIPTIONS $55 (US, <ent type='GPE'>Canada</ent>, APO, FPO)
PER YEAR UNTIL 1 Oct 90 $60 Thereafter
OVERSEAS ASK MILITARY-RT FOR RATES

IRAQ'S MISSILES
<ent type='GPE'>Iraq</ent> has bought or developed an impressive array of tactical
and medium-range ballistic missiles. These include:
* Al-Abid: Tested in Dec 1989 as a satellite launcher. Would
have a range of 2000km (1250 miles) if used in a surface-to-surface mode. It is a three-stage missile weighing 48 tons. The
first stage has a cluster of five (Scud?) engines with a combined
thrust of 70 tons.
* Tammuz: Possibly another version (or use) of the Al-Abid. Has
a range of 2000km (1250 miles). Was tested in Dec 1989.
Warhead could be 500-1000 pounds.
* <ent type='PERSON'>Condor</ent>-II: Developed jointly with <ent type='GPE'>Egypt</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Argentina</ent>. It
would have had a range of 965km (600 miles) and carried a 1000-pound warhead, but the project was derailed by US diplomatic
More : <special>Y</special>es/<special>N</special>o ?
pressure. <ent type='GPE'>Iraq</ent>, which viewed <ent type='PERSON'>Condor</ent> as only one of several
programs, appears to have allowed it to drop while using much of
the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> and <ent type='NORP'>Italian</ent> technology in the Fahd.
* Al-Husayn: A modified version of the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> Scud rocket. The
<ent type='GPE'>Iraq</ent>is took three <ent type='ORG'>Scuds</ent>, removed the fuel tanks from one and cut
them in half, then used the sections to lengthen the fuel tanks of
the other two <ent type='ORG'>Scuds</ent> (increasing fuel from 4 to 5 tons). This gave
them the 620km (400 mile) range to reach <ent type='GPE'>Teheran</ent>, although the
warhead was reduced to as little as 300 pounds. [When it first
appeared, the Al-Husayn raised questions about the INF treaty
(which left <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Scuds</ent> in Europe as legal short-range missiles).
It was thought that the range increase had been achieved by less
extensive modifications and that the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent>s could evade the
treaty with similar modifications. The US is now satisfied that the
modifications are impossible to hide.] Reports that this missile
used strap-on boosters are now known to have been only
speculation on the part of Western analysts. The Al-Husayn is
horribly inaccurate, with a CEP of (i.e. a 50% chance of landing
within) 2000m of its target. It is strongly suspected that <ent type='GPE'>Iraq</ent> can
now manufacture the entire Al-Husayn.
* Al-Abbas: This missile, an upgraded version of Al-Husayn built
in <ent type='GPE'>Iraq</ent>, has been flight tested. It has a range of 900km (560
miles), more than enough to reach <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent>. The improved range
More : <special>Y</special>es/<special>N</special>o ?
does not bring more <ent type='NORP'>Iranian</ent> cities within striking distance, but
does allow the missile to be launched from most of <ent type='GPE'>Iraq</ent>, rather
than the limited area north of Al Amarah where most Al-Husayns
were launched. The small 250-pound warhead would be little more
than a nuisance (beyond the city block it fell into) unless it was
equipped with a chemical charge. It is reportedly much more
accurate than the older Al-Husayn, with a CEP of only 300m.
* Fahd: Originally begun as Project 395, Fahd is a solid-fuel
family of missiles. One variant has a range of 250km, another of
500km+. They will eventually replace Al-Husayn.
* SS-300: A <ent type='NORP'>Brazilian</ent> missile with a range of only 190 miles but a
huge 2200-pound warhead, enough to do serious military
damage. <ent type='GPE'>Brazil</ent> has tested the engines of this missile; <ent type='GPE'>Iraq</ent> has
them on order.
* Scud-B: A <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> free-flight bombardment missile with a range
of 175 miles and a 2000-pound warhead. While the <ent type='GPE'>Iraq</ent>is have
these, they are primarily used as a source of parts and
technology for the improved Al-Husayn.
* Frog-7: A <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> artillery bombardment weapon with a range of
only 45 miles and a payload of 1000 pounds. Huge numbers of
an improved version (range 90km), built locally as the Laith, were
fired at <ent type='NORP'>Iranian</ent> forces and border towns during the war. <ent type='GPE'>Iraq</ent> is
developing a chemical warhead for the Laith.
More : <special>Y</special>es/<special>N</special>o ?
* <ent type='ORG'>Ababil</ent>: A family of artillery rockets based on the <ent type='NORP'>Yugoslav</ent>
M87 design. There are 50km and 100km versions.
END OF <ent type='GPE'>FILE</ent>

</p></xml>