<xml><p>Issue No. 19, December 1984</p>

<p>For <ent type='EVENT'>the White Race</ent>, <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> democracy has
been an <ent type='ORG'>Unmitigated Disester</ent>.</p>

<p> The Era of Political
Parties is over</p>

<p>With the Reagan landslide the U.S. is rapidly mov-ing towards a tyrannical one party <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> dictatorship
aimed at the destruction of <ent type='EVENT'>the White Race</ent>. Conventional
Politics are no longer the answer. To be effective the <ent type='ORG'>White</ent>
Race must use other means.</p>

<p>One of the most effective stratagems the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> have developed
over the millenniums for controlling the <ent type='ORG'>goyim</ent> is the Divide and Con-quer technique. This they have done brilliantly and honed to a fine
edge. They utilize it in a thousand different areas of endeavor, among
which religion, race and politics are only a few of the major
categories.</p>

<p>The main target and the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> most dangerous enemy is without
a doubt <ent type='EVENT'>the White Race</ent>, although only the <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent> is aware of this. Con-versely, the <ent type='ORG'>White</ent> Man, who may be brilliant in many field, is
strangely, also the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> most gullible and cooperative victim. When
it comes to the issues of race and religion, the <ent type='ORG'>White</ent> Man is un-doubtedly one of the dumbest creatures on the face of the earth
the <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent> has capitalized handily on this <ent type='ORG'>White</ent> Man's <ent type='PERSON'>Achilles</ent>' heel.
In this dissertation we want to examine the issue of <ent type='ORG'>potitics</ent> and how
the <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent> has utilized the technique of Divide and Conquer to
neutralize, subdue, and manipulate <ent type='EVENT'>the White Race</ent>, not only in
<ent type='GPE'>America</ent>, but throughout the world.</p>

<p>The key word in this deadly game of confuse, divide, manipulate
and conquer is DEMOCRACY. Whereas our Founding Fathers were
not astute enough to excrete the <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent> from our political system and
our society (<ent type='PERSON'>Benjamin Franklin</ent> tried. See P. 260 of Nat. Etern. rel
they were intelligent enough to know that every "democracy" had
In It the seeds of its own self-destruction. They tried to set up a
Republic, which in essence really differs very little from a democracy.
Both cater to the lowest elements of a free-loading political electorate,
until the parasites and the free-loaders are eventually the masters
of an ever shrinking productive segment of the population. The end
rest is the destruction of the producers and the breakdown of the</p>



<p>political and social structure. Chaos, race-mixing and crime mount
inneasingly as the social fabric disintegrates. In the final breakdown,
unfortunately, the best elements of our race do not necessarily sur-vive. In fact, history teaches us just the opposite. As In <ent type='GPE'>Mexico</ent>, as
in <ent type='GPE'>San Domingo</ent> (<ent type='GPE'>Haiti</ent>), as In <ent type='PERSON'>Rhodeia</ent> (<ent type='GPE'>Zimbabwe</ent>), the scum, the
niggers, the mulattoes survive as the <ent type='NORP'>Whites</ent> retreat. But in all cases
the <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent> stage manages, manipulates and controls the show from the
beginning to the end.</p>

<p>How does the <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent> himself manage to survive throughout all this
disintegration and chaos? What technique does he use in politics in
particular to manipulate and take control?</p>

<p>These are two separate questions that are inextricably interwoven
and I will try to deal with them separately.</p>

<p>First of all the jew manages to survive and stay on top because
he has a powerful RACIAL RELIGION, <ent type='ORG'>Judaism</ent>, to polarize
around. It is this pole star that has been the guide and mainstay
with which he has been able to unite his mongrelized race and his
religious cohorts. This is the secret, the bedrock of all his further
conspiracles and manipulations. Without it, as former <ent type='NORP'>Israeli</ent> Prime
Minister <ent type='PERSON'>Golda Meir</ent> flatly stated, the <ent type='NORP'>jews</ent> would have been nothing.</p>

<p>Secondly, the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> practiced and continue to practice RACIAL
LOYALTY. This they do fervently to the point of fanaticism.</p>

<p>Thirdly they practice RACIAL TEAMWORK. This is
something the CHURCH OF THE CREATOR has repeatedly been
urging <ent type='EVENT'>the White Race</ent> to do with equal fervor and ingenuity.</p>

<p>Fourthly they have both short range and long range goals,
all designed for the survival and benefit of the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> race.</p>

<p>There are many other facets to the tenacious cohesiveness of
the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> race but the above are the fundamentals, all of which,
now that <ent type='EVENT'>the White Race</ent> has a racial religion of its own, we Creators
strongly advocate <ent type='EVENT'>the White Race</ent> practice with equal dedication.</p>

<p>Now, addressing the question as to how the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> continue to
control and manipulate the <ent type='ORG'>goyim</ent>, the list of tricks, <ent type='ORG'>shatagems</ent> and
devices the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> use is endless. They utilize their financial domina-tion, control of the media, religion (both <ent type='ORG'>Judaism</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>Chrisdanity</ent>),
government, race and every other means, device and Issue that will
accrue in their benefit. Today, however, in the wake of the re-cent farce we call election, we want to study the Divide and
Conquer technique, how it applies to the <ent type='ORG'>White</ent> Man's political
demise, and what we must do to overcome it in order that we may
oust the <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent> from our society and once again have the <ent type='ORG'>White</ent> Man
regain control of his own destiny.</p>

<p>Let us once again look at the Divide and Conquer technique,
which in essence is very simple.</p>

<p>If you were locked up in a dungeon with two powerful brutes,</p>



<p>and you yourself were a 97 pound weakling, and all of you were hostile
to each other, it would seem that as a comparative inferior your
chances of survival would be slim. If, however you were cunning
enough to whisper incendiary provocations into the ears of the two
brutes, one at a time, about what insults the one had said about the
other, and goad them into a life and death fracas, your chances of
survival might greatly improve. If you egged them on until they beat
each other senseless, then you could easily finish them off separate-ly and without too much effort.</p>

<p>This is exactly what the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> have been doing to the <ent type='ORG'>White</ent>
<ent type='ORG'>goyim</ent> for centuries. Divide the dumb brutes up into two hostile
camps, incite them to war and let them beat each other senseless.
We fell for this ruse in <ent type='EVENT'>the Civil War</ent>, we did it again in <ent type='EVENT'>World War</ent>
I, again in <ent type='EVENT'>World War</ent> II, to cite a few major examples, although the
list is endless. We can cite the Hundred Years War, or the Thirty
Years War. No maner which we choose, <ent type='ORG'>White Men</ent> killed other
<ent type='ORG'>White Men</ent> and each time the parasite reaped a <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> harvest in
power and monetary gain.</p>

<p>The same insidous technique is utilized in the field of
political action, which comes under the fraudnlent label of
demonracy. The <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> line up two (or more) political parties, all of
which they control with their financial power and their controlled
press.</p>

<p>In <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> in the Twentieth Century the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> have utlized main-ly two political parties, namely <ent type='ORG'>the Republican party</ent> and the
<ent type='NORP'>Democratic</ent> party. Occasionally, they have thrown in a third party,
such as <ent type='ORG'>the Bull Moose Party</ent> of <ent type='PERSON'>Teddy Roosevelt</ent> which split the
<ent type='NORP'>Republican</ent> Party, derailed <ent type='PERSON'>William Howard Taft</ent> and slipped in that
<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> stooge, <ent type='PERSON'>Woodrow Wilson</ent>. With hls election the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> assured
themselves of ramming through the <ent type='ORG'>Federal Reserve</ent> chicanery of
1913 and staging the most ghastly war up to that time, <ent type='EVENT'>World War</ent>
I.</p>

<p>Since then the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> have utilized the third party ruse a few more
times, such as the <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n Independent party, the Libertarian par-ty, <ent type='ORG'>the Populist Party</ent> and a few others, but they have been of minor
import, except to further confuse and spilnter the <ent type='ORG'>White</ent> voting block,
a block that for all practical purposes hardly exists.</p>

<p>Now that the <ent type='NORP'>Republican</ent> Reagan administration has won the
last election by a landslide and the <ent type='NORP'>Democratic</ent> Party is in shambles,
I foresee a steady but rapid drift towards one party rule similar to
that of <ent type='GPE'>Mexico</ent>, and finally a hard-core <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> communist dictator-ship as in <ent type='GPE'>Cuba</ent> and in <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>. All the while the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> will be
trumpeting the virtues of democracy and how great Is our freedom
of choice and our freedom of speech. Let us wake up and realize
one thing. <ent type='NORP'>Democracy</ent> and its multitude of political parties</p>



<p>have not benefited <ent type='EVENT'>the White Race</ent>. On the contrary, democracy
has been a treacherous <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> tool for the destruction of our
superlative culture and our precious gene pool. Let us not be fooled
any longer. Business as usual, politics as it now exists, is not going
to help save <ent type='EVENT'>the White Race</ent> from its one-way, helter-skelter onrush
to self-destruction. The <ent type='NORP'>Republican</ent> Party is not going to save us,
neither is the <ent type='NORP'>Democratic</ent> Party, nor <ent type='ORG'>the Libertarian Party</ent>, nor the
<ent type='ORG'>Populist Party</ent>.</p>

<p>Conventional politics as far as <ent type='EVENT'>the White Race</ent> Is concerned is
now as dead as a dodo, and a hopeless exercise in futility. Not that
we don't want to seize political power. On the contrary, that is our
Number One goal. We Creators have said time and again that none
of the muiltitudinous pro<ent type='GPE'>blem</ent>s that beset us today will ever be solved
until the <ent type='ORG'>White</ent> Man again grasps control of his destiny into his own
capable hands. But playing the game of <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> politics as now con-stituted is not the way to achieve this lofty goal. The day of political
parties is gone forever as far as <ent type='EVENT'>the White Race</ent> is concerned.</p>

<p>How then do we go about taking over political control of the
government of <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> in particular, and of our own destiny in the
world in general?</p>

<p>The answer is loud and clear. The means is building a
worldwide <ent type='ORG'>ideologiul movement</ent> based on race, the same
means, the miserable, parasidcal <ent type='NORP'>jewish</ent> minority has so suc-cessfully used for <ent type='ORG'>centurlies</ent> to gain control of the world. In
total dedication to an ideological movement will The <ent type='ORG'>White</ent>
Race find its salvation.</p>

<p>How do we go about formulating such an ideological racial
movement? The answer to that, too, is loud and clear. In CREATIVI-TY we already have it - complete, comprehensive, consis-tent and fully spelled out. It is now every <ent type='ORG'>White</ent> Man's duty to
promote it to the hilt and convince his <ent type='ORG'>White</ent> Racial Comrades that
the answer to the <ent type='ORG'>White</ent> Man's dilemma lies before him - right in
front of his eyes. All he has to do is examine it, embrace it and join
with his <ent type='ORG'>White</ent> Racial Comrades to expunge the curse of history -
the treacherous <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> network.</p>

<p>DELENDA EST JUDAICA! We must destroy the beast that has
been the disastrous plague on the body of <ent type='EVENT'>the White Race</ent> for millen-niums. The means is our own racial religion.</p>

<p>Strangely, this idea, which is so obviously logical, or should be,
has escaped <ent type='EVENT'>the White Race</ent> since the very beginning of civilization.
It is a powerful idea that must be brought home to the consciousness
of every <ent type='ORG'>White</ent> Racial Comrade until it becomes an integral part of
our very being. All we need do is look at history to observe the power-ful stimulus of a creed, a religion or an ideology has proved to be
in moving people, events and changing history.</p>



<p>I have already chronicled the powerful instrument <ent type='ORG'>Judaism</ent> has
proved to be for the benefit and advancement of a miserable
parasitical tribe. I have done so in Nature's Eternal Religion, in the
<ent type='ORG'>White</ent> Man's Bible and in any number of issues oi Racial Loyalty so
there is hardly a need to again reflect it here. Whereas <ent type='ORG'>Judaism</ent> is
probably the most outstanding example in demonstradng the power
of a racial religion, we can, nevertheless, quote any number of other
historical examples.</p>

<p>1. <ent type='ORG'>MOHAMMEDANISM</ent>
When <ent type='PERSON'>Mohammed</ent> came forth out of the desert in the seventh
century with what was essentially a racial religion, he fired the
<ent type='NORP'>Bedouin</ent> desert tribes (mostly <ent type='NORP'>Arabs</ent>) with such fanatic religious zeal
that this loose group of shiftless and lazy mud races soon were
amalgamated into a powerful army of world conquerers. <ent type='GPE'>Egypt</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Syria</ent>,
<ent type='LOC'>Asia</ent> Minor, <ent type='PERSON'>North</ent> <ent type='LOC'>Africa</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Spain</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>Constantinople</ent> fell before the
fanatic <ent type='NORP'>Moslem</ent> onslaught. They pushed on eastward into India and
converted by fanaticism and by the sword.</p>

<p>At the other end of the crescent, the <ent type='PERSON'>Mohammed</ent>ans pushed up-wards from <ent type='GPE'>Spain</ent> into the very heart of <ent type='GPE'>France</ent>, where they were stop-ped by <ent type='PERSON'>Karl Martel</ent> (Charles The <ent type='PERSON'>Hammer</ent>) at the Battle of Tours in
732. Had that battle been lost, perhaps all of Europe, then wallow-ing in the Dark Ages, might have succumbed to the <ent type='NORP'>Moslem</ent> Creed.
It was at a <ent type='NORP'>Hme</ent> when <ent type='EVENT'>the White Race</ent> was at its lowest and weakest
level.</p>

<p>2. <ent type='ORG'>AYATOLLAH KHOMEINI</ent> IN <ent type='GPE'>IRAN</ent>.
To further demonshate how long lasting, how powerfuI, how
much more significant a religious creed can be than a mere political
party we can take <ent type='NORP'>Moslem</ent> religion forward into histnry another thir-teen centuries from its founding, and look at its significance in the
<ent type='NORP'>Arab</ent> world of today.</p>

<p>When we look at the chaotic mess that is the <ent type='NORP'>Arab</ent> world of the
1980's we And there is one, and only one, powerful, cohesive force
that binds them all together all that is the <ent type='NORP'>Moslem</ent> religion.
The <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> have done a powerful number on the <ent type='NORP'>Arab</ent> states also and
fractured and fragmented them seven ways to <ent type='LOC'>Sunday</ent>. The <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> have
used the Divide and Conquer technique on them as well as in
trying to set up their parasitical state of <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent>.</p>

<p>But nevertheless, it is the powerful force of the <ent type='NORP'>Moslem</ent> creed
that binds the <ent type='NORP'>Arabs</ent> together, and it is this that the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> fear.</p>

<p>How powerful this force can be is aptly demonstrated by
<ent type='PERSON'>Ayatollah Khomeini</ent> in <ent type='GPE'>Iran</ent>. When in 1978 The <ent type='PERSON'>Shah</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>Iran</ent> held
an iron group on that oil rich nation, and one of the most powerful
and ruthless secret police forces at his command, the <ent type='PERSON'>Ayatollah</ent> was
sitting in <ent type='GPE'>Paris</ent>, a lonely refugee and a political outcast. But the
religious fervor of his <ent type='NORP'>Moslem</ent> followers welled up day after day in</p>



<p>street demonstration, in rebellion, in sabotage and just woudn't quit
Despite the supposed backing of <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States, we all know what
followed. The <ent type='PERSON'>Shah</ent> was deposed, died as a miserable and unwanted
refugee in a foreign land, and the AyatoIlah emerged as the now vic-torious dictator of <ent type='GPE'>Iran</ent>, where he still rules with a bloody and tyran-nical hand today.</p>

<p>In so saying, I am not condoning the <ent type='PERSON'>Ayatollah</ent>, whom I con-sider a political idiot, and vastly more brutal and tyrannical than the
<ent type='PERSON'>Shah</ent>. But what it does demonstrate is the power of a religious move-ment in the political affairs of a country.</p>

<p>Nor is that all. This same religious-political take over of <ent type='GPE'>Iran</ent>
has fired up the whole <ent type='NORP'>Arab</ent> world and inspired the other <ent type='NORP'>Moslem</ent>
countries to a racial fervor not witnessed for centuries. Their fervor
and hatred is directed not only against <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent>, but against all <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>,
and against the <ent type='ORG'>White</ent> world, and in particular that scape goat for
all <ent type='ORG'>White</ent> transgressions, <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States of <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>. In putting
the finger on <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States, the <ent type='NORP'>Arabs</ent> are not totally in the wrong.
Being at the mercy of its <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> masters, <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States since
<ent type='EVENT'>World War</ent> II has meddled in the affairs of more countries, caused
more wars, revolutions and pro<ent type='GPE'>blem</ent>s in the world than any country
in history in a similar short period of time.</p>

<p>In summary, considering the poor racial material the
<ent type='NORP'>Arabs</ent> and other racial misfits that embraced Moham-medanism had to work with, this religious creed never-theless has been a most powerful and cohesive force for the
<ent type='NORP'>Arabs</ent>, far beyond comparison to any mere passing political
party that has emerged in the last 13 centuries of its
existence.</p>

<p>9. <ent type='ORG'>THE BLACK MUSLIMS</ent> IN <ent type='GPE'>AMERICA</ent>. Let me again state
flatly that the nigger in <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> has no future in our civilized culture,
nor does the nigger have a meaningful future anywhere else in the
world, including <ent type='LOC'>Africa</ent>. The nigger is inherently dumb, shiftless and
lazy and is one of Nature's most flagrant failures.</p>

<p>Nevertheless, with the advent of the <ent type='NORP'>Black Muslim</ent> religion in
<ent type='GPE'>America</ent> it has worked wonders, considering the miserable material
it has had to work with. Whereas the <ent type='NORP'>Black Muslim</ent> religion is a mish-mash, a mixed bag, an abortion at best, lamely tring to ape the
<ent type='PERSON'>Mohammed</ent>an religion, it has done much to install black pride (where
there is little to be proud of), a sense of purpose and destiny (going
nowhere) and above all, created an independent cohesion among
hese bastardized animals that poses a highly potential danger to
<ent type='EVENT'>the White Race</ent>. In the racial upheaval that is bound to come within
less than a decade, these black animals will be armed and organiz-ed and will be the spearhead of the black killers the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> plan to
unleash on an unarmed, disorganized and hapless <ent type='ORG'>White</ent> Race.</p>



<p>MARK MY WORDS.</p>

<p>Now I Implore my <ent type='ORG'>White</ent> Racial Comrades: if these mongreliz-ed black animals can mount an organized threat to <ent type='EVENT'>the White Race</ent>
even though they are inferior in numbers, in intelligence, and in
resources, and can do so with a muddled, haphazard plece of <ent type='PERSON'>gar</ent>-bage that passes for a religion, how much better can the intelligent,
resourceful <ent type='ORG'>White</ent> Race do with a well thought-out, organized
religious creed and program that is complete, comprehensive and
consistent, and embodies the ultimate racial idea of Nature's Finest?
So why don't we get busy and do the fob that must be done?</p>

<p>4. I could cite a number of other examples of the power-ful influences a religion, even though half baked, can work on a group
of peoples, races or nations. A few of these other examples are the
mormons, the <ent type='LOC'>Moonies</ent>, the Seventh Day Adventists, Jehovah's
Winesses, the <ent type='ORG'>Pentecostals</ent> and any number of others. I rould detail
their history, their struggles and the tremendous influence they have
had on their followers, and of the financial empires they have built.
could also cite the considerable power structures they have built.
that could have been directed towards the survival, expansion and
advancement of <ent type='EVENT'>the White Race</ent>. I could do so, but I do not have
the name or the space to do so here. All I can regretfully say is that
as far as benefits to <ent type='EVENT'>the White Race</ent> are concemed most of the money,
resources, energy and goals have been misdirected and wasted on
(a) throwing it all down a bottomless rathole, and (b) glorifying the
ego, and enriching the coffers of its deceitful hierarchy, who are by
and large, nothing more than polished con-artists.</p>

<p>5. My own Political Experience in trying to work within
the Political Establishment.</p>

<p>As you probably know, If you have read NATURE'S ETERNAL
RELIGlON (Chapter 22. Part II, "My Own Spiritual Awakening"),
at one Name in the middle 1960's I was naive enough to believe I could
get into politics and do my bit in trying to change the course of events.
soon found out I was wrong.</p>

<p>In 1966 while still affiliated with <ent type='ORG'>the Birch Society</ent>. I threw my
hat in the ring and ran for <ent type='ORG'>the Florida</ent> State Legislature as a
<ent type='NORP'>republican</ent>, and, against odds, I was elected. When I got to the
regislature in <ent type='GPE'>Tallahassee</ent> and the power establishment found out
that I would not go along with the chicanery, my own part turned
against me. In a situation not unlike that of <ent type='PERSON'>Tom Metzger</ent> in 1980
in <ent type='GPE'>California</ent>. I soon found out that with the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> news media
against you, with your own party against you, a sincere candidate,
any candidate in politics, is soon on the outside looking in.</p>

<p>In short order in 1967 <ent type='ORG'>the Supreme Court</ent> decided <ent type='GPE'>Florida</ent> had
to "re-apportion", and had to have new elections all over again. In
the "new" election I opted to run for <ent type='ORG'>the Florida</ent> Senate and was</p>



<p>roundly defeated when <ent type='ORG'>the Republican Party</ent> bosses and the news
media turned hostile against me.</p>

<p>The biggest (and only) main headline I ever got in my hometown
paper of Pompano <ent type='PERSON'>Beach</ent> was "<ent type='ORG'>KLASSEN DEFEATED</ent>". It was the
main, big biack headline on the <ent type='ORG'>hont</ent> page the day aher the elec-tion. To my credit, I must add that tn my own precinct in Lighthouse
Point where I was personally known, I won overwhelmingly. A small
compensation.</p>

<p>The positive outcome of all this was that I learned one hard and
irrevocable lesson-you cannot hope to win by collaborating with,
and working within the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> establishment. You cannot overcome
the enemy by playing the game by the enemy's rules. You cannot
expect the enemy to collaborate and throw a few crumbs your way
by collaborating with the enemy. No! The enemy is ruthless and the
battle we are locked into is a matter of life and death!</p>

<p>I started groping for a new answer - a new means.
Three years later, after several false starts, I had the answer:
a powerful new racial religion for <ent type='EVENT'>the White Race</ent> was needed, and,
indeed, had been needed for millenniums!</p>

<p>I started putting together the pieces. I started writing NATURE'S
ETERNAL RELIGION.</p>

<p>Today, fourteen years later, I am convinced that we have the
total answer, the only answer. In Creativity we have the Total
Program, the Final Solution, the Ultimate Creed.</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> has said that there are obvious truths lying around on the
streets and most peopIe pass them by, ignoring them because they
are too dumb to see the obvious. He was referring to the racial issue.
As it was in Hitler's time, so it is in <ent type='ORG'>White</ent> <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> today, re<ent type='PERSON'>gar</ent>ding
not only race, but also religion.</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>The Church</ent> Of The Creator has come a long way since we
published NATURE'S ETERNAL RELIGION IN 1973. We have for-tified and completed our creed and program with two further basic
books, namely <ent type='ORG'>The WHITE MAN</ent>'S BIBLE and SALUBRIOUS LIV-ING. We have now established a <ent type='ORG'>World Center</ent> for our movement
<ent type='ORG'>the Blue Ridge Mountains</ent> of <ent type='PERSON'>North</ent> Carolina. We have launched
our own conveyor belt for spreading the word, namely RACIAL
LOYALTY, our official periodical for our religious movement. We
are building a Scbool for Gifted <ent type='ORG'>White</ent> Boys, which is now near-comyleted and ready to open next summer. The foundations for
the <ent type='ORG'>White</ent> racial religion have been laid for the next million years.</p>

<p>But <ent type='GPE'>Rome</ent> wasn't built in a day. One of the biggest pro<ent type='GPE'>blem</ent>s
we have to overcome is the hubris, the jealousies and the
roadblocks thrown in our path by our own <ent type='ORG'>White</ent> Racial
Comrades, by the multitude ot splinter grounds who at best have
a confused, meaningless and fractured approach to the monumen-</p>



<p>tal pro<ent type='GPE'>blem</ent> that confronts us, but would rather torpedo a meaningful
solution than give up their pointless and eccentric little hangups.</p>

<p>The biggest pro<ent type='GPE'>blem</ent> that confronts us is not overcoming the
<ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, niggers and mud races. The main pro<ent type='GPE'>blem</ent> is straightening out
the muddled, confused and suicidal thinking that lies on the brain
of the <ent type='ORG'>White</ent> Man like a poisonous drug, or like the virus of
encephalitis.</p>

<p>Like Adolf <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> did in uniting the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> peopIe, it is now the
task of <ent type='ORG'>the Church</ent> Of The Creator to unite all the <ent type='ORG'>White</ent> peoples
of the World into one mighty movement - into one powerful batter-ing ram. We can never do so as long as we have 20000 confused,
effective little groups that neither understand the total pro<ent type='GPE'>blem</ent>,
nor even profess to have a solution, but by and large, only bitch -
deplore and lament, deplore and lament. Not only is this the extent
of their approach, but when a movement comes along that has a
comprehensive creed, purpose and solution these same little "leaders"
then turn their full invective on such a movement in order to protect
their own little hubris.</p>

<p>In the meantime, we want to re-emphasize the solution. In
CREATIVITY we have the answer, the total answer, the whole ball
of wax. It is complete, it is comprehensive, it is consistent. It is in
harmony with the Eternal Laws of Nature. It derives its hard earned
conclusions from experience and lessons of history. It is based not
only on Logic and Common Sense (a rare commodity) but also the
inherent stirrings of the <ent type='ORG'>White</ent> Man's Soul. Why not join with us and
build! build! build! a mighty <ent type='ORG'>White</ent> racial-religious movement that
can and will steam roller and crush the vicious enemy once and for all.</p>

<div> * * * * *</div>

<p>We Creators are determined to solve the pro-<ent type='GPE'>blem</ent>, not just endlessly agonize over it.</p>

<div> * * * * *</div>

<p><ent type='NORP'>Democracy</ent> and <ent type='NORP'>Christianity</ent> must be replac-ed by the LEADERSHIP PRINCIPLE and by
CREATIVITY.</p>

<div> * * * * * </div>

<p>We Creators don't straddle issues. We
delineate and resolve them.</p>

<div> * * * * *</div>

<p>104

* * * * *

Now that 1984 is almost past, RESOLVE
that as a <ent type='ORG'>White</ent> Man you will never again be a
slave to <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Christianity</ent> or the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> tax
collector.</p>

<div> * * * * *</div>

<p><ent type='NORP'>Democracy</ent> and <ent type='NORP'>Christianity</ent> have spelled the
death knell of <ent type='EVENT'>the White Race</ent>.</p>

<div> * * * * *</div>

<p>We cannot win a war of ideas if we have
nothing more than a mixed bag of unresolved
shibboleths to fight with and for. The <ent type='ORG'>White</ent> Race
must polarize in order to survive.</p>

<p> * * * * *

105
</p></xml>