<xml><p>Issue No. 17, October 1984</p>

<p>Knocking The Key Weapon</p>

<p> From Out Of</p>

<p> The Enemy's Hands</p>

<p>Let us realize our Tremendous Potential on
Utilize our Weapons to the Utmost.

Throughout history warring factions have sought to gain advan-tage over their enemies by having superior weapons with which to
rout and destroy the enemy. The goal has been to get the
"ultimate" weapon first, and then keep it out of the hands
of the enemy.</p>

<p>If keeping it out of the enemy's hands is not possible, (and usually
it is not) then the idea is to keep the weapon from the enemy at least
as long as possible, and in the meantime develop even more deadly
weapons of <ent type='ORG'>destruc</ent>tion.</p>

<p>This, then, has consciously been the strategy of mankind ever
since man emerged out of the caves with club in hand. Although the
change in weaponry evolved slowly in ancient times, nevertheless,
it changed significantly from time to time, from clubs to spears, too
bows and arrows, to cavalry, chariots, to gunpowder and artillery,
to tanks and aircraft, to rocketry and an up to the deadly hydrogen
bomb of today, the latter being considered the "ultimate" weapon.</p>

<p>The premise of having weapons superior to that of the enemy
and keeping such superior weapons out of the enemy's hands, is,
of course strategically sound, as history has proved countless times.
When the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Man arrived in <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> with musketry and horses,
the inferior <ent type='NORP'>Indian</ent> with his bows and arrows and on foot was no match
for the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Man, and of course, it was not only the difference in
weaponry in which the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Man was superior.</p>

<p>When the <ent type='NORP'>Hyksos</ent> arrived in <ent type='GPE'>Egypt</ent> with chariots and horse at
about the 18th century B.C.E., they easily conquered the amazed
<ent type='GPE'>Egypt</ent>ians. However, the <ent type='GPE'>Egypt</ent>ians soon caught on and soon began
to utilize the same weapons, and the wheel had come to <ent type='GPE'>Egypt</ent>. A
few centuries later, they drove the <ent type='NORP'>Hyksos</ent> out.</p>

<p>When <ent type='ORG'>Bismarck</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Kaiser Wilhelm</ent> confronted the <ent type='NORP'>Austrians</ent>
at <ent type='ORG'>Koeniggratz</ent> (the Battle of Sadow) in 1866 with breech loading
rifles to the <ent type='NORP'>Austrians</ent>' muzzle loaders, the engagement became a</p>



<p>wholesale slaughter - of the <ent type='NORP'>Austrians</ent>.</p>

<p>When <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States dropped the atomic bomb on "<ent type='GPE'>Hiroshima</ent>
and <ent type='GPE'>Nagasaki</ent> in 1945, that war was over. (It had really been over
six months, earlier, but the U.S. ignored and kept secret the
fact that the <ent type='NORP'>Japanese</ent> tried to surrender and sue for peace.
Evidently the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> wanted to continue the slaughter of
<ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n boys as long as possible).</p>

<p>We can, of course, cite innumerable other examples of inven-tions on one side, and cloak and dagger methods with which to either
obtain the secrets from the other side, or prevent the enemy from
getting their hands on the new technology. All kinds of fascinating
spy stories, mysteries and cloak and dagger tales have emerged from
even the great war (<ent type='EVENT'>WWII</ent>) about the Norden bomb sight, about radar
technology, about V-1 and V-2 rockets and about our continued
saturation bombings of the research center where the <ent type='NORP'>Germans</ent> were
trying to develop their first atomic bomb, and our own overwhelm-ing secrecy in the development of that bomb.</p>

<p>In every case of advancing weaponry and technology, the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent>
Man was by far the leading, the outstanding innovator, if in fact,
not the only contender in the field. Not only was the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Man the
leader in the field, but, strangely enough, as recent history has
so dramatically demonstrated, <ent type='EVENT'>the White Race</ent> was also the
leading victim of his own brilliant technology. The <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent>
Man's greatly superior weapons were in each case turned
against <ent type='EVENT'>the White Race</ent> itself, and only <ent type='EVENT'>the White Race</ent> could,
and did, kill millions of other members of nature's finest.
In short, <ent type='EVENT'>the White Race</ent> engaged in a frantic race to forge superior
weapons, the ultimate weapons of <ent type='ORG'>destruc</ent>tion in order that it could
kill its own faster, more effectively, and probably even wipe itself
the face of the earth.</p>

<p>What a monstrosity! How did such an idiotic, suicidal, horrible
situation come about? Especially, how did Nature's Finest, Nature's
most intelligent, the Inventor of all this technology and the creator
of all civilizations, get boxed into such an unbelievable dilemma?</p>

<p>We Creators have the answer to that question. The <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> ac-complished all this through their DIVIDE and CONQUER techni-que, using nationalism as the main divisive factor, as well as
any one of several other issues, such as religion, language, etc. But
there is another overriding factor, there is another ultimate weapon
that is as old as history itself that the enemy has relentlessly employed
against <ent type='EVENT'>the White Race</ent>, and until now has moved heaven and earth
to keep it out of the hands of <ent type='EVENT'>the White Race</ent> itself.</p>

<p>That ultimate weapon is the RACIAL IDEA COMBINED
WITH THE B-BOMB. Once <ent type='EVENT'>the White Race</ent> grasps this
ultimate weapon into its own powerful and capable hands,</p>



<p>our enemies will shortly be wiped out, and they know it on-ly to well. That is why they have left no stone unturned and
unceasingly bombarded us with the B-bomb (brain bomb)
to the point of over saturation. The idea they have unceasingly
and relentlessly inundated us with is that WHITE RACISM is evil,
evil, evil; <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> racism is great! Black racism is wonderful. <ent type='NORP'>Hispanics</ent>
have every right to exercise THEIR civil rights, to band together,
violate and flout our immigration laws and flood the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Man's
domain with their hungry hordes. The <ent type='NORP'>Vietnamese</ent> have "rights", the
<ent type='NORP'>Jamaicans</ent> have rights, the <ent type='NORP'>Cubans</ent> have rights, and the <ent type='NORP'>Indian</ent>s, too,
poor things, have their inalienable rights. Ah yes, and when we speak
of those decrepid relics of the stone age we must respectfully talk
about <ent type='NORP'>Indian</ent> "braves", the "noble" red man and how the despicable
and sneaky <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Man lied and cheated him and his "nations" out
of his lands: That is what the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> press says we must say and
the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Man collaborates and babbles such inanities not unsimilar
to the way a conditioned <ent type='NORP'>Pavlovian</ent> dog does his trained act.</p>

<p>But what about the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Man? What about <ent type='EVENT'>the White Race</ent>?
Does it have any rights in this greatest land on the face of the earth?
A land, a civilization and an empire built by the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Man's own
illustrious Ancestors? Do we have any rights to even voice our
opinions?</p>

<p>Hell no! Didn't you know that <ent type='NORP'>Judaism</ent> has decreed that <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent>
Racism is the most heinous evil to ever be conceived by the mind
of man? It must be purged. It must be attacked, smeared, slandered,
disgraced and expunged from the face of the earth! Such a power-ful onslaught have the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> launched over the years against
the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> race's ever organizing itself and realizing its own
potential that race mixing (although never spelled out into
a law) has now become not only the most fanatically pur-sued goal of this (and preceding) administrations, but it has
now actually become the state religion of the formerly <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent>
Man's United States. Every law, every court decision, every ser-mon from the pulpit is now directed to promote race mixing. We must
race mix! Race mix with all deliberate speed until the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Man
is expunged and exterminated. This, then, has become the unwrit-ten but pervading official religion of this once great <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> that
our own glorious ancestors built!</p>

<p>All right, so there we have it. There lies the dire secret right
out there in front of the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Man's eyes, right out there in the open
for every man to see. The stupid niggers can see it and understand
it, so do the lowly <ent type='NORP'>Mexicans</ent> and so does every other minority. Only
the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Man is blind as a bat, and cannot, or will not, see it. Only
<ent type='EVENT'>the White Race</ent> seems conditioned to shun and ignore this powerful
combination of the RACIAL IDEA and the B-BOMB.</p>



<p>But now <ent type='ORG'>the Church</ent> Of The Creator sees it, understands it, and
has it. We now have it all put together, comprehensive, com-plete consistent,, in a fervent racial religion. It is called
CREATIVITY. We are now determined to blare it out to the world
to promote the hell out of it until every <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Man sees it, understands
it, grasps it and makes it his very own. Actually we have been
preaching it from the very beginning of Creativity. RACIAL LOYAL-TY, the name of the paper you are now holding in your hands is THE
VERY heart of the idea.</p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>The Church</ent> Of The Creator is determined to implement-the solu-tion totally and with finality and not just wallow in the pro<ent type='GPE'>blem</ent> as
do most other <ent type='ORG'>DEPLORE AND LAMENT</ent> discussion societies.</p>

<p> How are we going to implement the racial idea combined with
the B-bomb? That, too, is very basic and easy to understand. With
are going to promote it in the same way as every other idea and move-ment has been promoted. The only difference is we will do it with
more urgency, more fervor and a great deal more reason than has
any cause that has ever been conceived in the history of mankind
Nothing, but nothing, is more vital, more important than the sur-vival of Nature's Finest - <ent type='EVENT'>the White Race</ent>.</p>

<p> This is where you come in. How much do you care? You know
what to do (Read again "Spreading the Good Word" in issue No. 14
16. Read again all of issue No. 10 about becoming an Ordained
Minister of <ent type='ORG'>the Church</ent>, about how to form your own church group.
Read again about "Dispersion and <ent type='ORG'>Polarization</ent>" in issue No. 14.</p>

<p> So now let's go to work. When you realize what the miserable
<ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>, a small, despicable minority, has been able to do with these
weapons, imagine what <ent type='EVENT'>the White Race</ent>, still 500 million strong, can
do with these same weapons. Let us grasp the impact of this ultimate
weapon and change the world forever - and make it a beautiful place
for <ent type='EVENT'>the White Race</ent> to live, to love and to prosper.</p>

<div> * * * * *</div>

<p> Nature has never read the Declaration of In-dependence. It continues to make us unequal.</p>

<div> * * * * *</div>

<p> Let us permit Nature to have her way; she
understands her business better than we do.</p>

<div> * * * * *</div>



<p> How To Overcome</p>

<p> The Real Haters</p>

<p>Undoubtedly the most persistent and the most vicious haters of
all time have been the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>. The <ent type='ORG'>Talmud</ent> is full of it, their whole
religious creed is founded upon it, and the survival of their race is
based upon the theory that the strongest cement binding together
an organization, any organization, is to have a common enemy.</p>

<p>Whom have the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> selected as their enemy? To make sure
they never run out of hatred, all "<ent type='GPE'>Gentiles</ent>" are their enemies. This
means, in fact, that all the peoples of the world who are not <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>
are their enemies. The <ent type='ORG'>Talmud</ent> repeatedly restates this
premise and furthermore derogates non-<ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> into the
category of animals, to be denounced, to be deceived, lied
to, killed and destroyed. According to the teaching of the <ent type='ORG'>Talmud</ent>,
the most sacred of all their holy books, all non-<ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> are "<ent type='ORG'>gois</ent>", or
"<ent type='GPE'>goyim</ent>", which means animals, and any property they may possess
rightfully belongs to <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>. Any treacherous act in stripping the
"<ent type='GPE'>goyim</ent>" is considered fair and square and is condoned by the code
of the <ent type='ORG'>Talmud</ent>.</p>

<p> The exercise of these ground rules is further reinforced by
teaching the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> from early childhood to hate the <ent type='GPE'>goyim</ent>, that they
are evil and a threat to their own survival.</p>

<p>This <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> creed has been in existence for thousands of years.
The <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> have avidly pursued this course with a fanaticism that
knows no bounds, and have harbored an intense, pathological hatred
for all <ent type='GPE'>goyim</ent> with a vengeance. But their fiercest hate is, and has
been reserved for <ent type='EVENT'>the White Race</ent>, especially the <ent type='NORP'>Romans</ent> of Ancient
history, and the <ent type='NORP'>Germans</ent> of today. The Jew's motto always has
been, and is today, "Always kill the best first".</p>

<p>So complete a monopolistic stranglehold do the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> hold on
the worldwide propaganda machinery that only a few of the honest
students of history are aware of this sinister situation. So thoroughly
confused and programmed is the average goy yokel that he or she
will join with their destroyers and hate and denounce those few
courageous fighters that will even so much as investigate, or look
into, or talk about this strange historic phenomena.</p>

<p>The <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> have honed to a sharp edge many of the weapons at
their disposal, and one that they have become most expert at is tur-ning the tables on their accusers. Their motto in this connec-</p>



<p>tion is to ACCUSE THE ACCUSER. In short, accuse their enemies
of the very thing they themselves are doing, but do it first, do it louder
and more blatantly than any campaign their enemies might be able
to muster.</p>

<p>There are thousands of historic examples of this, going back as
far as the history of Ancient <ent type='GPE'>Egypt</ent>, in which the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> through the
monopolization of the grain and food of the <ent type='GPE'>Egypt</ent>ians, managed
to enslave them. When the <ent type='GPE'>Egypt</ent>ians finally realized this and drove
them out en masse, the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> turned the tables on them and claimed
(a) the <ent type='GPE'>Egypt</ent>ians enslaved them, and (b) wouldn't them leave,
until, of course, <ent type='PERSON'>Moses</ent> (a historical fiction) and their ever-loving
Jehovah (a <ent type='ORG'>Fictious</ent> concept) came to their rescue and led them out
of <ent type='GPE'>Egypt</ent> to the consternation of the <ent type='GPE'>Egypt</ent>ians. Since they, not the
<ent type='GPE'>Egypt</ent>ians, wrote the Old Testament, and subsequent history as well,
that double lie persists as an accepted fact the gullible
<ent type='GPE'>goyim</ent> even to this day.</p>

<p>About half a century ago the <ent type='NORP'>Germans</ent> under the leadership of
<ent type='PERSON'>Adolf Hitler</ent>, finally realized the full depth of the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> conspiracy,
and tried to get the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> monkey oH their back. They united on
a national scale and broke the power of the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> in <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent>.
However, so powerfully entrenched was the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> financial and pro-paganda network that they enveigled the rest of the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> world to
come to their (the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>) rescue, and to destroy the <ent type='NORP'>Germans</ent>. This
they succeeded in doing with a vengeance and no sooner was that
phase completed when the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> immediately turned on their rescuers
to undermine and destroy them.</p>

<p>They then again aimed for the <ent type='ORG'>destruc</ent>tion of the best
first, namely <ent type='GPE'>Great Britain</ent>, and above all, <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States,
both of whom they held in the palm of their hands.</p>

<p>Since we who live in <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States and are <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> are now
the number one target for <ent type='ORG'>destruc</ent>tion you might wonder how do
the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> go about getting the hateful <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> <ent type='GPE'>goyim</ent> to help them, the
<ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, destroy their enemy the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n?</p>

<p>It is very simple, and they employ the same historic tried
and true stratagems they utilized against the <ent type='GPE'>Egypt</ent>ians.</p>

<p>(a) Accuse the <ent type='PERSON'>Accuser</ent>, and (b) destroy the first best.</p>

<p>Having unlimited monopoly of the propaganda machinery in the
United States (and the world), having complete control of the TV
networks, the news wires, the newspapers, radio, and every other
mechanism, the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> turn on the heat. Any <ent type='GPE'>goyim</ent> who dares to so
much as mention their obvious program of hate and <ent type='ORG'>destruc</ent>tion is
immediately braned as a hater. And we should all hate a hater,
shouldn't we?</p>

<p>So how do we Creators, who are in the forefront of ex-posing the sinister <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> conspiracy defend ourselves</p>



<p>against this kind of tactic?</p>

<p>Well, we must first of all face a few basic facts of life and drive
them home to our <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Racial Comrades whom we are trying to
save from genocide, and whose mutual help we must enlist to save
ourselves and, in fact, the total <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Race. These realities are:</p>

<p>1. The <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> know exactly what their deadly game is and that
they must proceed at full speed, and destroy their enemy (Principal-ly <ent type='EVENT'>the White Race</ent>) before we catch on, and destroy them. Therefore,
it is pointless to argue with them, try to persuade them to ameliorate
or mend their ways, or any other means of conciliation. The <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>
are hell bent on the <ent type='ORG'>destruc</ent>tion of <ent type='EVENT'>the White Race</ent> and nothing will
divert or deter them. Our only hope, our only solution, is to
render them harmless so they cannot now or ever in the
future again threaten the survival and well-being of the
<ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Race. But forget any solution through conciliation, bargain-ing, coming to terms by means of understanding, or any similar
shibboleths.</p>

<p>2. Our efforts at persuasion, recruiting and enlightenment must
be directed at our own <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Racial Comrades where the real pro-<ent type='GPE'>blem</ent> and also the real solution lies. We must bring home to our <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent>
brothers and sisters the magnitude of the sinister conspiracy the
diabolical designs of the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> perpetrators on the future of their
own lives and those of future <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> generations. We must enlighten
them that the only hope of survival and a viable future is to
build! build! build! A powerful <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> movement, a <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent>
Racial religion such as CREATIVITY that has the goal and
the means of sweeping our enemies before us like a huge
tidal wave, and that are that we must again wrest control of the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent>
Man's destiny into our own capable hands.</p>

<p>To provide some of the tools to help persuade our <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Racial
Comrades, we come back to the question that constituted the heading
of this article, namely how do we overcome the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> accusation
that we are the haters, the only haters, and therefore the real culprits?</p>

<p>Well, since the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> propaganda networks are so pervasive
and all-encompassing this is not easy, not for any lack of argument
or evidence, but because of the sheer massiveness of the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> pro-paganda apparatus. But through tenacity, aggressiveness and sheer
hard work we can overcome it. Here are some of the questions and
arguments we can advance with which to awaken our <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Racial
Comrades:
1. Is hating your enemies a good thing or is it bad?
2. If it is bad to hate under any circumstances, then is it a
bad to hate a <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>?
3. Do the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> hate <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>s?
4. Do you hate <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>s? Do you hate <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent>?</p>



<p> 5. If it is alright to hate <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>s and to hate <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent>, and what's
fair for the goose is fair for the gender, isn't it then also justifiable
for the <ent type='NORP'>Germans</ent> to retaliate and hate the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>?
6. Have you ever wondered why the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> have been hated by
nearly all nations of the world at one time or another to the point
where they were driven out of their land? (See Creative Credo No.
35, "Unrelenting Warfare Between the parasitic <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> and their Un-fortunate Victims" in The <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Man's Bible.)
7. Do you believe that It is a sensible idea to love your enemies
(Man. 5:44) and to hate your father and mother, brothers and sisters
(<ent type='PERSON'>Luke</ent> 14:26) and hate your own kind?
8. Did you know that the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Talmud</ent>, which is considered
by the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> as being their most sacred religious text (even above
the Old Testament) is full of hate for all peoples?
9. Did you know that the foundation of the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> religion is
hatred, and their cohesiveness is built upon that very hatred for all
<ent type='GPE'>goyim</ent>?
10. Is it alright to try to defend yourself against a person or a
group that has designs upon your <ent type='ORG'>destruc</ent>tion?
11. Is it possible for you or your race to survive without defending yourself/itself?
12. In real life, is it possible to fight a battle for survival without
hating your enemy?
13. Would you be utterly uncon<ent type='ORG'>cerned</ent> if this country
became 90 per cent black, 5 per cent <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> and was con-trolled by a tightly organized <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> network?
14. If you realized such was happening would you do anything
to avert It?
15. Just what would you do and where would you start?
16. Is it alright to hate someone if they hated you first?
17. If so, the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> are the world's oldest and most persist
haters, as is evidenced both by the Old Testament, the <ent type='ORG'>Talmud</ent> and
their history. Would you care to ignore this fact, or do you think it
bears looking into?
18. If your mother or sister were attacked, would you defend
them?
19. Would you love their attacker or would you show signs of
hatred and anger while you defended them? (If you have the guts to
do so.)
20. Do you think it is alright to defend <ent type='EVENT'>the White Race</ent> if some
other race, or coalition of races ganged up on <ent type='EVENT'>the White Race</ent> and
worked and plotted for its <ent type='ORG'>destruc</ent>tion?
21. If it came to a showdown between the niggers and the
<ent type='PERSON'>White</ent>s, what side, if any, would you choose?</p>



<p> 22. if it came to a showdown between the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> and the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent>
Race, what side, if any, would you choose?
23. If it came to a battle for survival between <ent type='EVENT'>the White Race</ent>
on the one hand, and the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, niggers and mud races in coalition
against it, which side, if any, would you choose?
24. If you had to choose between <ent type='NORP'>Christianity</ent> and the survival
<ent type='EVENT'>the White Race</ent>, what side, if any, would you choose?
25. Do you believe that the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> are to be commended for <ent type='PERSON'>giv</ent>-ing their first -loyalty to their own race?
26. Do you approve of the idea of blacks practicing RACIAL
LOYALTY?
27. Do you believe the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> people should also have equal
rights in practicing RACIAL LOYALTY towards their own race?
28. Do you realize that your <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> ancestors consistently prac-ticed RACIAL LOYALTY for thousands of years, and if they did not,
you would be a mongrelized mulatto today?
29. Would you perhaps rather be black, or a mulatto, than
<ent type='PERSON'>White</ent>?
30. Would you like to see your sister marry a nigger? If not, why
not?
31. If your mother were widowed, would you like to see her
remarry a nigger? If not, why not?
32. Is there any county In the U.S. that is predominantly black,
that you would like to live in?
33. Is there any country in the world that is predominantly black,
say, like <ent type='GPE'>Haiti</ent>, you would like to live in?
34. Would you like to live in the middle of <ent type='LOC'>Harlem</ent>, and if so,
how long do you think you could survive?</p>

<p> There are many more similar questions we could devise, and
undoubtedly you yourself could think of many more. The main idea
in our thesis is this:</p>

<p>1. Our real pro<ent type='GPE'>blem</ent> is not overcoming the <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent> and the
mud people, but straightening out the confused and
scrambled thinking of our own <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>-programmed <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent>
Racial Comrades. These are the people we must work on and work
with. It is the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> people we must enlighten and bring to their
senses. It is the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> people, our own <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> brothers and sisters,
we must bring to their senses, that we must instill a feeling of racial
pride and loyalty, that we must organize. There lies the solution -
not with convincing the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> or the niggers, or any other mud races.
So let us not waste our time and energy in misdirection.</p>

<p>In order to bring the issue of hate into proper perspective Read
again Creative Credo No. 62 in The <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Man's Bible entitled "love
and Hate".</p>

<p>In order to enlighten and organize our <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> racial brethren we</p>



<p>must do the following:</p>

<p>1 . Have a powerful all-encompassing racial creed that the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent>
Race can and must polarize around. This we have now.</p>

<p>2. Build a propaganda network of our own that will overshadow
and overpower the present <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> stranglehold. Why not? We can
do it! We have the intelligence, we have the numbers, we have the
customers, the advertisers, the producers and the energy to do the
job. All we need is leadership, direction and dedication. Our
periodical, RACIAL LOYALTY is the spearhead in building a vast
and powerful transmission belt for the spreading of WHITE IDEAS.
All we have to do now is build! build! build! and work like hell. This
means your participation and dedication. Help expand the subscrip-tions of our periodical RACIAL LOYALTY to the limits of your
resources.</p>

<p>3. Help promote <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> racial schools and programs such as our
SCHOOL. FOR GIFTED BOYS. Help make this the seedbed of a
vast network of education, training and enlightenment for the benefit
of <ent type='EVENT'>the White Race</ent>. Donate to our cause. It's your cause.</p>

<p>4. Promote <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Racial Loyalty. Talk it, preach it, disseminate
literature, leaflets and flyers in its behalf. Think <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent>. Practice <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent>
Racial Teamwork. Help build a <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent>r and <ent type='ORG'>Brighter World</ent>.</p>

<p>The alternative is black, very black. Think about it. Do
something about it. HELP BUILD A WHITER AND BRIGHTER
WORLD.
* * * * *</p>

<p> Only by facing reality, no matter how grim,
can <ent type='EVENT'>the White Race</ent> free itself from the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent>
vampire.</p>

<div> * * * * *</div>

<p> If <ent type='EVENT'>the White Race</ent> is ever to revert back to
sanity, <ent type='NORP'>Christianity</ent> will HAVE TO GO. To again
regain its sanity, it will first have to dump
<ent type='NORP'>Christianity</ent>.</p>

<div> * * * * *</div>

<p> Creativity is the mighty Wave of the Future.</p>

<div> * * * * *</div>



<p>The following article appeared tn the Miami Herold:</p>

<p> WHAT A <ent type='ORG'>FRIEND</ent>
WE HAVE IN JESUS</p>

<p>In <ent type='GPE'>Colorado Springs</ent> this week, a federal judge threw out a
million dollar lawsuit filed by a cuckolded husband against a Roman
Catholic priest who had an affair with plaintiffs wife during the course
of marital counseling. The judge ruled that litigation could not con-stitutionally be pursued because it violated the priest's "FREE EX-ERCISE OF RELIGION."</p>

<p>Moral of the story: If you are a Minister of the Cloth, you
really have clout!</p>

<div>* * * * *</div>

<p> We neither want to impress you nor enter-tain you. We want to inspire you to become a mili-tant activist.</p>

<div>* * * * *</div>

<p> Starting with a polyglot society that is sick
and degenerate, we CREATORS are determin-ed to build a <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent>r and <ent type='ORG'>Brighter World</ent>. Your
dedication will make it possible.</p>

<div>* * * * *</div>

<p> It is our unswerving and sacred GOAL TO
place 10 million <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Man's Bibles IN THE
hands of our <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Racial Comrades. Once we
have accomplished that much the war against the
<ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, niggers and mud peoples will be as good
as over, and it will be the best bargain the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent>
Race will ever have invested in. Help bring it
about! Do your part.</p>

<div> * * * * *</div>



<p>Our Autistic World</p>

<p>The Supreme Importance of being able to distinguish
between Reality and Fantasy.</p>

<p>Last Christmas my daughter gave me a small wall calendar that
had a unique feature about it. To help my vocabulary there was
new and uncommon word presented for each and every day of the
year. Along with it was the definition of the word, also an exemplary
usage in a sentence. I found that even at my age an old dog can learn
new tricks, or at least add new words to his vocabulary.</p>

<p>The other day the word "autistic" came up, and although I was
aware of its meaning as applied to autistic children, the definition
"having the tendency to fulfill one's needs by fantasies, unmindful
of objective reality" gave me pause for reflection that it is not just
a rare child that suffers from this affliction.</p>

<p> autistic</p>

<p> (@ tis' tik) adj. Psychol. having the
tendency to fulfill one's needs by
fantasies, unmindful of objective
reality</p>

<p> The autistic child didn't acknowledge the world around him.</p>

<p> Thursday
August30
1984</p>

<p>Looking at the mess the world Is in today, and how a diversity
of polyglot people are trying to cope with an impossible mess they
don't understand, or better stated, trying to escape from coping with
reality I came to the conclusion that probably more than 99 percent</p>



<p>of the more than 5 billion people living on this planet today have
advanced symptoms of being autistic.</p>

<p>1. One of the most alarming phenomena of this present "now"
generation is the ballooning increase in the use and abuse of
drugs of all kinds. This varies from smoking pot, sniffing cocaine,
injecting heroin with a needle into the "<ent type='ORG'>mainliner</ent>", sniffing "angel
dust", and a whole variety of other outright dangerous and addic-tive drugs that confuse, maim, paralyze and kill. <ent type='GPE'>Florida</ent> U.s. Senator
<ent type='PERSON'>Paula Hawkins</ent> made the statement to the effect that there is hardly
a public school in <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States today where the children above
the fourth grade have not been subjected to drugs, and, in many
schools it is out of control and in flagrant abuse.</p>

<p>This is a terrible indictment of our present society and especial-ly of "our" public schools. How did we get into such a horrible situa-tion and why do so many children (and adults) take to drugs?</p>

<p>It is a long story, but let us first examine the WHY of the
situation.</p>

<p>Despite all the modern conveniences of "civilization", despite
nearly 2000 years of <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Christianity</ent>, despite welfare and anti-poverty programs and all the rest - people today are living in a
highly confused, artificial world. It is a polyglot world in which every
individual feels alienated, a world in which they feel they are not at
home, but an alien living amongst pluralistic aliens. People are vastly
confused, they are without hope and without direction. This applies
to all peoples of the world, whether they be niggers, <ent type='NORP'>Arabs</ent>, <ent type='NORP'>Hindus</ent>,
<ent type='NORP'>Indian</ent>s or mongrels of other breeds such as <ent type='NORP'>Mexicans</ent>. But it applies
especially to the one and only race with which we Creators are con-<ent type='ORG'>cerned</ent>, namely <ent type='EVENT'>the White Race</ent>.</p>

<p>The <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Man of today finds himself living in an alien world
that is rapidly closing in on him. He is living in a <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>-dominated
culture that is repugnant to him, but he cannot put his finger on it
as to WHY. He does not understand it. As the <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Marcus Eli Ravage</ent>
said, "We have imposed upon you an alien book (the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> bible
and an alien faith which you cannot swallow, or digest, which is at
cross-purposes with your native spirit, which keeps you everlasting-ly ill at ease, and which you lack the spirit to either reject or accept
in full." See "Confessions of a <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>" Creative Credo No. 43, Page 286
of the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Man's Bible.)</p>

<p>The <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> have done so indeed. But starting nearly two thou-sand years ago with <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Christianity</ent>, they have steadily pursued
their warfare against <ent type='EVENT'>the White Race</ent> relentlessly, as I hove expounded further in the article "Unrelentless Warfare Between The Parasitic
<ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> And Their Unfortunate Victims" starting on page 6 of this paper.
<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Christianity</ent> was the mighty, massive mind-bender that pro-vided the breakthrough for the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> to get a handle on the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent></p>



<p>Man's mind and destiny. But it did not stop there.</p>

<p> Since the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> have aggressively taken control of the finances
of the world, they have seized a monopoly of the newsmedia, televi-sion, films, radio and the book publishing business; music and the
"arts", If they can still be called such; control our government without
so much as a challenge; either have their hand in almost every Gen-tile religion or are the prime instigators of it, or both: and worst of
all, they have pervaded and prostituted the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Man's culture. All
this they have done and are accelerating without the overwhelming
majority of <ent type='EVENT'>the White Race</ent> even realizing or admitting that this is so.</p>

<p>This is why I can say without reservation: 99 percent of the
<ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> race are living in a dream world, an unreal fool's
paradise. They are AUTISTIC, unable or unwilling to face
reality. They are also, by and large, extremely confused, and unhap-py, living on the edge of hopeless desperation, hardly knowing WHY.</p>

<p>As a result they try a wide variety of escape mechanisms. We
have already cited the widespread resort to drugs. Unfortunately, the
more a person, or a nation, or a race tries to avoid coming to grips
with reality and solving the multitude of pro<ent type='GPE'>blem</ent>s, the worse the
pro<ent type='GPE'>blem</ent>s become. The penalties for such cop-outs are usually tragedy
and catastrophe, as witness such recently chronicled deaths of John
Belushi or <ent type='PERSON'>David Kennedy</ent>. Let us cite other forms of escapism than
the indulgence in hard drugs.</p>

<p>2. Alcoholism, of course, is as old as <ent type='PERSON'>Noah</ent>, if not older. It is,
of course, another form of drug abuse, but is more readily condoned
by society and outside of the Prohibition Era, Is legal. There are pro-bably 150 million <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>ns who drink, of which about 12 million
are alcoholics, people who have a weakness or affinity for alcohol
which they can no longer control. Their solution to a pro<ent type='GPE'>blem</ent> is not
to face it and solve it, but to drown it out with alcohol, thereby
postpone it and add to the pro<ent type='GPE'>blem</ent> itself, the very real pro<ent type='GPE'>blem</ent> of
alcoholism. The end result of this route is exemplified by the tragic
and miserable death of <ent type='PERSON'>William Holden</ent> and many other celebrities,
as well as millions of nonentities who die in the gutter, unheraled
and unsung.</p>

<p>3. Probably the largest single group of escape artists are
those who indulge in religion as a means of escaping the
realities of the world. Now we Creators do not take the position
that religion is bad in itself. Like the weather, it can be bad or good,
Like fire, it can be extremely useful and beneficial, when for exam-ple, it heats your home or drives a steam engine; or it can be ex-tremely <ent type='ORG'>destruc</ent>tive, as when, for instance, it burns your house down.
We Creators maintain that like fire, religion is a powerful
force for good or evil - depending on what religion it is,
by whom it is used, and on whom. For example - <ent type='NORP'>Judaism</ent> has</p>



<p>been an extremely powerful tool in the hands of the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> in promoting
the survival and evil influence of their race, whereas <ent type='NORP'>Christianity</ent> has
been a devastating tool In their hands in crippling and destroying
<ent type='EVENT'>the White Race</ent>, as I have pointed out any number of times.</p>

<p>Be that as it may. Most <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> people are either partially or whole
ly addicted to, and afflicted with <ent type='NORP'>Christianity</ent>, and use it as an escape
mechanism from reality. They go to church on <ent type='LOC'>Sunday</ent> and listen
to the preacher blabber about pie-in-the-sky when they die, and if
you don't believe him you will be barbecued in the fiery pit. They
pray to an unseen spook in the sky, and plead for his "blessings",
blabber about marriages sealed in heaven, about being born again
about going off into orbit in a "rapture", and a lot of other nonsense
that has not the slightest, basis in reality. They are, in fact, indulg-ing in mass insanity, since the best definition of insanity I know of
is having lost the ability to distinguish between what is real and what
is fantasy. When a whole group of people indulge in a similar fan-tasy such as heaven, hell, spooks and demons and babble into the
void in unison, then I believe that we can rightfully conclude that
they are indulging in mass insanity.</p>

<p>There are other forms of escapism that are flights of fantasy that
are not based on religion. Children perhaps are prone to do so when
hey believe their dolls are alive and real, or their tin soldiers or their
stuffed teddy bears are alive, and engage them in one-way conversa-tions. This is not unusual and perhaps part of the growing up pro-cess. It is when such fantasies, like the alcoholism pro<ent type='GPE'>blem</ent>, get out
of hand that they are branded autistic. Such a state is arrived at when
they can no longer be reached and oriented to the real world around
them. This is a mental condition and sometimes it can be remedied,
and sometimes it can lead to total insanity.</p>

<p>But children are not by any means the only ones that indulge
in mental fantasies as an escape. Any number of grown people also
resort to such escapisms. We have read the story of HARVEY. A
few years ago we read about the "Son of Sam" in <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent> who
claimed that a dog by that name commanded him to murder a
number of people and he did just that over a period of years, until
he was finally caught. This, too, is an extreme form of autism.</p>

<p>5. We now come to that group of people who are not aware of
an overwhelming fact of life in the present-day world - and that fact
is that the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> powerhouse controls and enslaves the people of
the world. They are living in a FOOL'S PARADISE and either
will not reconcile their thinking with reality, or fail to understand it.
this group takes in the overwhelming mass of all peoples of the
world, especially those of <ent type='EVENT'>the White Race</ent>. This includes segments
of <ent type='EVENT'>the White Race</ent> that are highly intelligent in other spheres, such
as lawyers, doctors, politicians (?) scientists, educators, journalists</p>



<p>and the whole spectrum, including (and especially) <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent>
Preachers.</p>

<p>I repeat, they are living in a dream world, detached from reali-ty, and are in the true sense of the word, as previously defined,
autistic.</p>

<p>We Creators believe in facing reality and making a sharp distinc-tion between what is fantasy and what is real. We also believe in fun
and games and what is called "R &amp; R" in the business world. There
is nothing wrong in Indulging in recreation of one kind or another
as a form of relaxation from work. We Creators especially believe
in living the good Life, the interesting life, and enjoying our stay here
on earth. This recreation can take many forms and may even involve
meandering in the world of fantasy such as seeing a play, or a movie,
or reading fiction, or even reading fairy tales to our children. But
the important distinction is this: treat a fantasy as such but don't
confuse it with reality. As <ent type='ORG'>Hypatia</ent>, that wonderfully intellectual
woman of <ent type='GPE'>Alexandria</ent> in the fourth century clearly delineated: "Fables
should be taught as fables, myths as myths, and miracles as poetic
fancies. To teach superstitions as truths is a most terrible thing. The
child-mind accepts and believes them, and only after great pain and
perhaps tragedy can he be in after years relieved of them. In fact,
man will fight for a superstition quite as quickly as for a living truth
- often more so, since a superstition is so intangible you cannot get
at it to refute it. but truth is a point of view, and so is changeable."
(See Page 310 of the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Man's Bible).</p>

<p>In CREATIVITY we finally have a religion that dispenses with
all the clutter, debris and hogwash that the human race has ac-cumulated over the ages from its superstitious and primitive <ent type='PERSON'>Stone</ent>
age ancestors. We dump it overboard once and for all and take a
refreshing, honest look at the real world that Nature has presented
to us. We do this for several good reasons (a) It greatly clarifies the
thinking process (b) It rids the mind of a lot of useless, nagging clut-ter, such as the fear of hell (c) It helps tremendously in solving the
real pro<ent type='GPE'>blem</ent>s of the world and, believe me, we have plenty of real
big ones to solve. (d) And finally, it is the one and only way we can
stop the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> onslaught in its insane obsession to destroy the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent>
Race. Only by clear thinking, total dedication and racial polariza-tion can we stave off the final and irreversible disaster that the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>
have in store for us.</p>

<p>When <ent type='PERSON'>Adolf Hitler</ent> in the 1920's came to the conclusion that none
of the old parties, or even the philosophical underpinnings of the past
could save <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> from the onslaught of <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> Communism, he
threw all the old trash overboard and started anew. He designed a
completely new political party and philosophy that was geared to
do the job that needed to be done. As we all know, National Socialism
75</p>

<p>did do the job extremely well in uniting the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> people and clean-sing the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> scene from <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> influence and manipulation. The
fact that the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> utilized the awesome might of other <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> na-tions that were still under their control to smash <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> from the
outside is another story. The point is that <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> did cleanse and
rebuild <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> with his new political philosophy and he did an ex-cellent job of it.</p>

<p>So, too, now we find the whole world in a <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> chaos, with
this sinister monster zeroing in on <ent type='EVENT'>the White Race</ent> for its total <ent type='ORG'>destruc</ent>-tion. None of the old political parties, none of the old philosophies,
or old religions, are up to the job of stopping the steam roller. In
fact, most of them have been enlisted in helping the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> in their
vicious, sadistic program. We Creators are therefore, like <ent type='PERSON'>Adolf Hitler</ent>
did half a century ago, chucking all the old garbage overboard, star-ting from square one and have designed a worldwide religion for the
<ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Race that is capable of doing the job, doing it right, and do-ing it once and for all. In CREATIVITY we are building the first
genuine RACIAL RELIGION <ent type='EVENT'>the White Race</ent> has ever had.
Just as <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> succeeded in uniting the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> people, it is our deter-mined goal to unite all the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Peoples of the world into one solid
battering ram with which to smash the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> monster. Once the
<ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Race of the world is united there is no force left to ever again
threaten it, and the battle is over for all time.</p>

<p>We must now all get behind this holy crusade or perish.
CREATIVITY is our last great opportunity. We must (and that means
you!) now polarize around that powerful central core and build and
build. We must put our shoulder to the wheel and promote, we must
propagandize, we must proselytize, we must organize. Let us get with
it!</p>

<div> * * * * *</div>

<p>For <ent type='EVENT'>the White Race</ent>, CREATIVITY has it all,
says it all, encompasses all.</p>

<div> * * * * *</div>

<p> The <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Race must learn to think in term
of: To hell with the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, To hell with the nig-gers. To hell with the mud races. THINK WHITE

* * * * *
76 </p></xml>