<xml><p>Issue No. 15, August 1984</p>

<p>Let Us Get Our Priorities Straight
Who's Trying to Save
What &amp; Whom - Precisely</p>

<p>A comprehensive and realistic survey of
the situation as it exists to date by carefully
sorting out the pretenders, the friends and the
enemies of the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Race.</p>

<p>Throughout history - individuals, groups, organizations,
religions - have been trying to "save" others of like categories from
the dire consequences of something they deem inherently evil. Some
of these crusades have been sensible and urgent, some have been
fanatically unreal, and some have been plain idiotic, depending on
the viewpoint of the observer. Some of these campaigns to save
somebody from something have been of long duration (thousands
years) some of only recent origin, some of temporary and frivolous
nature.
Since we ourselves are engaged in a holy war to save the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent>
Race from mongrelization and <ent type='ORG'>extinc</ent>tion, it behooves us to take a
clearer look at what some other groups and individuals are doing,
have been doing, and will be doing. We want to more dearly delineate
those who might be our allies. We also want to expose more clearly
those who are obviously our out-and-out enemies, but have not been
recognized as such by most of our <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Racial Comrades.
One other matter I want to clarify. Since we of <ent type='ORG'>the Church</ent> of
the Creator have been so carelessly classified and categorized with
several previously existing organizations, we again want to make it
abundantly dear that we are a comprehensive and far-reaching racial
religion that is dedicated to the survival, expansion and advance-ment of the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Race, and the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Race alone. As such we are
unique and none other exists today, and as far as we know, in all
previous history none has ever existed before.
So let us look at history and examine precisely <ent type='ORG'>WHO</ent> has been
trying to save <ent type='ORG'>WHO</ent>M and WHAT precisely, and let us start with the
<ent type='NORP'>Egyptians</ent>, who in their own way were eager beavers and fanatically
engaged in trying to save something, and what they did has grossly
affected us to this day.</p>

<p>29 THE ANCIENT
EGYPTIAN
CIVIlIZATION</p>

<p>As I have reviewed in the articles on <ent type='GPE'>Egypt</ent> in RACIAL LOYAL-TY Nos. 11 and 12, the entire <ent type='GPE'>Egypt</ent>ian civilization, the first really
Great <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> civilization, was overwhelmingly dominated by religion.
Furthermore, their religious beliefs were wholly based on <ent type='ORG'>FIC</ent>-<ent type='PERSON'>TITIOUS CONCEPTS</ent>, rooted in superstition, gullibility and hocus-pocus. Intelligent and advanced as the <ent type='NORP'>Egyptians</ent> were, they never-theless were as superstitious and gullible as any primitive barbarian.</p>

<p>But they were much more than that. They were highly ingenious
and inventive, especially in the realm of the supernatural. In fact it
is the Ancient <ent type='NORP'>Egyptians</ent> who deserve credit for mostly all the fic-titious concepts on whose sleazy foundations later were built the
so-called major religions of today. These religions include primarily
<ent type='NORP'>Judaism</ent>, <ent type='NORP'>Christianity</ent>, Mohammedanism, Buddhism, Mormonism,
and what have you.</p>

<p>What were there major innovations and concepts of the
spook world that were invented by these ancient
religionists? They were numerous, major and far-reaching.
They include: (a) The idea of the human "soul" as being separate
and apart from the mind as such. (b) The idea of immortality of the
human soul, and a life in the "hereafter". (c) The idea of reward and
punishment for acts committed in this life, to be meted out in the
"next" life. (d) The idea of heaven and hell. Although vague in <ent type='ORG'>Egyp</ent>-tian times, they laid the foundations for the monsters the <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent>:
developed in later times. (e) The idea that "gods" with supernatural
powers could, and did, control our <ent type='ORG'>liv</ent>es and mete out punishment
and rewards, not only in the "hereafter", but also in the earthly life
of each person. (f) The idea of placating, appeasing, pleasing, pray-ing and kowtowing to these imaginary gods. (Not necessarily original
with the <ent type='NORP'>Egyptians</ent>, but they expanded it into a major production)
(g) The idea of building huge temples in honor of these imaginary
gods, in order to please, placate and honor them. (h) The idea of
tombs, sarcophagi, etc. for the soul. This led to gross excesses such
as building huge pyramids. (i) Complex rituals of worship. Again,
this too was not exactly original with the <ent type='NORP'>Egyptians</ent>, but the dimen-sions to which they pushed this idea became the framework for the
later and present-day religions. (j) The widespread practice of cir-cumcision. The <ent type='NORP'>Egyptians</ent> were the first major civilization to prac-tice this barbaric mutilation of the human body as part of their
religious ritual. (k) The idea of tithing, that is extracting goods and
money From religious victims for the benefit of the priesthood, a prac-tice that has been greatly improved upon by modern religions,</p>



<p>especially the sophisticated electronic evangelists of today, the super
con-artists of all time. (I) The idea of religious hymns was already
spawned by the <ent type='NORP'>Egyptians</ent>. (m) The idea of baptism, cleansing the
"soul" by ablution with water. (n) The idea of one god (<ent type='PERSON'>Akhnaton</ent>).
(o) Six of the highly touted "Ten Commandments" that the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> brag
they gave to the world were really plagiarized directly from the <ent type='ORG'>Egyp</ent>-tians. (p) There are a number of other hocus-pocus religious ideas,
customs and terms for which we are indebted to the <ent type='NORP'>Egyptians</ent>, not
the least of which is the oft repeated, but meaningless word, "Amen",
deriving from praise of their god Amen-Ra.</p>

<p>Perhaps I am spending a little more time on the <ent type='NORP'>Egyptians</ent> than
I should, but when we contemplate the tremendous burden of
religious debris they have dumped on succeeding generations, and
especially those <ent type='ORG'>liv</ent>ing today, I believe it is highly important to unders-tand where much of it originated.</p>

<p>Now let us answer the question: WHAT were the <ent type='NORP'>Egyptians</ent>
trying to save?</p>

<p>The answer is they were trying to save their "souls" and pro-vide for a comfortable immortality - a fanaticism pursued even more
fervently by the <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent>s thousands of years later. They also had
a few lesser goals on the side. One was to overcome "time". and in
the building of their huge pyramids they have at least partly been
more successful than any other people. But they also wanted to ex-tend and glorify their "earthly" name (ego), and in this, too, they
succeeded better than most.</p>

<p>THE JEWS</p>

<p>it is one of the most fateful accidents of history that the parasitic
<ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> were spawned out of the religious milieu of the <ent type='GPE'>Egypt</ent>ian culture.
Certainly this accidental development has proved to be one
of the most catastrophic events in the development of the
<ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Race and one which in the present era may well pro-ve to be the death knell of Nature's Finest. It is the holy vow
of <ent type='ORG'>the Church</ent> Of The Creator to see to it that this will not happen.</p>

<p>In any case, the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> being a parasitic race, were also an egocen-tric race. Everything they learned they utilized for their own advan-tage - and they learned plenty from the <ent type='NORP'>Egyptians</ent>. They learned:
that religious hocus-pocus is a powerful means of controlling and
directing people's minds. (b) That people's actions follow their in-nermost motivations, and once you have control of their minds their
actions can be controlled to follow any direction their manipulators
wish.
31</p>

<p>They then set about turning these ideas into reality and went
to work converting religion per se into a powerful racial tool -
RACIAL RELIGION. They further copied from the <ent type='NORP'>Egyptians</ent>: (c) The
idea of monotheism (<ent type='PERSON'>Akhnaton</ent>). (d) Building temples for their god
(e) The idea of immortality. (f) The idea of the soul. (g) Life in the
hereafter. (h) Rituals of worship. (i) Circumcision for members of
their tribe. (j) Six of their "Ten Commandments". (k) Religion
fanaticism, this however, always in the direction of loyalty towards
their tribe.
What is it the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> are trying to save? They have one of
the clearest and most sensible goals of any existing religion in history
- the survival and expansion of their race to the point where
all other races have been mongrelized, lost their identity and
utterly destroyed, only to be enslaved into the toils of their
<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> master. They fanatically pursue their goals with a zeal as
no other race ever has - to enslave and dominate the rest of
mankind and to accrue unto themselves all the gold, silver
and other assets on the face of the earth. Their goals are
clear, they are vicious, and they make a lot of sense - for
the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>.</p>

<p>What do we Creators have in common with the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>? Absolutely
nothing, and everything. The <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> are our most vicious and bitter
foes. It is our desire to wipe <ent type='NORP'>Judaism</ent> from the face of the earth
DELENDA EST JUDAICA is our battle cry! But we have learned
just about everything from the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> about how to build a racial
religion for the survival, expansion and advancement of the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent>
Race.</p>

<p>One major difference between us and the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> is this: Whereas
the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> have throughout their history been a parasitic minority <ent type='ORG'>liv</ent>-ing on the backs of productive <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> civilizations, we Creators are
just the opposite. We <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Creators are the most productive,
creative species on the face of the earth. We need no <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, no
mud races, no slaves, for our welfare and the sooner we get
all the parasites off of our back, the sooner every <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Man
can <ent type='ORG'>liv</ent>e like a king. Nor do we plan to stay a minority. Whereas
we have no desire to dominate or enslave anybody, we want to ex-pand the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Race until we crowd out the mud races and inherit
the earth - all of it - for the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Race.</p>

<div> * * * * *</div>

<p>Once we get the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, muds and other
parasites off our backs, every <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Man can <ent type='ORG'>liv</ent>e
like a king and every <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Woman like a queen.</p>

<div> * * * * *</div>

<p> 32 THE GREEKS</p>

<p>The inherent characteristic of the <ent type='NORP'>Greeks</ent> was their love of beau-ty, culture, and their innate intelligence. Their limited goals were to
save their own city states from neighboring city states, and because
of such limited political and racial vision they warred on each other
endlessly in such fratricidal bloodletting as the <ent type='NORP'>Peloponnesian</ent> wars,
and thereby destroyed themselves. It was this fratricidal infighting
and their failure to realize the Divine Seed they possessed, that led
to their political downfall and the mongrelization of their excellent
gene pool.</p>

<p>What do we Creators share with the <ent type='NORP'>Greeks</ent>? Well, we also pur-sue the goals of culture, beauty, art and intelligence, but that is all.
We are aware of one great bonus the <ent type='NORP'>Greeks</ent> were not - how to
protect our gene pool and advance it ever higher and onward
to levels the <ent type='NORP'>Greeks</ent> never even dreamed of.</p>

<p>THE ROMANS</p>

<p>Like the <ent type='NORP'>Greeks</ent>, the <ent type='NORP'>Romans</ent> started with excellent racial stock,
but oriented in a somewhat different direction. Whereas the <ent type='NORP'>Greeks</ent>
were highly innovative, and gifted in the arts and in culture, the
<ent type='NORP'>Romans</ent> were more pragmatic. They were great warriors, organize
and law givers, and as a result they not only conquered the <ent type='NORP'>Greeks</ent>
but all of the then known and worthwhile world around the Mediter-ranean. Because they were such excellent conquerors they soon had
slaves by the millions to do their menial labor for them and this pro-ved to be their downfall. Because they took in all the conquered
peoples of the era, they also took in a lot of mud genes and bastar-dized their once noble race.</p>

<p>What was their main passion? To save <ent type='GPE'>Rome</ent> - the Em-pire. This they did for a thousand years but they lost their precious
genes in the meantime because they lacked a racial religion. As a
result, the collapse of <ent type='GPE'>Rome</ent> was one of the greatest tragedies in
history.</p>

<p>What do we Creators have in common with the <ent type='NORP'>Romans</ent>? A great
deal, really. Our love for law and order, the desire to build, and the
desire for empire building, as well as many other noble traits. Had
The <ent type='NORP'>Romans</ent> only realized the preciousness of their inherent
genes and the value of a racial religion!</p>

<div> * * * * *</div>

<p>Help build a mighty <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Racial Movement.
Help build CREATIVITY.</p>

<p> 33
THE CHRISTIANS</p>

<p>Whereas the <ent type='NORP'>Judaic</ent> religion was spawned out of the hocus-pocus
welter of <ent type='GPE'>Egypt</ent>ian religions, <ent type='NORP'>Christianity</ent> in turn was a planned
deliberate outgrowth of <ent type='NORP'>Judaism</ent>. Without the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent>
Race would never had the scourge of <ent type='NORP'>Christianity</ent> in-flicted upon it. I have already elaborated on this subject in
NATURE'S ETERNAL RELIGION (Christ's Existence Not Substan-tiated By Historical Evidence) and several other places in my writings.</p>

<p>Briefly the story as it can be pieced together is this: When <ent type='GPE'>Rome</ent>
dominated the world in the first century C.E., (Common Era) they
assimilated, among many other territories, the minor <ent type='NORP'>Judaic</ent> kingdom
in <ent type='GPE'>Palestine</ent>, whose Capitol was <ent type='GPE'>Jerusalem</ent>. As always, although
militarily conquered, the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> were rebellious against authority. In
order to subdue them and lay waste to their cities, Emperor Vespa-sian sent General <ent type='PERSON'>Titus</ent> to <ent type='GPE'>Judea</ent> to quell the rebellion. With a few
legions he laid siege to <ent type='GPE'>Jerusalem</ent> and in less than two years he con-quered and leveled <ent type='GPE'>Jerusalem</ent> to the ground.</p>

<p>That should have been the end of the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> as the destruction
of <ent type='GPE'>Carthage</ent> was the end of the <ent type='NORP'>Carthaginians</ent>. But it was not. The
<ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> were a tenacious tribe, thanks to the virulence and cohesiveness
of their racial religion, <ent type='NORP'>Judaism</ent>. They planned revenge, and the
destruction of the <ent type='NORP'>Romans</ent>: (See <ent type='ORG'>Creative Credo</ent> No. 43 "Confession
Of A <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>", in <ent type='ORG'>the WHITE MAN</ent>'S BIBLE)</p>

<p>The <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> took a deadly course of action for which the <ent type='NORP'>Romans</ent>
were completely defenseless and unprepared, and which even while
the poison was being administered to them, they never understood.
Even to this day the overwhelming majority of the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Race fails
to understand it, although the evidence is laid out before them, loud
and clear.</p>

<p>The <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> now put into play the tenaciousness of their <ent type='NORP'>Judaic</ent>
religion - they put into full practice their trump cards - polariza-tion and dispersion. (See Issue No. 13).</p>

<p>The <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> utilized their tremendous accumulation of religious
knowledge and psychological expertise. They went to work on the
brains of the <ent type='NORP'>Romans</ent>. They transformed the dauntless world con-quering <ent type='NORP'>Roman</ent> warriors into whimpering, peace-loving wimps. The
tool they used was <ent type='NORP'>Christianity</ent>.</p>

<p>Instrumental in this brilliant idea was a <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent> by the name of <ent type='PERSON'>Saul</ent>
of Tarsus, who later became the <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent>s' St. Paul. In order to put
this piece of chicanery together he dredged up the teachings of a
little known and dying religious sect around the <ent type='LOC'>Dead Sea</ent>. They were
known as the <ent type='ORG'>Essenes</ent>, and they were a <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> sect, completely out
of the mainstream of <ent type='NORP'>Judaism</ent>.</p>

<p>From their suicidal teachings ("Sell all thou hast", "Love your</p>

<p> 34 enemies", "turn the other cheek"), he concocted a deadly religion</p>

<p>to feed to the <ent type='NORP'>Romans</ent>. The whole <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> network soon threw
themselves into the battle with a frenzy seldom before witnessed in
history. What they accomplished next through the power of their
religious zeal is, and remains, one of the most outstanding events
in history.</p>

<p>The peoples of the <ent type='NORP'>Roman</ent> <ent type='GPE'>Empire</ent> (who by now were a mere
shadows of the original <ent type='NORP'>Roman</ent> stock) became obsessed with this new
Religion. As their minds became more and more drugged with this
anti-natare, anti-life doctrine, the <ent type='GPE'>Empire</ent> slowly sank, civilization
disintegrated, and an ominous dark pall settled over Europe for the
next thousand years. <ent type='EVENT'>The Dark Ages</ent> set in.</p>

<p>The <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> had triumphed with their B-bomb (brain-bomb). Their
triumph over the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Race prevails to this day, more ominously
than ever. The B-bomb is still ticking. What is it the <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent>s
are trying to save? Why, souls! All kinds of souls! All kinds of souls
- <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> brown and black, from the fiery pit of hell. And who con-cocted this horrible booby-trap? Why, the sweet loving (<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent>) god
who at the same time is supposedly making a big to-do that he is
trying to save us all from that same fiery pit.</p>

<p>What a crock of nonsense! Nobody has ever seen, heard, felt
or smelt a god, or spook, or a soul. Talk about fictitious concepts!
The <ent type='NORP'>Egyptians</ent> invented them, the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> capitalized on them, and the
stupid <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent>s swallowed the poisoned bait. (Read again "Fictitious
Concepts" in R.L., Issue No. 7, of <ent type='NORP'>Expan</ent>ding Creativity</p>

<p>What do we Creators have in common with the <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent>s? Not
much , except that about half of the <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent>s of the world are <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent>,
and most <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> people, unfortunately, are still quasi-<ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent>s.</p>

<p>NATIONAL SOCIALISM</p>

<p>When we speak of the <ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent>, I think it is extremely important
that we differentiate between the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> era of <ent type='PERSON'>Adolf Hitler</ent> in <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent>,
and the neo-<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> groups that have spawned here in <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>. They
are not the same.</p>

<p>First the <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> era. Since I reviewed fairly thoroughly "<ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent>,
<ent type='PERSON'>Adolf Hitler</ent> and National Socialism" in Chapter 5, Book II of Nature's
Eternal Religion (p.290), it is not necessary for me to do so again.
I Will simply state what their goals were. Basically the thrust of
Hitler's movement was to (a) save <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> from <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> communism
(b) tear up the Versailles Treaty and recover territories lost by <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> to surrounding countries (<ent type='GPE'>France</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Poland</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Czechoslovakia</ent>,
ect.), (c) break the back of <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> money manipulators (d) expand
<ent type='NORP'>German</ent> hegemony and territory castward into the fertile lands of</p>



<p>Russia and <ent type='ORG'>Eastern</ent> Europe. There is more, but basically this sums
it up. The main idea was pan-<ent type='NORP'>German</ent>ism (Deutschland uber <ent type='GPE'>Alles</ent>!)
and vigorous <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> expansion, at the expense of many other <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent>
nations such as the <ent type='NORP'>French</ent>, <ent type='NORP'>Poles</ent>, <ent type='NORP'>Czechs</ent>, <ent type='NORP'>Slavs</ent>, <ent type='NORP'>Rumanians</ent>, Rus-sians and others.</p>

<p>We have now come to the helter-skelter of neo-<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> groups
<ent type='GPE'>America</ent> that have sprung up since <ent type='PERSON'>George Lincoln Rockwell</ent> reviv-ed the neo-<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> movement in 1958. We could also cite the Silver
Shirts of the 1930's, but they were actually a different breed, spawn-ed and supported directly out of <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent>, and died out when <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> lost the war.</p>

<p> What is it the neo-<ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent> in <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> are trying to save?</p>

<p>Well, there is no one clear answer. They are at best a mixed
breed, with motives as diverse and confused as are their members.
Some are out-and-out plants organized by the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>
themselves so that the <ent type='ORG'>ADL</ent> can point with alarm to their
own dues paying members about the horrible threat of <ent type='PERSON'>nas</ent>-cent Neo-<ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent>m. This drives the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> wild and they will quickly
cough up millions to help swell the war chest of the <ent type='ORG'>ADL</ent>. It works
beautifully.</p>

<p>Then there are the <ent type='GPE'>Hollywood</ent> type of <ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent>, who, like the Civil
War buffs, love to parade in <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> uniforms, arm bands and all, and
throw the stiff-arm salute repeatedly. Basically they are shallow in-dividuals indulging themselves on an ego trip. I have met quite a few
of them and find most of them are as confused as a little boy who
has just lost his chewing gum on the floor of a chicken pen.</p>

<p>then there are the more serious type that want to emulate the
brilliant success of <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> in the 1930's and believe they can transpose
those same procedures onto the <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n scene of the 1980's. Their
main success seems to pigeonhole itself into glorifying <ent type='PERSON'>Adolf Hitler</ent>
(nothing wrong with that) but not in really having a ghost of a chance
of actually building a meaningful movement in <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> to do the
job that needs to be done. Why? Because they don't have a grasp
on reality and only a superficial understanding of the situation.
Among other things, they don't seem to understand at all (a) that
<ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> was a phenomena, a genius of unbounded energy, and the suc-cess of the movement was more due to the personality of this great
unusual man than the philosophy he espoused, and (b) his program
was tailor-made for the situation in <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> during the 1920's, but
not geared to the <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> of the 1980's, and (c) were a young, vibrant
<ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> a<ent type='ORG'>liv</ent>e in <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> today he would, I am sure, take an altogether
different approach. (d) None of the personalities on the scene in
<ent type='GPE'>America</ent> today are even comparable to the genius of <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> (e) That
because 13 million <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>ns fought against the <ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent> in
<ent type='EVENT'>WWII</ent>, the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> image in anathema to average <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n,</p>



<p>many of whose relative were killed in that war. Not only
is the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> image of no help, thanks to the massive
<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> propaganda barrage over the past 50 years it is a
tremendous barrier towards a feasible solution to the
<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> scourge</p>

<p>So what are the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> groups trying to save? It is a confused pic-ture. Most of them are merely on an ego trip, hoping they will become
A <ent type='GPE'>MODERN</ent> DAY INCARNATION OF ADOLF HITLER.</p>

<p>Most of the various splinter groups are feuding amongst
themselves and are as hostile to each other as they are to the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>.
Most of them have no clear philosophy of any kind, no goals, take
a wimpy stand on <ent type='NORP'>Christianity</ent>, and no program whatsoever on how
to achieve the goals they don't have.</p>

<p>Some advance specious argument such as "when the race war
starts and there is blood flowing in the streets, then all these groups
will unite!" Really? How are they going to do that? (Read again "Make
Hay While The <ent type='LOC'>Sun</ent> Shines" in Racial Loyalty issue No. 13). Their
vague answer to that: "<ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> did it." That just isn't so. <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> did not
unite with, or merge, the thousands of political groups that were
spawned in <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> after <ent type='EVENT'>WWI</ent>. In fact, in his book <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> definite-ly denounces the merging of organizations as weakening and/or
destroying the original organizations. What <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> did was con-vert and absorb the individual members of other groups in-to one solid <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Party</ent>. In short, he polarized the individuals
into one mighty movement under his leadership, and he did
not do it while anarchy ran rampant and blood flowed in the streets.
He did it under fairly civilized and orderly conditions. I repeat - let
us do likewise and unite under the banner of a racial religion - the
most powerful idea we have to work with, now or ever.</p>

<p>So what are the neo-<ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent> trying to save? It varies from group
to group. But the main thing they have in common is they are trying
to save their own hubris. (<ent type='PERSON'>Webster</ent> defines hubris as overwhelming
personal ego.)</p>

<p>THE ODINISTS</p>

<p>Like <ent type='EVENT'>the Civil War</ent> buffs and the <ent type='GPE'>Hollywood</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent>, the Odinists
in a way are playing games with an era that has slipped away into
the distant past and can never be revived again, any more than you
can revive a dead horse, though you may try to awaken it with a
massive blast of dynamite.</p>

<p>Though small, the members of the revised Odinists movement
are Intellectually a cut above the neo-<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>, and their racial goals
are sensible, although they have little or nothing to do with Odin,
Thor or Wodin. Basically they use these <ent type='NORP'>Norse</ent> mythologies as a sort</p>



<p>of backdrop, a Mythos, as <ent type='PERSON'>Alfred Rosenberg</ent> would describe, to cling
to as a point of departure.</p>

<p>But why must they use such cluttered window dressing as a
necessary prop? True, the <ent type='ORG'>Vikings</ent> were great fighters and excellent
physical specimens, but intellectually they were on a level with <ent type='PERSON'>Hagar</ent>
the Horrible in the Comic Strips. Mostly they were highly illiterate
and most of what we know about their mythologies were conveyed
to us by the more literate <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent>s of a later date. In any case, the
Viking understood nothing of the more powerful mind.
bending tactic of the more cunning <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, and were no
match for them at any time. In consequence they succumbed to
the more sinister and seductive <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> lure and today their descen-dants - the <ent type='NORP'>Danes</ent>, <ent type='NORP'>Swedes</ent> and <ent type='NORP'>Norwegians</ent>, are the most sub-missive <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>-loving wimps on the face of the earth. <ent type='NORP'>Christianity</ent> and
other <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> propaganda has done its job well.</p>

<p>So what would convince anyone that an insipid set of Mother
goose myths could and will reverse a situation from an era that has
passed on and is now as dead as a doornail? The answer -
nothing. We believe that the Odinists, good people that they are,
should dump this unnecessary garbage and join with us In a full fledg-ed racial religion that covers the complete spectrum, but is not bogg-ed down with a mass of ballast that can only be an insult to any <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent>
Man's intelligence.</p>

<p>What are the Odinists trying to save? Here we have to differen-tiate between the Odinist of the ancient <ent type='ORG'>Vikings</ent> and that of the small
modern group with their revived version. The original Odinists were
lainly indulging in unadulterated superstition playing religious games
with their own concocted gods and myths, as had so many other
peoples before them - the <ent type='GPE'>Egypt</ent>ian, the <ent type='NORP'>Greeks</ent>, the <ent type='NORP'>Romans</ent>, and
even hundreds of mud races. Even In that category the quality of the
Viking myths were several cuts below that of the more erudite and
civilized <ent type='NORP'>Greeks</ent> and <ent type='NORP'>Romans</ent>.</p>

<p>The revived and revamped modern day Odinists have somewhat
different goals that can be delineated into two incompatible and
unrelated categories. One, to vicariously re<ent type='ORG'>liv</ent>e the trappings of a
bygone era. which, if it were to be really duplicated would be pretty
miserable. and secondly. to revive a "mythos" upon which to build
an "<ent type='NORP'>Aryan</ent>" religion end be able to point to it with pride and say "this
is a <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Man's religion, not a Judeo-<ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> religion". Although
even in this category their modern day version has many gaps and
is incomplete, we Creators share these goals with Odinists. In rejec-ing <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Christianity</ent> the Odinists have already gone a long way
towards our position. We there suggest that they stop play-ing games, join with us all the way in a real <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Man's
religion that has the total Program, the Final Solution, the</p>

<p> 38
Ultimate Creed.</p>

<p>THE PATRIOTS
We now come to the group in <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> that is probably the
largest, the most amorphous, and also the most disorganized and
the most confused.</p>

<p>Since this category includes so many groups that it is impossi-ble to list, I will go straight to the common denominator and ask
the rhetorical question: What are they trying to save? And the
noble sounding answer is "We are trying to save the
country".</p>

<p>When asked: From whom? Their answers become extremely
fuzzy. From the bureaucrats, from the <ent type='NORP'>Democrats</ent>, from the
<ent type='NORP'>Republicans</ent>, from <ent type='PERSON'>Carter</ent>, from Reagan, from the politicians, from
the C.F.R., from the <ent type='NORP'>Bilderbergers</ent>, from the <ent type='NORP'>Trilateralists</ent>, from the
"internationalists", from the "insiders", from the <ent type='NORP'>communists</ent>, from
the <ent type='NORP'>Zionists</ent>, from the Dual Loyalists, from the U. N., from special
interests, from the bankers, from ourselves (even!). Depending on
whom you ask, you can come up with a whole plethora of different
answers - but strangely they all have one other thing in common
- they will never put their finger on the real culprit - thee
<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> powerhouse.</p>

<p>When asked a second meaningful question, namely for whom
are they trying to save the country, they act as if they had never
given that a thought. Why the people, of course, is their bland
answer. When this line of questioning is pursued further - would
you fight and lay down your life to save this country so it
could be populated with wall-to-wall niggers and other mud
peoples, and run by the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>? Would you try to "save the coun-try" although its government, press and whole power establishment
was intensely hostile to the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Race, and had, in fact a series
of aggressive programs in force aimed at mongrelizing and/or com-mitting genocide on the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Race? Would you fight for a govern-ment and country whose loyalty was overwhelmingly for the bandit
state of <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent> and everything <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> but extremely hostile to the
<ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Race? Would you again fight a war for a government
and country that joined hands with the <ent type='NORP'>Russian</ent> <ent type='NORP'>communists</ent>
in 1941, and fought a war that killed millions of our best
<ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> men, only to save the necks of the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> monsters?
At this point the <ent type='ORG'>Patriot</ent> becomes extremely alarmed, agitated,
confused, and even hostile. They start mumbling incoherent phrases
programmed into their unthinking minds by the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> propaganda
mill. Automatically they mumble something about racists, <ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent>,</p>

<p> 39 bigots, and they don't want to get into "it".</p>

<p>Well, nuff said. I have covered this subject more fully in Chapter
2 (Part II) of NATURES'S ETERNAL RELIGION, "Your Loyalty -
a <ent type='ORG'>Sacred Trust</ent>", and also several chapters in <ent type='ORG'>the WHITE MAN</ent>'S
BIBLE, namely <ent type='ORG'>Creative Credo</ent> Nos. 17, 18, 21, 29, 32 and several
others.</p>

<p>What do we Creators have in common with the <ent type='ORG'>Patriot</ent>s? Well,
quite a lot - mostly in the fact that the majority of our good <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent>
friends belong to this confused and helpless lot. It is also in this group
that most of our potential members now lie dormant, in great need
of both awakening and education.</p>

<p>However, I must make clear the distinction between "patriot"
Individuals and "patriotic" organizations, and post a warning. Most
of the organizations that appeal to the average <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n's patriotism
are <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent> spawned, are designed to distract, confuse and relieve the
average <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n of his money - especially his money. In
short, most of them are <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> rackets, surprisingly many based in
the <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent> capital of the world - <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, D. C. Most such come
In well sounding appeals such as "Help save the Panama Canal".
(Now who but a rogue wouldn't want to help save the Panama Canal
for <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>?) They come equipped with neatly printed, self-addressed, postage paid envelopes, and of course the standard fare,
the card which says "I enclose $5.00, $25.00, $100.00, $500.00,
$1000.00". They have it down to a science and it works beautifully</p>

<p>THE
CONSTITUTIONALISTS</p>

<p>Closely allied to the patriots, but better read, and intellectually
a few cuts above the average <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n <ent type='ORG'>Patriot</ent> are the Constitu-tionalists, although they have much the same attitude. They are for
saving the Constitution for God, flag and country. The main dif-ference is they want to do it in a specific way, by "enforcing" the
Constitution.</p>

<p>When asked the rhetorical question - Who do you expect will
enforce the Constitution as you want it enforced? The answer is: the
government!</p>

<p>It is a useless hassle to point out the obvious to them: The
government is Public Enemy No. 1, hostile as hell to the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Race
and hell-bent on the total destruction of the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Race and every
value we hold dear. Our <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n government is totally in the hands
of our mortal enemy the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, who are using the Constitution to rob,
loot and destroy the best and most productive element of the polyglot
<ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n melting pot - the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> worker.</p>

<p>To try to reason with the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> powerhouse, to explain con-</p>

<p> 40 stitutional niceties, to "convince" them they should change their</p>

<p>ways, is pure insanity. The <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> are fully aware of what they are do-ing, although the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Man is not, and nothing, but nothing, is go-ing to "persuade" them to change their course - except raw, massive
power.</p>

<p>In order to generate such a power base the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Man has
build his own massive movement and brutally smash the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent>
establishment to smithereens. Only a massive <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> steamroller
movement an do this, and before we can do so we have to
get our priorities straight. This, of course, is what Creativity is
all about and I will have more to say about this in the conclusion
of this article.</p>

<p>THE WHITE CHRISTIAN
RACISTS</p>

<p>This group is really a breed apart and needs special mention from
that of the <ent type='ORG'>Patriot</ent>s and the <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent>s. in this category we can list
The <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> Vanguard, The Thunderbolt, <ent type='ORG'>The National</ent> States
Rights <ent type='ORG'>Party</ent> (which claim they are now UN-connected from each
other). The various <ent type='NORP'>Klans</ent> also fit into this category, although loose-ly. There are a few dozen other small groups that also espouse the
cause of <ent type='NORP'>Christianity</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> racism.</p>

<p>This whole string of groups, too, is highly amorphous and a com-pletely mixed bag of tricks. Without examining each one in detail
the common characteristic or goal of all these groups is they are
presumably trying to save your soul from the fiery pit and the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent>
Race at the same time. This, of course, is a highly contradictory goal
and self-defeating. It is like trying to win the <ent type='ORG'>Indy</ent> 500, but you make
sure that every time you push down on the accelerator with one foot,
you push down even harder on the brakes with the other. (Read again
"Self-imposed Handicaps" in Racial Loyalty Issue No. 6 of <ent type='NORP'>Expan</ent>-ding Creativity). That is one hell of a way to win a race, and, of
course, you never do.</p>

<p>The biggest harm these groups do is confuse the hell
out of the average <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> racist by pounding away at the term
"<ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent>" over and over and over, until like the
<ent type='NORP'>Pavlovian</ent> dog, the victim begins to think that the two terms
are synonymous, when, in fact, we have shown throughout
this and dozens of other articles that <ent type='NORP'>Christianity</ent> is poison
to the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Race, was a major cause of the disintegration of the
<ent type='NORP'>Roman</ent> race and the fall of its <ent type='GPE'>Empire</ent>, and was spawned by the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>
for that very purpose in the first place.
One other immense value these Pro-<ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> anti-<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> Chris-tians have to the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> cause is this: It provides a feasible argu-</p>

<p> 41 ment against clarifying the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent>-<ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent>-<ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Race</p>

<p>dilemma Protagonists for <ent type='NORP'>Christianity</ent> can point to the fact that
<ent type='NORP'>Christianity</ent> can't be a <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> hoax because <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent>s like (the above
mentioned) are strongly anti-<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent>. Sounds reasonable.</p>

<p>But the dominant fact is the overwhelming majority of Chris-tians like <ent type='ORG'>the National Council</ent> of <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>es, <ent type='ORG'>the World Council</ent> of
<ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>es, like Moral Majority and <ent type='PERSON'>the Jerry Falwell</ent> Crowd, Billy
Graham, the <ent type='ORG'>Catholic Church</ent>, are all strongly PRO-<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent>, PRO-<ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent>, PRO-race-mixing and ANTI-<ent type='PERSON'>White</ent>. These groups represent
more than 99 Per cent of the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent>s of the world, and the
comparative handful of ANTI-<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent>s do nothing
more than confuse the issue by Providing a credible argu-ment for not exposing the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> nature and origins of
<ent type='NORP'>Christianity</ent></p>

<p>The end result most of these groups accomplish is similar to that
of <ent type='ORG'>the Birch Society</ent> and that is as its members see one defeat after
another, the enticements of throwing in the towel and thinking more
and more of the blandishments of the next world in heaven become
stronger and stronger. In this way one good <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Racial fighter after
another is neutralized and finally becomes a total victim of that
<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> mind scrambler. He becomes a "devoted", "dedicated" Chris-tian and lets the real world (and his race) go to hell - into the hell
of the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>.</p>

<p>THE POPULISTS</p>

<p>Recently, especially under the auspices of The Spotlight out
of <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>the Populist Party</ent> has received some mediocre pro-minence and publicity (nothing in comparison to, for example, what
that little talentless mongrel, <ent type='PERSON'>Michael Jackson</ent> has been showered
with). Since The Spotlight has a relatively large circulation for a
paper that (overtly) professes to be ANTI-<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> (Well, at least ANTI-<ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent>) this phenomena deserves some attention.</p>

<p>What does <ent type='ORG'>the Populist Party</ent> stand for?</p>

<p>Well, basically it is supposed to be <ent type='ORG'>the People</ent>'s <ent type='ORG'>Party</ent> and repre-sent the will of the people (aren't all Political Parties made up out
of people, and stand for, by, of, behind, and in front of the people?
It is supposed to represent <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>nism - to go back to the good
old times, and plethora of old time goodies, including stick candy
with red, white and blue stripes on it.</p>

<p>Let us go back a little into the history of <ent type='ORG'>the Populist Party</ent>.</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>The Populist Party</ent> was founded as an agrarian political party
in February, 1892, in St. Louis, MO. It represented in general three
groups: (a) <ent type='NORP'>Western</ent> farmers. (b) <ent type='NORP'>Southern</ent> farmers who through the
Farmers Alliance had sought to, but failed, to capture the</p>



<p>Democratic <ent type='ORG'>Party</ent>, and (c) Representatives of several labor and reform
groups. At their first convention on July 4, 1892, in <ent type='GPE'>Omaha</ent>, they
adopted a platform of the graduated income tax (we have it now,
do we ever!), direct election of U.S. Senators (we have that now also),
free coinage of gold and silver in a ratio of 16 to 1, and other reforms
relating to land, currency and transportation.</p>

<p>By 1896 the party was captured by <ent type='PERSON'>William Jennings Byran</ent> and
it soon committed suicide, hobbling along until 1908, when it became
defunct.</p>

<p>A revival of this same party today is as archaic as trying to revive
the Odinist gods, or the <ent type='ORG'>Klan</ent> of the 1880's or the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Party</ent> of the
1930's. They do not fit the massive fob at hand. They do not address
the overwhelming issue staring us in the face - the racial issue. They
only fiddle around the fringes, but never come to grips with
the nitty gritty - <ent type='NORP'>Christianity</ent>, the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, the explosion of the
mud races.</p>

<p>Besides the obviously blatant inadequacy of <ent type='ORG'>the Populist Party</ent>
and its platform to do the massive job that needs to be done, it has
inherent in it that basic weakness characteristic of all democracies
- it is based on mob psychology. History has taught us - or should
have by now - that no great heroic thought or act ever emerges
from the mob. On the contrary, only the lowest, basest demands
come out of any mob. It always sinks to the lowest denominator,
namely - how can I get a free ride at the public trough. As <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent>
has pointed out - all great ideas emerge out of the minds of great
individual personalities - great leaders.</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>The Populist Party</ent> runs exactly counter to the Leadership Prin-ciple and instead seeks to cater to the wishes of the mob for its direc-tion. Since the mob, collectively, never really knows what it wants
and at best has a multi-polyglot mind that is usually confused beyond
belief, you can be sure the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> will quickly take control, if they didn't
instigate the whole scam in the first place.</p>

<p>I predict that <ent type='ORG'>the Populist Party</ent> will go the way of its earlier
counterpart around the turn of the century, and as did George
Wallace's <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n Independent <ent type='ORG'>Party</ent>, namely, belly up.</p>

<p>So what is <ent type='ORG'>the Populist Party</ent> trying to save? Well, presumable
the country, for the people. But which of the polyglot mess of peo-ple that inhabit this country, they don't say. Basically, the Populist
<ent type='ORG'>Party</ent> is only the Spotlight, and the Spotlight is <ent type='PERSON'>Willis Carto</ent>. So what
is <ent type='PERSON'>Willis Carto</ent> trying to save? Well, looking at his record and that
of the Spotlight, it seems to me that <ent type='PERSON'>Willis Carto</ent> is trying to save
his own hubris and his own little empire at any cost - for Willis
Carto.</p>

<p>The Spotlight is riding a tricky little tightrope and has tried to
play both sides, whichever pays best, and sells the most books and</p>



<p>papers. <ent type='PERSON'>Willis Carto</ent> has written a glowing endorsement as the
<ent type='ORG'>FOREWORD</ent> to Nietsche's "Anti-Christ" which his publishing house,
<ent type='ORG'>Noontide Press</ent>, puts out. At the same time he will publish equally
glowing reports about what a great <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> is the movie actor, Ty
Hardin, and isn't it wonderful. When a fairly innocuous article about
the Odinists and the Creativity movement brought down the wrath
of the <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent>s on his neck with numerous cancellations, he again
hastily retreated to publishing long installments by <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> pastors
about the wonderful complexities of <ent type='NORP'>Christianity</ent>.</p>

<p>He admitted frankly that the <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent>s are the mainstay of his
paper and he cannot afford to offend them, no matter how deluded
they may be.</p>

<p>Is Carto going to help save the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Race? For years I thought
he might. He claims to print what the "controlled press" is afraid
to print and will suppress. But when it comes to <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> directly,
or the <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> hoax, he evidently is as cowardly as the rest
of them, and if he "must" cater to the <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent>s, then, The
Spotlight is as controlled as is the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> press. They never
attack the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> as such, but fritter around the edges with such terms
as the Dual Loyalists, the <ent type='NORP'>Zionists</ent>, and other silly terms.</p>

<p>Can we look to <ent type='ORG'>the Populist Party</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Willis Carto</ent> for guidance?
I don't think so. After being snookered by experts, I am beginning
to have an intuitive sixth sense about such people, and my sixth sense
tells me that The Spotlight and <ent type='PERSON'>Willis Carto</ent> will go the way of William
Buckley and his <ent type='ORG'>National Review</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Robert Welch</ent> and his <ent type='ORG'>Birch Socie</ent>-ty, <ent type='PERSON'>George Wallace</ent> and the <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n independent <ent type='ORG'>Party</ent>. (Since I
was chairman of the <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n independent <ent type='ORG'>Party</ent> for <ent type='GPE'>Florida</ent> in its
heyday I believe I am speaking from experience about that betrayal).
That route is to raise the hopes of the victims, to take the people's
money, sell them down the river, thoroughly neutralize them, and
continue to play ball with the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>. Business as usual.</p>

<p>In the meantime a lot of good <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> people will pour a lot of
their time, money and energy down the rathole, emerge sadder but
wiser, and probably be permanently neutralized. We Creators want
no part of it. Personally I learned my lesson from the <ent type='PERSON'>Wallace</ent> fracas.
Never again.</p>

<p>THE INTELLECTUALS</p>

<p>There is one other group, minor in impact, that are ideologically
on our side, but do little to further our movement. These are the
armchair strategists, the intellectuals, who write all kinds of
erudite books, booklets and articles, but really do little if anything
to help the cause.</p>



<p>I will take only one case in point because this fine old gentleman
who is now in his 90's, illustrates what many others do less brilliant-ly than he has.</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>William Gayley Simpson</ent>, over a period of forty years wrote the
material for his masterpiece: "Which Way <ent type='NORP'>Western</ent> Man?" I read the
book several years ago and think it is great, but also have several
criticisms regarding its content, such as the long drawn out disser-tation about his infatuation with <ent type='NORP'>Christianity</ent> and his gradual disillu-sionment. Also I believe the obsession with <ent type='ORG'>Nietsche</ent> is far longer
than serves any purpose.</p>

<p>Nevertheless, and be that as it may, my main point is this: After
the wealth of information he brilliantly displays about the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>,
money, the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Race, and other vital subjects that concern the
survival of the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Race, he comes to the dour conclusion that
there really isn't much hope that we will be able to pull out of our
dilemma before it's too late, and anyway he knows of no solution.
He admits he has no answer.</p>

<p>The book ends just the way the title begins, saying namely, I
don't have the answer, only the question.</p>

<p>This kind of approach always aggravates the hell out of me. If
you are an expert and you give me a long drawn out diagnosis, but
have no solution, why did you waste a lot of my time telling me (again)
about the problem? (Read again "The Flat Tire Syndrome" in Racial
Loyalty Issue No. 1 of <ent type='NORP'>Expan</ent>ding Creativity).</p>

<p>We Creators are not interested in hearing a rehash of
the problem for the hundredth time no matter how intellec-tual, how cleverly it might be rephrased. Nor are we interested
in witnessing a brilliant display of some writer's intricate knowledge
of past details, If in all of this there is no answer toward solving the
problem that overwhelms all other issues, and that is - the survival,
expansion and advancement of the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Race.</p>

<p>In one way such intellectual armchair strategists do a great deal
of harm, other than taking the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Man's money and wasting his
time in rehashing the same old problem, and that damage is this:
The average yokel, who does not consider himself an expert by any
means, upon reading such "expert" analysis, is greatly depressed and
discouraged. He comes to the logical conclusion that if such a
knowledgeable expert has no answer, has no solution, and thinks there
is no hope, how can he be expected to know what to do? He con-cludes that it is hopeless and throws in the towel.</p>

<div> * * * * *</div>

<p> 45 CONCLUSION</p>

<p>There are, of course, thousands of other groups that I have not
mentioned that are organized to save something. There is the
<ent type='ORG'>Greenpeace</ent> group that are fanatically and actively out to save baby
seals. There is <ent type='ORG'>the Audubon Society</ent> that has tens of thousands of
members that are concerned about the environment in general and
birds in particular. There are even more specialized groups that are
spending real money and energy trying to save the remaining 50
Whooping Cranes. There is the <ent type='ORG'>NAACP</ent> and dozens of similar
organizations that are trying to save niggers.</p>

<p>The list is endless. The bottom line on mostly all of them, in one
way or another, is - it is the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Man's time and money that goes
into practically all these endeavors. This spans the entire spectrum,
all the way from saving ephemeral "souls" to saving Whooping
Cranes. We say this: The birds are for the birds, the niggers are for
the niggers, the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> are for the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, and are they ever! What about
the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Race? Who is for them?</p>

<p>The question that screams to high heaven is that if the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent>
Man can become so involved and concerned about saving every
meaningless trifle on the face of the earth, why is he so lethargic,
dead on his feet, yes, even ashamed, to save the most
precious value on the face of the earth that is dying out (ac-tually being murdered), namely the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Race itself?</p>

<p>Doesn't the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Race know about the <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>? He should. Henry
Ford spelled out the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> problem back in 1921-22 when he
published the "International <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>". He was not the first and by no
means the last. But that was 60 some years ago - spanning three
generations - and writers about the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> problem have repeatedly
been doing just that - endlessly rehashing the problem, but never
spelling out a meaningful solution. I ask all these intellectuals (and
I am not now referring to Mr. Wm. G. Simpson), how long do you
want to keep rehashing the problem without a solution to the pro-blem? How long do you want to pontificate without doing
something meaningful to solve the problem? Three genera-tions? Five? Until the problem has liquidated itself with the <ent type='ORG'>extinc</ent>-tion of Nature's Finest?</p>

<p>There is an overwhelming answer to the problem and <ent type='ORG'>the Church</ent>
Of The Creator has it. We have spelled out the solution loud and
clear. One of the biggest roadblocks to the intellectuals is
helping to put into action a meaningful solution that already
exists is the hubris of these intellectual experts in
themselves. They are extremely obtuse and intransigent in
accepting what is obvious: Implementing a <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> racial
religion. Yes, hubris. They didn't think of it first, therefore, ignore</p>



<p>it, torpedo it, even if it means the death of the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Race itself.</p>

<p>History speaks loud and clear, especially the history of the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>,
and the message is this: The <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Race needs, the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Race
must have a racial religion of its own, and the most massive
roadblock standing in the way is <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Christianity</ent>. It is
there. It was placed there to obstruct, confuse, and fragment the mind
of the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Race so that it could never realize its own great poten-tial. it is therefore obvious we must dump this <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> mind-scrambler
and replace it with Creativity - a comprehensive, meaningful, racial
religion of our own.</p>

<p>After we have reviewed a number of flimsy and trifling causes
the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Man has been chasing and on which he has been wasting
his time, money and energy, we pose the rhetorical question: What
is <ent type='ORG'>the Church</ent> of the Creator trying to save?</p>

<p>The answer is loud, clear and unequivocal. We are striving
for the survival, expansion and advancement of the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent>
Race.</p>

<p>In so saying, I am only too well aware that enemies of our <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>
and of the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Race are going to drag out their well-rehearsed bag
of tricks to destroy us. Especially I expect them to dump on us the
old <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> and <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> ploy of ACCUSE THE ACCUSER,
and accuse me of a hubris of my own.</p>

<p>To them I say this: you can dredge up all the slanderous names
in your lexicon and do so twenty-four hours a day, seven days a week
- it will not deter our movement one bit. Yes, we're deter-mined to see it through - whatever is takes-Yes, we are pro-ud of our religion, the first real racial religion the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Race
has ever had. And yes, we are mighty proud to be <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent>, and
we have the most valid reasons in the world for all the above
as to why we should.</p>

<p>But personal hubris, if any, on my part is a minor item in the
whole determination. I am not a public person. I have no desire to
be in the limelight, and I don't care about publicity. The fact is, I
am a loner and enjoy my privacy. I would just as soon some
dynamic young promoter half my age took over the leader-ship, the publicity, the glory, if any, and the awesome burden. I
have said so publicly and repeatedly. (See the "Search for the
Great Promoter" in Issue No. 10 of <ent type='NORP'>Expan</ent>ding Creativity on P. 165)
And as soon as we find him that is what will be done. (Fortunately
we are already in contact with some encouraging prospects).</p>

<p>Be that as it may, slander or no slander, I am determined that
the Creativity movement will go on and expand until it em-braces all of the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> world. We are going to see to it that it
does, whatever it takes, whatever the costs. I am doing it not because
of any hubris on my part, but because the ramifications of the suc-</p>



<p>cess or failure of the movement are awesome, and the job has to
be done.</p>

<p>Never in history has a more real, more meaningful, more im-portant, more portentous cause been set forth than that to which
we, <ent type='ORG'>the Church</ent> of the Creator have committed our <ent type='ORG'>liv</ent>es, our liber-ty, our honor and our fortunes. In so doing, I must remind every <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent>
Racial Comrade, not only our own <ent type='ORG'>liv</ent>es and fortunes are at stake,
but those of our children, our grandchildren and hundreds, yes,
thousands of future generations of the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Race yet unborn.</p>

<p>The stakes are high, and we have the answer. Yes, you're damn
right, we have the answer, hubris or no hubris. Never in the history
of the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Race has a full-blown racial (or any other kind
of) religion appeared on the scene that is as complete, as
comprehensive, that has the solutions to practically every
major problem that today confronts an angry, seething
world in utter chaos. We have the complete framework of solu-tions to the racial pro<ent type='ORG'>blems</ent>, the economic pro<ent type='ORG'>blems</ent>, the health pro-<ent type='ORG'>blems</ent>, the farm pro<ent type='ORG'>blems</ent>, the educational pro<ent type='ORG'>blems</ent>, the religious
pro<ent type='ORG'>blems</ent>, the environmental pro<ent type='ORG'>blems</ent> - all of them are inherent
in our creed. We have the TOTAL PROGRAM, the FINAL
SOLUTION, the ULTIMATE CREED. Whatever bits and pieces
need to be supplemented within that framework are minor, but the
program itself encompasses all aspects of life on this planet earth
- our only home now and forever.</p>

<p>If CREATIVITY succeeds - and it will - it will be a
universal blessing not only for the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Race but for that
Whole entity we now call humanity. If we fail, this Planet
Earth will become a <ent type='ORG'>liv</ent>ing hell for all "humanity", if we can
then still call it that.</p>

<p>So we ask all good <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Racial Comrades to join with us. After
three generations of fiddling, it is time we quit rehashing the pro-blem and get to work implementing the solution. We say to
the intellectuals, to the pseudo-experts, quit spinning your wheels
and wet nursing your little hubris. You can stop searching. Save the
<ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Race. The answer is staring you in the face. There is a hell
of a lot more than your individual little hubris at stake. Our own great
race - Nature's Finest - is now on the chopping block and we need
action, not endless pontification.</p>

<p>So join with us. Build your own <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> Of The Creator
Organization in your area, but let's get our act together.
Remember - the bottom line as to whether or not we save
our own race is this: How much do you really care? Only you
can answer that question.</p>

<div>* * * * *</div>



<div>* * * * *</div>

<p>Unfortunately, at this time the average <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent>
Man's mind is too cluttered with superficial trash
to be able to grasp the full ramifications and
magnitude of the idea we Creators are expounding. But we will get to them all, sooner or later.</p>

<div>* * * * *</div>

<p>ZEALOUSNESS in the promotion of the
<ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Race is no vice; <ent type='ORG'>APATHY</ent> in its defense is
no virtue.</p>

<div>* * * * *</div>

<p> A logical mind is in close touch with reality
Insanity is characterized by <ent type='ORG'>liv</ent>ing in a world of
fantasy.</p>

<div>* * * * *</div>

<p>There ore no two issues so wide apart a politi-cian can't straddle them.</p>

<div>* * * * *</div>



<p>CREATIVITY UNIQUE</p>

<p>Not a rehash of the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> Philosophy</p>

<p>In Issue No. 4 of EXPANDING CREATIVITY (P. 56) we clearly
delineate eight fundamental issues on which we Creators differ with
Hitler's <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> philosophy. In this dissertation we conclude our analysis
of the eventful episode in history created by that great genius, Adolf
<ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent>. He now belongs to the ages and history will never
again see another man like him. He was unique and the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>
era be created in <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> was unique. And it, too, now belongs
to history.</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Adolf Hitler</ent> made a tremendous breakthrough for the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent>
Race, but unfortunately be did not break the back of the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent>
monster. On the contrary, the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> emerged victorious from the
ashes of a defeated <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent>. When <ent type='EVENT'>WWII</ent> ended, the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> were
ten times more powerful than before that holocaust began.
Now, forty years later they have further consolidated that power and
tightened their death grip on the world, and on the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Race. It
remains up to us the present generation, to break that stranglehold
Nobody else will do it for us.</p>

<p>We CREATORS have learned much from the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> experience
and the mistakes made in dealing with the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> monster. We have
come up with a completely different approach and use the same
weapons the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> have used so successfully for over 3500 years,
namely the power of religion.</p>

<p>In Issue No. 4 of <ent type='NORP'>Expan</ent>ding Creativity (P. 56), I list eight Fun-damental Differences between Creativity and the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> movement.
believe it would be useful to recapitulate those differences here. They
are as follows:</p>

<p> 1. Whereas the concern of <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> and the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> movement was
to save <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> from the enemies that surrounded her, the over-whelming goal of <ent type='ORG'>the Church</ent> Of The Creator is the survival,
expansion and advancement of the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Race.</p>

<p> 2. <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> himself stated that the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> movement was a political
movement exclusively for the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>s and not for export.
CREATIVITY is, in contrast, a RELIGIOUS movement design-ed for global proportions to embrace all the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> peoples
of <ent type='LOC'>this Planet Earth</ent>.</p>

<p> 3. Whereas <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> never tackled the issue of <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent>i-ty, and, in fact, sometimes even mildly identified with it, we con-front <ent type='NORP'>Christianity</ent> head-on, expose its treacherous and
deceitful nature, and its <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> origin.</p>

<p> 4. <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> left us a burdensome legacy that still lingers on the
minds of many of his admirers, and that is that the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> Problem</p>



<p>must be solved as a political problem. We Creators say: not so,
it is a religious problem that can only be solved by replac-ing <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Christianity</ent> with a powerful racial religion for
the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Race. In CREATIVITY we have it.</p>

<p> 5. Whereas the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> movement took a harsh and hostile stance
toward many of its <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> neighbors - The <ent type='NORP'>French</ent>, the <ent type='NORP'>Poles</ent>, the
<ent type='NORP'>Czechs</ent>, etc., Creativity, on the other hand, seeks to embrace and
unite all the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> peoples of the world.</p>

<p> 6. Whereas <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> formed a military alliance with one of the more
powerful mud races, namely the <ent type='NORP'>Japanese</ent>, to help kill <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> peoples,
to us CREATORS this is sheer treason and must never hap-pen again.</p>

<p> 7. Whereas the "mythos" of the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> movement was the smart,
goose-stepping <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> Storm Trooper, the capable <ent type='NORP'>Prussian</ent> Generals
of the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> General Staff, and the era of Frederick the Great,
we Creators instead point with pride to the Winning Of The West
and prefer the <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n "Manifest Destiny" as our "mythos"
for the Winning of the World.</p>

<p> 8. We shun the "personality cult" approach to the overwhelm-ing problem that confronts us and rely instead on logic and com-mon sense; on the experience of history; and on the Eter-nal Laws of Nature as the broad and solid base upon which to
build our powerful religious movement.</p>

<p> Read again FUNDAMENTAL DIFFERENCES in <ent type='NORP'>Expan</ent>ding
Creativity, Issue 4 (P. 56).</p>

<div>* * * * *</div>

<p>We Creators consider <ent type='PERSON'>Adolf Hitler</ent> the
greatest leader the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Race has ever had and
the greatest <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Man that ever <ent type='ORG'>liv</ent>ed.</p>

<div>* * * * *</div>

<p>National Socialism was the first mighty
breakthrough, for the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Race, but it was not
the total answer. CREATIVITY IS.</p>

<div>* * * * *</div>

<p>The time to get our act together is NOW or
NEVER</p>

<div>* * * * *</div>

</xml>