<xml><p>Issue No. 18, November 1984</p>

<p> Selection of Racial
Terms Deliberate</p>

<p> WE HAVE GOOD REASONS</p>

<p> In the field of propaganda, programming, education and
enlightenment, certain key rules come into play. The battle in which
<ent type='EVENT'>the White Race</ent> is now involved and in fact, is fighting for its very
survival, is basically a battle for the mind. Overwhelmingly, it is a
battle for the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> mind, a mind that is now sorely polluted not on-ly with chemical drugs but psychological mind benders as well.
We are sorely besieged not only with drugs but even more so
by a poisonous onslaught of ideas.
We are at the mercy of a deadly siege of psychological warfare,
yet, <ent type='EVENT'>the White Race</ent> is hardly aware of it. Call it propaganda, mind
warping, mind scrambling, programming or whatever you like, the
<ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Race is mostly on the receiving end, practically defenseless
and not returning so much as a volley.
It is the psychological warfare I want to zero in on in this treatise,
and the fact that the main issue of this warfare is racial. In short,
we are at the losing end of a psychological war that is being waged
against us, <ent type='EVENT'>the White Race</ent>, by our deadly enemies, the mud races
in general and by the cunning <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>. In this field, these master sneaks
of all time are the unchallenged experts and have been such from
time immemorial. No other race has even come close. They have
been overwhelmingly successful and although inferior in numbers and
creativity, they now control the human and material resources of the
world.
As in every other endeavor there are a number of key ground
rules that must be followed that spell success, and certain boo-boos
that are just plain dumb that must be avoided. This applies to ten-<ent type='ORG'>nis</ent>, to business, to education, to politics, or to our subject at hand
- propaganda and enlightenment. You have to follow certain ground
rules to be effective; you have to avoid known pitfalls or else fail.
All this brings us back to our main subject at hand: effective
psychological tactics in the racial warfare being aggressively pushed
upon us by the <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>s and the mud races - a war we are losing
I am now going to list some of these basic ground rules that apply
to this particular warfare, though some of these apply equally to any</p>

<p> 77
type of warfare.
1. Clearly identify your enemy. You can't fight an abstraction
or a ghost (such as a devil).
2. War against enemies can only be successfully waged if it is
first preceded by a successful propaganda campaign of hatred for
the enemy, implicating them of all the sins and transgressions that
can be brought against them. The <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>s spent thirty years aggressive-ly conditioning the <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> people to hate and loathe the <ent type='NORP'>Germans</ent>
before they were ready to fight world war I. After <ent type='EVENT'>World War</ent> I was
over they feverishly continued that program of hate and vilification
changing their theme only slightly, from the <ent type='PERSON'>Kaiser</ent> to <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> as be-ing the villain of the peace. (This is only one example of hundreds
pursued by the <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>s.)
3. All is "fair" in warfare. Only survival matters. This is stated
in a different manner by General <ent type='PERSON'>Douglas</ent> MacArthur who said:
"There is no substitute for victory". But we Creators have even
stronger justification for our position, and we go back to fundamen-tals: THE <ent type='ORG'>ETERNAL</ent> LAWS OF NATURE. And Nature says loud and
clear: Take care of your own, no holds barred. The bottom line is
survival of your own species and Nature ruthlessly pu<ent type='ORG'>nis</ent>hes those
too stupid or too laggard to obey that law with the ultimate pu<ent type='ORG'>nis</ent>h-ment: extinction. (For further details on this subject see Creative
Credo No. 61, "The Guilt Complex and the fairness <ent type='ORG'>Neurosis</ent> -
Two Fatal Foibles in the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Man's Makeup" in The <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Man's
Bible.)
4. Organize and polarize your own forces to prepare them for
the oncoming (or on going) battle. in order to do so you have to have
an entity, a treasure that you love and cherish that you want and
must protect from a vicious and loathsome enemy. This enemy, too,
must be identified and we of <ent type='ORG'>the Church</ent> Of The Creator clearly do
so. To us the most precious treasure on the face of the earth is the
<ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Race, and <ent type='EVENT'>the White Race</ent> alone. To it we give our total
allegiance, our total loyalty, our total love. We state further that pro-tecting our <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> gene pool is our highest obligation, and failure to
do so is the ultimate crime. This means protecting it not only from
threat of extinction, but also, and perhaps even more so, from pollu-tion and contamination. Under no circumstances can we any longer
tolerate the <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>s sitting arrogantly at the master switch and pump-ing the black blood of <ent type='LOC'>Africa</ent> into the veins of <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>, or any
other <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> peoples, for that matter.
That the above is now becoming a flagrant reality and that the
<ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> racial gene pool is being polluted and contaminated, of that
there is no doubt. That <ent type='EVENT'>the White Race</ent> is idly sitting by and indif-ferent about this calamity unfolding before its very eyes, is the un-mitigated horror of our times.</p>



<p> <ent type='ORG'>The Church</ent> Of The Creator is in the forefront of battling this
treacherous catastrophe, is committed to exposing it and reversing
the tide.
in listing the above four points of warfare we have, of course.
only listed a few basics but these basics apply directly to the racial
and psychological warfare with which we are now counter attacking
and intend to wage in the future.
We see the main problem in this fight is not so much the strength
of the enemy - The <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>s, niggers and mud races - but the needless
and self-imposed weakness of our own <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Racial Comrades in
the willingness (or unwillingness) in defending themselves.
So badly has the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Man's brain become polluted and
scrambled by the enemy's propaganda, that it seems he can't, or
he won't think straight. This is our main problem and it is the target
of our campaign.
We are therefore giving the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Man a creed, a program,
religion he can polarize around. It is a highly aggressive racial
religion based on honor, on pride, and confidence in our own race.
It is a creed that advocates hostility, derision and contempt towards,
and for, our energies. And we do this for good psychological reasons.
When we call niggers what they are, we do so not because we are
uncouth and uneducated, but exactly for the opposite reasons. We
are neither uncouth nor are we uneducated. On the contrary, we take
this approach because on the racial issue especially we are far, far
better educated than the average yokel, who doesn't know the dif-ference between Nature's Finest, and a nigger or an orangutan. We
want to hammer home to <ent type='EVENT'>the White Race</ent> a few facts that all Nature
is fairly screaming at us - and they are these:
1. All men are not equal. On the contrary, there is no equality
in Nature.
2. We, <ent type='EVENT'>the White Race</ent> are at the very top of the Racial spec-trum and the niggers at the very bottom. A huge chasm separates
us - a chasm wider than that separating the niggers from the apes
3. The <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Race is unwittingly involved in a racial war of ex-tinction, a war that the enemy is waging savagely and relentlessly,
yet <ent type='EVENT'>the White Race</ent> is almost totally unaware of it.
4. in order to save <ent type='EVENT'>the White Race</ent> from uncontested extinction
we must rally and polarize <ent type='EVENT'>the White Race</ent>, we must clearly delineate
the issues, and clearly identify the enemy. This we have done, over
and over.
5. We also want to emphasize that it is not enough to just iden-tify the enemy, but we must also attack, heap accusations and
charges against the enemy (all of which are true) and condemn, vilify
and heap contempt and derision upon our enemy, just as they are
doing to us.
79</p>

<p> We must arouse the emotions on our side and bring forth all the
racial instincts with which Nature has endowed us if we are to sur-vive. And we mean for <ent type='EVENT'>the White Race</ent> to survive, at all costs. No
price is too high, no road too long.
6. We realize this war involves all aspect, all resources - racial,
psychological, economic, physical, mental and above all, a war of
semantics, It is the psychological and semantic war that we are par-ticularly focusing on in this examination, and in this respect cliches,
slogans and catch-words are of particular importance, as the <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>s
have amply demonstrated over the centuries.
Just as in <ent type='PERSON'>George Orwell</ent>'s 1984 the Establishment was <ent type='PERSON'>surrep</ent>-titiously phasing out certain words, memories and events "down the
memory hole", so, too, the <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish powerhouse is now turning our
language and our thinking around and phasing out all that which
would preserve the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Man's heritage and identity. To illustrate
how well he has succeeded in the short period of less than one genera-tion let us look at <ent type='ORG'>the Big Webster</ent>'s Dictionary.
I have three books around. One Webster's Third New interna-tional Dictionary (Unabridged) 1961. The other two are New
Webster's Dictionary of the English language 1981.
In the last two (1981) the word "nigger" does not even appear.
In the 1961 Edition there are seventeen different entries of which the
word nigger is either the basic word or the stem of a word or a phrase.
They are as follows: nigger, nigger baby(either of two herbs: a sani-cle (<ent type='PERSON'>Sanicula bipinnatifida</ent>) with purple flowers: a blue-eyed grass
(<ent type='PERSON'>Sisyrinchium</ent> bellum) with purplish blue flowers.), nigger bug (<ent type='ORG'>Negro</ent>
bug.), niggerchaser (a small firework that shoots about on the
ground.), nigger daisy (a black-eyed <ent type='PERSON'>Susan</ent>.), niggerfish, niggerhead
cactus, nigger heaven (the highest balcony or row of seats in a
theatre.), niggergoose, nigger in the woodpile something (as a con-cealed or obscure factor) contrary to appearances in a situation.),
nigger pine, nigger shooter (slingshot.), niggertoe (<ent type='GPE'>brazil</ent> nut.),nig-genweed, <ent type='ORG'>niggerwool</ent>.
This demonstrates how in a short period of 20 years they have
phased out "down the memory hole" of our language a major racial
distinction that is vital to the survival of <ent type='EVENT'>the White Race</ent>.
Just think of it! if our <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> ancestors had not had racial pride,
recognized racial identity and practiced racial loyalty and racial
segregation you and I would now be a miserable mulatto as the <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>
is viciously determined our future progeny shall be.
For the above reasons it behooves us to use such terms of deri-sion as niggers and mud races to distinguish them from Nature's
Finest. Just to bring these words back into common usage by our
<ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Racial Comrades is already a big step forward in fortifying
our own ranks, polarizing <ent type='EVENT'>the White Race</ent> and identifying the enemy.</p>



<p>We recommend that this consistently be done among our own
members and all <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Racial Comrades in general.
in this respect we find that although at this time our own
membership is still relatively small (but growing) we are having
widespread ripple effects, and much of our verbiage, such as the
usage of the words "niggers", "mud races" are beginning to creep
into general usage in papers, magazines and literature of other <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent>
Racial groups. So are such phrases as "spooks-in-the-sky", the "cut,
burn and poison" reference in cancer treatments, and several other
distinctive words and phrases brought into play by <ent type='ORG'>the Church</ent> Of
The Creator.
So take heart. What we are doing is not happenstance. It is
planned, it is deliberate, and it is effective. Not only are we growing
but we are influencing and setting the pace of the whole <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> racial
movement. Remember, Rome was not built in a day, and neither
was the <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish-<ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> movement. Remember, we are planning
for eternity, not just the day after tomorrow, and the foundations you
are helping to lay are both short term and long term.
So get with it. Join our racial religious movement and get in-volved. <ent type='ORG'>Distribute</ent> 100 copies of this periodical each month.
Remember the future - your own and that of your progeny depends
on the success of what we are now doing - the success of the
Creativity movement. To say that this success will mean so much
to so many is a gross understatement. <ent type='ORG'>Hel</ent>p build a <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent>r and
<ent type='ORG'>Brighter World</ent> - a world in which the mud races can no longer be
a threat, any more than the <ent type='NORP'>Indians</ent> of today are in the state of
<ent type='GPE'>Oregon</ent>.</p>

<div> * * * * *</div>

<p> It is our unswerving goal to place 10 million
<ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Man's Bibles in the hands of our <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent>
Racial Comrades. Once we have accomplished
that much the war against the <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>s, niggers and
mud peoples will be as good as over, and it will
be the best bargain <ent type='EVENT'>the White Race</ent> will ever have
invested in. <ent type='ORG'>Hel</ent>p bring it about! Do your part.</p>

<div> * * * * *</div>



<p>Odi<ent type='ORG'>nis</ent>m: A Rising Phoenix</p>

<p> or a Dead Horse?
Foreword: For the last decade or so Mr. <ent type='PERSON'>Dietz</ent> has published the
<ent type='ORG'>Liberty Bell</ent> Magazine, which is pro-<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>, pro-<ent type='PERSON'>White</ent>, Anti-<ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent>
and anti-<ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish. In the last several years Mr. <ent type='PERSON'>Dietz</ent>, the Editor, has
also published any number of articles taken directly out of the
chapters of Nature's Eternal Religion and The <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Man's Bible,
with our permission and approval. A few issues ago Mr. Ronald S.
Hand published a letter which ended with the fervent hope there be
fewer identity <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent>s and more Odi<ent type='ORG'>nis</ent>ts. If so, we would stand
a better chance of wresting our destiny from the hands of the <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>s.
He concluded his letter with the offer that he would be glad to answer
any questions.
Rev. Carles C. <ent type='PERSON'>Messick III</ent>, Hasta Primus of <ent type='ORG'>The Church</ent> Of The
Creator took note of this letter and wondered why. Mr. Hand was
really so interested in overcoming the <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>s, he completely ignored
CREATIVITY which is soley dedicated to breaking the <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish
stranglehold and wresting the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Man's destiny back in his own
hands. The following <ent type='ORG'>cor</ent>respondence ensued, the, first two letters
of which Mr. <ent type='PERSON'>Dietz</ent> published in <ent type='ORG'>Liberty Bell</ent>, but the third one he
refused. It is because Mr. <ent type='PERSON'>Dietz</ent> refused to print that third letter that
we are now publishing all three letters in this forum.
Rev. <ent type='PERSON'>Messick</ent> had been a long time subscriber to the <ent type='ORG'>Liberty Bell</ent>
before he discovered <ent type='ORG'>the Church</ent> Of The Creator. He then joined the
Creativity movement because he was convinced that Creativity had
the answer, the TOTAL ANSWER.
First of all, here is Rev. <ent type='PERSON'>Messick</ent> as letter was published in the Liber-ty <ent type='ORG'>Bell</ent>:</p>

<div> * * * * *</div>

<p> This letter is in response to that of Ronald S. Hand, Odi<ent type='ORG'>nis</ent>t,
which appeared in the May issue of "<ent type='ORG'>Liberty Bell</ent>," Whereas I have
little criticism of what Mr. Hand says, it is what he doesn't say that
is somewhat disturbing. In the last paragraph he comes to the con-cluslon that "if we had in <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> 'Odi<ent type='ORG'>nis</ent>ts' instead of Identity Chri-tians we would stand a much better chance of wresting our destiny
from the hands of the <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>s."
With this, too, I do not disagree, but he seems to completely
ignore a racial religious movement, CREATIVITY, that is well known
to the readers of "<ent type='ORG'>Liberty Bell</ent>," a religious movement that is solely
dedicated to the survival, expansion, and advancement of the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent></p>



<p>Race. It is a religion of this era, not a moldy relic from the past. It
is already doing just what Mr. Hand claims he desires to see happen
- wrest the destiny of <ent type='EVENT'>the White Race</ent> from the hands of the <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>s
and into the capable hands of <ent type='EVENT'>the White Race</ent> itself.
Mr. Hand adds that he will answer questions. Here are a few
vital questions to which I would like to have a few reasonable
answers.
1. After all the articles Mr. <ent type='PERSON'>Dietz</ent> has published In "<ent type='ORG'>Liberty Bell</ent>"
that came directly out of the pages of "Nature's Eternal Religion"
and "The <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Man's Bible," the basic books of the Creativity move-ment, surely Mr. Hand must have heard of it?
2. Since Odi<ent type='ORG'>nis</ent>m failed to hold it's own against the treachery
and the cunning of the wily <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent> a thousand years ago when the <ent type='PERSON'>Vik</ent>-ings were the fiercest and the most feared warriors in Europe, what
makes Mr. Hand think that today Odi<ent type='ORG'>nis</ent>m, when it has been a dead
horse for a millennium, can now turn the tables?
3. Isn't Odi<ent type='ORG'>nis</ent>m merely trading one set of spooks, namely the
<ent type='ORG'>Norse</ent> gods, for another set of spooks, namely the <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish passel,
and can any intelligent and educated man in the 20th century really
believe in either without insulting his own Intelligence?
4. True, the Odi<ent type='ORG'>nis</ent>t gods are at least our own brand of fantasies,
but since they do not have (and never had) any defense or understan-ding of the insidious <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish perfidy, how can you expect them to be
a solution to anything?
5. Why does Mr. Hand deliberately choose to ignore CREATIVI-TY when it has a comprehensive racial creed, program, and religion,
that is geared to the eternal realities of Nature, to the 20th century,
to exposing the <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish fraud that is <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent>ity, and to blasting the
<ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish menace from the face of the earth? Just how serious is Mr.
Hand or any other <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Racist group in dealing the most effective
blow against the <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>s and mud races?
It would seem to me that we would do much better to forget our
own small fragmented individual hubris and combine forces to build
a mighty <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Racial Movement under the only aegis that has a
chance of success, namely the CREATIVITY movement. It is the only
<ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> racial religion in the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Man's history that was designed
to exactly do the job that now overwhelmingly needs to be done if
<ent type='EVENT'>the White Race</ent> is to survive.
I am not attempting to insult or demean any <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Racist, but
only to point out the obvious lessons of the past. We need something
that has a better than average chance to succeed. If something fail-ed us in the past there is a good chance that it will do so again.
We do not need to play games with such weak and meaningless
props as the existence or nonexistence of Atlantis, nor <ent type='ORG'>Norse</ent> gods,
nor <ent type='PERSON'>Mother Goose</ent> tales in order to forge a powerful racial religion.</p>



<p>Nature Is very real and says it all, but some of us are not paying at-tention. "Creativity" is based on and embodies the Eternal Laws of
Nature for the survival, expansion and advancement of our own kind
- Nature's Finest - The <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Race. All we have to do is stop play-ing games of fantasy and get back to using the good sense with which
Nature endowed us.
I fooled around with several <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Racialist groups - Posse
Comitatus, Euro-<ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n Alliance, <ent type='NORP'>Aryan</ent> Nations, etc. - most
were hung up on Christ being our only hope and were really <ent type='GPE'>ineffec</ent>-tual. They have been around for years and practically accomplished
nothing except to get themselves killed or jailed without dealing an
effective blow at any <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>. Once I realized the absurdities of spooky
religions "CREATIVITY" became the only logical answer. I am,
myself, as <ent type='ORG'>the Hasta Primus</ent> for <ent type='ORG'>the Church</ent> of the Creator, ac-complishing more now than ever I could hope to do in a hundred
years of practicing spookcraft with whatever religion. I am serious
as hell about ridding the world of the <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish menace.
I don't play games anymore.</p>

<p> Rev. Carles C. <ent type='PERSON'>Messick III</ent>
Hasta Primus for the
Church of the Creator</p>

<div> * * * * *</div>

<p> Before publishing Rev. Messick's letter, Mr. <ent type='PERSON'>Dietz</ent>, however, first
sent a copy of that letter to Mr. Hand so that he could prepare a
rebuttal to it, which he did. Mr. <ent type='PERSON'>Dietz</ent> then published both letters
consecutively in the same issue. Here is Mr. Hand's letter:</p>

<p>Dear Rev. <ent type='PERSON'>Messick</ent>:
Thank you for your letter of 7 June, 1984.
I am glad that you have opened to me a door to opportunity to
answer some vital questions concerning "<ent type='ORG'>The Church</ent> of the Creator."
Yes, I am aware of "Creativity," and have read most of "The <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent>
Man's Bible," and "Nature's Eternal Religion " I find in both a cer-tain evangelical concern for enlightening <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> people about the sub-tle insinuations of <ent type='NORP'>Judaeo</ent>-Christanity, and a style of logic which is
convincing and intellectually spicy. However, I did not find in
"Creativity a religion which offered any real compelling reasons why
I should become a part of it. My reasons are as follows:
"Creativity" is after all, a modern innovation which attempts
to meet certain needs of the <ent type='NORP'>Aryan</ent> community in its juxtaposed an-tago<ent type='ORG'>nis</ent>m to <ent type='ORG'>Judaism</ent> and Commu<ent type='ORG'>nis</ent>m. With this I feel comfortable.
But, at several points I am made to sense a kind of lostness in it.
Let me call it an alienation. I refer to the chapters on "Salubrious</p>



<p>Living," for not too long after I was reading about dietary regulations
I came to the conclusion that I would have to part company with
my charcoal grill and barbeque pit. I am, after all, not a vegetarian
as was Adolf <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent>. Furthermore, I don't think that an <ent type='NORP'>Aryan</ent> counter-part to Leviticus chapter 11 is of central importance to the survival,
expansion and advancement of <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> people. Yet the gist of
"<ent type='PERSON'>Salubrious Living</ent>" was tilted heavily in favor of vegetaria<ent type='ORG'>nis</ent>m and
Hinduism. "Where's the Beef" If <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> people came to embrace this
practice generally, then I suspect that <ent type='PERSON'>Steven Spielberg</ent> will send in-diana Jones to rescue the <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>s from the newly passed <ent type='GPE'>Nuremberg</ent>
Laws which forbid <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>s to eat mutton or gefillte fish. I'm being
facetious of course.
Nevertheless, there is another one or two objections. How often
I have thought about "Creativity," "what God is revered, or worship-ped?" And all I could find out was that "<ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> people", who are the
"building race," are the creators. Do <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> people then worship
themselves collectively? I hate to say this, but there are some <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent>
people that I regard as <ent type='ORG'>Untermenschen</ent>, race traitors, scum and
worse. So, a <ent type='ORG'>Carte Blanche</ent> approval of <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> people is both naive
and false insofar as the interests is concerned. One reason for <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish
triumph is not <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish genius, but Gentile stupidity and lack of
backbone. And if this statement is true, then the single greatest task
we have before us is not a negative program of indicting <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>s, but
of examining ourselves to discover foibles, weaknesses, excesses, in-dulgences, grossness, callousness,insensitiveness (to certain things)
casualness, foolishness, etc., which have become the bane of our
survival. So, why or how can we even talk of expansion and advance-ment of <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> people when their very survival is In question? You
see, there have been too many <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> suckers in the last two thou-sand years who took the <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish bait, to land all the blame on the
<ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>s. We need to start looking at ourselves, too. Why and how did
we let It happen? So you see, I doubt the present "capability" of the
<ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Race to govern and rule the world in its present dilemma. The
<ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Race needs to be purged, disciplined, and nurtured back to
health before any of our leaders will be able to grasp the helm of
our destiny with confidence and certainty.
And now in my own defense.
Neo-Odinlsm is not a naive acceptance of ancient Nordic Gods.
It is rather a personal quest, a search for Life's meaning, as can be
sifted out of our own religious past as It is understood through a
demythologized and psychologically researched examination of that
religion. My Paga<ent type='ORG'>nis</ent>m is new, but it is based upon the few extant
runes which have become to me a bible for my race. Modern
historionomy, philology, etymology, literary criticism, and study of
comparative religions can make possible some very enlightening</p>



<p>discoveries of the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> psyche, when applied to our knowledge of
our racial and natural Gods. For our Gods are not unlike ourselves.
As <ent type='PERSON'>Jehovah</ent> is nought but a big <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent> in the sky, so <ent type='PERSON'>Thor</ent>, Odin, Tyr,
and <ent type='PERSON'>Freya</ent> are nought but big <ent type='NORP'>Aryan</ent>s in the sky. By studying them,
we are studying ourselves. Thus, self-knowledge becomes a way to
health and a remedy to our bibles.
Odi<ent type='ORG'>nis</ent>m, unlike "Creativity," can say "we do believe in God."
But what God? Fimbulvetr is here, the <ent type='GPE'>Gotterdaemmerung</ent> is now.
And the <ent type='ORG'>Norse</ent> eddas, sagas, and epics have told us that the old Gods
who ruled so long would die. But in the process, the wolf <ent type='PERSON'>Fenrir</ent> will
also die, and the great <ent type='ORG'>Serpent</ent> (<ent type='ORG'>Judaism</ent>) shall be slain. <ent type='PERSON'>Baldur</ent> will
be released from <ent type='ORG'>Hel</ent>, and <ent type='PERSON'>Heimdall</ent> shall prepare a new age with
new Gods. Ragnarok is now passing, and new things are in the mak-ing. Are we to be many <ent type='PERSON'>Baldur</ent>s and <ent type='PERSON'>Heimdall</ent>s, who will squeeze
through the fjords and crevasses of time to reach the other side of
the great catastrophe? We shall see!
In the meantime, "Creativity" will have accomplished its task
of confronting <ent type='NORP'>Judaeo</ent>-<ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent>ity with its own absurdities. "Creativi-ty," to be sure, is not detrimental to <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> racism. But, neither is
Odi<ent type='ORG'>nis</ent>m. Both have specialized tasks to perform and both work on
different kinds of problems. The strength of Creativity is its poignant
factualism, its matter-of-factness, its loquacious logic, and its sty-mying criticism. Its weakness is its coldness and emotional dryness.
It doesn't go to our own soul, to answer our heart's cry. It remains
heady and cerebral. It provides much light, but doesn't warm our
hearts. On the contrary, the strength of Odi<ent type='ORG'>nis</ent>m Is that it is ours.
It came from our gene pool before miscegenation set in. It remains
a re<ent type='ORG'>cor</ent>d of poetic wisdom, humor, and truth, containing both tragedy
and comedy, loyalty and treachery, heroism and cowardice. We can
read epic stories of our ancestors instead of <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish ones, i.e., the
Bible. Also, we can read about our past, the now-alien, pre-<ent type='NORP'>Chistain</ent>
culture, or when <ent type='NORP'>Semitic</ent> religion was still kept at the periphery of
Nordic borders..
On the other hand, Odi<ent type='ORG'>nis</ent>m has weaknesses, as you pointed
out. But these are not insurmountable. The fact that several thou-sand neo-Odi<ent type='ORG'>nis</ent>ts can be counted shows that it is no "dead horse,"
but a rising phoenix. Perhaps what is needed in both Creativity and
Odi<ent type='ORG'>nis</ent>m is a thoroughgoing eclectic theology which can better
ground our ideas in an eternal constancy, and consistency.
In any case, Odi<ent type='ORG'>nis</ent>m has this edge over non-religion: It allows
for afterlife, continuous life, or reincarnation, or combination of the
two. Odin was, among other things, God of the dead, especially war-riors. Thus Odi<ent type='ORG'>nis</ent>m becomes an affirmation of the continuity and
stability of existence, however you wish to explain it. Odi<ent type='ORG'>nis</ent>m allows
us to speak of God in very general terms also; in fact, <ent type='ORG'>the High</ent> God</p>



<p>is still unknown. The High God is spoken of as though the Aesir Gods
are much inferior to it. The High God is the cosmic force, the stuff
which glues the universe together; the medium of all sympathetic
and intellectual communication, the buffer between the antago<ent type='ORG'>nis</ent>tic
forces and rivalries. The High God cannot be named, for to do so
would denigrate him to lower status by means of limitation and
mislabeling. The High God remains aloof because of his presences
everywhere, and he also remains aloof because of his immediate
presence in the lowest of matter. His highest or greatest manifesta-tion is when he is active in the process of evolution, i.e., the act of
surpassing himself. The greatest experience we can have of <ent type='ORG'>the High</ent>
God is when we participate in the evolutionary process by intent
(eugenics, cultivation, organization) and communicate in circles of
concentrated intelligence by cooperation. Persons who accumulate
both historical and technological knowledge may unconsciously be
serving the purposes of <ent type='ORG'>the High</ent> mind, and may be affecting the
historico-evolutionary process. Mental ability, or capacity in itself
is not indicative of any special blessing of <ent type='ORG'>the Super Intelligence</ent> of
<ent type='ORG'>Universe</ent>. This is a more genetic combination. But, when mental
energies are aimed at improving, <ent type='ORG'>cor</ent>recting, adjusting or perfecting
the already good, then we may say that the evolutionary process is
still at work. And, by way of extension, we may suppose the subtle
activity of infinite intelligence joined to good will.
This notion of an almost pantheistic God is hard for many peo-ple to swallow. But, any sympathy man may have for Nature must
be grounded in an earthly, naturalistic type of God. Any man's con-cern for the future of his race and family is bound up with his
for his personal survival after death, and eventual reunion with his
Comrades.
On the other hand, Commu<ent type='ORG'>nis</ent>m and nihilism, which are based
on mere biology and sociology, cannot lead people to long term hopes
and plans. Neither can capitalistic materialism promise anything of
lasting quality. Adherents of the two materialistic cults just mentioned
can have only a "ball-game" attitude toward racial cohesiveness. If
a man's life ends with biological disintegration, then it would be futile,
unnecessary, and wasteful to try to improve. perfect, adjust, of <ent type='ORG'>cor</ent>-rect anything that did not serve an immediate materialistic purpose.
So we need a spook, but not <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish hell fire and brimstone. We
need the "Awe," the "<ent type='ORG'>Mystique</ent>," the "wonderful," and the "elusive,"
if for no other reason than to make us probe further, to discover,
to uncover.
Sincerely.
Ronald S. Hand
Odi<ent type='ORG'>nis</ent>t Church of God</p>

<div> * * * * *</div>



<p> Your Editor then took note of Mr. Hand's letter and decided that
a number of Mr. Hand's statements about both Odi<ent type='ORG'>nis</ent>m and Creativi-ty are grossly native and in<ent type='ORG'>cor</ent>rect. He sent the following letter to
the <ent type='ORG'>Liberty Bell</ent>, but Mr. <ent type='PERSON'>Dietz</ent> refused to print it. Here is the full text
of my letter:</p>

<div>* * * * *</div>

<p>Dear Mr: <ent type='PERSON'>Dietz</ent>:
In the July issue of LIBERTY BELL, Mr. Ronald S. Hand, in
answer to Rev. Carles C. Messick's letter of the same issue, makes
a broadside attack on CREATIVITY, The <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Racial religion of
<ent type='ORG'>the Church</ent> Of The Creator. Since I am the founder of this church,
I believe I have a vested interest in answering these charges. In so
doing I almost feel like a mosquito in a nudist colony, I hardly know
where to begin. Since Mr. Hand makes so many ridiculous
statements, he leaves himself wide open, and all I can say is - he
asked for it.
In his attack, Mr. Hand uses (among others) two sleazy tactics
at which <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>s and <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent>s are especially adept: (a) he
misrepresents our position and then attacks that false position (b)
he attempts to discredit us through guilt by association and links
us with reprehensible entities such as the <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>s and the <ent type='NORP'>Hindus</ent>, when
we have absolutely nothing In common with them.
So let us start with our position regarding <ent type='PERSON'>Salubrious Living</ent>
which is spelled out in considerable detail in our classic text of the
same name and embodied in its 244 pages. I am sure that Mr. Hand
has never read It, since he seems completely ignorant of its contents
In the first place we are not vegetarians as Mr. Hand seems to think,
but <ent type='ORG'>frugitarians</ent>, a considerable difference. If Mr. Hand does not
understand that difference he is invited to educate himself at leisure
by reading the book. I don't have the space to do so here. He will
probably also find out that meat is suitable food for dogs and other
carnivores, but highly unsuitable for humans. He might even find
out that charcoal broiled meat is carcinogenous (cancer causing) and
after he gets his facts straight, might even want to dispose of his
much prized charcoal broiler that he hates so to give up.
The facts are that the wealth of advice given in <ent type='GPE'>Salubrious Liv</ent>-ing for living a healthier, happier and longer life is based on solid
scientific facts, and has nothing to do with the primitive superstitious
hocus-pocus of <ent type='NORP'>Hindus</ent> or the <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish Leviticus with which Mr.Hand
so <ent type='PERSON'>surrep</ent>titiously seeks to associate us.
Furthermore, proper diet is only one of the 14 cardinal points
that we list in "<ent type='PERSON'>Salubrious Living</ent>" (See Page 9) for creating our
desired goal of a SOUND MIND in a SOUND BODY in a SOUND
SOCIETY In a SOUND ENVIRONMENT.</p>



<p> Does Mr. Hand object to such goals? If so, that is mighty
strange, since in his letter he roundly denounces and insults the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent>
Race in scathing terms, such as, quote: "<ent type='ORG'>Untermenschen</ent>, race
traitors, scum and worse " When we Creators have a well-planned,
thoroughgoing program to upgrade the health, eugenics, and en-vironment of our <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Racial Comrades, he stupidly denounces that
too, because, to his own detriment, he is totally Ignorant of what
we are talking about in <ent type='PERSON'>Salubrious Living</ent>.
One final point and that is this: We do not INSIST that anyone
HAS to follow the beneficial guidelines laid down, even to be a
member of the church. We do not twist anyone's arm. We offer a
set of constructive, scientifically proven guidelines for anyone to follow
in order to live a healthier, happier and longer life. Whether they
do so is each individuals own choice, but, again for the benefit of
a better race and a <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent>r and <ent type='ORG'>Brighter World</ent>, we hope that every
<ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Man, woman and child will learn to practice a lifestyle that
is far superior to the drug and Junk food Infested world of today.
So much for <ent type='PERSON'>Salubrious Living</ent>, which although extremely important, is not the main thrust of our religious program, and was
not even mentioned In "Nature's Eternal Religion; our first <ent type='ORG'>cor</ent>ner
stone. Let us get down to the "spooky" business in which Mr. Hand
seems to take such primitive delight. He says in Odi<ent type='ORG'>nis</ent>m "we do
believe in God." He then immediately trips himself up and says, "But
what God?" He is not sure. He then lists such absurdities as <ent type='PERSON'>Thor</ent>,
Odin, Tyr and <ent type='PERSON'>Freya</ent>, all of which are presumably dead, and resting
somewhere In Lower Slobbovia. Then there are the <ent type='PERSON'>Baldur</ent>s and the
<ent type='PERSON'>Heimdall</ent>s sneaking around the fiords (somewhere) and oozing out
of, and squeezing through the crevasses (somewhere). Supposedly,
somehow, somewhere, they will finally come to our rescue. Big deal!
But we Creators are not holding our breath waiting for such nonsense
to materialize. How any rational, grown man can believe In, and spout
such ridiculous nonsense is beyond me.
But, Mr. Hand says, we have to worship something, and why
not spooks, they're good for us, we need them. Well, we Creators
don't need any such idiotic and artificial props. If you need them,
Mr. Hand, you had better see your <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish psychiatrist. He will con-fuse you even more, and make you like it In the process.
Speaking of worship, Mr. Hand asks categorically: What God
do we Creators worship? He then goes on to accuse us of <ent type='GPE'>worshipp</ent>-ing our own <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Race, which he next proceeds to roundly de-nounce abuse and insult as viciously as would any <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent> or nigger.
I therefore want to set Mr. Hand straight on two points. (a) We
Creators do not "Worship" anything, not even <ent type='EVENT'>the White Race</ent>, as
he implies, and (b) To us the whole idea of "worship" is stupid,
ridiculous and demeaning. It implies that the "<ent type='GPE'>worshipp</ent>er" willfully</p>



<p>places himself in an extremely inferior position in relation to some
stupid abstract "Quantity X" that he or she has set up to worship.
This may be something as ridiculous as a cow, a cat, a <ent type='GPE'>spookie</ent>, or
a hot rock. He or she then proceeds to <ent type='PERSON'>Jabber</ent> some meaningless,
yes, Insane praise at said inanimate or imaginary object, in order
to completely humiliate himself or herself. To us the whole idea is
primitive, repugnant and reflects a throwback to our primitive and
barbaric Stone Age ancestors. So when someone asks us - "If you
don't worship God, what do you worship?", it reminds us of the pa-tient in the doctors' clinic, who when told that a cancerous tumor
would have to be cut out, asked, "But doctor, what are you going
to replace it with?" No, Mr. Hand, we don't need spooks or anything
else to worship, nor do we need a pacifier to suck on, either. You
can have the whole messy passel, <ent type='NORP'>gratis</ent> and wholesale.
We now come to the Odi<ent type='ORG'>nis</ent>t admission that, well yeah, we ad-mit all this <ent type='ORG'>Norse</ent> mythology is hocus-pocus, but at least it is <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent>,
not <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish hocus-pocus. Big deal! If we must deal In hokum at all,
why not pick a higher grade of hocus-pocus, when <ent type='EVENT'>the White Race</ent>
has such an excellent selection to choose from? The <ent type='PERSON'>Vik</ent>ings were
neither the first nor the best in that category. If I were to indulge
in playing games with <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> spooks, why, I would choose the <ent type='NORP'>Greek</ent>
or the <ent type='NORP'>Roman</ent> gods ten to one over the <ent type='PERSON'>Vik</ent>ing's. Their stories are
much richer in classic lore, mystique, wealth of characters and any
other critique that may tickle your fancy. Compared to them, the
<ent type='PERSON'>Vik</ent>ings were crude, brutish and bordering on the dense. In fact, on
the intellectual level the <ent type='PERSON'>Vik</ent>ings were on a similar level to <ent type='PERSON'>Hagar</ent> the
Horrible as portrayed in the <ent type='LOC'>Sunday</ent> comics. They were, in fact, il-literate, and most of the <ent type='ORG'>Norse</ent> Myths the Odi<ent type='ORG'>nis</ent>ts bandy about to-day are only through the gratuity of being preserved in <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent>
writings. The <ent type='PERSON'>Vik</ent>ings, in turn, slaughtered the <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent>s wholesale,
but in the end the latter conquered the <ent type='PERSON'>Vik</ent>ings by the insidious ap-plication of their <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish B-bomb (brain bomb). So what we have of
all this Odi<ent type='ORG'>nis</ent>t hocus-pocus today is really only a more or less Chris-tian re<ent type='ORG'>cor</ent>ding or residue, and who needs more primitive hocus-pocus
Mr. Hand claims the Odi<ent type='ORG'>nis</ent>ts are not a "dead horse", nor a relic
from a primitive past, but a "rising phoenix", because, see, we have
several thousand already yet. Well, if he wants to play the numbers
game, I am not impressed. It is no substitute for quality. "Where is
the beef?" indeed, (his quote). There are any number of cults, religions
and insanities that have far larger numbers than "several thousand".
The <ent type='LOC'>Moonies</ent> have millions, Jehovah's Witnesses number in the
millions, the <ent type='NORP'>Moslems</ent> number in the hundreds of millions, and the
<ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent>s claim to embrace 750 million "souls". So what are a paltry
few thousand in comparison? And anyway, with all those billion of
believers in the old spooks in the sky swindle, the bottom line still</p>



<p>is that the world is in one hell of a mess, is rapidly screeching towards
a traumatic cataclysm, is still in the hands of treacherous <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>s, and
Odin, Wodin. Blynken and <ent type='PERSON'>Nod</ent> will do damn little, if anything, to
save us. I would rather be a minority of one who was set on the right
course than be a polyglot part of a multi-million member cult that
had its thinking all screwed up.
We need something much more realistic, tough, well planned,
thoroughgoing and comprehensive than a rehash of a few primitive
and warmed up myths to do the job. In Creativity we have the whole
ball of wax. Just as Adolf <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> found it necessary to <ent type='PERSON'>chuck</ent> over-board all the old political parties In <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> because they were in-adequate to do the job, and devise a completely new philosophy and
political party to cope with a major catastrophe, so too, we Creators
find it necessary to devise a completely new philosophy and religion
for the total <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Race of the Planet Earth. In so doing, instead
of rummaging around in the debris and garbage heap of old dead
religions of the past, we instead go to the greatest teacher of them
all - Mother Nature. Her laws are eternal, they are real, they have
the innate wisdom of the eons embodied In them. There is our source,
and there is our answer.
If Mr. Hand finds that being natural, logical, realistic, organiz-ed and deliberate leaves him "cold" and without purpose, I again
suggest that he see his <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish psychiatrist to confuse him further.
Evidently there are some maladjusted people In this world, in fact,
millions of them, who are so hopelessly confused that they cannot
face reality in a disintegrating world. So they seek an escape
mecha<ent type='ORG'>nis</ent>m of some kind. Some resort to alcohol, some to hard
drugs, some to the spooks in the sky fantasy. But it is no solution,
and reality will have to be faced and problems have to be solved.
To try to escape them with all these trick escape mecha<ent type='ORG'>nis</ent>ms does
not solve them but makes the situation only more disastrous and the
end of the line for such "escape" artists is usually similar to that of
a <ent type='PERSON'>John Belushi</ent>, or a <ent type='PERSON'>David Kennedy</ent>.
We Creators do not seek to hide our heads in the sand, or on
cloud nine in the sky. We are problem solvers and we have answers,
meaningful, comprehensive and realistic answers. Just as Adolf <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent>
sought to unite the <ent type='NORP'>Whole German</ent> nation under one political party,
so we Creators seek to unite the total <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Race and <ent type='EVENT'>the White Race</ent>
alone. Just as <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> succeeded in uniting all the <ent type='NORP'>Germans</ent> under Na-tional Socialism, so we Creators believe (yes we DO have faith!) that
we can and will unite the present 500 million <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> peoples on the
face of the earth into one powerful, solid battering ram that will crush
and demolish the narcotic poison of <ent type='ORG'>Judaism</ent>. We believe it because
it is the only way for <ent type='EVENT'>the White Race</ent> to go, and once <ent type='EVENT'>the White Race</ent>
is united there is no power on the face of the earth that will ever again</p>



<p>be in a position to threaten its existence or survival.
At this point I would like to make a highly encouraging and op-timistic observation. The <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> racial movement in <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> has now
advanced far enough to win over and smash the <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish establish-ment. It could do it now in 1984, if the different factions would unite
and polarize under the banner of <ent type='ORG'>the Church</ent> Of The Creator, the
most comprehensive thoroughgoing, effective weapon it has to work
with. Standing in the way is the hubris (overweening ego) of the
leaders of the individual groups. They take the position that "if I didn't
think of it first, I'm going to torpedo it, and to hell with the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent>
race", and I think Odi<ent type='ORG'>nis</ent>m is a prime example. But think of it! We
could win now! Forget about wet-nursing your private little hubris!
It we lose nobody will remember you anyway. But If we win, what
a glorious <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent>, bright world this would be. Yes, the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Man
knows how to govern the world, Mr. Hand, contrary to what you
claim in your desultory appraisal of <ent type='EVENT'>the White Race</ent>. The <ent type='NORP'>Roman</ent>s
already did so beautifully 2000 years ago, and Pax <ent type='NORP'>Roman</ent>a with its
200 years of peace and prosperity was undoubtedly the finest epoch
in the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Man's history. It lasted until <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent>ity came
along and infected the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Man's mind with a running sore that
has persisted to this day.
But we Creators are not nearly as much interested in that
<ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Race "govern" the world, as that <ent type='EVENT'>the White Race</ent> POSSESS
IT IN TOTAL. In an increasingly contaminated, poisoned, and
polluted world of exploding mud races, we are now at a point of no
return. Either <ent type='EVENT'>the White Race</ent> inhabits it all and exclusively or it will
be crushed, stifled and exterminated. It is now all or nothing, and
we Creators want to make damn sure it is <ent type='EVENT'>the White Race</ent> that sur-vives. Succinctly, it is only <ent type='EVENT'>the White Race</ent> that can reverse the avalan-che, clean up the planet again and build a world worth living in.
But our program does not stop there. Through our program of
<ent type='ORG'>Eugenic</ent> up-breeding we mean to advance the quality of life, health
and happiness to levels never before even dreamed of by the <ent type='NORP'>Greek</ent>s
and <ent type='NORP'>Roman</ent>s, much less the brutish <ent type='PERSON'>Vik</ent>ings.
We further believe there is no real problem accomplishing this
lofty goal as far as the <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>s and the mud races are concerned. The
real obstacle is the confused and cluttered thinking of <ent type='EVENT'>the White Race</ent>
itself, and the most pervasive clutter of all Is the spooks in the sky.
obsession that contaminates the minds of so many of <ent type='EVENT'>the White Race</ent>.
We do not And that our lofty goal of uniting <ent type='EVENT'>the White Race</ent> in
a powerful <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> racial religion as either "cold" or without purpose,
as Mr. Hand seems to. (In fact, he reminds me of the nigger who
said, "Boss, even if it's good, I don't like it.") We find the challenge
exciting, exhilarating and the most intelligent and meaningful ever</p>



<p>proposed in any religion, creed or philosophy. It sure beats the hell
out of chasing non-existent spooks, be they <ent type='NORP'>Roman</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Vik</ent>ing or <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish.
Our members feel the same way. They are excited, filled with
hope, determination and purpose now that they have a meaningful,
constructive goal in life. Let me quote to you just a small part of a
four page letter I received just last week. It begins with...."Dear In-spirational...." and here are a few excerpts: "I have sworn an oath
and have dedicated my entire being, heart and mind and what years
of my life remaining to just those ends...." Referring to our basic
books: "For it IS my Bible, it IS my belief and although you, sir,
are the author, its every utterance reverberates throughout my very
being as if it were I whose pen raced across the paper for fear of los-ing a word." There is more. You can read the full letter in the
September issue of Racial Loyalty. We have thousands of other let-ters in our file that reflect similar emotions and sentiments. Cold,
Mr. Hand? If you need a spook to keep you warm I again suggest
you go see your <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish psychiatrist, or are you perhaps yourself part
of the confusion creating apparatus that is inherent in the tribe of
the Hidden Hand? I hope not.
In conclusion I say to Mr. Hand and all our good <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> Racial
Comrades - don't knock us, but Instead, join with us. We are the
best friend you have in a confused, crumbling and disintegrating
world. For a <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent>r and <ent type='ORG'>Brighter World</ent>,
Creatively yours,
<ent type='PERSON'>Ben Klassen</ent>
Pondifex Maximus
Church Of The Creator</p>

<p>Conclusion: In his Editorial Policy on the Inside cover of Liberty
<ent type='ORG'>Bell</ent> Magazine Mr. George <ent type='PERSON'>Dietz</ent>, the editor, states categorically the
following noble words:
"Freedom of Speech - Freedom of Thought - Freedom
of Expression."
The editor-publisher of <ent type='ORG'>Liberty Bell</ent> does not necessarily agree
with each and every article in this magazine, nor does he subscribe
to all conclusions arrived at by various writers; however, he does
endeavor to permit the exposure of ideas suppressed by the controll-ed news media of this country.
"It is, therefore, in the best tradition of <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> and of free men
everywhere that liberty <ent type='ORG'>Bell</ent> strives to give free reign to ideas, for
<ent type='ORG'>Ultimate</ent>ly it is ideas which rule the world and determine both the
content and structure of culture...... No effort will be spared and no
idea will be allowed to go unexpressed if we think it will benefit the</p>



<p>Thinking People, not only of <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>, but the entire world."
George P. <ent type='PERSON'>Dietz</ent>, Editor &amp; Publisher.
In the past Mr. <ent type='PERSON'>Dietz</ent> has fairly well followed this policy. When
several years ago he saw the light about the gigantic fraud <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish
<ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent>ity had perpetrated on <ent type='EVENT'>the White Race</ent> he fearlessly came
out and said so, despite the vituperative backslash from the misguid-ed fanatics.
He, too, after much soul searching came to the conclusion the
Church Of The Creator had been preaching for years, namely, that
the spooks in the sky swindle spelled the death knell of the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent>
Race.
It is therefore extraordinarily strange that Mr. <ent type='PERSON'>Dietz</ent> has turned
to and embraced another, on ersatz spooks-in-the-sky swindle, name-ly, Odi<ent type='ORG'>nis</ent>m. The cop-out that - well, at least the spooks are <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent>
is really a poor excuse. It is still a hoax, an escape mecha<ent type='ORG'>nis</ent>m, a
child's game. One thing we do not need at this critical stage in the
fight for the survival of <ent type='EVENT'>the White Race</ent> is another cop-out. another
childish game to divert us when we should and must come to grips
with stark reality and do battle with a ruthless enemy. We do not
need more meaningless splinter groups to go off on pointless tangents.
The last thing we need is to dredge up ancient failures from the scrap
heap of history and substitute such nonsense for a comprehensive,
meaningful creed and program. We have to make up our cotton-picking minds on what is best and polarize into one solid battering
ram.
Mr. <ent type='PERSON'>Dietz</ent> admitted to me that in Creativity "We have the whole
ball of wax." He also admitted that reading Nature's Eternal Religion
and a few years of contemplative thinking straightened out his former
confusion about <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent>ity.
In the light of the above, it is hard to understand why, after see-ing the whole picture, Mr. <ent type='PERSON'>Dietz</ent> would now backslide from one set
of spooks to another such piece of nonsense. When <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> tackled
the <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish-<ent type='NORP'>Marxist</ent> mess in post-war <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> he did not dredge up
some ancient political party that was a relic and failure from the past
but instead constructed a completely new, hard hitting political creed
and program that fitted the needs of the times and with it he did the
job that needed to be done. We now need a creed, a philosophy and
a program that meets the exigency of the sorry mess <ent type='EVENT'>the White Race</ent>
is in today, on a total global basis. CREATIVITY has it. It has the
whole ball of wax. Why then revert to past failures and indulge in
silly childish games? In CREATIVITY we have the Total Program,
the Final Solution, the <ent type='ORG'>Ultimate</ent> Creed. Why try to ignore or sup-press it? If you are really more interested in saving <ent type='EVENT'>the White Race</ent>
than nurturing your own private and transient little hubris why not
latch on to and promote the real solution and help build a <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent>r</p>



<p>and <ent type='ORG'>Brighter World</ent>.</p>

<div> * * * * *</div>

<p> It is now the official religion and policy of the
U.S. government to push race mixing at all cost,
and mongrelize <ent type='EVENT'>the White Race</ent> into oblivion.</p>

<div> * * * * *</div>

<p> Never trust any <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent>. Any hypocrite who
will lie to himself will also lie to others.</p>

<p> * * * * *

95 </p></xml>