<xml><p>=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-

THE KENNEDY FILES
FILE #1
January 3, 1992</p>

<p> Copyright 1992 by <ent type='PERSON'>Mark</ent> D. <ent type='ORG'>Turner</ent>
P.O. Box 1955, Bluefield, WV 24701-6955
The Outer Limits BBS - 703-322-2529</p>

<p>=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-
This file may be freely distributed but <ent type='PERSON'>Mark</ent> D. <ent type='ORG'>Turner</ent> retains all
copyrights. Do not make any changes to this file, please. Comments
and suggestions for future issues are appreciated.
=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-</p>

<p> WHY CARE?</p>

<p>Many people have the opinion that the assassination of President <ent type='PERSON'>John</ent>
F. <ent type='PERSON'>Kennedy</ent> is ancient history and it really doesn't matter who killed
him. It's been over 28 years now, so why care? Anyone else involved
might not even be alive anymore. If they are, how could you prove
them guilty after so long?</p>

<p>There's probably many reasons to care about such an old case. History
buffs would be interested even if it had been 528 years ago. People
who were alive at the time might care because they thought so highly
of the young President. After all, he was a man with the visions of
creating the <ent type='ORG'>Peace Corp</ent>, sending a man to the moon, starting to with-draw troops from <ent type='GPE'>Vietnam</ent> as early as 1963, saving <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> from the
clutches of <ent type='ORG'>the Federal Reserve</ent> and putting an end to the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>.</p>

<p>Probably the most important reason is that <ent type='PERSON'>Kennedy</ent> was the man
chosen by the <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n people to lead their country. A few selfish
men decided that he was the wrong choice and basically overthrew our
elected government by murdering the main man. We often hear of such
things happening in other countries, usually small places that we know
little about, but don't realize that the exact same thing happened
in our own country with the assassination of <ent type='PERSON'>John</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Kennedy</ent>. What makes
it even more frightening is that it was immediately covered up at the
highest levels of government and evidence has been suppressed and
locked away ever since.</p>

<p> WHO TO BLAME</p>

<p>Many cases have been presented to implicate people such as Presidents
Lyndon <ent type='PERSON'>John</ent>son, <ent type='PERSON'>Richard Nixon</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Gerald Ford</ent>! <ent type='ORG'>FBI</ent> director J. Edgar
<ent type='PERSON'>Hoover</ent> apparently helped in the cover-up and probably even knew about
it in advance. Facts have finally surfaced recently that even George
<ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent> was a <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> agent investigating the killing in November, 1963.
When <ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent> was chosen to head the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> in the mid-1970's he swore to
<ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent> and the <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n people during his nomination hearings that
he had NEVER worked for the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> before. Even though the <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>ional
investigation of the late 1970's ruled that there was a 95 percent
chance of a conspiracy in the murder, <ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent> stated on January 1, 1992
that he still thought <ent type='PERSON'>Oswald</ent> did it alone. It is also widely believed
that he was involved in <ent type='LOC'>the Bay</ent> of Pigs planning, a covert action that
<ent type='PERSON'>Kennedy</ent> withdrew support from.</p>

<p>Today it is known that when <ent type='PERSON'>LBJ</ent> appointed the members to the Warren
<ent type='ORG'>Commission</ent> that <ent type='PERSON'>Earl Warren</ent> was told lies in order to secure his
cooperation. He was basically mislead to believe that <ent type='GPE'>Cuba</ent> and the
<ent type='GPE'>USSR</ent> may have been responsible and that revealing the truth to the
<ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n people would lead to a new <ent type='EVENT'>World War</ent>; one with nuclear
weapons. He agreed to serve on the <ent type='ORG'>Commission</ent> and help in the cover-up because he thought he was saving the world.</p>

<p>Another main member of the <ent type='ORG'>Commission</ent> was <ent type='PERSON'>Allen Dulles</ent>. He had been
head of the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> until <ent type='PERSON'>JFK</ent> caught him in lies. He fired <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent> and
vowed to destroy the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> because of the many covert activities that
they were involved in. <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent>, a man who hated <ent type='PERSON'>Kennedy</ent> because of
<ent type='LOC'>the Bay</ent> of Pigs fiasco and his dismissal, was appointed to the very
committee that was supposed to find Kennedy's killers. He was in
charge of previewing all of the evidence that the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>FBI</ent> turned
over for consideration. He was the one who decided what the other
members saw. Since it is now widely believed that the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> was
responsible for the murder, it is easy to see that <ent type='GPE'>Dulles</ent> was an
extremely poor choice for an investigator.</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Jack Ruby</ent>, who killed Lee Harvey <ent type='PERSON'>Oswald</ent> (JFK's murderer), is now
known to have worked for <ent type='PERSON'>Richard Nixon</ent> in 1947. <ent type='PERSON'>Nixon</ent> wrote a letter,
which is available at last, that asked <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent> to excuse him from
testifying before them. Ruby was an <ent type='ORG'>FBI</ent> informant in the late 1950's.
He was tied up with the mafia for well over 20 years. He was even
arrested in <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> in the 1930's for the murder of the president
of the Teamster's union. The murder paved the way for <ent type='PERSON'>Jimmy Hoffa</ent>
to take over that organization. One of Nixon's first actions as
President was to pardon <ent type='PERSON'>Hoffa</ent> from prison.</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Nixon</ent> had other connections to the case. Although nearly every
<ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n can tell you where he was when he heard <ent type='PERSON'>Kennedy</ent> was dead,
<ent type='PERSON'>Nixon</ent> says he can't remember. This is the man who had only recently
lost an election to <ent type='PERSON'>JFK</ent>. This is a man who was in on the planning of
<ent type='LOC'>the Bay</ent> of Pigs invasion which <ent type='PERSON'>JFK</ent> pulled out support for. This is
the man who's <ent type='EVENT'>Watergate</ent> burglars included E. Howard Hunt, a suspected
conspirator in the <ent type='PERSON'>JFK</ent> assassination. This is the man who chose
<ent type='PERSON'>Gerald Ford</ent> (who served on <ent type='ORG'>the Warren Commission</ent> and helped with the
cover-up) to replace him as President. This is the man who was in
<ent type='GPE'>DALLAS</ent> the day of the murder! He had been there for a <ent type='ORG'>Pepsi Cola</ent>
meeting along with another man who had dinner with <ent type='PERSON'>Jack Ruby</ent> the
night before JFK's death. <ent type='PERSON'>Nixon</ent> was in <ent type='GPE'>Dallas</ent>, the scene of the
murder, and says he can't remember where he was.</p>

<p>It also interesting to note that <ent type='PERSON'>Robert</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Kennedy</ent> had told people
that if he won the <ent type='GPE'>California</ent> primary then he would announce the
next day that he'd re-open the <ent type='PERSON'>JFK</ent> case as soon as he was elected
President. He won the primary but was immediately assassinated,
too. <ent type='PERSON'>Robert</ent> would have been Nixon's main obstacle in the upcoming
election but was now out of the way. In the following election,
Nixon's main competitor was <ent type='PERSON'>George Wallace</ent>, who was also shot down!</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Kennedy</ent> had already told people that he was dropping <ent type='PERSON'>LBJ</ent> as his
running mate in the next election. He had also already signed
papers and issued orders to withdraw all <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>ns from <ent type='GPE'>Vietnam</ent>
by 1965. One of <ent type='PERSON'>John</ent>son's first actions after becoming President
was to reverse this decision. One of <ent type='PERSON'>John</ent>son's companies made
millions of dollars from the war because they had a contract to
fly soldiers to and from <ent type='GPE'>Vietnam</ent>. He was also the man who ordered
Kennedy's body removed from <ent type='GPE'>Dallas</ent> before an autopsy could be
performed, which was a violation of state law. He was the man who
told his mistress the day before the assassination "After tomorrow,
<ent type='PERSON'>Kennedy</ent> won't be a problem to me anymore." He was the man who
chose the members of <ent type='ORG'>the Warren Commission</ent> who, in turn, produced
the false and misleading report that blamed the entire murder and
planning on Lee Harvey <ent type='PERSON'>Oswald</ent>.</p>

<p>J. <ent type='PERSON'>Edgar Hoover</ent> had been head of the <ent type='ORG'>FBI</ent> for years but was approaching
mandatory retirement age. <ent type='PERSON'>Kennedy</ent> had made it clear that he was not
going to make an exception to the rule and allow <ent type='PERSON'>Hoover</ent> to continue
in the position. <ent type='PERSON'>John</ent>son did. <ent type='PERSON'>Hoover</ent> also claimed that there was no
such thing as organized crime in <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States although he was
close friends with some of the main mafia leaders. <ent type='PERSON'>John</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Robert</ent>
<ent type='PERSON'>Kennedy</ent> worked overtime to put them out of business.</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Gerald Ford</ent> was just another Senator when he was placed on the Warren
<ent type='ORG'>Commission</ent>. There he, too, helped in the cover-up. Later, he broke
federal law by publishing a book which contained classified documents.
The book, of course, said <ent type='PERSON'>Oswald</ent> was the lone assassin. When <ent type='PERSON'>Nixon</ent>
was facing his final days as President and knew he would have to
resign soon, he chose <ent type='PERSON'>Ford</ent> as his new Vice-President. Various <ent type='PERSON'>Nixon</ent>
flunkies have been implicated in the conspiracy (E. Howard Hunt, Frank
Sturgis, <ent type='PERSON'>Jack Ruby</ent>). Was the Presidency Ford's reward for helping in
the cover-up?</p>

<p> CONCLUSION</p>

<p>It is evident that the men in power had good reasons to keep the
<ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n people from learning the truth. At the very least, they each
gained from the murder and therefore had no reason to be in charge of
the investigation. This series of articles hopes to enlighten people
to the evidence and theories in the case. Only by awakening enough
citizens and bringing out the truth can we hope to insure that no more
of our chosen leaders will be so easily taken away from us. When we
loose the power to chose our own leaders then we have lost everything.</p>

<div>=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-</div>

</xml>