<xml><div>=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-</div>

<p> THE KENNEDY FILES
FILE #3</p>

<p> Copyright 1992 by <ent type='PERSON'>Mark</ent> D. <ent type='ORG'>Turner</ent>
P.O. Box 1955, Bluefield, WV 24701-6955
The Outer Limits BBS - 703-322-2529</p>

<p>=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-
This file may be freely distributed but <ent type='PERSON'>Mark</ent> D. <ent type='ORG'>Turner</ent> retains all
copyrights. Do not make any changes to this file, please. Comments
and suggestions for future issues are appreciated.
=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-</p>

<p> THE GEORGE <ent type='PERSON'>BUSH</ent> CONNECTION</p>

<p>In this day and age when some people can not even name the president
of <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States, it is not the least bit surprising that most
have no knowledge of <ent type='PERSON'>George Bush</ent>'s possible connections to the <ent type='PERSON'>Kennedy</ent>
assassination. The relationship has its roots in Bush's "former"
employment with the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>. As <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> agents have been quoted in the past,
you never really leave the <ent type='ORG'>Agency</ent>.</p>

<p> THE <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> DID IT!</p>

<p>Many researchers place the blame for the murder of John F. <ent type='PERSON'>Kennedy</ent> on
the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>. The easiest way to clear the mafia or other non-governmental
groups is to look at the massive cover-up that the government has
participated in over the years. If mafia boss <ent type='PERSON'>Carlos Marcello</ent> had
really ordered the hit, could he have had the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>FBI</ent> suppress so
much evidence from the public for so long? Could he have had the
normal security lowered for the assassination? Could he have had the
<ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent> D.C. phone system knocked out of order for an hour right
as the shooting took place? Could he have convinced the Warren
<ent type='ORG'>Commission</ent> to release such an idiotic official version of the murder?
Of course not. The set-up and cover-up had to take place INSIDE of
the government, not outside.</p>

<p>The <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> seemed to have the most (and best) motives for the elimination
of <ent type='PERSON'>Kennedy</ent>. During the <ent type='PERSON'>Eisenhower</ent> presidency, the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> came up with a
plan to invade <ent type='GPE'>Cuba</ent> at <ent type='ORG'>the Bay</ent> of Pigs. The thought was that the
citizens would hear of the attack and join in to overthrow <ent type='PERSON'>Castro</ent>.
Former <ent type='GPE'>Cuba</ent>ns were trained by the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> and the U.S. government fur-nished them with weapons and transportation. Since it was near the
end of his administration, <ent type='PERSON'>Eisenhower</ent> put the plan on hold so the
new president would not have to deal with any problems which might
arise from the mission.</p>

<p>Upon entering office <ent type='PERSON'>Kennedy</ent> decided that the plan's requirement of 16
planes would obviously reveal <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> backing of the plot. The plan
had hoped that <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> involvement would not become known to the
world. The use of 16 planes would make <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> backing obvious to
everyone. <ent type='PERSON'>Kennedy</ent> cut the number of planes down to six. As the date
of the invasion neared, <ent type='PERSON'>Kennedy</ent> decided against the plan and announced
in the press that <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States would not invade <ent type='GPE'>Cuba</ent> with the
military.</p>

<p>The <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> went ahead with the plan and quickly found that things were
not going as they had hoped for. They asked for more planes but were
told they would have to be held back until the forces captured a <ent type='GPE'>Cuba</ent>n
airport. Then, the planes could be sent and the explanation would be
that they were captured planes which the rebels had put into use. The
<ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>-backed rebels never got that far and were quickly defeated. The
citizens of <ent type='GPE'>Cuba</ent> never joined them in the fight. The <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>, as has been
revealed in books by participants, blamed <ent type='PERSON'>Kennedy</ent> for the defeat. The
books and papers reveal a deep hatred for the imagined betrayal.</p>

<p>Later, <ent type='PERSON'>Kennedy</ent> formed a panel to keep him informed as to what was
going on in <ent type='GPE'>Vietnam</ent>. <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> involvement was still low at this
point but <ent type='PERSON'>Kennedy</ent> was worried. He has been quoted as saying he could
not justify sending <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> boys half-way around the world to fight
communism when it existed just south of <ent type='GPE'>Florida</ent> in <ent type='GPE'>Cuba</ent>. One of the
panel's members was <ent type='PERSON'>Allen Dulles</ent>, head of the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>. <ent type='PERSON'>Kennedy</ent> caught
him in various lies and fired him. The fact that the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> had kept
training <ent type='GPE'>Cuba</ent>ns for another invasion until <ent type='PERSON'>Kennedy</ent> finally sent in
<ent type='ORG'>FBI</ent> agents to break up their camps and confiscate their weapons was
another reason for the dismissal. Other high-ranking <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> officials
were fired, too, including the brother of <ent type='GPE'>Dallas</ent>' mayor. <ent type='PERSON'>Kennedy</ent>
changed the operating procedure of the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> so they would have to get
approval for any future covert actions from Robert <ent type='PERSON'>Kennedy</ent>.</p>

<p>Due to persistent problems with the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> and their continual involve-ment in matters which were not their concern, <ent type='PERSON'>Kennedy</ent> declared that
he was going to shatter the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> into a thousand pieces and scatter
them to the winds. Even former president <ent type='PERSON'>Truman</ent>, who had created
the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>, expressed concerns about their behavior. <ent type='PERSON'>Kennedy</ent> was
apparently going to leave their destruction until after the next
election but did start withdrawing troops from <ent type='GPE'>Vietnam</ent>, much to the
dislike of the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>. One of Johnson's first moves after he replaced
<ent type='PERSON'>Kennedy</ent> as president was to increase <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> involvement in <ent type='GPE'>Vietnam</ent>.
It seems he owned an airline company that was contracted to fly troops
back and forth across the <ent type='LOC'>Pacific Ocean</ent>, but that is another matter.</p>

<p>Later, E. Howard Hunt, on behalf of the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>, faked cables to implicate
John F. <ent type='PERSON'>Kennedy</ent> in the assassination of South Vietnam's president, Ngo
Dinh Diem. So, it is apparent that the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> disliked <ent type='PERSON'>Kennedy</ent> and had
the means to set-up and cover-up the assassination. Now, it is known
that they convinced <ent type='ORG'>the Warren Commission</ent> that <ent type='GPE'>the Soviet Union</ent> and
<ent type='GPE'>Cuba</ent> had murdered <ent type='PERSON'>Kennedy</ent>. They scared the members into believing
that revealing this to the <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> public would result in a nuclear
war in which millions would be killed. To further this theory, they
produced fake evidence showing that <ent type='PERSON'>Oswald</ent> had visited the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> and
<ent type='GPE'>Cuba</ent>n embassies in <ent type='GPE'>Mexico</ent> to arrange the killing and escape. The head
of the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> operations in <ent type='GPE'>Mexico</ent> has since admitted that no such real
evidence ever existed. A <ent type='ORG'>Warren Commission</ent> investigator has admitted
that they acted to save millions by sacrificing one man (<ent type='PERSON'>Oswald</ent>).</p>

<p>The job was not too hard to pull off since former <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>-head Allen
Dulles was a member of the <ent type='ORG'>Commission</ent>. He was the only one to attend
more than half of the hearings and was also in charge of deciding
what intelligence data was seen by the other members. President
<ent type='PERSON'>Johnson</ent> didn't seem to find it strange to appoint the man that
<ent type='PERSON'>Kennedy</ent> had fired to investigate his hated former boss' murder.</p>

<p> SO HOW DOES <ent type='PERSON'>BUSH</ent> FIT IT?</p>

<p>Although he denies it, there is a growing body of evidence that George
<ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent> was working for the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> as early as 1961. Many feel he was
actually recruited during his college days (which is when he joined
the <ent type='ORG'>Skull</ent> and Bones Society, a front for the <ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent>). <ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent> claims
to have been working for his own oil company during the early 1960's.
It would make for a convenient front since he claims to have been off-shore on drilling rigs for weeks at a time. The rigs were located all
over the world. Was he really on the rigs or was he running around on
<ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> business? The various biographies of <ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent> are all sketchy on this
phase of his life.</p>

<p>During this time, <ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent> had moved to <ent type='GPE'>HOUSTON</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Texas</ent>. His wife was,
of course, <ent type='ORG'>BARBARA</ent>. His oil company was <ent type='PERSON'>ZAPATA</ent> Off Shore Co. (which
he named after a communist <ent type='NORP'>Mexican</ent> revolutionary who would invade
towns and murder every man, woman and child. <ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent> also named an
earlier oil company after <ent type='PERSON'>Zapata</ent>, a questionable choice for a hero).
The code name for <ent type='ORG'>the Bay</ent> of Pigs invasion was Operation <ent type='PERSON'>ZAPATA</ent>!
A former high-ranking <ent type='ORG'>Pentagon</ent> official, Col. Fletcher Prouty, was
the man who secured two <ent type='ORG'>Navy</ent> ships for the operation. He has told
of seeing the two ships repainted to non-<ent type='ORG'>Navy</ent> colors for the
invasion. The ships were given the new names <ent type='GPE'>HOUSTON</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>BARBARA</ent>!</p>

<p>Of course, maybe the names were just coincidences, but <ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent> was
living in <ent type='GPE'>Houston</ent> with <ent type='PERSON'>Barbara</ent> and running <ent type='PERSON'>Zapata</ent> in 1961 during
the planning of the invasion. The name "Operation <ent type='PERSON'>Zapata</ent>" was top
secret and known only to a very few.</p>

<p>In 1977 and 1978, the government released nearly 100000 pages of
documents on the <ent type='PERSON'>Kennedy</ent> assassination. One which slipped out by
mistake was from the <ent type='ORG'>FBI</ent> to the State Department written a few days
after the assassination. The State Department was worried that anti-<ent type='PERSON'>Castro</ent> groups in <ent type='GPE'>Miami</ent> might stage another invasion of <ent type='GPE'>Cuba</ent> in the
aftermath of the <ent type='PERSON'>JFK</ent> murder. The <ent type='ORG'>FBI</ent> informed them that they had
questioned both pro-<ent type='PERSON'>Castro</ent> and anti-<ent type='PERSON'>Castro</ent> groups and could find no
information about such plans. The memo went on to state that the
information was passed along to "<ent type='PERSON'>George Bush</ent> of the <ent type='ORG'>Central Intelli</ent>-gence <ent type='ORG'>Agency</ent>" the day after the assassination.</p>

<p>Why was the information passed along to the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>? Probably because of
their previous invasion attempt and other planned attacks. Why George
<ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent>? Probably because he was involved in previous invasion plans!</p>

<p>When the document first surfaced no one paid much attention to it.
When the presidential campaigns began for the 1980 election then the
name <ent type='PERSON'>George Bush</ent> caught researchers' eyes. When asked about the
memo, <ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent> denied working for the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> at the time. As evidence built
that it was indeed him, the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> claimed it was a different <ent type='PERSON'>George Bush</ent>
although their policy had always been to neither confirm nor deny a
person's employment. The other <ent type='PERSON'>George Bush</ent> was tracked down by
reporters and said that although he did work for the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> at the time,
he was never involved in that sort of work. The interesting point
is that the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> did not bother to contact the other <ent type='PERSON'>George Bush</ent> and
inform him that reporters might soon be calling. Other evidence
surfaced that showed the <ent type='PERSON'>George Bush</ent> mentioned in the document was
actually George H. W. <ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent> and had the same address as the famous
<ent type='PERSON'>George Bush</ent>.</p>

<p>Another <ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent> connection involved George de Mohrenschildt, a rich
<ent type='NORP'>Russian</ent> oil man who lived in <ent type='GPE'>Texas</ent> when Lee Harvey <ent type='PERSON'>Oswald</ent> settled
there after his trip to <ent type='GPE'>the Soviet Union</ent>. De Mohrenschildt was a
long-time <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> agent and quite possibly served as a <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> control officer
for <ent type='PERSON'>Oswald</ent>. The <ent type='ORG'>Warren Commission</ent> described him and his wife as being
the two people friendliest to <ent type='PERSON'>Oswald</ent> at the time of the assassination.
De Mohrenschildt's son-in-law told <ent type='ORG'>the Warren Commission</ent> that if any-one had helped with the assassination it was most likely de Mohren-schildt. De Mohrenschildt was also the man who moved <ent type='PERSON'>Oswald</ent> to
<ent type='GPE'>Dallas</ent>.</p>

<p>Shortly before <ent type='ORG'>the House Select Committee</ent> on Assassinations started
meeting in the late 1970's a new doctor appeared in de Mohrenschildt's
town. De Mohrenschildt started seeing him and quickly became mentally
unstable. His wife convinced him to stop seeing the doctor. The
doctor then moved away and left a false forwarding address. The very
day the <ent type='ORG'>Committee</ent> tried to contact de Mohrenschildt about testifying,
he was found dead of a gun shot wound. His personal address book was
found and it contained the entry "<ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent>, George H. W. (Poppy) 1412 W.
<ent type='GPE'>Ohio</ent> also <ent type='PERSON'>Zapata</ent> Petroleum Midland." Bush's full name is George
Herbert Walker <ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent> which matches the initials given and his earlier
oil company was named <ent type='PERSON'>Zapata</ent> Petroleum Corp. Why was his name in de
Mohrenschildt's book? Is "Poppy" his <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> code name?</p>

<p>It is known that in the early 1960's de Mohrenschildt made frequent
trips to <ent type='GPE'>Houston</ent>, which was the location of Bush's home. He told
friends he was visiting the <ent type='PERSON'>Brown</ent> brothers, who were close friends
and financial supporters of Lyndon <ent type='PERSON'>Johnson</ent>. <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> documents reveal
that during the planning phase of Operation <ent type='PERSON'>Zapata</ent>, de Mohrenschildt
made frequent trips to <ent type='GPE'>Mexico</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Panama</ent> and gave reports to the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>.
His son-in-law told <ent type='ORG'>the Warren Commission</ent> that he believed de Mohren-schildt was spying for the planned <ent type='GPE'>Cuba</ent>n invasion.</p>

<p> A QUESTION OF CHARACTER</p>

<p>When <ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent> was picked to be director of the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> in 1976, he testified
to <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent> that he had never worked for the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> before. Of course,
it did not make much sense to appoint a director who had no such back-ground but <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent> approved him anyway. Now it would seem that <ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent>
committed perjury in his congressional testimony.</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>George Bush</ent> was apparently high enough in the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> to help plan the
Bay of Pigs invasion. It would probably be safe to assume that he
even named the operation and its two ships. Considering the hatred
that the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> felt toward <ent type='PERSON'>Kennedy</ent> over their failed mission and Bush's
involvement in that same mission, it would be quite interesting to
know what Bush's feelings toward John F. <ent type='PERSON'>Kennedy</ent> really were and what
his full role in the assassination investigation was.</p>

<div>=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-</div>

<p>Further information on the <ent type='PERSON'>George Bush</ent> connection may be obtained from
<ent type='PERSON'>Mark</ent> Lane's "Plausible Denial" (Thunder's Mouth Press) and James "Bo"
Gritz's "Called To Serve." Lane's book is an excellent accounting of
the CIA's involvement (especially E. Howard Hunt and <ent type='PERSON'>Frank Sturgis</ent>).
<ent type='ORG'>Gritz</ent> (a 1992 presidential candidate) tells about many of the CIA's
questionable ventures and also about his trips to <ent type='GPE'>Laos</ent> to attempt
rescues of <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> POWs who are still held by <ent type='GPE'>Vietnam</ent>.</p>

<div>=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-
</div></xml>