<xml><p>Article 6526 of alt.conspiracy:
From: plemkin@igc.org (<ent type='PERSON'>Peter Lemkin</ent>)
Newsgroups: alt.conspiracy
Subject: 100 CONSPIRACY Q'S ON <ent type='PERSON'>JFK</ent> <ent type='ORG'>ASSASSIN</ent>
<info type="Message-ID"> 1299600016@igc.org</info>
Date: 30 Dec 91 00:21:00 GMT
Sender: Notesfile to Usenet Gateway <special>notes@igc.org</special>
Lines: 1278
Nf-ID: #N:<ent type='ORG'>cdp</ent>:1299600016:000:17631
Nf-From: <ent type='ORG'>cdp</ent>.<ent type='ORG'>UUCP</ent>!plemkin Dec 29 16:21:00 1991</p>

<p> J.F.K. <ent type='ORG'>ASSASSIN</ent>ATION 11/22/63</p>

<p> COINCIDENCE OR CONSPIRACY?</p>

<p>1) Why were over 58 eye-witnesses to the assassination ignored by
<ent type='ORG'>the Warren Commission</ent> when they said they felt shots had NOT come
from the Book Depository? </p>

<p>2) Why did most persons in Dealey Plaza run up the Grassy Knoll
after the shots while the authorities ran to the Book
Depository? </p>

<p>3) Why were MULTIPLE rifles found at the Book Depository and then
all but one made to 'disappear'? </p>

<p>4) Why were ongoing de-escalation plans for <ent type='GPE'>Vietnam</ent> reversed
within 48 hrs of the assassination? </p>

<p>5) Why were the ten persons taken into custody in Dealey Plaza
all released, some without so much as their names taken? What is
the evidence (officially ignored) that some of them were directly
involved? </p>

<p>6) How was '<ent type='EVENT'>Watergate</ent>' and the ensuing <ent type='EVENT'>Watergate</ent> scandal DIRECTLY
connected to the <ent type='PERSON'>JFK</ent> assassination? </p>

<p>7) What MULTIPLE lines of evidence connect the <ent type='PERSON'>JFK</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>RFK</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>MLK</ent>
assassinations? </p>

<p>8) What are the known (often frightening and bizarre) details of
the over 200 persons who were murdered or died VERY suspiciously
(and conveniently) after 11/22/63 because they had seen the
'wrong' things, tried to speak up, etc.? Why did they die in
"clusters" when investigations were ongoing - sometimes just
hours before they were to be questioned? </p>

<p>9) Why was <ent type='PERSON'>Nixon</ent> one of the few <ent type='NORP'>Americans</ent> who could not correctly
remember where he was when the assassination occurred? Why may
he have 'forgotten' he was on a plane out of <ent type='GPE'>Dallas</ent>? </p>

<p>10) Why could J.E. Hoover also not 'remember' he was in <ent type='GPE'>Dallas</ent>
for a meeting just days before the assassination? Why did he
show NO surprise at the announcement of JFK's death? </p>

<p>11) What is the evidence that <ent type='ORG'>FBI</ent> informants (perhaps even Lee
Harvey <ent type='PERSON'>Oswald</ent> himself) had warned the <ent type='ORG'>FBI</ent> of an impending
assassination attempt on <ent type='PERSON'>JFK</ent> which the <ent type='ORG'>FBI</ent> ignored and later
denied even getting? </p>

<p>12) What multiple lines of evidence show <ent type='PERSON'>Ruby</ent> and Oswald's <ent type='ORG'>FBI</ent>
and <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> connections? </p>

<p>13) What documents are still being withheld from public scrutiny
in <ent type='ORG'>the National Archives</ent> and WHY? Why 'hide' any when the
government 'believes' the act was committed by a 'lone nut'!? </p>

<p>14) Why did so MANY government documents involving Lee Harvey
<ent type='PERSON'>Oswald</ent> and others 'disappear' or were said to have been
'destroyed' - including <ent type='PERSON'>Lee Harvey Oswald</ent>'S <ent type='ORG'>Army Intelligence</ent>
files, <ent type='PERSON'>Lee Harvey Oswald</ent>'S letter to his <ent type='ORG'>FBI</ent> contact <ent type='ORG'>Hosty</ent> and
MUCH MORE? </p>

<p>15) Why when <ent type='PERSON'>Lee Harvey Oswald</ent> returned to the <ent type='GPE'>USA</ent> from the <ent type='GPE'>USSR</ent>
was he NOT officially met by any representatives of the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>FBI</ent>,
State Dept. etc., but WAS met by <ent type='NORP'>Spas</ent> T Raiken, a former <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>
collaborator with intelligence community connections who the
<ent type='ORG'>Warren Commission</ent> claimed was with 'Traveller's Aid'. </p>

<p>16) Why was Marina <ent type='PERSON'>Oswald</ent> sequestered in a hotel, surrounded with
intelligence community connected persons, coached as to what to
say and what she had experienced, and threatened with deportation
if she did not cooperate? </p>

<p>17) What evidence connects EVERY president since the
assassination (with the lone exception of <ent type='PERSON'>Carter</ent>) directly with
the assassination or its cover-up!? What are George H.W. Bush's
connections to the events of 11/22/63? Why was his name and
address in <ent type='PERSON'>Lee Harvey Oswald</ent>'S <ent type='GPE'>Dallas</ent> friend's address book? </p>

<p>18) Why did Jack <ent type='PERSON'>Ruby</ent> repeatedly implore of the <ent type='PERSON'>Warren</ent>
Commissioners to take him out of <ent type='GPE'>Dallas</ent> and to <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent> where
he felt he could speak the truth? Why did they NOT take him up
on his offer and pleas? </p>

<p>19) What did Jack <ent type='PERSON'>Ruby</ent> mean when he said that he was "no more
involved in a conspiracy than you gentlemen" when he spoke to the
<ent type='ORG'>Warren Commission</ent>? </p>

<p>20) Why did <ent type='PERSON'>Ruby</ent> suddenly contract cancer and die just before his
new trial was to begin? </p>

<p>21) Why did <ent type='PERSON'>Dorothy Kilgallan</ent>, the only reporter to interview
<ent type='PERSON'>Ruby</ent> in prison, die mysteriously days after she said she would
"break the case wide open" and her best friend die some days
thereafter? </p>

<p>22) How do the events of 11/22/63 and its immediate aftermath
<ent type='ORG'>STILL</ent> effect our everyday political and even personal lives? </p>

<p>23) What Government agencies and other groups were involved in
the planning and execution of the President and then cover it
up? </p>

<p>24) Why was the single-bullet or "Magic Bullet" theory of the
<ent type='ORG'>Warren Commission</ent> a physical and medical <ent type='ORG'>IMPOSSIBILITY</ent>? </p>

<p>25) Why do those who played prominently in the assassination and
its 'investigation' continually show up in contemporary political
life? Are they being 'rewarded' for a 'job well done"? </p>

<p>26) Why did the U.S. Government deliberately LIE to <ent type='ORG'>the American</ent>
People and World about what they knew of the events of the
assassination? Why do the CONTINUE to do so? </p>

<p>27) Who felt threatened by <ent type='PERSON'>JFK</ent>? And who gained by his murder?
Who had the means to kill him and cover it up to look like the
work of a lone-nut? </p>

<p>28) How was the Media sometimes cleverly controlled and, at
times, complicit in the coverage of events, facts and fiction? </p>

<p>29) Which <ent type='ORG'>Mafia</ent> bosses and employees, many of whom worked for and
with the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>, were involved in the assassination? </p>

<p>30) What did <ent type='ORG'>LBJ</ent> mean when he said the U.S. Government had been
running a 'Murder Incorporated' down in the <ent type='LOC'>Caribbean</ent> in the
'60's? </p>

<p>31) Why did <ent type='ORG'>LBJ</ent> insist on being sworn in on Air Force One when he
was quite legally President AUTOMATICALLY upon the death of <ent type='PERSON'>JFK</ent>? </p>

<p>32) Why were some of the very same persons who were in <ent type='GPE'>Dallas</ent> on
11/22/63 also just by 'coincidence' near the <ent type='PERSON'>RFK</ent> murder and
<ent type='GPE'>Memphis</ent> for the <ent type='PERSON'>MLK</ent> assassination? </p>

<p>33) Why did so MANY fear for their lives in the wake of an
assassination by a (then dead) lone-nut? Why did so many die
suddenly, mysteriously and 'conveniently'? </p>

<p>34) Why did the <ent type='ORG'>FBI</ent> not react to an informant's report that
<ent type='PERSON'>Joseph Milteer</ent> knew in detail how <ent type='PERSON'>JFK</ent> was going to be
assassinated weeks before the event? Why did the public never
hear that <ent type='PERSON'>Milteer</ent> traveled hundred of miles to witness the
execution with his own eyes? Why was he never questioned by the
<ent type='ORG'>Warren Commission</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>House Select Committee</ent> or anyone else? </p>

<p>35) Why were the few who attempted to tell the truth of the
events harassed, punished, fired from their jobs, discredited,
intimidated, marginalized, threatened and often killed? </p>

<p>36) Why did all those who met in Ruby's apartment the evening
<ent type='PERSON'>Ruby</ent> killed <ent type='PERSON'>Oswald</ent> die mysteriously thereafter? </p>

<p>37) Why did so many bullets and so much of the physical evidence
'disappear'? </p>

<p>38) Who were the multitude of PHONY '<ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>' and '<ent type='ORG'>Secret Service</ent>'
persons (complete with official looking ID) on the Grassy Knoll
and around Dealey Plaza on 11/22/63? Why were they stopping
persons from moving into certain locations? </p>

<p>39) Why did the driver of the Presidential limousine slow the car
during the fusillade rather than accelerate? </p>

<p>40) Why did <ent type='ORG'>Secret Service</ent> men jump over the body of <ent type='ORG'>LBJ</ent> and not
<ent type='PERSON'>JFK</ent>? </p>

<p>41) Why were several of the <ent type='ORG'>Secret Service</ent> agents out drinking
very late the night before at a club owned by a friend of
Ruby's? </p>

<p>42) What did Jack <ent type='PERSON'>Ruby</ent> know when he said "I'm Jack <ent type='PERSON'>Ruby</ent>. You
don't know me, but you soon will" just BEFORE the assassination? </p>

<p>43) What evidence is there that <ent type='PERSON'>Ruby</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Oswald</ent> and Tippit (as well
as others possibly involved) all knew and had been seen meeting
each other? </p>

<p>44) Why was so much evidence and testimony suppressed and at
times altered? </p>

<p>45) Why to THIS DAY do many live in fear to speak the truth of
what they saw or know of the events of <ent type='GPE'>Dallas</ent> 11/22/63? </p>

<p>46) Why are powerful forces trying to discredit the new <ent type='PERSON'>JFK</ent>
movie? Why have 'critics' of the official version of events long
been subject to harassment, surveillance and more? </p>

<p>47) Why were so MANY of the movies and photos taken in Dealey
Plaza that day <ent type='ORG'>CONFISCATED</ent> by persons representing themselves as
government officials and NEVER returned nor shown to the public? </p>

<p>48) Why do governmental and extra-governmental forces <ent type='ORG'>STILL</ent> spin
dis-information stories related to 11/22/63 and its aftermath? </p>

<p>49) Why were several witnesses offered bribes and/or threatened
by the <ent type='ORG'>FBI</ent> and others to NOT disclose the truth of what they
saw? </p>

<p>50) Why were witnesses coached and badgered to get the testimony
<ent type='ORG'>the Warren Commission</ent> 'wanted' to hear? Why were those who saw a
different scenario ignored or worse? </p>

<p>51) Why did <ent type='PERSON'>Warren</ent> suggest the Report NOT be published to save
printing costs? </p>

<p>52) Why and how did police have a full description of <ent type='PERSON'>Oswald</ent>
before those on the investigation scene could have assembled any
information to lead to such a conclusion? </p>

<p>53) Why did some newspapers get information only the <ent type='ORG'>FBI</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>
had on <ent type='PERSON'>Oswald</ent> to print in their stories within hours of the
event? Who leaked this information or had it on hand prior? </p>

<p>54) Why do so few know of the photos that show clear evidence of
a conspiracy and even show images of the other conspirators and
gunmen? </p>

<p>55) What is known of the multiplicity of mysterious activities of
many in <ent type='GPE'>Dallas</ent> and Dealey Plaza that day? </p>

<p>56) Why did the <ent type='ORG'>FBI</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> at the HIGHEST levels suppress
information and work to foil a real investigation into aspects of
the assassination? </p>

<p>57) What were the many <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> and <ent type='NORP'>Fascist</ent> connections to the
assassination? </p>

<p>58) What evidence is there of MULTIPLE gunmen in <ent type='ORG'>the School Book</ent>
Depository and other buildings, as well as the Grassy Knoll? </p>

<p>59) Why was '<ent type='PERSON'>Lee Harvey Oswald</ent>' repeatedly seen at several places
SIMULTANEOUSLY in the weeks before the assassination and who were
those impersonating him and why? </p>

<p>60) What evidence shows that the person murdered by <ent type='PERSON'>Ruby</ent> is NOT
the person exhumed from that grave? </p>

<p>61) Why were so many of the medical evidences tampered with or
made to 'disappear'? Why were so many others seemingly altered? </p>

<p>62) Why did someone construct forged composite photos to frame
<ent type='PERSON'>Lee Harvey Oswald</ent> prior to the assassination? </p>

<p>63) Why did the <ent type='PERSON'>JFK</ent> autopsy doctor who burned his notes and first
draft of the autopsy report get a promotion shortly after this
obstruction of justice and/or alteration of fact? </p>

<p>64) Why do the locations of wounds as seen by a team doctors in
<ent type='GPE'>Dallas</ent> and that evening by another team of doctors in Bethesda
Naval Hospital NOT match in number or location!? </p>

<p>65) Why did the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> and other government entities try to
discredit and obstruct Garrison's investigation and frame him on
false charges? Why were they so afraid of his investigation? </p>

<p>66) Who was the <ent type='ORG'>Army Intelligence</ent> man in and around the <ent type='GPE'>Texas</ent>
School Book Depository? </p>

<p>67) Why were Jack <ent type='PERSON'>Ruby</ent> and several of the <ent type='GPE'>Dallas</ent> Police and
others seen repeatedly at multiple assassination-related
locations in <ent type='GPE'>Dallas</ent> that day? How did they seem to 'know' where
the 'action' was - or was to be? </p>

<p>68) Why do different documents and identifications of Lee Harvey
<ent type='PERSON'>Oswald</ent> show different height and even different faces - not to
mention names? What was <ent type='PERSON'>Lee Harvey Oswald</ent>'s REAL 'mission' in
the <ent type='GPE'>USSR</ent> and in <ent type='GPE'>New Orleans</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Dallas</ent> after his return? Who did
he work for? <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>? <ent type='ORG'>FBI</ent>? <ent type='ORG'>ONI</ent>? </p>

<p>69) Who were the several different men seen fleeing from the
Plaza seconds after the shots rang out? </p>

<p>70) Why did the eye-witness reports of persons seeing men with
rifles in Dealey Plaza before and during the shooting receive so
little 'official' attention and even suppression? </p>

<p>71) Why was JFK's body <ent type='ORG'>ILLEGALLY</ent> removed from <ent type='GPE'>Dallas</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Texas</ent>
jurisdiction? Why did the <ent type='ORG'>FBI</ent> remove all of the other physical
evidence to <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>? Why was a Grand Jury never convened? </p>

<p>72) Why did <ent type='ORG'>the Warren Commission</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>FBI</ent> seem to repeatedly and
consistently mis-spell the names of those who's involvement might
shed light on a possible conspiracy? Was this 'conspiratorial
dyslexia' on the government's part? </p>

<p>73) Were one or more bullets and bullet fragments removed
secretly from JFK's brain as much evidence indicates? </p>

<p>74) Why was his brain never sectioned and studied? Why and to
where did it disappear along with other essential medical
evidence? </p>

<p>75) Why do the descriptions of the size, color and other details
of the coffin JFK's body was placed into in <ent type='GPE'>Dallas</ent> NOT match
those his body was in when it arrived for autopsy in <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>?
Was there a 'switch' and tampering with the body during the
flight? </p>

<p>76) Why were the autopsy doctors ORDERED to NOT follow certain
STANDARD medical procedures and investigate certain wounds etc.? </p>

<p>77) What was <ent type='ORG'>the Government</ent>'s role in obstruction of justice
after the fact...if not before? </p>

<p>78) Why were the seven particular persons on the <ent type='PERSON'>Warren</ent>
Commission selected? Why did several have intelligence community
connections? Why were some enemies of <ent type='PERSON'>JFK</ent>? </p>

<p>79) Has our Government been 'illegitimate' since 11/22/63? Are
we still living with the legacy of a coup d'etat in <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>? Are
the 'coup' leaders still firmly in control? </p>

<p>80) Is: 'ignorance bliss'? Does: 'knowledge imply
responsibility'? Does: 'silence equal complicity'? </p>

<p>81) What can be done to understand and finally undo this entire
(long overdue) situation? Is Knowledge and Truth the first step
to talking back our country? What ARE the facts? Why are they
obscured from the average <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n? </p>

<p>82) Is the assassination of <ent type='PERSON'>JFK</ent> the <ent type='GPE'>PIVOTAL</ent> event of <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n
History since <ent type='EVENT'>the Second World War</ent>? Is an understanding of the
events a <ent type='GPE'>NECESSARY</ent> precursor to understanding EVERY MAJOR
political event that has happened since - right up to <ent type='GPE'>TODAY</ent>!? </p>

<p>83) Why did Jack <ent type='PERSON'>Ruby</ent> suddenly have a dramatic improvement in his
financial situation just prior to the assassination? </p>

<p>84) Why did several persons not 'officially' thought to have been
involved suddenly flee <ent type='GPE'>Dallas</ent> immediately after the Event? </p>

<p>85) Why did the <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent> D.C. phone system fail for several
minutes immediately during and after the assassination? </p>

<p>86) Why were most of the <ent type='ORG'>Cabinet</ent> conveniently and coincidentally
out of the country at the time? </p>

<p>87) Why was the <ent type='ORG'>Navy</ent> man with the launch codes for the atomic
weapons separated from <ent type='PERSON'>JFK</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>LBJ</ent>? What foreknowledge did the
Military have? What possible participation? </p>

<p>88) Can the deaths and destruction at home and abroad in <ent type='GPE'>Vietnam</ent>
and ALL the subsequent wars be understood by an analysis of the
<ent type='PERSON'>JFK</ent> assassination? </p>

<p>89) Was <ent type='PERSON'>Lee Harvey Oswald</ent> a <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> agent, as much evidence seems to
indicate? </p>

<p>90) Need <ent type='ORG'>the American</ent> People question if our government and
institutions of government have had ANY legitimacy since
11/22/63? </p>

<p>91) What Right-Wing groups and Businessmen were involved in the
plot? Why? </p>

<p>92) Why were NO notes kept by <ent type='PERSON'>ANYONE</ent> who interrogated Lee Harvey
<ent type='PERSON'>Oswald</ent> over a 48 hr period? </p>

<p>93) Why did <ent type='PERSON'>Lee Harvey Oswald</ent> say "I am just a patsy"? Was he
100% correct? </p>

<p>94) Why does much evidence show that <ent type='PERSON'>Lee Harvey Oswald</ent> did not
even hold a rifle that day - and perhaps NOT even OWN one? </p>

<p>95) Why did then Governor Reagan refuse to extradite several
persons suspected of direct involvement in the assassination for
trial and then get suggested as a Presidential candidate? </p>

<p>96) Why did <ent type='PERSON'>Lee Harvey Oswald</ent> have to be executed within 48hrs of
his alleged crime? Was he 'supposed' to have been killed prior? </p>

<p>97) How did <ent type='PERSON'>Ruby</ent> gain entry into the Police station? Were the
police waiting for <ent type='PERSON'>Ruby</ent> to enter before moving <ent type='PERSON'>Oswald</ent>? </p>

<p>98) Why did forces high in the <ent type='ORG'>FBI</ent> order the DESTRUCTION of a
note <ent type='PERSON'>Oswald</ent> had given to <ent type='ORG'>FBI</ent> agent <ent type='ORG'>Hosty</ent> in <ent type='GPE'>Dallas</ent> days before
the assassination? </p>

<p>99) Why do <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> and other documents show a coordinated effort to
'destroy' the critics of <ent type='ORG'>the Warren Commission</ent> and the
Government's BIG LIE of the events of 11/22/63? </p>

<p>100) Did <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> DIE along with <ent type='PERSON'>JFK</ent> that day in <ent type='GPE'>Dallas</ent> 11/22/63?
Can we revive it and take back OUR country from the assassins and
their heirs? Are we as a People more satisfied with the
'COMFORTABLE LIE' or the 'UNCOMFORTABLE TRUTH'?!? </p>

<p>*If you would like to read more on the <ent type='PERSON'>JFK</ent> assassination AND
DECIDE FOR YOURSELF the answers to the above questions, the
following footnoted sources are readily available: </p>

<p>1) High Treason, Groden, Robert J. and Livingstone, Harrison E.;
<ent type='ORG'>Berkeley Books</ent>, l990 </p>

<p>2) On The Trail Of The Assassins, <ent type='PERSON'>Garrison</ent>, Jim; Sheridan Quare
Press, l988 </p>

<p>3) Crossfire, Marrs, Jim; Carroll and <ent type='PERSON'>Graf</ent>, l989 </p>

<p>4) Conspiracy, Summers, Anthony; Paradon, l989 </p>

<p>5) Best Evidence, <ent type='ORG'>Lifton</ent>, David; Carroll and <ent type='PERSON'>Graf</ent>, l988 </p>

<p>6) Plausible Denial, Lane, Mark; Thunder's Mouth Press, N.Y.
l991 (HC) </p>

<p>7) Act Of Treason, <ent type='PERSON'>North</ent>, Mark; Carroll and <ent type='PERSON'>Graf</ent>, l991 (HC) </p>

<p>8) Spy Saga, Melanson, Philip; Praeger, l990 (HC) </p>

<p>9) <ent type='ORG'>Mafia</ent> Kingfish, Davis, John H.; McGraw Hill, l989, (HC) </p>

<p>DON'T FORGET TO QUESTION AUTHORITY AND SEEK THE TRUTH -
YOURSELF! BE AN ACTIVE PARTICIPANT IN HISTORY AND LIFE AND NOT
JUST A SILENT OBSERVER! WORK TO EXPOSE THE TRUTH IN THE <ent type='PERSON'>JFK</ent>,<ent type='PERSON'>RFK</ent>,
<ent type='PERSON'>MLK</ent> AND OTHER <ent type='ORG'>ASSASSIN</ent>ATIONS AND THE VARIETY OF 'BLACK'
OPERATIONS WHICH HAVE THREATENED AND ARE THREATENING OUR
DEMOCRACY AND BROUGHT US TO THE BRINK OF FASCISM AS WELL AS
MORAL, FINAN<ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>L AND ENVIRONMENTAL BANKRUPTCY IN AMERICA! IF YOU
DO NOT <ent type='ORG'>ACTIVELY</ent> WORK TO PRESERVE YOUR RIGHTS AND FREEDOMS AND OUR
DEMOCRACY, REMEMBER - SOMEONE ELSE WILL BE <ent type='ORG'>ACTIVELY</ent> WORKING TO
DESTROY THEM! </p>

</xml>