<xml>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>ANNOTATED</ent> BIBLIOGRAPHY
OF
BOOKS CONCERNING SOVIET STATE SECURITY
by <ent type='PERSON'>Charles Trew Burke</ent>, Virginia </p>

<p> The following is a short collection of books concerning,
either directly or indirectly, <ent type='ORG'>the Soviet Committee for</ent> State
Security (<ent type='PERSON'>Komitet Gosudarstvennoy Bezopasnosti</ent>, or <ent type='ORG'>KGB</ent>).
All of the books were written during the 1980's and are
arranged alphabetically by author or editor.
The list is not intended to be comprehensive. The list
contains a wide range of authors. Among the group are scholars,
government officials (active and retired), <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> bloc defectors,
and other people in positions that afford them the ability to
provide information on the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> state security apparatus. Some
of the works deal only with the <ent type='ORG'>KGB</ent>. Others deal primarily
with other topics yet, still provide insightful commentary on a
specific topic concerning the <ent type='ORG'>KGB</ent>. </p>

<p> INTRODUCTION</p>

<p> During the late spring of 1989, at the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent> of
People's Deputies, former weight lifter <ent type='PERSON'>Yuri Vlasov</ent> made one of
the harshest attacks on <ent type='ORG'>the Soviet Committee for</ent> State Security
(<ent type='ORG'>KGB</ent>) in recent memory.
<ent type='PERSON'>Vlasov</ent>, whose father disappeared in 1953, stated live on
<ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> television: "This service sowed grief, cries, torture on
its native land...The democratic renewal in the country has not
changed the position of the <ent type='ORG'>KGB</ent> in the political system." <ent type='PERSON'>Vlasov</ent>
also made a number of other emotional and dramatic charges during
his speech. At the conclusion of his remarks, the hall gave him
an extended ovation.
The incident is, indeed, evidence of how far political
changes have come to the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> Union. A very short time ago,
Vlasov's comments would have placed him in very serious trouble.
Yet, <ent type='PERSON'>Vlasov</ent> is quite correct that the <ent type='ORG'>KGB</ent> has retained its power
and privileged postion in the <ent type='GPE'>USSR</ent>.
The organization that is now the <ent type='ORG'>KGB</ent> has undergone a
number of reorganizations and name changes since the inception of
the <ent type='ORG'>Cheka</ent> on December 7 (or 20), 1917. Although the organization
was supposed to be temporary, the <ent type='ORG'>Cheka</ent> and its successors (the
<ent type='ORG'>GPU</ent>, O<ent type='ORG'>GPU</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>GUGB</ent>, NKVD, N<ent type='ORG'>KGB</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>MGB</ent>, and now the <ent type='ORG'>KGB</ent>) have remained
a key element in the administration of internal and external
policies of the <ent type='GPE'>USSR</ent>. Interestingly, members of the <ent type='ORG'>KGB</ent> still
call themselves <ent type='ORG'>Chekists</ent> in recognition of a hallowed tradition.
Despite the widespread public recognition of the
organization's existence, few, even in the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> field,
comprehend the full role of the <ent type='ORG'>KGB</ent> in <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> society. Most
frequently the <ent type='ORG'>KGB</ent> is compared to the <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> Central
Intelligence Agency (<ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>). However, the scope of activities
carried out by the <ent type='ORG'>KGB</ent> include the functions that are carried out
in <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States by at least a dozen Federal agencies.</p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>ANNOTATED</ent> BIBLIOGRAPHY
OF
BOOKS CONCERNING SOVIET STATE SECURITY
by <ent type='PERSON'>Charles Trew Burke</ent>, Virginia</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Barron</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>John</ent>. <ent type='ORG'>KGB</ent> Today. <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent>: Reader's Digest, 1983. 489 pp.
Contains photographs and index. </p>

<p> <ent type='PERSON'>Barron</ent>, an editor at Reader's Digest, has written a number
of articles and books on the <ent type='ORG'>KGB</ent>. He has benefitted enormously
from <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> cooperation on his books. His access to government
officials and documents, and a number of <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> defectors, has
allowed him to put together two of the best-selling works ever on
the <ent type='ORG'>KGB</ent> (his previous work was <ent type='ORG'>KGB</ent> published in 1974 by Reader's
Digest).
Aside from providing a wealth of information, <ent type='PERSON'>Barron</ent>
writes in a style that is to easy read. He dosen't get too
technical for the non-specialist or place footnotes everywhere.
For this work, <ent type='PERSON'>Barron</ent> worked extensively with Stanislav
<ent type='PERSON'>Levchenko</ent>, a former <ent type='ORG'>KGB</ent> Major who defected while on operational
assignment in <ent type='GPE'>Japan</ent> in the late 1970's (<ent type='PERSON'>Levchenko</ent> has also been
involved in two other works that will be discussed further on). </p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Corson</ent>, William R. and <ent type='PERSON'>Robert</ent> T. <ent type='PERSON'>Crowley</ent>. The New <ent type='ORG'>KGB</ent>. <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent>:
<ent type='PERSON'>William Morrow</ent> and Company, Inc., 1985. Contains index and
photographs. 560 pp.</p>

<p> Both authors are retired <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> intelligence officers.
This work is a very well researched piece which covers many
different periods of <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> state security.
The objective of the work is to present the reader a
"fresh way of looking at the current operations and global
strategies of the new <ent type='ORG'>KGB</ent>." The authors argue that the <ent type='ORG'>KGB</ent> has
taken on a more active role in <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> government and has
increased its dominance in <ent type='ORG'>the Communist Party</ent> of the <ent type='GPE'>USSR</ent>. </p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Dzhirkvelov</ent>, Ilya. Secret Servant. <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent>: Harper &amp; Row,
Publishers, 1987. 398 pp. Contains index. </p>

<p> A fascinating account by a former member of the <ent type='ORG'>KGB</ent> who
defected to the <ent type='LOC'>West</ent> in 1980. <ent type='PERSON'>Dzhirkvelov</ent>, who participated in
many "direct action" operations, is particularly interesting
because he defected for personal reasons and remains unrepentant
for many of his activities. He is still an admirer of Joseph
Stalin, for example, and some of the extermination operations he
participated in against nationalist minorities in the <ent type='GPE'>USSR</ent> after
WWII. A very unusual autobiography. </p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Dziak</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>John</ent> J. Chekisty. <ent type='GPE'>Lexington</ent>, MA: <ent type='GPE'>Lexington</ent> Books, 1988.
234 pp. Contains index. </p>

<p> A very well written historical account by a senior
intelligence official with <ent type='ORG'>the Defense Intelligence Agency</ent> (<ent type='ORG'>DIA</ent>).
The extensive documentation, frequently using <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> materials,
is invaluable. The bibliography is also quite useful.
This hard-hitting work has many classic quotes and
comments including the infamous comment on the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> secret
police by <ent type='PERSON'>Felix Dzerzhinski</ent>, its founder: "We represent in
ourselves organized terror --- this must be said very clearly..."
(interview with B. <ent type='EVENT'>Rossov</ent>, "From Our <ent type='GPE'>Moscow</ent> Correspondent,"
<ent type='PERSON'>Novaya Zhizhin</ent>,' June 9, 1918, p. 4). Highly recommended work. </p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Knight</ent>, Amy W. the <ent type='ORG'>KGB</ent>. <ent type='GPE'>Boston</ent>: Unwin Hyman, 1988. 348 pp.
Contains index.</p>

<p> An excellent scholarly work by a senior analyst with the
Congrssional Research Service of the Library of <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>.
The focus of the work is the politcal role of the <ent type='ORG'>KGB</ent> in
the government of the <ent type='GPE'>USSR</ent>. This work is very rich in
documentation and detail and is definately more for a specialist.
Other readers may find the work rough going. Researchers will
find this work invaluable and very well balanced. Highly
recommended work. </p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Leggett</ent>, George. The <ent type='ORG'>Cheka</ent>: Lenin's Political Police. <ent type='ORG'>Oxford</ent>:
Clarendon Press, 1981 (reprinted with corrections as
paperback, 1986). 514 pp. With index.</p>

<p> This piece is a masterwork of research by a <ent type='NORP'>British</ent>
scholar. This book is one of the best works ever on the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent>
secret police, certainly on the <ent type='ORG'>Cheka</ent>. Totally comprehensive and
"must reading" for information on the beginnings of <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> state
security.</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Levchenko</ent>, Stanislav. On the Wrong Side. <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>: Pergammon-Brassey's, 1988. 244 pp. </p>

<p> <ent type='PERSON'>Levchenko</ent> was a member of <ent type='ORG'>the First Chief Directorate</ent> of
the <ent type='ORG'>KGB</ent> (Foreign Operations) working in <ent type='GPE'>Japan</ent>. This book is his
autobiography and covers the early years of his life and career
up to his defection to <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States in 1979.
This work is very <ent type='NORP'>Russian</ent> and emotional in style. While
telling the reader about his life and career, <ent type='PERSON'>Levchenko</ent>
effectively illustrates the difficuly and strains of conflicting
loyalties and beliefs. </p>

<div> </div>

<p><ent type='ORG'>Pacepa</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Ion Mihai</ent>. <ent type='ORG'>Red Horizons</ent>. <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>: Regnery Gateway,
1987. 446 pp. With index and photographs.</p>

<p> A controversial work by a <ent type='NORP'>Romanian</ent> spymaster who defected
to <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States in 1978. <ent type='ORG'>Pacepa</ent> had held a number of
exteremely sensitive positions in the <ent type='NORP'>Romanian</ent> Securitate. One of
his duties included directing the personal security of <ent type='NORP'>Romanian</ent>
President <ent type='PERSON'>Nicolae Ceusescu</ent>. His defection accelerated a massive
purge being conducted in the <ent type='NORP'>Romanian</ent> Communist Party by
President <ent type='PERSON'>Ceusescu</ent>. <ent type='ORG'>Pacepa</ent> was debriefed by the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> on a full-time basis for three years following his defection.
His remarks on the turbulent <ent type='NORP'>Romanian</ent>-<ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> relationship
and <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> control mechanisms over <ent type='ORG'>Warsaw Pact</ent> allies are
insightful.


<ent type='ORG'>Richelson</ent>, Jeffrey T. Sword and Shield. <ent type='GPE'>Cambridge</ent>, MA: Ballinger
Publishing Co., 1986. 279 pp.</p>

<p> The author, a professor from the <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent> DC area, has
written a number of works on intelligence matters.
Compared to some of the other works available on the <ent type='ORG'>KGB</ent>,
this work has pretty shallow research behind it. In a number of
areas, up to 20 footnotes will be taken up using only two, maybe
three different sources. Non-specialists may, however, find the
work an easier read than some of the more thoroughly researched
books. </p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Rocca</ent>, Raymond G. and <ent type='PERSON'>John</ent> J. <ent type='PERSON'>Dziak</ent>. Bibliography of <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent>
Intelligence and Security Services. Boulder, CO: <ent type='LOC'>West</ent>view
Press, 1985. 203 pp. With index. </p>

<p> An indispensible tool for researching the <ent type='ORG'>KGB</ent> and its
cousins. The work covers other bibliographies, <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> accounts,
Defector/First Hand accounts, <ent type='ORG'>Second Hand</ent> accounts, and
government materials. This is another "must have" work. </p>

<p><ent type='GPE'>Rommerstein</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Herbert</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Stanislav Levchenko</ent>. The <ent type='ORG'>KGB</ent> Against
Main Enemy. <ent type='GPE'>Lexington</ent>, MA: <ent type='GPE'>Lexington</ent> Books, 1989. 369 pp.
With index.

<ent type='GPE'>Rommerstein</ent> was recently director of <ent type='ORG'>the Office</ent> to Counter
<ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> Active Measures and Disinformation at the US Information
Agency. This work, by two intelligence professionals, traces the
history of <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> intelligence operations against the Glavny
Vrag, or Main Enemy, as the US is called in <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> intelligence
literature.
The work covers both old and new ground. The authors were
able to successfully dig up some new information on past events
through <ent type='ORG'>the Freedom</ent> of Information Act. The book also includes
material on events in the late 1980's.


<ent type='PERSON'>Sharansky</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Natan</ent> (Anatoly). Fear No Evil. <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent>: Random House,
1988. 437 pp. Contains index and photographs. </p>

<p> This is the memior from one of the most well-known of the
<ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> refuseniks and dissidents. Sharansky's dislike of the <ent type='ORG'>KGB</ent>
is matched only by the dislike of the <ent type='ORG'>KGB</ent> toward him. The book is
a dramatic testament from an intense, determined man.
The work is useful because of the unique view it gives of
some of the KGB's internal roles. <ent type='PERSON'>Sharansky</ent> also has a very
articulate and effective writing style.</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Shevchenko</ent>, Arkady. Breaking With <ent type='GPE'>Moscow</ent>. <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent>: Alfred A.
<ent type='ORG'>Knopf</ent>, 1985. 378 pp. With index.</p>

<p> <ent type='PERSON'>Shevchenko</ent> was serving as under Secretary-General of the
United Nations during the 1970's when he agreed to spy for the
United States. He later defected.
Because of Shevchenko's senior diplomatic position, he has
information to provide in a number of areas. One area is <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent>
intelligence operations. <ent type='PERSON'>Shevchenko</ent>, and most other <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent>
employees at the UN, had to preform duties for the <ent type='ORG'>KGB</ent>. Because
of his senior position, <ent type='PERSON'>Shevchenko</ent> had regular contact with the
top <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> security personnel in <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>. </p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Wise</ent>, David. The Spy Who Got Away. <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent>: Random House, 1988.
288 pp. With index and photographs.</p>

<p> <ent type='PERSON'>Wise</ent> is a journalist with a number of articles and books
on intelligence matters to his credit. In this book <ent type='PERSON'>Wise</ent> analyzes
the <ent type='PERSON'>Edward Lee Howard</ent> affair. <ent type='PERSON'>Howard</ent> was an employee of the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>
being trained to run US agents in <ent type='GPE'>Moscow</ent>. The <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> discovered that
<ent type='PERSON'>Howard</ent> had lied about his personal life, specifically his drug
use and past thefts. <ent type='PERSON'>Howard</ent> was fired and then retaliated by
passing information to the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent>s. He later made a rare US
defection to the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> Union shortly before he was to be
arrested by the <ent type='ORG'>FBI</ent>.
<ent type='PERSON'>Wise</ent> was actually able, with <ent type='ORG'>KGB</ent> permission, to interview
<ent type='PERSON'>Howard</ent> in <ent type='GPE'>Budapest</ent>, Hungary (around the same time <ent type='NORP'>British</ent>
espionage journalist Phillip <ent type='PERSON'>Knight</ent>ly was allowed to interview
<ent type='PERSON'>Kim Philby</ent> in <ent type='GPE'>Moscow</ent>). <ent type='PERSON'>Wise</ent> also reveals very interesting details
of <ent type='ORG'>FBI</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> counterintelligence operations. A good story. </p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Wright</ent>, Peter. Spy Catcher. <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent>: <ent type='ORG'>Viking Penguin</ent>, Inc., 1987.
392 pp. With index and photographs.

The highly controversial memior from a former MI5 official
that the <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> government tried desperately (and
unsuccessfully) to prevent from being published. The book is a
treasure trove of accounts of <ent type='NORP'>American</ent>, <ent type='NORP'>British</ent>, and <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent>
intelligence operations. The intrigues and conspiricies run wild
in this one. </p></xml>