<xml><p> COINCIDENCE OR THE <ent type='ORG'>KISS</ent> OF DEATH?
Copyright (c) 1993 by <ent type='PERSON'>Linda</ent> D. Thompson, All Rights Reserved.
AEN News, Fidonet 1:231/110, BBS line 317-881-2743, Voice: 317-780-5204</p>

<p> In investigating events surrounding the massacre at <ent type='GPE'>Waco</ent>, I have
made some rather startling discoveries. For instance, I discovered that
three of the four <ent type='ORG'>ATF</ent> agents killed during the initial seige at <ent type='GPE'>Waco</ent> had
been <ent type='PERSON'>Bill Clinton</ent>'s bodyguards during his presidential campaign. Film
footage from the initial seige (which can be seen in the video tape,
"<ent type='GPE'>Waco</ent>, the Big Lie"), shows an <ent type='ORG'>ATF</ent> agent throwing a grenade and shooting
a machine gun into the room where three other <ent type='ORG'>ATF</ent> agents have just
entered a window. In other words, this footage appears to show that these
agents were assasinated. In the March 3, 1993, <ent type='ORG'>Dallas Morning</ent> News, all
three of the agents who went into the window on the roof of the Branch
Davidian house at Mt. <ent type='ORG'>Carmel</ent> were reported by the <ent type='ORG'>ATF</ent> to have been
killed inside. This certainly seemed curious, as did the connections to
<ent type='GPE'>Waco</ent> of numerous highly placed government officials. <ent type='ORG'>Curiouser</ent> and
curiouser.
A former <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> agent and a former <ent type='ORG'>FBI</ent> agent both told me to begin
checking into the body count around <ent type='PERSON'>Hillary</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Bill Clinton</ent>, during
Clinton's rise to governor of <ent type='GPE'>Arkansas</ent> and since he has become
President. With just a little preliminary research of the period just
prior to the election through the present, I found 21 people who
<ent type='PERSON'>Clinton</ent> knew personally, many of whom he knew intimately, and several
who had been his escorts or bodyguards, all of whom had died under
mysterious circumstances or been ki "accidental" airplane or helicopter
crashes:
CLINTON BODY COUNT</p>

<p>(Not including 96 Branch Davidians murdered in <ent type='GPE'>Waco</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Texas</ent>, Feb. 28,
1993 through April 19, 1993):</p>

<p>PEOPLE WHO KNOW WHERE THE MONEY COMES FROM:</p>

<p>+ 2 July 30, 1992, C. Victor Raiser II, 52, the national
finance co-chairman of the <ent type='PERSON'>Clinton</ent> for President campaign, and his son,
R. Montgomery Raiser, 22, were among five (5) people killed July 30 in a
crash of a private plane near <ent type='GPE'>Dillingham</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Alaska</ent>. <ent type='PERSON'>Vincent Raiser</ent> was a
past national finance chairman of <ent type='ORG'>the Democratic National Committee</ent>, and
he served on the boards of <ent type='ORG'>the Democratic Business Council</ent> and the
Center for National Policy and the board of advisers of the Democratic
Leadership Counc native of <ent type='NORP'>Indianapolis</ent>, he graduated from Princeton
University and received a law degree from <ent type='ORG'>the University</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>Virginia</ent>. He
worked in <ent type='GPE'>Buffalo</ent> before moving to <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent> in 1979. He was a
specialist in communications and corporate law and consultant to the law
firm of <ent type='ORG'>Jones Day</ent> Reavis &amp; <ent type='PERSON'>Pogue</ent> until 1991. He was chairman of the
<ent type='NORP'>American</ent> Mobile Satellite Corp., a telecommunications development
company in <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, and vice chairman of Mobile Telecommunication
Technologies Corp. of Jackso n, Miss., a pagin g and voice messaging
company. Its main subsidiary in <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent> is SkyTel Corp., a paging
company. [Reported in OBITUARIES, "D.C. Lawyer C.V. Raiser II And Son
Die," The <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent> Post, August 01, 1992, FINAL Edition, Section:
METRO, p. b07.]</p>

<p>+ 1 July 21, 1993 (<ent type='GPE'>UPI</ent>): <ent type='PERSON'>Vincent Foster</ent>, A top legal aide to
President <ent type='PERSON'>Clinton</ent> was announced to have "committed suicide in a park
outside <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>," by <ent type='ORG'>the White House</ent>.
In a statement, <ent type='ORG'>White House</ent> press secretary <ent type='PERSON'>Dee Dee Myers</ent> said
<ent type='PERSON'>Vince Foster</ent> Jr., 48, <ent type='ORG'>the White House</ent> deputy counsel, was found dead in
a suburban <ent type='GPE'>Virginia</ent> park, apparently killed by a self-inflicted gunshot
wound. <ent type='PERSON'>Foster</ent>, originally from Hope, Ark., like <ent type='PERSON'>Clinton</ent>, had come to
<ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent> from the law firm of <ent type='PERSON'>Hillary</ent> Rodham <ent type='PERSON'>Clinton</ent>.
No note was found near the body, which was discovered by local
authorities in Fort Marcy Park, near <ent type='GPE'>Fairfax</ent>, Va., officials said, nor
was any possible reason <ent type='PERSON'>Foster</ent> might have taken his life put forward.
<ent type='PERSON'>Foster</ent> most recently was involved in the administration's
so-called <ent type='ORG'>Travelgate</ent> scandal, involving the abrupt firing of seven
longtime employees from <ent type='ORG'>the White House</ent> travel office and the hiring of
a distant cousin of Clinton's.
An internal investigation by <ent type='ORG'>White House</ent> chief of staff Thomas
McLarty documented Foster's involvement in the process, which included
contacts with the first lady on the subject of possible criminal
wrongdoing. But <ent type='PERSON'>Foster</ent> was not among the four <ent type='ORG'>White House</ent> staffers
reprimanded for their roles in the dismissals.
<ent type='PERSON'>Foster</ent> was among those responsible for initiating a private
audit, then an <ent type='ORG'>FBI</ent> investigation of the matter. [Also reported in "Park
Police To Conduct Inquiry 'Routine' Probe Set On Foster's Death," The
<ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent> Post, July 27, 1993, FINAL Edition By: <ent type='PERSON'>Michael Isikoff</ent>,
<ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent> Post Staff Writer, Section: A SECTION, p. a08.]
<ent type='PERSON'>Foster</ent> was purportedly speaking with an Editor at a <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>
newspaper prior to his death. He was found shot in the back of the head
with a 1913 Colt .38 revolver which he did not own. The revolver had no
serial number, even though all Colt revolvers since the late 1800's have
had serial numbers except a special series issued to the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>. <ent type='PERSON'>Foster</ent>
advised the Clinton's on their finances. There are presently at least
two bank scandals that are emerging from <ent type='GPE'>Little Rock</ent> <ent type='GPE'>Arkansas</ent>, involving
banks in which the <ent type='PERSON'>Clinton</ent>s have an interest. Additionally, it is now
well established that gun and drug running out of <ent type='ORG'>Mena</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Arkansas</ent>, via
CIA's <ent type='ORG'>Evergreen Aviation</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Pat Foley</ent>'s <ent type='ORG'>Summit Aviataion</ent> has fuelled
political coffers for sometime, as the beneficiaries turned a blind eye.
Perhaps <ent type='PERSON'>Foster</ent> was privy to this information, among others.</p>

<p>+ 1 June 22, 1993, the partially decomposed body of <ent type='PERSON'>Paul Wilcher</ent>, a
49-year-old investigative lawyer, was found on a toilet in his Capitol
Hill apartment in <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, D.C. At the time of his death, he was
investigating the "October Surprise" conspiracy during the 1980 federal
election campaign. He had been interviewing an inmate who claimed to
have piloted <ent type='PERSON'>George Bush</ent> to <ent type='GPE'>Paris</ent> so he could secretly seek to delay the
release of 52 <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> hostages in <ent type='GPE'>Iran</ent>. [Reported in the "<ent type='ORG'>Autopsies</ent>
delayed as body count rises," The <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent> Times, Thursday, July 15,
1993, By: <ent type='PERSON'>Brian Reilly</ent> - Edition: Final Section: A Page: A1.] Not
mentioned in this article are other facts. Prior to his death, <ent type='PERSON'>Wilcher</ent>
had recently spoken with <ent type='PERSON'>John Parsons</ent>, a producer of syndicated
television programs, about making a documentary of his findings. He had
also spoken with <ent type='PERSON'>John Vassillos</ent>, the attorney for <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> operative Mike
Riconosciuto. Riconosciuto claims he was involved in a web of
underworld, <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>, and <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> of Justice dealings, revealed in
allegations brought by a computer company called <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> Inc. that the
Justice <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> had st s software product, "Promis," then driven the
firm into bankruptcy and that the program had been sold to countries all
over the world by persons affiliated with then attorney-general Ed
Meese. Riconosciuto says that the program was provided to <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent>
Corp. of <ent type='ORG'>Coral Gables</ent>, FL, and that <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> hired 50 of the world's
top programmers to modify the code of the software at the <ent type='NORP'>Southern</ent>
<ent type='GPE'>California</ent> Cabazon <ent type='NORP'>Indian</ent> reservation. Riconosciuto also has detailed
his involvement in gun running and drug dealing conducted out of <ent type='ORG'>Mena</ent>,
<ent type='GPE'>Arkansas</ent>. <ent type='PERSON'>Danny Casalero</ent>, 44, a reporter who was investigating the
<ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> scandall and had spoken with Riconosciuto, was found murdered in
a hotel bathtub in Washing C. in 1991, the day after telling friends and
family that was about to receive material that would provide him with
documentation linking <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> to October Surprise and the <ent type='GPE'>Iran</ent>-Contra
scandals. <ent type='PERSON'>Paul Wilcher</ent> was also investigating these same links, as well
as their connection to the deaths of the <ent type='ORG'>ATF</ent> agents and Branch Davidians
at Mt. <ent type='ORG'>Carmel</ent> at the time of his own death.</p>

<p>THE USS DEATHSHIP (a/k/a USS ROOSEVELT):</p>

<p> Both the Carrier <ent type='PERSON'>Roosevelt</ent> and the 1st <ent type='ORG'>Armored Division</ent> figure
prominantly in a "<ent type='ORG'>Nato</ent> Peacekeeping Plan" for <ent type='GPE'>Serbia</ent>/<ent type='GPE'>Bosnia</ent>. Both also
figure prominantly in three separate crashes, killing more than a dozen
people associated with <ent type='PERSON'>Clinton</ent> [Reported in "All Plans Include Key <ent type='ORG'>Navy</ent>
Role <ent type='GPE'>Virginia</ent>n-Pilot" (<ent type='GPE'>Norfolk</ent>, VA) (VP) - Saturday, May 8, 1993, By:
Phyllis W. Jordan, Edition: FINAL Section: FRONT Page: A8.] And
interestingly, the commanders of both the <ent type='PERSON'>Roosevelt</ent> and the 1st Armored
Division either die re replaced in late February or early March, 1993,
as did personnel involved in escorting or guarding <ent type='PERSON'>Clinton</ent> on the
Carrier <ent type='PERSON'>Roosevelt</ent>:</p>

<p>+ 4 February 23, 1993: Maj. Gen. Jarrett J. Robertson, 52, the
deputy commanding general of V Corps, died when an <ent type='ORG'>Army</ent> UH-60 <ent type='ORG'>Blackhawk</ent>
helicopter crashed as it attempted to land at <ent type='GPE'>Wiesbaden</ent> air base
February 23, 1993. V Corps is an armored force headquartered in nearby
<ent type='GPE'>Frankfurt</ent>, and is the U.S. Army's chief combat component in Europe which
currently has troops in <ent type='GPE'>Somalia</ent> and a medical unit in <ent type='GPE'>Croatia</ent>. Also
killed were Col. William J. Densberger, 47, the corps' chief of
operations and plans; Col. Robert J. Kelly, 48, its chief of
intelligence; and <ent type='ORG'>Spec</ent>. Gary L. Rhodes, 23, the helicopter crew chief.
The officers were returning from a meeting at the U.S. European Command
headquarters in <ent type='GPE'>Stuttgart</ent> when their <ent type='ORG'>Blackhawk</ent> fell suddenly to the
ground not far from the <ent type='GPE'>Wiesbaden</ent> air base's control tower and burst
into flames.[Reported in "U.S. General, Aides Die in Helicopter Crash in
<ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent>," The <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent> Post, February 25, 1993, FINAL Edition, By:
<ent type='ORG'>Spec</ent>ial to The <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent> Po st, Section: A SECTION, p. a14.]</p>

<p> And we now have the entire U.S. 1st <ent type='ORG'>Armored Division</ent>, in this
same European Command, under the direct control of a <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> general.</p>

<p> On March 2, 1993, Rear Adm. L.E. <ent type='PERSON'>Allen</ent> Jr. relieved Rear Adm.
Frederick L. Lewis as commanding officer of <ent type='ORG'>Carrier Group</ent> 4 and
Commander Carrier Striking Force on March 2, 1993, in <ent type='GPE'>Norfolk</ent>, Va.
(which includes the USS <ent type='PERSON'>Roosevelt</ent>). <ent type='PERSON'>Allen</ent> was formerly stationed in
<ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, D.C., where he served as deputy director for operations on
<ent type='ORG'>the Joint Chiefs</ent> of Staff. Lewis was reassigned to a land job as
commander of <ent type='ORG'>Naval Doctrine</ent> Command, which later became operational on
March 12. [Reported in "COMMAND C " <ent type='ORG'>VIRGINIAN</ent>-PILOT (<ent type='GPE'>Norfolk</ent>, VA) (VP)
- Tuesday, March 2, 1993, Edition: FINAL Section: LOCAL Page: D4].</p>

<p>+ 5 March 25, 1993: Five <ent type='ORG'>Navy</ent> aviators were lost at sea at 7 p.m.,
Thursday, March 25, 1993, when their E-2C Hawkeye early warning plane
crashed into the sea while attempting to return to the aircraft carrier
USS Theodore <ent type='PERSON'>Roosevelt</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Navy</ent> officials said yesterday. <ent type='EVENT'>Hours</ent> earlier,
the <ent type='PERSON'>Roosevelt</ent> had arrived in <ent type='LOC'>the Ionian Sea</ent> on a six-month European
deployment. The carrier's air wing had just completed its first
operational mission, flying night combat air patrol off the <ent type='NORP'>Yugoslav</ent>
coast, while <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent>-based U.S. cargo planes dropped food to besieged
<ent type='NORP'>Muslims</ent> in <ent type='GPE'>Bosnia</ent>. [Reported in "Five <ent type='ORG'>Navy</ent> Fliers Lost at Sea," The
<ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent> Post, March 27, 1993, Final Edition, By: <ent type='PERSON'>Barton Gellman</ent>,
<ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent> Post Staff Writer, Section: A, p. A24.]</p>

<p> These five men had been escorts for President <ent type='PERSON'>Clinton</ent> when he
visited the Carrier <ent type='PERSON'>Roosevelt</ent>.</p>

<p>+ 4 May 19, 1993: On May 21, 1993, <ent type='ORG'>the Marine Corps</ent> grounded its
entire presidential fleet of nine VH-60N helicopters pending the outcome
of the investigation of a crash involving one of the presidential fleet
helicopters, a VH-60N <ent type='ORG'>Blackhawk</ent> helicopter that went down in a heavily
wooded area near <ent type='LOC'>the Potomac River</ent> about 35 miles southwest of
<ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent> on May 19, 1993. Killed in the crash were Maj. William S.
<ent type='PERSON'>Barkley</ent>, Jr., Staff Sgt. Brian D. <ent type='ORG'>Haney</ent>, and Sgt. Timothy D. <ent type='ORG'>Sabel</ent>, and
Capt. Scott J. <ent type='PERSON'>Reynolds</ent>.</p>

<p> Maj. <ent type='PERSON'>Barkley</ent>, 27, of <ent type='GPE'>Hickory</ent>, N.C. became a naval aviator in 1977
and was assigned to the presidential squadron in January 1990. He was
one of only eight pilots in the squadron authorized to fly the
president, according to Betty Jo Bragg, longtime secretary to Barkley's
father.
Sgt. Timothy D. <ent type='ORG'>Sabel</ent>, 27, of Ripon, Wis., was "responsible for
the maintenance of the airplane. He goes on all flights," said Master
Sgt. <ent type='PERSON'>Paul Earle</ent>, a <ent type='ORG'>Marine</ent> spokesman at <ent type='GPE'>Quantico</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Virginia</ent> (which is also
<ent type='ORG'>FBI</ent> headquarters).
Staff Sgt. Brian D. <ent type='ORG'>Haney</ent>, 32, of <ent type='PERSON'>North</ent> <ent type='GPE'>Ridgeville</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Ohio</ent>, was the
quality assurance representative on the helicopter. Carolyn <ent type='ORG'>Haney</ent>, his
mother, said her son had flown with President <ent type='PERSON'>George Bush</ent> to Europe and
in the presidential campaign "all over <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States."
Capt. Scott J. <ent type='PERSON'>Reynolds</ent>, 33, of <ent type='GPE'>Wausau</ent>, Wis., joined the <ent type='ORG'>Marine</ent>s
in 1984, was designated a naval aviator in 1987 and was a veteran of the
Persian Gulf War
<ent type='PERSON'>Clinton</ent> had flown once on that particular craft, according to
<ent type='ORG'>White House</ent> spokeswoman <ent type='PERSON'>Dee Dee Myers</ent>. That flight took the president to
the aircraft carrier USS Theodore <ent type='PERSON'>Roosevelt</ent> off the <ent type='GPE'>Virginia</ent> coast in
March, she said. [Reported in "<ent type='ORG'>Marine</ent>s identify crash victims,"
<ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent> Times, Saturday, May 22, 1993, Edition: Final Section:
METROPOLITAN LOCAL ROUNDUP MARYLAND, page A11; "<ent type='GPE'>Charles County</ent>
helicopter crash kills 4 <ent type='ORG'>Marine</ent>s," Thursday, May 20, 1993, By: Jim
Keary, <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent> Times, Edition: Final Section: METROPOLITAN Page: B4;
"Helicopter fleet is grounded," Friday, May 21, 1993, <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent> Times,
Edition: Final Section: METROPOLITAN LOCAL ROUNDUP, MARYLAND, Page: B2;
"9 <ent type='ORG'>White House</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Copters Grounded</ent> As Crash Victims Are <ent type='GPE'>Mourned</ent>," May 21,
1993, FINAL Edition, By: Eugene L. Meyer, The <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent> Post, Section:
METRO, <ent type='ORG'>Story Type</ent>: News <ent type='GPE'>Maryland</ent>, p. D01.]
Notice, above, that the President's escorts during Clinton's one
visit to the Carrier <ent type='PERSON'>Roosevelt</ent> on March 12, 1993, were all later killed
in a plane crash, too.</p>

<p>More Bodyguards:</p>

<p>+ 4 February 28, 1993. In the initial assault on Mt. <ent type='ORG'>Carmel</ent> in
<ent type='GPE'>Waco</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Texas</ent>, four agents of <ent type='ORG'>the Bureau</ent> of Alcohol, Tobacco and Firearms
were killed. Those killed in the attack were : <ent type='PERSON'>Steve Willis</ent>, 32, of
<ent type='GPE'>Houston</ent>; Robert J. Williams, 26, <ent type='GPE'>Little Rock</ent>, Ark.; Conway LeBleu, 30,
<ent type='GPE'>New Orleans</ent>; and Todd McKeehan, 28, <ent type='GPE'>New Orleans</ent>. [Reported in "UPDATE:
AT LEAST FIVE DEAD, 15 INJURED IN TWO SHOOTOUTS AT <ent type='GPE'>TEXAS</ent> CULT COMPOUND
WACO, <ent type='GPE'>TEXAS</ent>," MARCH 1, 1993, <ent type='GPE'>UPI</ent>.]
President <ent type='PERSON'>Clinton</ent> himself revealed that these men had been his
bodyguards in a speech on March 18, 1993, before employees of the
Treasury <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent>:
"My prayers and I'm sure yours are still with the families of
all four of <ent type='ORG'>the Alcohol</ent>, Tobacco and Firearms agents who were killed in
<ent type='GPE'>Waco</ent> -- Todd McKeehan and Conway Le Bleu of <ent type='GPE'>New Orleans</ent>; <ent type='PERSON'>Steve Willis</ent> of
<ent type='GPE'>Houston</ent>, and <ent type='PERSON'>Robert Williams</ent> from my hometown of <ent type='GPE'>Little Rock</ent>. Three of
those four were assigned to my security during the course of the primary
or general election." ["REMARKS BY THE PRESIDENT TO EMPLOYEES OF THE
TREASURY DEPARTMENT," The Cash Room, Treasury <ent type='ORG'>Department</ent>, March 18,
1993, 11:48 A.M. EST.]</p>

<p>21 - Total confirmed deaths of persons connected to <ent type='PERSON'>Clinton</ent> in the past
year. (I have not included people who were also killed in the crashes
with whom there is no confirmed link at this time, such as the three
persons who were killed in the same crash as <ent type='PERSON'>Vincent Raiser</ent> and his
son). All of these people died of unnatural causes. Four were shot, 17
were killed in crashes of helicopters or airplanes.
The statistical probabilities of <ent type='PERSON'>Clinton</ent> knowing 21 people, all
of whom died either in accidents or under mysterious circumstances in
less than a year's time, is virtually zero.</p>

<p> And Where Do These Guys Fit In:</p>

<p>+ 3 July 21, 1993, (AP): Three <ent type='GPE'>Texas</ent> National <ent type='ORG'>Guard</ent>smen, reportedly
mistaken for pop-up targets, were shot to death by fellow soldiers
Wednesday during a night vision training exercise.
"They were hit by fire from other soldiers," said Lt. Col. Ed
<ent type='PERSON'>Komandosky</ent>, a spokesman at <ent type='ORG'>Guard</ent> headquarters in <ent type='GPE'>Austin</ent>. <ent type='PERSON'>Komandosky</ent>
said the victims were members of the 3rd Battalion, 141st Infantry of
the <ent type='GPE'>Texas</ent> National <ent type='ORG'>Guard</ent> in Mc<ent type='PERSON'>Allen</ent>, had experience in the training
exercise and "had been in the <ent type='ORG'>Guard</ent> for some time."
Killed were <ent type='PERSON'>Spc</ent>. Daniel F. <ent type='PERSON'>Benitez</ent>, 27, of <ent type='PERSON'>Donna</ent>; <ent type='PERSON'>Spc</ent>. Jose C.
Ramos Jr., 42, of <ent type='PERSON'>Weslaco</ent>; and Sgt. <ent type='PERSON'>Raul Cardenas</ent>, 27, of <ent type='PERSON'>Weslaco</ent> were
pronounced dead at Darnall <ent type='ORG'>Army</ent> Community Hospital in <ent type='GPE'>Killeen</ent>.
Did these people have any connection to the flame-throwing tank
that was used to set the fire at Mt. <ent type='ORG'>Carmel</ent>, in <ent type='GPE'>Waco</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Texas</ent> on April 19,
1993? All of them were <ent type='NORP'>Latinos</ent>. Were they killed in <ent type='LOC'>South America</ent> and
an accident arranged to explain their deaths?</p>

<p>+ 1 Could <ent type='PERSON'>John</ent> A. <ent type='ORG'>Wilson</ent> have known too much about insider politics?
<ent type='PERSON'>John</ent> A. <ent type='ORG'>Wilson</ent>, for 16 years a <ent type='ORG'>City Councilman</ent> in <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, D.C., was
found dead from a supposed suicide. His wife had already left for work
and he was found in his underwear, hanging in his basement, later in the
morning, as if he had awakened, gone to the basement and hung himself.
No suicide note was found.</p>

<p> What is emerging from the research I have conducted is a clear
picture that those who know too much or those who interfere with the one
world government plan, die. Did any of these people know too much? And
what is it that they know or saw? As the information develops, I will
provide updates. Stay tuned.</p>

<p>[<ent type='PERSON'>Linda</ent> Thompson is an attorney in <ent type='NORP'>Indianapolis</ent>, <ent type='NORP'>Indian</ent>a. She is
Chairman of the <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> Justice Federation, a group dedicated to
stopping <ent type='EVENT'>the New World</ent> Order and getting the truth out to the <ent type='NORP'>American</ent>
public. <ent type='PERSON'>Linda</ent> Thompson and the <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> Justice Federation have
produced a videotape, "<ent type='GPE'>Waco</ent>, the Big Lie," which shows that a
flame-throwing tank was used to set the fire at Mt. <ent type='ORG'>Carmel</ent> in <ent type='GPE'>Waco</ent>,
<ent type='GPE'>Texas</ent>, proving that the government murdered the Branch Davidians and
intentionally destroyed the evidence. To obtain a copy of this video,
which is 32 minutes long, send $20 to: <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> Justice Federation, 3850
South Emerson Ave., <ent type='NORP'>Indianapolis</ent>, IN 46203.]</p>

</xml>