<xml><p>Police Forces Keep the Take

The "loot" that's coming back to police forces all over the nation has
redefined law-enforcement success. It now has a dollar sign in front of
it.

For nearly eighteen months, undercover <ent type='GPE'>Arizona</ent> State Troopers worked as
drug couriers driving nearly 13 tons of marijuana from the <ent type='NORP'>Mexican</ent>
border to stash houses around <ent type='GPE'>Tucson</ent>. They hoped to catch the <ent type='NORP'>Mexican</ent>
suppliers and distributors on the <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> side before the dope got on
the streets. // But they overestimated their ability to control the
distribution. Almost every ounce was sold the minute they dropped it at
the houses. // Even though the troopers were responsible for tons of
drugs getting loose in <ent type='GPE'>Tucson</ent>, the man who supervised the setup still
believes it was worthwhile. It was "a success from a cost-benefit
standpoint,'' says former assistant attorney-general <ent type='PERSON'>John Davis</ent>. His
reasoning: It netted 20 arrests and at least $3 million for the state
forfeiture fund.

"That kind of thinking is what frightens me,'' says <ent type='PERSON'>Steve Sherick</ent>, a
<ent type='GPE'>Tucson</ent> attorney. "The government's thirst for dollars is overcoming any
long-range view of what it is supposed to be doing, which is fighting
crime.'' // <ent type='PERSON'>George Terwilliger III</ent>, associate deputy attorney general in
charge of the U.S. Justice Department's program emphasizes that
forfeiture does fight crime, and "we're not at all apologetic about the
fact that we do benefit (financially) from it.'' // In fact, <ent type='PERSON'>Terwilliger</ent>
wrote about how the forfeiture program financially benefits police
departments in the 1991 Police Buyer's Guide of Police Chief Magazine.

Between 1986 and 1990, the U.S. Justice Department generated $1.5
billion from forfeiture and estimates that it will take in $500 million
this year, five times the amount it collected in 1986. // <ent type='GPE'>District</ent>
attorney's offices throughout <ent type='GPE'>Pennsylvania</ent> handled $4.5 million in
forfeitures last year; <ent type='GPE'>Allegheny County</ent> (ED: <ent type='ORG'>Pgh</ent> is in <ent type='GPE'>Allegheny County</ent>)
$218000, and the city of <ent type='GPE'>Pittsburgh</ent>, $191000 -- up from $9000 four
years ago. // Forfeiture pads the smallest towns coffers. In <ent type='GPE'>Lexana</ent>,
Kan, a <ent type='GPE'>Kansas City</ent> suburb of 29000, "we've got about $250000 moving
in court right now,'' says narcotic detective <ent type='PERSON'>Don Crohn</ent>. // Despite the
huge amounts flowing to police departments, there are few public
accounting procedures. Police who get a cut of the federal forfeiture
funds must sign a form saying merely they will use it for "law
enforcement purposes.'' // To <ent type='GPE'>Philadelphia</ent> police that meant new air
conditioning. In <ent type='GPE'>Warren County</ent>, N.J., it meant use of a forfeited yellow
Corvette for the chief assistant prosecutor. //

{At this point in the article there is a picture of three people in
an empty apartment, with the following caption:

<ent type='PERSON'>Judy Mulford</ent>, 31, and her 13-year old twins, <ent type='PERSON'>Chris</ent>, left, and
<ent type='ORG'>Jason</ent>, are down to essentials in their Lake Park, <ent type='GPE'>Fla</ent>., home,
which the government took in 1989 after claiming her husband,
<ent type='PERSON'>Joseph</ent>, stored cocaine there. Neither parent has been
criminally charged, but in April a forfeiture jury said Mrs.
<ent type='ORG'>Mulford</ent> must forfeit the house she bought herself with an
insurance settlement. The <ent type='ORG'>Mulford</ent>s have divorced, and she has
sold most of her belongings to cover legal bills. She's asked
for a new trial and lives in the near-empty house pending a
decision. }</p>

<p>--- Renegade v6-27 Beta
</p>
<p>* Origin: Shark's Mouth 313-658-1110 750 MEGS <ent type='PERSON'>Dual Amiga</ent>/<ent type='ORG'>IBM</ent> (23:313/108)</p></xml>