<xml><p> 28 page printout</p>

<p> Reproducible <ent type='ORG'>Electronic Publishing</ent> can defeat censorship.</p>

<p> This file, its printout, or copies of either
are to be copied and given away, but NOT sold.</p>

<p> Bank of Wisdom, Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
**** ****</p>

<p>Edited by E. <ent type='ORG'>Haldeman</ent>-<ent type='PERSON'>Julius</ent></p>

<p>THE BLACK INTERNATIONAL No. 19</p>

<p> THE FRUITS OF ROMANISM</p>

<p> THE CATHOLIC CHURCH DOES FAR MORE HARM THAN GOOD</p>

<p> by Joseph McCabe</p>

<p> HALDEMAN-JULIUS PUBLICATIONS
GIRARD -- : -- KANSAS</p>

<div> **** ****</div>

<p> CHAPTER</p>

<p> I Progress in <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> and Non-<ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> Countries ..... 1</p>

<p> II The <ent type='ORG'>Black International</ent> always in the Rear .... 8</p>

<p> III The Wicked World Educates <ent type='ORG'>the Church</ent> ......... 14</p>

<p> IV The Contrast of <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent> and Priest-Ruled Countries .. 19</p>

<p> V The Monstrous Attempt to Restore <ent type='LOC'>the Middle Ages</ent> ... 25</p>

<div> **** ****</div>

<p> Chapter I</p>

<p> PROGRESS IN CATHOLIC AND NON-CATHOLIC COUNTRIES</p>

<p> Throughout these ten booklets, in which I have shown that the
<ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>Rome</ent> is the natural ally of the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>, <ent type='NORP'>Japanese</ent>, and
<ent type='NORP'>Italians</ent>, I have asked the reader to see it as primarily a vast
economic corporation, the <ent type='ORG'>Black International</ent>, fighting for
survival, in an age in which educated people despise its doctrines
and all informed people loathe its methods. Whether any, or how
many, of this monstrous regiment of cardinals and bishops, priests
and monks, sincerely believe the medieval sophistication of ancient
<ent type='NORP'>Greek</ent> and oriental superstitions which they profess is here
entirely irrelevant. We are studying <ent type='ORG'>the Church</ent> as an institution
because we are trying to understand its action throughout the
world.</p>

<p> It admits that it seeks wealth and power but insists that this
is only in order that it may more effectively promote what it calls
the spiritual and eternal interests of men. With that pretext also </p>

<p> Bank of Wisdom
Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
1
.
THE FRUITS OF ROMANISM</p>

<p>we are not concerned. The apologist will hardly expect us to admit
that it entered into an alliance with (in this order) <ent type='GPE'>Italy</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Japan</ent>,
and <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y because it believed they would help it to look after
the soul's of men. Such a plea would raise a broad grin from
<ent type='GPE'>Cologne</ent> to <ent type='GPE'>Tokyo</ent>. Those nations sought wealth and power; so did the
Bleak International. They meant to secure and protect this wealth
and power by a regime of bloody tyranny; and the <ent type='LOC'>Black</ent>
International, which has for 800 years relied upon that method,
needed it more urgently than ever. The bandits wanted the
international influence of the Vatican to help to dupe the world
about their designs; and they promised it a very large share of the
spoils of victory by annihilating its critic's and recovering its
lost provinces for it.</p>

<p> After what we have seen that is as obvious as the Empire State
Building. Men of the <ent type='GPE'>Munich</ent> mentality as regards <ent type='ORG'>the Church</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>Rome</ent>
petulantly exclaim that it is a monstrous charge. Yes: and the war
and the Pope's share in it, the debasement of <ent type='GPE'>France</ent> by priest-ridden traitors, and the horrors of the <ent type='NORP'>Spanish</ent> and <ent type='NORP'>Portuguese</ent> hell
are a monstrous reality. If these narrow-minded folk who think
themselves so superior to prejudice were to look facts in the face
they Would see that we accuse <ent type='ORG'>the Church</ent> of doing only what it has
done over and over again since the Albiginsian Massacre and the
founding of the Inquisition 700 years ago. They would find that the
<ent type='NORP'>Roman</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Black International</ent> is not the only spiritual army that has
prostituted itself for gold in our time.</p>

<p> In 1937 there was a Parliament of Religions at <ent type='LOC'>Calcutta</ent>. The
report of the proceedings in two fat volumes makes a materialist
like myself blush. Representatives of all the world's religions and
sects joined enthusiastically in the good work, and the speeches
glitter like <ent type='ORG'>Woolworth</ent> jewelry with nice phrases about the
spiritual and the <ent type='ORG'>Ideal</ent>, the sins of men and the wickedness of the
world, the lofty morality by which these folk are going to save the
race. As you will remember, the Japs had by this time completely
enslaved and debauched <ent type='GPE'>Manchuria</ent> and the north of <ent type='GPE'>China</ent> and they
were openly gathering for their next orgy of brutality. And not a
single one of these <ent type='NORP'>Asiatic</ent> word-spinners of the hundred beautiful
religions said one single word about it. One foreigner, a <ent type='NORP'>British</ent>
professor, ventured to say ten very mild words about it.</p>

<p> If you want to know why, though of course nobody did at the
time, it was not simply because people who live on these shining
heights find it difficult to see the common earth. It was mainly
because the <ent type='ORG'>Black International</ent> or <ent type='NORP'>Japanese</ent> Buddhism was doing in
<ent type='LOC'>Asia</ent> just what the <ent type='NORP'>Roman</ent> priests were doing in Europe and <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>.
We must not offend our <ent type='NORP'>Buddhist</ent> fellow-citizens.</p>

<p> Some of my readers will remember that in 1937, while these
spiritual folk were having their jamboree in <ent type='LOC'>Calcutta</ent> and the
world-press was following their beneficent work with admiration. I
published, through <ent type='ORG'>Haldeman</ent>-<ent type='PERSON'>Julius</ent>, a booklet with the title
Imperialistic <ent type='GPE'>Japan</ent> and its Aims. I described how by that time the.
criminal plot of the Japs was so far from being secret that scores
of patriotic societies, some with millions of member's, publicly
boasted of it and gloated over realistic pictures and panoramas
exhibited in the stores of the cities, of the destruction of the </p>

<p> Bank of Wisdom
Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
2
.
THE FRUITS OF ROMANISM</p>

<p><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n fleet. I gave the evidence that the <ent type='NORP'>Buddhist</ent> priests and
monks, 150000 strong, had been bought by the government and the
capitalists and were conducting an intensive campaign all over
<ent type='LOC'>South</ent> <ent type='LOC'>Asia</ent> to create a Fifth Column for the "<ent type='NORP'>Japanese</ent> Liberator's."
They had been bought in cash, just as the Vatican had been bought
by <ent type='PERSON'>Mussolini</ent>, and, like the Vatican, they looked for even greater
profit when the job was done.</p>

<p> They earned their pay. Not only did they work up the <ent type='NORP'>Japanese</ent>
people to a fanatical enthusiasm for the plan of making themselves
rich by exploiting a third of the world but they created nests of
traitors from <ent type='NORP'>French</ent> Indo-<ent type='GPE'>China</ent> to the <ent type='LOC'>Persian Gulf</ent>. There were
10.000 <ent type='NORP'>Buddhist</ent> quislings in <ent type='GPE'>Rangoon</ent> alone and there were others in
key-positions all over <ent type='GPE'>Burma</ent>. Ceylon teems with them. For ten years
the work has proceeded under a very thin disguise of <ent type='NORP'>Buddhist</ent>
concern for the spiritual interests of men. Yet in a Parliament of
Religions held at <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> in 1939 <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> had been emphatically
warned that these <ent type='NORP'>Buddhist</ent> priests had already grown fat on
imperialist gold.</p>

<p> While disreputable atheists and materialists like <ent type='ORG'>Haldeman</ent>-<ent type='PERSON'>Julius</ent> and McCabe, who told the world the truth, were very properly
ignored by all respectable folk these spiritual gasbags, who
blinded it to the realities of life, where loaded with <ent type='ORG'>laurels</ent> and
dollars. It is nice, and so profitable, to be profound and
spiritual!</p>

<p> However. Immense as is the work which I bring to a close with
this booklet I have no space to enlarge, upon even so important a
side-issue as the corruption of Buddhism (which was quite willing
in every age to entertain a business proposition) by the fine
imperialist's of <ent type='GPE'>Japan</ent>. It is enough that "our two great religions"
have made a mockery of every compliment, that every long-haired
idealist in <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> had lavished upon them. They have prostituted
themselves to the <ent type='ORG'>Butchers Union</ent>, while atheistic <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>, upon
which most of these idealists have poured abuse for the last twenty
years, has won a splendid tribute from a disillusioned world. But
I have still an important point to make in regard to <ent type='ORG'>the Church</ent> of
<ent type='GPE'>Rome</ent> to complete the explanation of its behavior.</p>

<p> In his recent work, 'You Can't Be Too Careful,' H. G. <ent type='ORG'>Wells</ent>
says: "The most evil thing in the world today is the <ent type='NORP'>Roman</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>
<ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>." It is also one of the most respected things in the world
today, especially in <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>. But there is no mystery about the
respect, the power, even the adulation which it enjoys. It commands
about 10000000 votes, nicely bunched together for the most part
in certain states and at the disposal of the priests. It has
$4000000000 invested, an income of about $1000000000 and an
army of about quarter of a million paid agents of one kind or
other. It has a very large press and radio-service. It has about
5000000 auxiliary troops, open fanatics and secret intriguers,
sworn to promote "the welfare of <ent type='ORG'>the Church</ent>." It has immense
opportunities of rewarding loyalty, from a Papal Knighthood to a
job as janitor. It has a control of editors, politicians, writers,
libraries, cinemas, radio programs, owners of halls and theaters,
professors, booksellers, even the police, the public school's,</p>

<p> Bank of Wisdom
Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
3
.
THE FRUITS OF ROMANISM</p>

<p>parole-boards, the mails, etc. It has . . . But maybe that will do.
What we had better ask is what excuse is made for themselves by the
politicians, professors, and others who chant the praises of "the
venerable <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>."</p>

<p> You know it. They reply that <ent type='ORG'>the Church</ent> does good -- oh, an
enormous amount of good: so much, in fact, that it is one of the
foundations of the state. In a recent book (Mission to <ent type='GPE'>Moscow</ent>),
which the pious Mr. <ent type='PERSON'>Gollancz</ent> spreads in <ent type='GPE'>England</ent>, Ambassador <ent type='PERSON'>Davies</ent>,
discussing the vices and virtues of <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>, says that with all its
faults it must not be classed with <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y and <ent type='GPE'>Italy</ent>, as a
totalitarian state. Phew! Are there still folk who talk like that?
However, what Mr. <ent type='PERSON'>Davies</ent> mean's is that the <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>n state is, and
the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> state is not, "based upon the altruistic principles of the
<ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> religion." If that is true of <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent> -- if you will
pardon the supposition -- how far more true it must be of the
<ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n civilization with its 100000 parsons and its more
brilliant exhibition of those principles. And of <ent type='ORG'>the Church</ent>es which
render this inestimable service <ent type='ORG'>the Church</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>Rome</ent> is immeasurably
the greatest: <ent type='ORG'>the Church</ent> that regards all the others with
contemptuous tolerance and pronounces them rebellious and
ineffective offshoots of the age-old <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> on which the sun never
sets.</p>

<p> In western stories, of which I am fond, I often read in
descriptions of cow-town of the "false front" of the bank. the
saloon, and the store. The phrase fits the <ent type='NORP'>Roman</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> In <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>,
for it is, to <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>ns, the false front of the international Papal
<ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>. That is why so many <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>ns hesitate in face of the most
conclusive evidence to admit the charge we bring against the <ent type='LOC'>Black</ent>
International. Why, they say, this is <ent type='ORG'>the Church</ent> that first raised
the banner of religious freedom on <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n soil: <ent type='ORG'>the Church</ent> that
gave even Europe the idea of democracies: <ent type='ORG'>the Church</ent> that
periodically provides the whole world, in Papal encyclicals, with
a guidance on problems of the hour which the press reproduces in
letters of gold: <ent type='ORG'>the Church</ent> that gathers 350000000 happy and
virtuous folk, without distinction of class, color, or odor, under
its <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent> mantle: <ent type='ORG'>the Church</ent> that promotes culture and exerts an
inflexible moral rule over the nations.</p>

<p> That is the false front. In these 20 booklets I have taken you
behind it and shown you the real <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>Rome</ent>. Its apologists lie
outrageously about it. They lie about its political and ethical
principles, its history and its law, its numbers and its quality,
its plots and its open action. They dare not allow the press today
to let the world know the truth about the social condition and the
action of <ent type='ORG'>the Church</ent> in a score of countries from <ent type='GPE'>Bolivia</ent> to <ent type='GPE'>Japan</ent>.
I have proved all this.</p>

<p> In my long literary career I have written books in strange
conditions -- in the smoking rooms and <ent type='PERSON'>Marconi</ent> cabins of liners, in
crowded apartments-houses or on the sunny beach, in the bed-rooms
of hotels of all grades -- but I never before wrote, as I have
written these 300000 words, on a battlefield. The National
Library, in which I delve for material, is charred and battered and
almost deserted and the books for which I call come to me sometimes
disfigured by fire or water or fail, and evermore fail, to come...</p>

<p> Bank of Wisdom
Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
4
.
THE FRUITS OF ROMANISM</p>

<p>But you can guess all that. I say that in spite of all this these
twenty booklets are from beginning to end just statements of fact,
on incontestable evidence, and they prove that the <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>
is, if not "the most evil thing in the world," certainly the most
treacherous and mendacious.</p>

<p> It may seem that I have reserved to the last the question
which will seem to many the most important: the question what the
<ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> is worth to the world on a balance of services and
disservices. But I have been replying to that question all through.
Many folk say that they do not care what <ent type='ORG'>the Church</ent> did in the 4th
Century, or the 13th or the 16th; and there is so much blood and
dirt on the pages of medieval history that <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>s often
encourage that feeling, or they would at least like you to believe
that the services they claim -- usually by a gross perversion of
history -- to have rendered were due to a noble spirit which is
ever fresh in <ent type='ORG'>the Church</ent>, while those immense splotches of blood,
those vast areas of servile squalor, and those equally vast areas
of priestly and monastic corruption were just temporary and local
foulings of the garments of <ent type='ORG'>the Church</ent> in the mud of a wicked
world. If you fancy that that childish stuff is really not written
today dip into any <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> book that deals with these matters.</p>

<p> We might leave the past of <ent type='ORG'>the Church</ent> in its smelly historical
tomb if <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> apologists would let us, but they will not. They
lie heroically about its history, and it is vital to an
understanding of the <ent type='ORG'>Black International</ent> that we should know that
its writer's lie habitually. In this connection their lies take the
shape of claiming that <ent type='ORG'>the Church</ent> rendered massive services to
civilization, and it is largely on the ground of these fictitious
services that they demand consideration today.</p>

<p> Moreover, <ent type='ORG'>the Church</ent> boasts, and on the whole justly, that it
never changes. It is a strange boast in a world that decidedly
grows in wisdom and sheds innumerable errors as it advances, but it
does at all events justify us in judging what <ent type='ORG'>the Church</ent> does today
by what it did in <ent type='LOC'>the Middle Ages</ent>, when it was perfectly free to
carry out its principles. When modern <ent type='PERSON'>Pope</ent>s are stung into
indiscretion they use just the same language as medieval <ent type='PERSON'>Pope</ent>s did,
as we found Plus XI doing in his open letter to Cardinal Gasparri
in 1929. The Canon Law, which is kept in a dead language so that
priests alone can read it, makes the same monstrous claim of a
power over life and death as the medieval <ent type='PERSON'>Pope</ent>s made. The
bestiality which the <ent type='PERSON'>Pope</ent> encourages in <ent type='GPE'>Spain</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Portugal</ent> today is
the same as <ent type='PERSON'>Pope</ent>s encouraged a century ago in the whole of <ent type='LOC'>South</ent>ern
Europe and in all Europe during <ent type='LOC'>the Middle Ages</ent>.</p>

<p> No, it is folly to ask us to let dead <ent type='PERSON'>Pope</ent>s bury their dead.
This work, however, is concerned with <ent type='ORG'>the Church</ent> today, and there
is so much to be said about it that I have to avoid history or
confine my short excursions into it within the strict needs of my
present task. So to the question whether <ent type='ORG'>the Church</ent> has done good
in the past and the race is indebted to it I just say bluntly that
practically every claim it makes is fictitious, as I have
exhaustively shown in earlier works, and on balance we must say
that it has retarded the advance of European civilization by many
centuries.</p>

<p> Bank of Wisdom
Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
5
.
THE FRUITS OF ROMANISM</p>

<p> I must say a little more than this in regard to what I call
the modern period. I believe that when scholarship and literature
are again free, when the disgraceful power over them of the <ent type='LOC'>Black</ent>
International is broken, historians will date the beginning of the
modern age from the outbreak of the <ent type='NORP'>French</ent> Revolution, The broad
ideal of a just life was then clearly formulated. The revolutionary
armies carried it, with their symbolic tricolor, as far as the
southernmost tips of <ent type='GPE'>Italy</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Spain</ent>, and <ent type='GPE'>Portugal</ent> and Napoleon's,
armies bore the ensign of at least a liberal civilization to the
bounds of Europe. <ent type='GPE'>Naples</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Madrid</ent> were for a time more advanced
than <ent type='GPE'>London</ent>. Latin <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> throbbed with a new passion.</p>

<p> From that age to ours the outstanding event of history has
been the long-drawn battle for those ideals, and <ent type='GPE'>Rome</ent> has
throughout been on the side of our enemies. Ever since the bloody
shambles it countenanced, if it did not inspire, in <ent type='GPE'>Naples</ent> in 1794
the <ent type='ORG'>Black International</ent> has allied itself with every power, however
corrupt and brutal it was, that took the field against those who
were fighting for the elementary rights of man, for freedom and
democracy. What has happened in the last ten years is simply that
the Vatican, which had been compelled for half a century to profess
in <ent type='NORP'>democratic</ent> countries that it was reconciled with the new age --
in <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> alone the <ent type='ORG'>Black International</ent> has the effrontery to
claim that <ent type='ORG'>the Church</ent> is the actual source of modern ideals --
became convinced that it had found more powerful allies than ever
in the fight against liberalism, and the war which began in 1798
and in one country or other (especially <ent type='GPE'>Spain</ent>) has been almost
continuously maintained, has entered upon a new and terrible phase.</p>

<p> That is the key-idea that you must keep clearly in mind if you
want to understand the relation of the <ent type='NORP'>Roman</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> to the world-war. It is an idea of crucial importance in estimating the world-situation but no journalistic oracle in <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States dare say
it, while what we may call the literary and ethical oracles who,
discuss the more profound aspects of the situation will put forward
any fantastic theory, from the growth of materialism to the
diversion of the <ent type='GPE'>Gulf Stream</ent>, rather than risk offending <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>s
and injuring their own prestige and circulation, by telling the
plain truth. That this is the plain truth I have shown, as regard's
the last ten years, in these 20 books and for the earlier phase in
larger works, The True Story of the <ent type='NORP'>Roman</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> and The
A peal to Reason Library.</p>

<p> A third work would be of very considerable use to the modern
reader, especially in <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>, where, apart from the one or two
brushes with <ent type='GPE'>Britain</ent>, the historical development has encouraged a
real cultural isolation from Europe as fir as our present theme is
concerned. An <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n writer who visited me some years ago
confirmed me in my suspicion that there is no good and adequate
work available on the mighty struggle in Europe in the 19th Century
against the clerical-royalist-capitalist attempts to kill what
survived of the best ideals of the <ent type='NORP'>French</ent> Revolution. For that
matter there is today no work published in <ent type='GPE'>England</ent>, for it would
have to tell the ghastly truth about <ent type='ORG'>the Church</ent>, and in both
countries the <ent type='ORG'>Black International</ent> uses its new power, not merely to
exclude the truth from literature and education but to see that
false versions of the story of man from 1789 onward are imposed </p>

<p> Bank of Wisdom
Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
6
.
THE FRUITS OF ROMANISM</p>

<p>everywhere. In the absence of such a work I can but reiterate that
from 1794 (in <ent type='GPE'>France</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Italy</ent>) until its present alliance with
Fascism (in <ent type='GPE'>Spain</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Poland</ent>, for instance) <ent type='ORG'>the Church</ent> has allied
itself with brutal oppressors and enemies of freedom, as I have
abundantly proved in earlier works, and sum up the evidence given
in this series of booklets in regard to the last ten years.</p>

<p> It is useful to take a broad view before we look at the
situation more closely. The alleged service of the <ent type='NORP'>Roman</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> in
promoting civilization can be very soundly tested from this broad
viewpoint. Just glance at the leading countries of the world and
note in each case what we -- the great majority of men and women in
the best-educated countries -- would assign as the grade of its
civilization and what proportion of the people the <ent type='NORP'>Roman</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>
claims to control; and to allow for the present appalling confusion
or violent distortion of conditions we will survey the world as it
was in 1939 and regard only countries where the <ent type='NORP'>Roman</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> is
substantially represented.</p>

<p> Granting that total wealth or size is not of itself a
criterion of civilization there would be general agreement to name
these ten countries as having attained the highest rank: <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent>
States, Great <ent type='GPE'>Britain</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>France</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Switzerland</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Holland</ent>,
<ent type='GPE'>Denmark</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Sweden</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Norway</ent>, and <ent type='GPE'>Argentina</ent>. In none of these countries
does the <ent type='NORP'>Roman</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> command the allegiance, of more than one-sixth of the population except <ent type='GPE'>Holland</ent>. where its members and
political representatives are one-third of the whole -- still not
enough to have Influence on the general character -- and <ent type='GPE'>Argentina</ent>,
where, however, the constructive class is (or was until 1935)
mainly skeptical (and probably still is). <ent type='GPE'>Argentina</ent> is, in any
case, the one, power whose place in this list would be disputed.</p>

<p> There would be general agreement to put these countries at the
lower end of the scale; <ent type='GPE'>Poland</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Spain</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Portugal</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Italy</ent>, Eire,
<ent type='GPE'>Brazil</ent>, and most of the smaller <ent type='LOC'>South</ent> <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n Republics. In these
<ent type='ORG'>the Church</ent> claims the great majority of the people and certainly as
regards the constructive forces they are <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> countries. They
are all <ent type='NORP'>Fascist</ent>, as none of the above ten are, but, for the moment
I am looking at what by general agreement would be called their
grade of civilization. The place of Hungary might be disputed, but
it is only little more than half <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> and its dictator is not
a <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>. <ent type='GPE'>Czecho</ent>-<ent type='GPE'>Slovakia</ent> as a whole was in the highest class,
but events have shown that the progressive qualities were in non-<ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> Bohemia, and that <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> <ent type='GPE'>Slovakia</ent> is at the level of
<ent type='GPE'>Poland</ent>. I have omitted <ent type='GPE'>Mexico</ent>, which on the ground of recent
accomplishment (reduction of crime and illiteracy, social
legislation, etc.) I should be disposed to put in the first class,
because its place would be warmly disputed. But one thing is not
open to dispute: whatever progress has been made in the last 20
years was due to an anti-<ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> body of statesmen and supporters.
<ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y must be left out of account unless we go back to pre-<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>
days, but even then Catholic's were a one-fourth minority and they
are In large part responsible for the triumph of <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>sm and ruin of
the country. In <ent type='GPE'>Belgium</ent> the forces are about equal, and the grade
of civilization corresponds.</p>

<div> </div>

<p> Bank of Wisdom
Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
7
.
THE FRUITS OF ROMANISM</p>

<p> You will see the full significance of this if you recall that,
as I said, all these countries entered upon the great race, as we
may call it, of the last 150 year's with much the same equipment of
ideals. The <ent type='ORG'>Revolutionary</ent> and the <ent type='ORG'>Napoleon</ent>ic armies, beating a path
for <ent type='NORP'>French</ent> literature, made those ideals familiar from <ent type='GPE'>Portugal</ent> to
<ent type='GPE'>Sweden</ent>, and Latin <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> was awakened from one end to the other by
the echoes of the struggle. Even <ent type='GPE'>Ireland</ent> had quite a notable body
of <ent type='NORP'>Deists</ent> and humanitarians (<ent type='PERSON'>Robert Emmet</ent>, Wolfe Tone, and many
others) amongst its educated men in the last years of the 18th
Century. It has none today or not one who dare open his lips, and
the country remains, with all its political and religious pride,
poor, squalid, ignorant, and of inferior general character. in
other words, every country in which the influence of the <ent type='ORG'>Papacy</ent> was
paramount failed to advance in the path that was indicated by those
new ideals of civilization which we all regard as sound. But the
countries in which <ent type='GPE'>Rome</ent> had no such influence or where, as in
<ent type='GPE'>France</ent>, it lost its power, joined the predominantly Protestant
countries in advancing to the higher rank. That is the first reply,
and it is perfectly sound from the sociologleal angle, to the claim
that the <ent type='NORP'>Roman</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> promotes civilization.</p>

<p> Chapter 11</p>

<p> THE BLACK INTERNATIONAL ALWAYS IN THE REAR</p>

<p> In this general survey I have repeatedly referred to the
ideals of freedom and democracy. For most of us these are partial
expressions of the modern spirit, the demand for justice, which, in
alliance with the advance of science, has lifted the ten countries
I named to the highest rank. The attempt of <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> writers in
various countries to represent them as mere political claims, or
even as a liberalism, that the world has tried and found wanting,
are mere excuses to cover the Vatican's alliance with Fascism or
the <ent type='NORP'>Fascist</ent> Encyclical of the <ent type='PERSON'>Pope</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Quadragesimo</ent> Anno. It must be
understood, however, that I have not assigned these 20 nations
their place in the scale of civilization on that test. If one
proposed to do this it would be simple and accurate to say that all
<ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> countries are now <ent type='NORP'>Fascist</ent> and all <ent type='NORP'>democratic</ent> countries are
non-<ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>. But it is more convincing if we apply a broader test
of civilization.</p>

<p> The <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> apologist would define the service of his <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>
by saying (first and chiefly) that it defends the family, that it
trains all people whom it can influence in general moral character,
that it preaches and insists upon justice, individual and social,
and that it is zealous for education and philanthropy. And since,
he would say, the family is, according to very many if not most
sociologists, the foundation of the state, the particular zeal and
rigorous measures of his <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>, which distinguish it in an age of
growing laxity, must especially recommend it to the statesman and
the social student.</p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>Piffle</ent>, as usual. The <ent type='NORP'>Roman</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> has three distinctive
features in its teaching about the family. First, it insist that
its priests, monks, and nuns shall not marry and shall not have any
recognizable families; and since the implication of this is that
sexual commerce has some sort of taint even where it is licensed</p>

<p> Bank of Wisdom
Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
8
.
THE FRUITS OF ROMANISM</p>

<p>one does not see how we can speak here of <ent type='ORG'>the Church</ent> guarding this
particular foundation of the state. Secondly, it alone amongst the
<ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>es -- in fact, it shares this distinction only with a few
groups of the lowest savages on earth -- forbids divorce; and since
this harsh restriction of human rights has either, as in <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>
countries, to be alleviated by the general use of mistresses or
brothels, or it amounts to a positive deterrent from marriage, we
again fail to perceive any service, and no statesman of any of the
leading civilizations has any respect for <ent type='ORG'>the Church</ent>'s teaching on
this point. The law of divorce which now exists in every
civilization except those of lower grade that are subject to the
<ent type='PERSON'>Pope</ent> is based upon the collective recognition of social experience
and upon a mature adjustment of the rights of the individual and
the needs of the state. The <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> opposition to it professes to
be based upon some words of an ancient <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> prophet of which we
have two contradictory versions in the records and which other
<ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>es, of equal scholarship and greater sincerity,
find compatible with divorce. It is in any case really based, as I
showed, on the fierce determination of the <ent type='PERSON'>Pope</ent>s of the early
Middle Age's to get complete control of life. On such frivolous and
anti-social grounds does this particularly strident claim of the
<ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> to render human service rest; and our contempt deepens when
we find <ent type='ORG'>the Church</ent> playing fast and loose with its "indissoluble
marriage" when its own interest or profit is involved, as I showed
in my analysis of the clauses of the Canon Law and the practice of
the Papal Courts.</p>

<p> Thirdly, the <ent type='ORG'>Black International</ent> boasts that it renders a
unique service to the state because it is the only <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> or
institution that condemns, and very fiercely condemns birth
control. The <ent type='ORG'>Black International</ent> is as usual, out of date. For the
last ten years it has shared that distinction with the criminal
leaders of the <ent type='NORP'>Italian</ent>, <ent type='NORP'>Japanese</ent>, and <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> people. They wanted
soldiers and the excuse of over-population to cover their
imperialist greed. The <ent type='ORG'>Black International</ent> wanted more contributors
to its <ent type='ORG'>treasury</ent> and, as priests have admitted, to beat rival
<ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>es by outbreeding them. The clerical opposition to birth
control is, in fact, such an obvious piece of priestcraft and has
so little foundation even in their own weird and wonderful theology
that they confess (as I quoted), the <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> laity in <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> are
to an alarming extent ignoring their sulphuric orders and
restricting their families: which makes their "social" argument
look rather anaemic.</p>

<p> The apologists have recently been encouraged by the appearance
of a new school of opponents of birth control whose leaders and
statements are not religious. These professors and their learned
lady friends recognize that the old opposition was based upon a
demand for as many soldiers as possible and that the industrial and
professional markets are, in normal times and in capitalist
countries, already overcrowded. They say that the really sound
scientific plea is that the birth rate is so far falling out of
balance with the death rate that there will soon be a debilitating
preponderance of old folk over young. They do not take into account
the fact that science and common sense are steadily raising what we
may call the vitality-period of men and women. I could write
caustic pages on my own recent experience in being rejected (as one</p>

<p> Bank of Wisdom
Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
9
.
THE FRUITS OF ROMANISM</p>

<p>in senile decay) from all departments of the <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> national
effort by men whose laziness, short hours, and easygoing methods
are notorious, But I have space only for one point. <ent type='GPE'>France</ent> has
practiced birth control for more than half a century almost as much
as <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> or <ent type='GPE'>Britain</ent> does today. But it was not old men who let
<ent type='GPE'>France</ent> down. It was a few <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> old men, who were pushed into
office by these priests who are so concerned about the vitality of
civilization, <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> adventurers like <ent type='PERSON'>Laval</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Bonnet</ent>, and
younger statesmen who were seduced by <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> mistresses.</p>

<p> In short, all this rhetoric about <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> marriage and the
social welfare is hypocritical claptrap, and every statesman and
social student knows it. Every state finds in time its equilibrium
on grounds of experience in sex-matters. Sex-laws and restrictions
that are based upon ancient philosophic's or religions, ultimately
upon more ancient taboos and superstitions, merely distract
attention and hamper the social activity. Apologists for them have
to repeat outdated and thoroughly exposed statements about the ruin
of older civilizations by vice. Five year's ago most folk would
have said that the two most vigorous nations were the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> and
the <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n, and both enjoyed an advanced degree of sexual
freedom. Today we should say that <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> are the most
vigorous nations. But according to the priests the <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n people
are only restrained from a monstrous parade of sex, in their books,
pictures, and theaters, by the severe paternal cheek of the clergy,
while <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent> has always had a liberal divorce law and for quarter
of a century has denied that marriage is a sacrament and birth
control a sin.</p>

<p> For reasons -- reasons of self-interest -- which I discussed
in an earlier book <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> apologists have always put this sex and
marriage-business in the forefront of their statement of claims. It
more or less excises the absurd official virginity of their
priests, monks and nuns: It evokes a golden echo in the hearts of
rich widows and spinsters: and it really does mark a distinction
between <ent type='ORG'>the Church</ent> and "the world." In theory, that is to say. And
not only is the theory itself an antiquated ethic rehabilitated for
priestly purposes, so that those who profess to lead civilization
are far in the rear of modern thought, but in practice <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>s
are no more "moral" than other folk. I leave it to my readers'
knowledge of <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n life what the situation is in <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>, saying
only that I have a very extensive familiarity with the best
<ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n fiction of a realist character and that I have made
extensive inquiries during the two years (at intervals) I have
spent in <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>. But for "<ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> countries" you may take as
typical the pleasant exaggeration which <ent type='PERSON'>Byron</ent> wrote when he saw a
statue of <ent type='GPE'>the Virgin Mary</ent> in a <ent type='NORP'>Portuguese</ent> city: "Well do I ween the
only virgin there." He had probably made inquiries.</p>

<p> Apologists obstinately insist that <ent type='NORP'>Irish</ent> girls are remarkably
chaste," though I have for 30 years given proof and bitter
complaints of English <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>s (including leading priests) that
the <ent type='NORP'>Irish</ent> girls are sent to <ent type='GPE'>Britain</ent> to drop their burdens and keep
down the record of illegitimate births in Eire. A <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent> attorney
writes me, or wrote me 30 years ago when I took up the question,
that the same complaint was made in the New <ent type='GPE'>England</ent> States. <ent type='PERSON'>Sanger</ent>
says in his History of Prostitution (1919 edition) that on personal</p>

<p> Bank of Wisdom
Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
10
.
THE FRUITS OF ROMANISM</p>

<p>interrogation of 2000 <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent> prostitutes he found that 977 (706
of whom had been born in <ent type='GPE'>Ireland</ent>) had had <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> parents, and had
been brought up as <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>s. The <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> Times (May 31, 1924)
quoted <ent type='PERSON'>Canon Hughes</ent>, one of the highest <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> authorities,
saying that 60 percent of the prostitutes of <ent type='GPE'>Liverpool</ent> -- one of
the most <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> and most vicious cities in <ent type='GPE'>England</ent> -- were <ent type='NORP'>Irish</ent>
and only 30 percent English. Ten years later another <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>
expert, Mrs. <ent type='PERSON'>Ellison</ent>, stated in a book that the situation is the
same in the cities of <ent type='GPE'>London</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Glasgow</ent>, and <ent type='GPE'>Newcastle</ent> (big centers
of <ent type='NORP'>Irish</ent> immigration). A leaflet on the subject issued by the
Protestant Truth Society (<ent type='NORP'>British</ent>) gives a mass of <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>
testimony and replies to the charge that illegitimacy is 3.4
percent in Protestant <ent type='PERSON'>Ulster</ent> and (for the above reasons) only 0.7
in <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> Connaught that it was at the time 9.30 in <ent type='GPE'>Belgium</ent>,
14.89 in <ent type='GPE'>Austria</ent>, 15.67 in <ent type='GPE'>Bavaria</ent>, and 50.00 in <ent type='GPE'>Guatemala</ent>. Since
emigration was checked the <ent type='NORP'>Irish</ent> have not boasted so much. I quoted
an editorial in the <ent type='NORP'>Irish</ent> Times (June 12, 1937) describing a
disgraceful official record of sex-crimes in <ent type='GPE'>County Clare</ent> which is
in Connaught!</p>

<p> This chastity-talk is not only outdated from the ethical and
sociological angle but it supported by a remarkable variety of
untruths. And if it is suggested that the real service of the
<ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> lies in promoting morals or character in the broader sense
the reply to just as devastating. This plea is just a relic of the
old and purely rhetorical assertion that a religious basis is
required for sound conduct. The sufficient reply is that, I have
repeatedly shown, the general level of character in the leading
civilizations has risen in the same proportion as <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> influence
has decayed. For the moment we are not concerned about cause and
effect. The fact is enough. As my friend Mr. E.S.P. <ent type='ORG'>Haynes</ent>, a
distinguished <ent type='GPE'>London</ent> attorney, has written -- and he is approvingly
quoted by <ent type='PERSON'>Julian Huxley</ent> in his Religion Without Revelation (P. 52):
"If morality did really depend on other worldly sanctions, the
religious changes of the last fifty years would by now have
dissolved society at large." What has happened is much the same as
with the old superstition that it is unlucky to pass under a
ladder. People now see that a good reason for not doing it is that
the man who does not keep clear of a ladder raised against a
building is apt to get drips of paint or bricks dropped on him. In
the same way they discover that sound moral law is a sanitation-regulation of the social life.</p>

<p> The irony of paying attention to the <ent type='NORP'>Roman</ent>ist version of the
old apologetic, which is the noisiest of them all, is that the
Papal <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> promotes sound character even less than the other
<ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>es. Middle-class folk, to which class most writers
belong, argue on these matters in the most slovenly fashion. Their
acquaintance with <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>s is confined to their class, and in this
they meet many <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> men and women of admirable character. So,
they lazily conclude, <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>ism molds character. Middle-class men
who are not puritans have insisted to me -- two of them were
attorneys -- that they find <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> girls easier to persuade or
less in need of persuasion than other girls. But let us remember,
the nature of <ent type='ORG'>the Church</ent> as I analyzed it. Of the 100000000 or so
adult subjects of the <ent type='PERSON'>Pope</ent> at least 80000000 have not the least </p>

<p> Bank of Wisdom
Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
11
.
THE FRUITS OF ROMANISM</p>

<p>resemblance to the middle-class <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n or <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>. Half
of them are imperfectly civilized Latin <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>ns (with <ent type='GPE'>Cuba</ent> and
the <ent type='GPE'>Philippines</ent>) and most of the remainder are illiterate or poor
and ignorant <ent type='NORP'>Spaniards</ent>, <ent type='NORP'>Italians</ent>, <ent type='NORP'>Portuguese</ent>, <ent type='NORP'>Slovaks</ent>, etc.</p>

<p> The general level of character in a nation is an elusive
factor but it is fairly determined, if we make allowances for
police-conditions, by the volume of crime. Criminal behavior in the
extreme form of unsocial conduct, and the number of criminals is a
good indication of the amount of unsocial conduct generally. If,
therefore, we find, as we do, that <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> countries are more
criminal than non-<ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>, and that as a mixed country a quite
disproportionate number of the criminals are <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>s, we must
conclude that <ent type='ORG'>the Church</ent> is no more effective in inspiring sound
social behavior than in securing the chastity about which it talks
so much.</p>

<p> I have given a few statistics in book No. 13. As <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>s are
apt to contest this I may add a few more. In No. 23 of his
Questions and Answer (p. 87) <ent type='ORG'>Haldeman</ent>-<ent type='PERSON'>Julius</ent> gives, from a book by
a <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> prison chaplain (Fr. <ent type='PERSON'>Leo Kalmer</ent>, Crime and Religion) a
most damning series of figures. The priest ascertained from his
colleagues the percentage of <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>s in 36 <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n
penitentiaries and the result extends to the whole of <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> the
truth disclosed in the figure's I gave for <ent type='PERSON'>Sing Sing</ent> (48.50 percent
in <ent type='GPE'>Joliet</ent>, 46.92 in <ent type='GPE'>San Quentin</ent>, 57.31 in <ent type='GPE'>Auburn</ent>, 63.64 in
<ent type='GPE'>Wethersfield</ent>, etc.). Analysis by the Rev. L.B. <ent type='PERSON'>Lehmann</ent> brings out
the fact that in 28 states, in which <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>s are 17 percent of
the population, they are 33 percent of the criminals. The whole
article in <ent type='ORG'>Haldeman</ent>-<ent type='PERSON'>Julius</ent>' book should be read.</p>

<p> The only other mixed states for which exact comparative
figures are available are <ent type='ORG'>the Commonwealth</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>Australia</ent> and the
Dominion of <ent type='GPE'>New Zealand</ent>. In the case of <ent type='GPE'>Australia</ent> the figures are
particularly interesting because the <ent type='NORP'>Roman</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> has as much power
there as in <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> and is just as blatant in its claims. It is 36
years since I first reproduced the full figures relating to crime
and <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>ism in that country, and I have brought them up to date
every few years. They are as damning as those of <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>, yet
<ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>s continue to claim in the most brazen manner that they
guard the foundations of the state by promoting character.</p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>The Queensland</ent> State Schools Defense Fund issued a leaflet
quoting the figures from the official publications. This showed
that in <ent type='GPE'>Victoria</ent> in 1936 the <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> prisoners numbered 2164,
whereas since the <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>s are only 18 percent of the population,
their ought to have been only 754 <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> prisoners if their moral
quality was equal to that of non-<ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>s. In <ent type='GPE'>New South Wales</ent> they
had 454 prisoners instead of the 145 to which their percentage of
the population entitled them. In <ent type='GPE'>Queensland</ent> the disproportion was
the same. In <ent type='ORG'>the Commonwealth</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>s, mostly <ent type='NORP'>Irish</ent>, had three
times the number of criminals they ought to have had if they were
as good as and no better than their neighbors. As <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>s in
<ent type='GPE'>Queensland</ent> had just published a new demand for the preferential
treatment of their schools, the Protestants retorted humorously
that they ought themselves to receive preferential treatment in the
matter of taxation because they maintain extra police and jails to
look after <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> criminals.</p>

<p> Bank of Wisdom
Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
12
.
THE FRUITS OF ROMANISM</p>

<p> In 1937 Archbishop <ent type='PERSON'>Mannix</ent>, the bitter muddle-headed <ent type='NORP'>Irish</ent>man
who in his very <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> hatred of <ent type='GPE'>England</ent> used all the influence
of <ent type='ORG'>the Church</ent> to induce <ent type='GPE'>Australia</ent>n's to confine themselves to their
pleasures and dollar-making while <ent type='GPE'>Britain</ent> fought and suffered for
ideals -- until the hideous face of the Japs appeared on the
horizon and <ent type='GPE'>Australia</ent> cried frantically to <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Britain</ent> for
help -- made one of his usual attacks on the public schools of
<ent type='GPE'>Australia</ent>. They were demoralizing even <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> boys. He said this
in <ent type='GPE'>Melbourne</ent> (<ent type='GPE'>Victoria</ent>). Shortly afterward's the Report of the
<ent type='GPE'>Victoria</ent>n Children's Courts for 1937 was published. Of 973 child
delinquents it appeared that 582, or 37.4 percent were <ent type='NORP'>Roman</ent>
<ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>s; and <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>s are only 18 percent of the population of
<ent type='GPE'>Melbourne</ent>.</p>

<p> That is typical of the value, of these loudly-shouted claims
of <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> apologists. They know that none of the papers will test
the claims by statistical or historical facts, and that letters to
the press which do this will be suppressed as "offensive to
<ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>s." The Protestant Watchman of <ent type='GPE'>New South Wales</ent> in 1941.
published, an analysis of the space given in the four daily papers
of <ent type='GPE'>Sydney</ent> to <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> and Protestant affair's respectively. In a
period of three months the <ent type='NORP'>Roman</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>s got 491 inches, the
<ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>England</ent> 280 (if we count out a large photo with the queen
in it), and the Methodists and <ent type='NORP'>Presbyterians</ent> 186. Is <ent type='GPE'>Sydney</ent> a
<ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> city? Far from it. The <ent type='NORP'>Roman</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> controls only 17
percent of the population: <ent type='ORG'>the Church</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>England</ent> 40 percent: the
Methodist and <ent type='NORP'>Presbyterians</ent> 14 percent. But the arms of the <ent type='LOC'>Black</ent>
Octopus are everywhere, strangling freedom and truth, from the
office of the cabinet minister or the trade union to the editorial
office and the public libraries.</p>

<p> Most countries do not now publish the figures of the religious
professions of criminals, and full figures of crime in <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> and
non-<ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> countries are not so easily obtained as one would
suppose. Few sociologists or criminologists omit to mention the
<ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>, and prominently, amongst the agencies which make for social
sanity and stability, but, though it will be understood that my
acquaintance with such literature is not complete, I do not know
one of them who dares to follow this up by examining the statistics
of crime and the profession's of criminals or the religious status
of the various countries.</p>

<p> The article "Homicide" in the Encyclopedia of the Social
Sciences has a little merit in this connection. It quotes Ferri's
table showing the reduction of it in recent times in five of the
leading European countries by giving the percentage per 100000 of
the population:</p>

<p> <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y 1.0 in 1865-85 and 0.6 in 1906-10
<ent type='GPE'>France</ent> 2.4 in 1827-31 and 1.4 in 1911-15
<ent type='GPE'>England</ent> 8.1 in 1856-60 and 0.7 in 1906-10
<ent type='GPE'>Spain</ent> 9.4 in 1881-85 and 5.2 in 1911-15
<ent type='GPE'>Italy</ent> 12.2 in 1871-75 and 4.1 in 1911-15</p>

<p> <ent type='GPE'>Italy</ent>, remember, was despotically ruled by the <ent type='ORG'>Papacy</ent> until
1870 and had an appalling record of crime to reduce. I may add that
crime doubled in a few years after the <ent type='NORP'>Fascist</ent>s usurped power in it</p>

<p> Bank of Wisdom
Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
13
.
THE FRUITS OF ROMANISM</p>

<p>and was not reduced when the Vatican made its corrupt bargain to
share the control. <ent type='GPE'>Spain</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Italy</ent> were both predominantly <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>
in the last century when they had such a high record of the gravest
crime, and the modern sociologist scorns the excuse of "the hot
blood of the south." I question the figure for <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y, as there
was no "<ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y" only a number of separate states -- until 1871.
Bodis (in Mulhall's Dictionary of Statistics) gives this percentage
of trials for murder in 1876-84: <ent type='GPE'>United Kingdom</ent> 12, <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y 14,
<ent type='GPE'>France</ent> (still mainly <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>) 23, <ent type='GPE'>Spain</ent> 105, Hungary 107, <ent type='GPE'>Italy</ent>
134. Add these to the figures I gave in No. 13, and you get such a
reply to the claim that <ent type='NORP'>Roman</ent>ism promotes a high standard of
character that you wonder that any apologist has the effrontery to
make it.</p>

<p> But all <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>s make it, and very emphatically, because it
is the only excuse they can provide for the politicians,
professors, and writers whom, in one way or other, they get to
praise <ent type='ORG'>the Church</ent> and denounce critics. If this claim is so
decisively disproved by the only exact test we can apply -- the
volume of crime in <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> lands and the proportion of criminals
in mixed lands -- so decisively that no sociologist in <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>
thinks it prudent to discuss the matter, where must we look for
even a plausible bit of color for it? The language of Papal
encyclicals and the gorgeous comments of apologists on them suggest
that there might be more sincerity in the claim that <ent type='ORG'>the Church</ent> is
more effective in inspiring social justice. We will defer the
examination of this to the next chapter, but the reader will be
prepared to smile. Social justice in <ent type='GPE'>Italy</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Vichy</ent> <ent type='GPE'>France</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Spain</ent>,
<ent type='GPE'>Portugal</ent>, and <ent type='GPE'>Brazil</ent> as compared with <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Britain</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>,
<ent type='GPE'>Denmark</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Sweden</ent>, or <ent type='GPE'>Switzerland</ent>! It sounds like a bad joke.</p>

<p> But what other test can we apply? Is the great 'service of the
<ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> that it provided, or moved the authorities to provide, free
education for the children of the workers? See the table of
steatitic of illiteracy which I gave in No. 13 (p. 21). They are
more damning than the statistics of crime or illegitimacy. Our
search for these massive social services of <ent type='ORG'>the Church</ent> begins to
remind us of that naughty definition of metaphysics -- looking in
a dark room for a black cat that isn't there. Let us, in order to
be quite just to our <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> fellow-citizens, approach the subject
in a different way.</p>

<p> Chapter III</p>

<p> THE WICKED WORLD EDUCATES THE CHURCH</p>

<p> This ghastly war and the <ent type='NORP'>Fascist</ent>-<ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> conspiracy that led
to it interrupted an unsteady and unequal but very real and
Substantial advance of civilization in Europe and <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>. If my
readers are not tired of my giving proof of that, I am. I have
routed the <ent type='NORP'>Lippmanns</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Spenglers</ent> who Strangely persuaded so many
to doubt it. I have riddled the sophistry of the novelty-monger and
pseudo-idealists who ranted that in our race to get ahead we had
created a monster of the <ent type='PERSON'>Frankenstein</ent> order or had let the
cultivation of our intelligence outrun our cultivation of
character. The revelation of the share of "our two historic </p>

<p> Bank of Wisdom
Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
14
.
THE FRUITS OF ROMANISM</p>

<p>religions" in drenching the planet with mud and blood ought to make
these prophets of the spiritual feel small, but I notice in the
<ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n press that they are as cocky as ever, and our Joads in
<ent type='GPE'>Britain</ent> orate at Empire Pageants. These people have nearly a
monopoly of the after-the-war planning which absorbs all our finer
spirits just now. They would return to just that distracting
activity of theirs under cover of which Japs and <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>s shifted
the attention of the world from the real evils that menaced it.</p>

<p> The world was making a very creditable progress on most lines
of a real advance of civilization, though it was checked by the
interests of wealth and religion, until the privileged folk and
their politicians were duped into thinking that the <ent type='LOC'>Black</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Tang</ent>
(or yellows) were merely accumulating power in order to annihilate
the <ent type='ORG'>Reds</ent>. This progress became appreciable about 1870, when the
United States settled down after <ent type='EVENT'>the Civil War and</ent> Europe
triumphed, in most countries, over the vicious clerical-royalist
reaction that had followed the fall of <ent type='ORG'>Napoleon</ent>. Briefly, the
period characterized not merely by an advance of from 1870 to 1914
was characterized, not merely by an advance of applied science
which more than doubled the wealth-reducing capacity of a nation
but by the employment of a very large part of the new wealth to
create systems of universal free education, an immense
multiplication of free libraries, the establishment in most
countries of fully <ent type='NORP'>democratic</ent> political regimes and the
enfranchisement of women, factory-legislation, schemes of old-age
pensions and health and unemployment insurance, sanitation, re-housing, and other measures which doubled the average expectation
of life, a considerable growth of temperance (or temperateness),
and great reduction of crime, the doubling (generally) of real
wages, the enormous improvement of hospitals and services for the
distressed, and the spread of an anti-war sentiment.</p>

<p> Some say that that is a materialistic conception of progress.
Most men and women in 1914 would have said that they did not care
a damn what you called it but that -- if they read a candid account
of life before 1870 -- the world, in spite of its lingering
defects, was a very much better place to live in. But let me again,
in passing, point out the humbug of this "spirit" and "matter"
business.</p>

<p> I have just been reading, dreary as the occupation was, one of
those numerous recent works on the beauty of modern high-brow
Buddhism and how it will save the world. Out of the mush of
Verbiage I picked the general statement that the <ent type='ORG'>Supreme</ent> aim of
Buddhism is "the extinction of suffering." Funny. That is exactly
the supreme aim of atheists and materialists. I pointed out years
ago that progress is not to be judged by some misty goal in the
clouds but by the success of a nation in reducing suffering. And
while a certain number of people in every generation can be
persuaded to lessen the risk of suffering for themselves by
despising the wicked world and its wine, women, and song, and
retiring to a semi-nudist colony to contemplate their navels --
which seems to be Buddhism -- it seems to us atheists and
materialists far better to remove or reduce as much as possible the
sources of suffering (disease, poverty, war, ignorance, etc.) for
millions of people.</p>

<p> Bank of Wisdom
Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
15
.
THE FRUITS OF ROMANISM</p>

<p> Talking of our navel-contemplators, I fancy you will find a
little irrelevance well worth inserting here. I do not know whether
you ever came across a priceless book published nine years ago by
Professor T. O'<ent type='PERSON'>Conroy</ent>. It ought to have been reprinted in 1938 and
scattered by the million over <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>, at the time, when the Japs
were spending millions a year in lying propaganda. O'<ent type='PERSON'>Conroy</ent> lived
in <ent type='GPE'>Japan</ent>, teaching in one of the leading universities, for 15
years. He married an aristocratic <ent type='NORP'>Japanese</ent> lady and was more
intimately admitted to <ent type='NORP'>Japanese</ent> life than any other white man. And
in 1933 he wrote this scalding indictment of the nation, showing
that for corruption, cruelty, and unscrupulousness the Japs could
not be beaten. Buddhism, he shows, fully shared this corruption,
though it was at that time -- the government had not yet invited it
to prostitute itself to the national greed -- a fat, indolent, and
useless body. But what I want to quote is an illustration of its
corruption which he gives (pp. 87-8) and which, sensational as it
is, like the similar revelation in <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> monasteries, I have not
seen reproduced or referred to since in <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n literature or
journalism.</p>

<p> A few mile's from <ent type='GPE'>Tokyo</ent> was a large and rich monastery of what
was understood to be the very strictest sect of <ent type='NORP'>Buddhist</ent> monks.
They were so holy that they closed their doors against the wicked
world and wanted to be alone. But in their extensive grounds there
was a home for feeble-minded women, tended by the good monks, and
a rumor spread in <ent type='GPE'>Tokyo</ent> that numbers of these unfortunates were
just unwanted wives whose husbands paid the monks to take them
over. A <ent type='GPE'>Tokyo</ent> paper organized a raid in 1928, and though the police
at once suppressed it, published an amazing story. The <ent type='NORP'>Buddhist</ent>
monastery was a colony of sadists, just as the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Franciscan</ent>
friars were found to be colonies of sodomists. When the raiders
burst in they found the monk-keepers gambling and squabbling with
blood-splotched paper money, while the women, half mad or half
dead, lay about, mutilated, exhausted, fouled with the monks'
excrements. Women were chained even in the temple, and rape, sexual
mutilation, and ignominy were but a few of the foul performances
that took place." And this is the second greatest "spiritual"
religion of our time: the religion over which our idealists and
scorners of materialism go into ecstasies!</p>

<p> Like the monasteries in the <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> provinces of <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y and
the more <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> republics of <ent type='LOC'>South</ent> and Central <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> and the
<ent type='GPE'>Philippines</ent>, these <ent type='NORP'>Buddhist</ent> monasteries -- O'<ent type='PERSON'>Conroy</ent> says that
decent <ent type='NORP'>Buddhist</ent> priests told him that 60 to 80 percent of their
body were corrupt -- illustrate what is always likely to happen in
medieval conditions; that is to say, wherever the monastery is
surrounded by a drowsy or drugged population of believers free from
the taint of heresy. It was the normal condition of <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>
monasteries throughout <ent type='LOC'>the Middle Ages</ent>, and it lingered, as in
<ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y, <ent type='GPE'>Italy</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Spain</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Portugal</ent>, <ent type='NORP'>Spanish</ent> <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>, and the
<ent type='GPE'>Philippines</ent>, wherever this parasitic <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> atmosphere lingered.
This is the first broad proof that <ent type='ORG'>the Church</ent> was taught sense and
virtue by what it calls the wicked world or the materialistic age.</p>

<p> An examination of the progress and the causes of social reform
in each country would clinch this proof, but obviously a
satisfactory treatment of that subject would require a large
volume; and, as it is one of those inquiries that <ent type='ORG'>the Church</ent> does</p>

<p> Bank of Wisdom
Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
16
.
THE FRUITS OF ROMANISM</p>

<p>not like, no historian or sociologist has taken it up and there is
no work to recommend to the reader. I have, as some readers will
know, not only given a large amount of material for the study in
previous works but have written one in which enough of the evidence
is condensed to satisfy any candid inquirer (How Freethinkers Made
Notable Contributions to Civilization, <ent type='ORG'>Haldeman</ent>-<ent type='PERSON'>Julius</ent> Co. 1938).
In this work I examined the record of progress, particularly during
the last 100 years, in respect of the struggle for freedom,
education, social and political rights, the emancipation of woman,
philanthropy, and general improvement, and I showed that, while in
those days religious folk, though by no means so lenient to
<ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>s as they now are, at least thought them an immeasurably
larger and more respectable body than freethinkers, yet fully one
half the pioneers in all reforms were freethinker's and none were
<ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>s.</p>

<p> You wonder what <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> apologists, loudly claiming that the
<ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> leads in progress and civilization, say to that. The answer
is: Nothing, as far as I can discover. I have several times quoted
a very popular apologetic work, published under the patronage of
heads and professors of several <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n universities, entitled The
Calvert Handbook of <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> Facts. It ought to say "of <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>
Rhetoric" or "<ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> Lies." It makes the usual generalized claims
but, as <ent type='ORG'>the Church</ent> must have exerted this mighty influence on
progress and civilization through definite individuals, the leaders
of chief workers in reform-movements, I look for the names of these
-- and find none. There is a lot about <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> relatives of
Presidents, rich <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> men of business, <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> diplomatists,
<ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> judges, and so on, but for every <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> named as a
worker in reform-movements I will undertake to name a hundred
skeptics.</p>

<p> There is in the book an article on <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>s who contributed
to <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n civilization in particular or civilization in general.
It names <ent type='PERSON'>Sobieski</ent>, whose monument is <ent type='GPE'>Poland</ent>, Ferdinand and
<ent type='PERSON'>Isabella</ent>, whose monument is <ent type='GPE'>Spain</ent>, and the discoveries of <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>,
who would have gone to the stake if they had not professed
<ent type='NORP'>Roman</ent>ism. That covers the later Middle Ages. Then we have a Father
<ent type='PERSON'>White</ent>, who is said to have set up the first printing press (from
<ent type='GPE'>England</ent>) in <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>, another who was great at shorthand in its
infancy, another who invented a balloon; and another who (getting
the idea from <ent type='GPE'>England</ent>) built the first railroad in <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>. Two or
three are credited with naval and military distinction, and there
is the usual bunch of great <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> scientists (Pasteur, Fabre,
etc.) most of whom were skeptics. There are the men who wrote
"<ent type='GPE'>Maryland</ent>" and "The Conquered Banner," the architect of the <ent type='PERSON'>White</ent>
House, the man who sold the estate for it, and the man who planned
the city of <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent> (a "majestic plan"). There you have the
sweepings of three centuries, from Europe as well as <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>. They
do not represent a small body of <ent type='NORP'>Quakers</ent> or still smaller body (at
that time) of freethinkers but the biggest religion in the world.</p>

<p> Did anybody ever say that no <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> ever won any sort of
distinction, even in shorthand, ballooning, or writing songs? We
are familiar with <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>s writing any sort of tripe for their own
hypnotized people, but this sort of thing is written for non-<ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>ns and has the patronage of <ent type='PERSON'>Nicholas Murray</ent> Butler </p>

<p> Bank of Wisdom
Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
17
.
THE FRUITS OF ROMANISM</p>

<p>and the President of <ent type='ORG'>the Carnegie Institute</ent> of Technology. The
great work for civilization was achieved from 1870 onward. How many
of these illustrious <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>s fall in that period? Only the
balloonist as far as I can see. We may admit that gas and hot air
are entitled to clerical respect, but what the <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> apologist,
claims is the inspiration of our progress in education, the
reduction of social service. How many of crime, and poverty, and
suffering these brilliant men figure in those fields? Not one.</p>

<p> Let us try another way. As the Jesuits are supposed to have
inspired <ent type='GPE'>Jefferson</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Adams</ent>, who loathed Jesuits and their creed
as much as <ent type='ORG'>Haldeman</ent>-<ent type='PERSON'>Julius</ent> does, perhaps it will be claimed that it
was the subtly compelling influence of Papal encyclicals that
permeated the world and somehow fired large bodies of men and women
(mostly skeptics) to devote their lives to ridding the world of its
medieval evils and miseries. This would be very singular when we
reflect that of those who are supposed to be the closest readers of
the encyclopedias, the priests, not one -- unless you want me to
count Father <ent type='PERSON'>Coughlin</ent> -- figures in the long list of reform-leaders, and not one <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> layman is found in any list of, say,
the hundred leading social workers of the 19th Century. The
influence of religion on leader's of reform is one of those studies
which our sociologists carefully avoid, though most of them give
religion a high-place in the list of inspirational agencies, but I
have made the research elsewhere, and the grotesque scratchings in
the byways of history of the Calvert Handbook confirm me. The Papal
encyclicals moved the world to great deeds and through atheists and
<ent type='NORP'>Quakers</ent>! Really, apologists ought not to advertise so blatantly
what they think of <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> intelligence.</p>

<p> But what are these grand encyclicals (or "to the whole world")
letters of the <ent type='PERSON'>Pope</ent>s on social matters. Even a <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> would beg
me not to go too far back, so let us begin about the beginning of
the modern progressive period. Pius IX (of "Blessed Memory," the
<ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> writer always adds, though <ent type='NORP'>Italians</ent> who knew him have
written some funny things about him) opened the series in 1864 with
the encyclical <ent type='ORG'>Quanta cura</ent> and the <ent type='ORG'>Syllabus</ent>. Your apologists now
never mention it. He, having still at that time the reactionary
<ent type='NORP'>French</ent> emperor to protect him against the wicked <ent type='NORP'>Italians</ent>, scorched
the whole reform-movement with the choicest Papal invectives. He
put "liberalism," which we now call pink tea, on a level with
Satanism, which is several notches lower than rape.</p>

<p> Then came the great encyclical-writer <ent type='PERSON'>Leo XIII</ent>. He was as fond
of writing encyclicals as <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>ill is of writing speeches. Two of
them are still gorgeously praised -- and falsely interpreted -- In
<ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> literature. But just keep your eye on the dates
and the historical background. <ent type='PERSON'>Leo</ent> won the tiara in 1878, when the
reform-movement was full on in Europe. <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> he knew only as a
raw outpost of civilization -- I suspect he knew it mostly from
Dickens's Letters and <ent type='PERSON'>Martin Chuzzlewit</ent> -- and he had many a brush
with its bishops, but he did follow social and political movements
in Europe. Yet it was not until thirteen years after his accession
that he issued the first encyclical which the most ingenious
apologist can call socially inspiring. He had not been silent. In
1878 he had issued an encyclical cursing Socialism root and branch.
Next year he had imposed the medieval "philosophy of Aquinas on the</p>

<p> Bank of Wisdom
Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
18
.
THE FRUITS OF ROMANISM</p>

<p><ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> world. In the following year he had thundered at the
world, which was reforming its marriage-laws, that divorce was a
mortal sin (except in the ingenious form in which rich <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>s
can get it from <ent type='GPE'>Rome</ent>). In 1881 he pointed out, apropos of the
assassination of the Tsar, that these appalling outrages were due
to the decay of religion (not, of course, to the bestiality of the
Tsarist regime), and in 1884 he put <ent type='NORP'>Freemasonry</ent> Under the ban. In
1885 he issued the <ent type='PERSON'>Immortale Dei</ent>, which <ent type='PERSON'>Ryan</ent> still applauds as a
fine <ent type='NORP'>democratic</ent> appeal; and I have shown that it is nothing of the
kind. In 1888 he savagely attacked the claim of religious freedom
and liberty of discussion. It was not until 1891, when he saw
Socialism gaining ground rapidly at the expense of <ent type='ORG'>the Church</ent>, that
he issued the one encyclical, Rerum novarum, which <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>s claim
to give a lead in social reform; and the only "revolutionary"
sentence in it was the statement that the workers must have a
living wage. (which he refused to define), which had been a
platitude of liberal literature for half a century. And in his last
beautiful messages to the world he retracted this and died
sputtering the most reactionary sentiments.</p>

<p> I pass on the next two <ent type='PERSON'>Pope</ent>s. <ent type='PERSON'>Ryan</ent> does not quote them. They
were stuffy and ill-informed reactionaries all their lives. And in
1931 the late <ent type='PERSON'>Pope</ent>, or the present <ent type='PERSON'>Pope</ent> writing in his name issue
the <ent type='NORP'>Fascist</ent> encyclical <ent type='ORG'>Quadragesimo</ent> anno which the <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> and
<ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n hierarchies dare not translate into English! It opened the
blatantly <ent type='NORP'>Fascist</ent>, conspiratorial, warmongering career of his
"holiness" Pius XII.</p>

<p> Need I point the moral? The <ent type='ORG'>Papacy</ent> was throughout the whole
period the enemy of progress of the rights of the people. It was
just compelled for a time to temporize because it looked even to
these owlish <ent type='NORP'>Italians</ent> priests as if democracy had won its war and
the world was adopting the liberalism in social matters which the
<ent type='PERSON'>Pope</ent>s scorned. Yet even when concessions had to be made to check
the leakage of millions of workers from <ent type='ORG'>the Church</ent> they took only
the feeble form of saying that if the <ent type='NORP'>French</ent> people really insisted
on having a republic they might, provided it kept the <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>
<ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> established by law and that capitalists must grant their
workers a "just wage," which it was left to them to determine.</p>

<p> What do I mean then, you will ask, by saying that the wicked
world educated <ent type='ORG'>the Church</ent>? The <ent type='PERSON'>Pope</ent>s apparently, never were
educated in sound views of social ethics. What I mean is that in
<ent type='GPE'>America</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Britain</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>France</ent>, <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y, and <ent type='GPE'>Italy</ent> a social-<ent type='NORP'>democratic</ent>
movement (without the capital letters) spread in the <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> world
after 1900. Quite bold books appeared, and there were "social
experts" and all sorts of novelties. What was the inspiration?
Evidently it did not come from the <ent type='ORG'>Papacy</ent>. Had local hierarchies
and their <ent type='PERSON'>Ryan</ent>s and <ent type='PERSON'>Williams</ent> a finer appreciation of the
implications of the faith than the Holy-Ghost-inspired Pope's and
all the great theological geniuses of <ent type='LOC'>the Middle Ages</ent>?</p>

<p> Enough of this nonsense. The plain truth is that after leaving
it to non-<ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>s for a century, when the work was heart-breaking
and the penalty often death or jail, to break the paths of social
and humanitarian reform, the local <ent type='ORG'>Black International</ent> in some
countries concluded that in the interest of <ent type='ORG'>the Church</ent> they must </p>

<p> Bank of Wisdom
Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
19
.
THE FRUITS OF ROMANISM</p>

<p>join in the work. It was a death-bed repentance. But the patient
recovered. That is to say, the <ent type='ORG'>Black International</ent>, which for a
time had despaired of life on the old lines of privilege and
autocracy, saw a new hope in the rise of Fascism and became
convinced that it was going to conquer the world. So the death-bed
confession of sin was torn up in <ent type='GPE'>Rome</ent> and in all countries that
passed under the pirate-flag, and it is only in one or two
countries like <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Britain</ent>, where democracy may survive and
may even regain the world, where in any case <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>s are a
minority and must behave like the <ent type='NORP'>Japanese</ent> in <ent type='GPE'>California</ent> or <ent type='GPE'>Oregon</ent>,
that one still hears how freedom and democracy are grand old
<ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> ideas conveyed to a wicked and despairing world by the
august, and fearless, and un-compromising encyclicals of the <ent type='PERSON'>Pope</ent>s.</p>

<p> Chapter IV</p>

<p> THE CONTRAST OF <ent type='GPE'>RUSSIA</ent> AND PRIEST-RULED COUNTRIES</p>

<p> While the services rendered by <ent type='ORG'>the Church</ent> to civilization are
as hard to find as the black cat in a dark room, the services it
rendered to the repulsive forces which have attempted to wreck
civilization are as plain as the peaks of the <ent type='ORG'>Rockies</ent>. The
alliances contracted by the Vatican with <ent type='GPE'>Italy</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Japan</ent>, and <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y
are events of recent history like the New Deal or the Atlantic
Charter. The dates and terms of the agreements are public property.
But one service requires special consideration: the organization of
the entire resources of <ent type='ORG'>the Church</ent> to engender hatred of <ent type='ORG'>Communism</ent>
in general and of <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent> in particular.</p>

<p> This service began, explicitly as far as the documents I have
seen tell us, in 1936, though the Vatican had begun its furious
attack upon <ent type='ORG'>Communism</ent> and even, in effect, its appeal for a crusade
against it, much earlier. From 1919 to 1924 the <ent type='PERSON'>Pope</ent> was, we saw,
straining, every nerve to get on friendly terms with <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>
so as to bring under his control the Orthodox <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> when its
leaders were scattered. The <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>ns repeatedly detected the
<ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> clergy in treachery and in 1924 closed the country against
missionaries from <ent type='GPE'>Rome</ent>. So in December of that year Pius XI, who
had hitherto in great charity kept in check his hatred of
<ent type='ORG'>Communism</ent>, attacked it in his <ent type='EVENT'>Consistorial Allocution</ent> (December 18)
and called the attention of all "heads of "governments" to the
danger of it. He, in fact, coupled Socialism with <ent type='ORG'>Communism</ent> as
equally dangerous. In 1931 he, we saw, ordered all <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> states
(in encyclical <ent type='ORG'>Quadragesimo</ent> anno) to adopt the <ent type='NORP'>Fascist</ent> state and
sternly forbade <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>s to take up either Socialism or <ent type='ORG'>Communism</ent>.
He said that <ent type='ORG'>Communism</ent> had brought "massacres and ruin upon <ent type='LOC'>Eastern</ent>
Europe." This attack on <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent> seems to have been taken up or
fostered by his representatives everywhere, as on December 30,
1932, the <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> Daily Worker said that "the clergy of all creeds
and denominations are, with religion as their pretext following the
lead of the <ent type='PERSON'>Pope</ent> in his call for a crusade against the U.S.S.R."</p>

<p> The direct and more pointed attack began, however, in 1936,
shortly after the outbreak of Franco's rebellion in <ent type='GPE'>Spain</ent>. We must
remember that <ent type='GPE'>Italy</ent> and <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y were not at that time open allies
of <ent type='PERSON'>Franco</ent>, and <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Britain</ent> had not declared their attitude </p>

<p> Bank of Wisdom
Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
20
.
THE FRUITS OF ROMANISM</p>

<p>to what everybody still called a rebellion. But there was no
reserve at <ent type='GPE'>Rome</ent>. In a blistering and most untruthful attack on
<ent type='ORG'>Communism</ent>, which he represented as the aggressor in <ent type='GPE'>Spain</ent>, the <ent type='PERSON'>Pope</ent>
spoke of it as a force that was attempting to subvert established
order of every kind from <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent> to <ent type='GPE'>China</ent>, from <ent type='GPE'>Mexico</ent> to <ent type='LOC'>South</ent>
<ent type='GPE'>America</ent>." From this year onward he appealed repeatedly for "the
extinction" of <ent type='NORP'>Bolshevism</ent> in <ent type='GPE'>Spain</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Mexico</ent>, and <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>, and, as we
saw, "he holy cry for blood was taken up in the <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> section of
every country.</p>

<p> When the <ent type='GPE'>Czecho</ent>-<ent type='GPE'>Slovakia</ent>n crisis, which might be called the
first stage of the world-war, arose in 1938 the service that the
Vatican and its <ent type='ORG'>Black International</ent> in every country had already
rendered the imperialist thugs by this propaganda was apparent.
<ent type='ORG'>Joint</ent> action at once by <ent type='GPE'>Britain</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>France</ent>, and <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent> would have
strangled <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent>ism in its cradle and put a cheek to the ambitions
of <ent type='GPE'>Japan</ent>. But <ent type='GPE'>Britain</ent> was under obligation only to support <ent type='GPE'>France</ent>,
and <ent type='GPE'>France</ent> was persuaded by its <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> politicians and military
leaders, the present <ent type='GPE'>Vichy</ent> crowd, that <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent> could not be trusted
to keep its word: in reality, that active partnership with so
disreputable a power and helping it to cheek the strength of
<ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y must not be undertaken by <ent type='GPE'>France</ent>. As late as 1940 <ent type='NORP'>British</ent>
generals of the stuffy <ent type='NORP'>Tory</ent> type were saying: "We may have to ally
our selves with <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>, but God forgive us." That contemptuous
attitude the <ent type='ORG'>Black International</ent> fed in every country for ten
years, to the very great profit of the bandits.</p>

<p> We admit the double root of this hatred of <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>, or the
capitalist and the <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> roots, but we have to recognize this
difference: that the capitalists, who make no pretence of moral
principle, are honest opponents of a dangerous rival system,
whereas the priests, who profess to be the moral saviors of a
wicked world lie about their motives and by their action run the
risk of bringing upon civilization precisely that ruin which they
untruthfully accused the <ent type='NORP'>Communists</ent> of contemplating. The Pope's
outburst in 1936 which I quoted in an earlier book and which was
clearly written by the present <ent type='PERSON'>Pope</ent> as Secretary of State, was a
tissue of untruthful charges. Instead of trying to "subvert
established order of every kind" by "an un-parallel confusion of
forces so savage and cruel as to have been thought utterly
incompatible" -- whatever the last phrase may mean -- <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent> had by
1936, as the whole world knew, wrought a miracle of the creation of
order out of chaos. In 1923, as a result of the European War, the
<ent type='EVENT'>Civil War</ent>, and the great famine, <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent> had been reduced to a
condition of disorder and misery which had not been seen in Europe
since the end of the Thirty Years War (1648). The restoration began
in earnest a few years later, and by 1936 the most respected writer
of <ent type='GPE'>Britain</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> reported, with a few reserves, that the
<ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> government had, especially in regard to the reduction of
crime and the establishment of social order, won a remarkable
victory.</p>

<p> Apologists in <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> had generally, to be less wild than the
<ent type='PERSON'>Pope</ent> in their indictment of <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>, but they were reckless enough.
The old lies about the massacre of priests and the persecution of
religion flourished in <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> literature from year to year; in
fact, there is good ground to believe that the official </p>

<p> Bank of Wisdom
Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
21
.
THE FRUITS OF ROMANISM</p>

<p>representatives of <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> demanded assurances on the latter point
when they began to negotiate with <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent> about military aid. The
conspiracies in which some of the leading <ent type='NORP'>Bolsheviks</ent> were involved
were eagerly snapped up as proof that the country was ruled by a
murderous bureaucracy, whereas we now have the weighty assurance of
Duranty (with a reserve in one case) and Ambassador <ent type='PERSON'>Davies</ent> that the
men were certainly guilty. <ent type='PERSON'>Davies</ent> himself repeats a perennial libel
in saying that the <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>ns are lamentably inefficient as compared
with the <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>ns and the <ent type='NORP'>British</ent>. He has had the cruel experience
of seeing his book appear, with this reproach, just at the time
when the world had proof before it daily of the relative efficiency
of the <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> and the <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>n military machine.</p>

<p> There are two plain reasons for the sacred fury of <ent type='ORG'>the Church</ent>
against <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>, and the first is entirely discreditable. It is
because the attack upon <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent> brought the <ent type='ORG'>Black International</ent> into
line with wealth and privilege in accordance with its old and
unwavering tradition. For an attack upon the <ent type='NORP'>Communist</ent> political
system <ent type='ORG'>the Church</ent> has no ground whatever since it declares that it
never interferes in politics. And when it plans its attack on
economic ground's it recognizes that it can make no distinction
between <ent type='ORG'>Communism</ent> and Socialism, since the degree of socialization
is not a matter of moral principle. But its claim that any moral
principle at all is involved is ludicrous. <ent type='PERSON'>Ryan</ent> is very eloquent on
the moral right of private ownership: he is, in fact so sure of it
that he says a Socialist government would be a violation of moral
law, and <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>ns would be justified in rebelling against
it. <ent type='ORG'>Piffle</ent>. A people has a right to choose its economic form just
as well as its political regime. The apologists who talk like this
are simply saying to the world's capitalists: The <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>Rome</ent> is
your friend so help to protect it from further decay.</p>

<p> The second and stronger reason is the tremendous loss which
the spread of <ent type='ORG'>Communism</ent> had inflicted upon the <ent type='NORP'>Roman</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>. I gave
the facts in the first book. The press and most writers conceal
them and leave the fierce hostility of <ent type='GPE'>Rome</ent> to <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent> not very
intelligible and cover up the vast amount of harm that the Vatican
did by spreading it's hatred over the world, yet <ent type='GPE'>Rome</ent> itself is
much more ready to admit this motive than to talk about its support
of the capitalist system. It, of course, does not speak of losses.
With its usual complete indifference to truthfulness it invites the
world to unite against <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent> because it "attacks religion." All
criticism of the <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> or telling the people the truth
about its history and its aims is "an attack" but criticism by the
<ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> of other <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>es or philosophies is, however acrid and
untruthful it may be, just a kindly warning to the world of the
dangers that surround it.</p>

<p> We may readily admit that for many years the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> government
gave every assistance to the voluntary organization that opened the
eyes of the people, but this official cooperation had ceased at the
time when the Vatican was shrieking about attacks on religion, and
in the other countries (<ent type='GPE'>Italy</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>France</ent>, <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y, <ent type='GPE'>Spain</ent>, and <ent type='NORP'>Spanish</ent>
<ent type='GPE'>America</ent>, etc.) in which the advance of Socialism and <ent type='ORG'>Communism</ent>
detached tens of million# from the <ent type='NORP'>Roman</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> there was certainly
no official encouragement of the movement. The mechanism of
propaganda was a substitution of facts for lies, of knowledge for </p>

<p> Bank of Wisdom
Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
22
.
THE FRUITS OF ROMANISM</p>

<p>ignorance. The policy of <ent type='ORG'>the Church</ent> when the <ent type='NORP'>Fascist</ent> reaction began
in each country sufficiently proves this. It closed the schools,
suppressed freedom of discussion, and strangled literature; and it
filled the jails with the men and women who had been most prominent
in exposing the clergy, and it had, and continues to have,
thousands of them labelled <ent type='NORP'>Communists</ent> and shot.</p>

<p> We talk about the blindness of men in the red haze of war, but
the third year of this most terrible of all war's has been, to the
intense mortification of the <ent type='ORG'>Black International</ent>, a year of
illumination. Self-interest has, of course, helped the <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> and
<ent type='GPE'>America</ent>ns to surmount the prejudices that have been pumped into
them by press, pulpit, literature, and the cinema for 20 years, but
it will hardly be questioned that the magnificent conduct of the
<ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>n people has been the main fact that opened the eyes of folk
to their great qualities and the soundness of their system. Right
until the hordes of <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> tanks, set free by the absence of any
opposition on the western front, were within a few hours run of
<ent type='GPE'>Leningrad</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Moscow</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Britons</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>ns were whispering that of
course the <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>n people would not fight with real devotion and
the requisite energy for a government that usurped power, treated
them despotically and mercilessly, and robbed them of their
previous religion. Novels, the class-books of so many millions,
still circulated in which the <ent type='ORG'>Commissars</ent> and leading officials were
represented as sadistic monsters who lived on champagne, caviar,
and <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> virgins.</p>

<p> History has rarely seen such a revulsion of sentiment, such a
triumph over two decades of priestly and aristocratic slander, as
has happened in the last six months. <ent type='NORP'>Conservative</ent> leaders now speak
in public about "our noble <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>n ally," and deputies from <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>,
who only six months ago were admitted at the back doors, so to
speak, are received with royal hands. And it is only in the last
few months that the press or most of it -- many papers still crab
at <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent> and frown on the popular enthusiasm -- has supported the
change of heart. In <ent type='GPE'>England</ent> most of the cinemas still treat <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>
as a power which it would be indecent to obtrude upon the notice of
a <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> people. Bands at Anglo-<ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>n functions are forbidden
to play the <ent type='NORP'>Communist</ent> national anthem, and rich if small
organizations continue to publish the old libels. But, the facts
have for the vast majority of people swept away the long-standing
prejudices as the first warm rains of spring wash away the snows.</p>

<p> The next step will be for the public to reflect how it has
been systematically duped over a long series of years. The share of
the <ent type='ORG'>Black International</ent> in this has been so conducted that most
people are unaware of it, but the truth slowly emerges and <ent type='GPE'>Rome</ent>
shudders. The <ent type='PERSON'>Pope</ent>, we saw, already puts out rumors that in his
intimate circle he, from the first, drew a sharp distinction
between what he blamed in <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>, which was virtuous on the wrong
grounds, and what he blamed in <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y and <ent type='GPE'>Italy</ent>. But no one has
read a line in which he gave a straight moral condemnation of the
<ent type='NORP'>Fascist</ent>s and the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>s -- he never blamed more than their
interference with <ent type='ORG'>the Church</ent> and the attempt to annihilate <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>
<ent type='GPE'>Poland</ent> -- whereas the <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> authorities themselves translated
and circularized the vicious, vitriolic speech on the <ent type='NORP'>Communists</ent> of
<ent type='GPE'>Spain</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Mexico</ent>, and <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>, which he delivered on September 14,
1936, (The <ent type='NORP'>Spanish</ent> Terror).</p>

<p> Bank of Wisdom
Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
23
.
THE FRUITS OF ROMANISM</p>

<p> Into whatever contortion the <ent type='ORG'>Black International</ent> is driven in
the next few years the world is confronted today by a situation
which sets in a glorious light all that the <ent type='PERSON'>Pope</ent> cursed and casts
a shade of ignominy and cowardice upon all that he blessed. <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>
shines, and even <ent type='GPE'>China</ent> wins honor and admiration: the two chief
countries in which the <ent type='PERSON'>Pope</ent> had seen the activity of the devil:
<ent type='GPE'>Spain</ent>, the Land which his shining <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> crusaders were going to
deliver from bondage and misery, is a country of spectral forms and
general mourning, a land in which innocent men face the firing-squad daily, while the priests wax fatter, and the <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>
"nobles" and politicians do actually carouse in <ent type='GPE'>Madrid</ent> as the
<ent type='ORG'>Bolshevik</ent> leaders were represented by the Pope's agents as doing in
<ent type='GPE'>Moscow</ent>.</p>

<p> <ent type='GPE'>Portugal</ent>, we saw on the authority of a writer whom <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n
<ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>s had imprudently recommended as veracious, is a country in
which priest-ridden jailers use the vilest tortures that were used
in the ages of faith: in which decades of Liberal work for the
education and elevation of the people have been trodden under foot,
and the dictators are richly rewarded by <ent type='GPE'>Rome</ent> because they declare
that they are ruling <ent type='GPE'>Portugal</ent> on the lines of the Pope's beautiful
(but untranslated) encyclical.</p>

<p> <ent type='GPE'>Italy</ent>, dragged at the heels of Hitler's bumping chariot, is in
so pitiful a condition that it wins the sympathy of its <ent type='NORP'>democratic</ent>
enemies. From his own Vatican windows the <ent type='PERSON'>Pope</ent> looks out upon a
people that in a very high proportion curses the man whom the
Vatican, by a sordid bargain, confirmed in his usurped power.
<ent type='GPE'>London</ent>, the bombed and ravaged city, is gay with confidence, well
fed, richly entertained at nights, reflecting the summer sun on the
faces of its citizens. <ent type='GPE'>Rome</ent> is beggared and dejected, despised and
bullied by the men who invited it to share the conquest of the
world.</p>

<p> <ent type='GPE'>Vichy</ent> <ent type='GPE'>France</ent> is sullen and simmering. The myth that it was
somehow ruled against its will by a posse of <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, <ent type='NORP'>Atheists</ent>, and
<ent type='NORP'>Freemasons</ent> and would, under such men of piety as <ent type='PERSON'>Laval</ent> and Petain,
flock cheerfully to the churches, is exploded. From <ent type='GPE'>Normandy</ent> to
<ent type='ORG'>Savoy</ent> people sigh for deliverance from the regime of <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>ism
and dishonor, rusticity and penury, which has been forced upon
them. The <ent type='NORP'>French</ent> people have provided most of the $10000000000
worth of loot that the blond beasts, whom the <ent type='ORG'>Black International</ent>
persuaded the <ent type='NORP'>French</ent> to admit, have dragged in <ent type='NORP'>French</ent> cars on
<ent type='NORP'>French</ent> petrol into <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y. Never since its earliest history has
proud <ent type='GPE'>France</ent> fallen so low as it is today, and it shudders to think
that it may not have reached the end of its humiliating surrender.
No people in the world today respects <ent type='GPE'>France</ent> -- except priest-ridden Quebec.</p>

<p> <ent type='GPE'>Belgium</ent> lies under an almost impenetrable cloud, earning its
dry bread only by working for the master whom it has for quarter of
a century hated more than any other on earth. <ent type='GPE'>Austria</ent> has perished.
It is again the despised southern fringe of the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent>. The
<ent type='NORP'>Croats</ent>, who were persuaded by their priests to betray their
country, fight the men to whom they betrayed it because they were
the Pope's allies. The <ent type='NORP'>Slovaks</ent> who were similarly persuaded to
complete the ruin of the country in which they had, enjoyed freedom</p>

<p> Bank of Wisdom
Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
24
.
THE FRUITS OF ROMANISM</p>

<p>and social welfare now melt away on the battlefield of <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>.
Latin <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>, the huge conglomeration of states which at the wave
of Pacelli's white hand declared itself <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>, once more, is
rent and bewildered. The Pope's allies, the people find, had
plotted to ruin them and now hang about their shares with murderous
intent. And <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y and <ent type='GPE'>Japan</ent>, on whose success the <ent type='PERSON'>Pope</ent> had
gambled the whole security of his <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>, seem to have reached the
peak of their victories and have begun the decline that leads to
the pit in which the fully developed strength of <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>,
and <ent type='GPE'>Britain</ent> is bound to bury them.</p>

<p> Chapter V</p>

<p> THE MONSTROUS ATTEMPT TO RESTORE THE MIDDLE AGES</p>

<p> The treacherous irruption by night of <ent type='GPE'>Japan</ent> into the war has
transformed it into the phenomenon which has been forecast, with
heavy foreboding, for 20 years -- a world-war. Almost the entire
civilized world is now involved in it. A few powers -- <ent type='GPE'>Sweden</ent>,
<ent type='GPE'>Switzerland</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Turkey</ent>, and <ent type='GPE'>Argentina</ent> -- are genuinely neutral, but,
however clearly we may understand the difficulties of their
position, no one regards it as an honorable distinction. The rest
of the civilized world is divided into countries which live under
the most hated emblems the world has seen for many centuries -- the
Swastika and <ent type='ORG'>the Rising</ent> <ent type='LOC'>Sun</ent> (for <ent type='GPE'>Italy</ent> writhes under the former of
these) -- and countries which are sworn to bring them down to the
dust.</p>

<p> Apart from Latin <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>, which is, as I said, distracted
between its Papal assurances and the discovery of the perfidy and
brutality of the Pope's allies, all <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> countries fall in the
first category. Their national flags where they still have any,
are, if not deeply stained with dishonor, generally regarded with
contempt or a pity that is tinged with disdain. There can be few
more miserable statesmen in the world than Eugene <ent type='PERSON'>Pacelli</ent>, or His
Holiness Pius XII. Ten years ago he pledged his <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> to a belief
in the ultimate victory of <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y, <ent type='GPE'>Italy</ent>, and <ent type='GPE'>Japan</ent>. In the ruin
of all liberal, as well as Socialist and <ent type='NORP'>Communist</ent>, ideals which
they would effect no strong voice would be raised in protest,
against his alliance with a bestial greed that sought to attain its
end's by brutality almost without precedent in history. His
gauleiter and his gestapo would, as always, loyally support the
Vatican policy. The end justifies the means. As to the mass of the
faithful, when did any large body of them ever rebel when <ent type='PERSON'>Pope</ent> and
<ent type='ORG'>Black International</ent> were united in their policy? And in the
glorious extension of the power and wealth of <ent type='ORG'>the Church</ent>, the
annihilation of its deadliest enemies, which the <ent type='PERSON'>Pope</ent> anticipated
from the victory of Swastika and <ent type='ORG'>the Rising</ent> <ent type='LOC'>Sun</ent> few <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>s would
be in a critical mood.</p>

<p> In the second stage of the war, when the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>s, finding
nearly all Europe in their power and confident of Subduing the
remainder, began to disclose their real sentiments about <ent type='GPE'>Italy</ent> --
which the Vatican ought to have learned from <ent type='PERSON'>Mein Kampf</ent> 20 years
ago -- and proposed to share the world with <ent type='GPE'>Japan</ent> only, the <ent type='PERSON'>Pope</ent>
had a new dream. It suited the interests of the Vatican just as
well as it was to the interest of <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y that <ent type='LOC'>South</ent>ern Europe </p>

<p> Bank of Wisdom
Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
25
.
THE FRUITS OF ROMANISM</p>

<p>should have its industries destroyed. Big industries mean clotted
urban populations, free discussion, freethought, birth control, and
so on. The Vatican had seen that painful development in <ent type='GPE'>France</ent>,
<ent type='GPE'>Belgium</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Italy</ent>, and <ent type='GPE'>Czecho</ent>-<ent type='GPE'>Slovakia</ent>. The <ent type='ORG'>Black International</ent> was
ready to join in the plot to de-industrialize those countries and
let <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y glow rich by a monopoly of industry, in Europe. Petain,
with the priests at his elbow, openly mumbles it, in his senile
honesty, and has within the last month closed down a thousand
industries in <ent type='GPE'>France</ent>. <ent type='PERSON'>Leo</ent>pold of <ent type='GPE'>Belgium</ent> and his <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>
satellites, <ent type='PERSON'>Franco</ent>, and <ent type='PERSON'>Salazar</ent> cheerfully send their skilled
workers to <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y or to the <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>n shambles. <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> would allow
a <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> League of <ent type='LOC'>South</ent>ern Europe, and through <ent type='GPE'>Spain</ent> and
<ent type='GPE'>Portugal</ent> the 100000000 folk of Latin <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> would be drawn into
it. <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> promised the Subjection to the Vatican of all branches
of the <ent type='NORP'>Greek</ent> and Oriental <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>es. <ent type='GPE'>Japan</ent> promised a monopoly of
<ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> missions (if thoroughly <ent type='GPE'>Japan</ent>ized) in <ent type='LOC'>the Far East</ent>. . . </p>

<p> That these were the plans on which the Vatican worked I showed
on <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> admissions and by the plain testimony of facts in the
first ten booklets. Already the vast field of <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> triumph is
a scorched earth. The <ent type='PERSON'>Pope</ent> is ill, silent, desperately watching the
last critical phases of a conflict that, unless it be won speedily
by the <ent type='ORG'>Axis</ent>, will inexorably be lost. From those windows of the
Vatican Palace which look out upon the world he sees only one flag
waving above the ruins unsullied: the <ent type='PERSON'>Hammer</ent> and Sickle. <ent type='GPE'>Britain</ent>
has won respect by the courage and endurance of her people but,
after a series of retreats that are rare in <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> history, has
still to, and doubtless will, redeem the honor of its flag. There
is a stain on the Stars and Stripes that has yet to be removed.
<ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>. has made no large blunders but has met the initial impact
of an irresistible force and the loss of vast fertile provinces and
great industries and has begun its recovery with a devotion,
energy, and self-sacrifice that have torn the Pope's libels to
tatter's. Bring on your stage today representative figures of all
the Pope's peoples -- the pale and ragged <ent type='NORP'>Italian</ent>, the gaunt
<ent type='NORP'>Spaniard</ent>, the illiterate and poverty-stricken <ent type='NORP'>Portuguese</ent>, the
shame-faced <ent type='NORP'>Belgian</ent> or <ent type='GPE'>Vichy</ent> <ent type='NORP'>French</ent>man, the hesitating Latin
<ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n -- and at the end of the file bring on a <ent type='ORG'>Bolshevik</ent>, and
listen to the judgment of the audience. What the <ent type='PERSON'>Pope</ent> cursed the
world blesses: what he blessed the world curses. The <ent type='PERSON'>Pope</ent> has lost.</p>

<p> But, aside from the fact that in <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> the <ent type='LOC'>Black</ent>
International is powerful enough to hide this truth from the mass
of people, remember that the <ent type='PERSON'>Pope</ent> has lost dozens of times before,
yet he has today more subjects than ever, immeasurably greater
wealth, and a new power in non-<ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> countries.</p>

<p> A week ago a powerful <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> air-fleet bombed <ent type='GPE'>Cologne</ent>. I had
wondered how long it would be before this was done. Here was one of
the most vital and most vulnerable bottle-necks in Europe. Through
it passed practically all the war-supplies from <ent type='GPE'>Holland</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Belgium</ent>,
and <ent type='PERSON'>Northern</ent> <ent type='GPE'>France</ent>. Thoroughly smash the railway through the city,
where it approaches the <ent type='GPE'>Rhine</ent>, and the great bridges, and you deal
<ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y a terrific blow. But -- I once spent five or six weeks in
<ent type='GPE'>Cologne</ent> -- the cathedral is close to the railway and the bridges.
It was unhurt, and who will believe that the vital part of the
railway and the bridge which carries it over the river, which are </p>

<p> Bank of Wisdom
Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
26
.
THE FRUITS OF ROMANISM</p>

<p>only a few hundred yards from the cathedral, were properly treated
if no bomb strayed across the square? I hear that, at the prayer of
<ent type='NORP'>British</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>s, our airman were told to run no risk of touching
the cathedral.</p>

<p> Why was <ent type='GPE'>Rome</ent> never bombed? There were times when this was
within our power, and it might have had a very considerable
influence on our fortunes in the Mediterranean area. H.G. <ent type='ORG'>Wells</ent>
asked me the other day if I knew why it was not done. I do not
know. These things are not put on paper, and if they were the paper
would never see the light. But there is a grapevine, and the
message went along it that through Roosevelt <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>s
threatened things, and there were <ent type='ORG'>Black International</ent> threats in
parts of the <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> Empire, if we bombed <ent type='GPE'>Rome</ent>. <ent type='PERSON'>Mussolini</ent> probably
patted his Papal friend on the back.</p>

<p> However these things may be, remember that <ent type='GPE'>Rome</ent> has many times
in history seemed to be doomed because of its Papal alliances with
brutality, but it recovered. About 850 years ago the <ent type='NORP'>Roman</ent>s
themselves drove one of the strongest of the <ent type='PERSON'>Pope</ent>s into exile for
such an alliance. In 1527 <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> armies wrecked <ent type='GPE'>Rome</ent> as <ent type='NORP'>Goths</ent> and
<ent type='ORG'>Vandals</ent> had never done. Early in the 19th Century, a contemporary
tells us, Napoleon's generals, entering <ent type='GPE'>Italy</ent> and carrying off the
<ent type='PERSON'>Pope</ent>, decided that this was to be the end of the <ent type='ORG'>Papacy</ent>; and not
many years later <ent type='PERSON'>Macaulay</ent> made his foolish prediction that there
would still be a <ent type='ORG'>Papacy</ent> when visitors from <ent type='GPE'>New Zealand</ent> came to see
the ruins of <ent type='GPE'>London</ent>.</p>

<p> I dislike prediction's, and indeed I have accomplished the
work which I set out to do in this series of books. I proved to the
hilt the indictment I brought against the <ent type='ORG'>Black International</ent>, and
I have now shown that <ent type='ORG'>the Church</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>Rome</ent> is of such a nature, so
dangerous in its structure and so feeble in its intellectual
appeal, that it is bound to look for such allies in every age. A
third line of evidence is found in Papal history, especially during
the last century and a half. Violence has always -- I do not know
if this was in the protocols given by <ent type='PERSON'>Jesus</ent> to <ent type='PERSON'>Peter</ent> -- been the
policy on which the <ent type='ORG'>Black International</ent> relied. The <ent type='PERSON'>Pope</ent>s merely
kept the weapon tucked under their cassocks during the few decades
between the death of feudal tyranny and the birth of totalitarian
tyranny. The leopard does not change its spots, but it may have
them white-washed.</p>

<p> Nevertheless I may conclude with a glance at the future. This
<ent type='NORP'>German</ent>-<ent type='NORP'>Japanese</ent> horror shall and will perish. As I write there is
still time for a serious setback to <ent type='GPE'>Britain</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>, or <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>, or
all three. I have never been tempted to underrate the ability of
the men who, behind the miserable tinfoil <ent type='PERSON'>Siegfried</ent> and his greedy,
friends, direct the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> effort or the cunning and lean energy of
the <ent type='NORP'>Japanese</ent>. If this serious advance of the <ent type='ORG'>Axis</ent> does not occur in
the next few weeks we may breathe freely. Within, two further
months the retreat will begin. The end, this year (if <ent type='GPE'>Britain</ent> opens
a second front) or next, is certain.</p>

<p> What will <ent type='GPE'>Rome</ent> do? Remember first that comparatively few
people know the story of its guilt. A few <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n papers have at
intervals reported Vatican events which suggested it. The vast
majority of the leading papers, both in <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Britain</ent>, never </p>

<p> Bank of Wisdom
Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
27
.
THE FRUITS OF ROMANISM</p>

<p>gave any news which gave their readers an inkling of the truth.
Fortunately, much had been reported -- the compact with <ent type='PERSON'>Mussolini</ent>,
the Concordat with <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent>, the enthusiastic support of <ent type='PERSON'>Franco</ent>, the
diplomatic arrangement with <ent type='GPE'>Japan</ent>, and so on -- before the
bestiality of Fascism had revealed itself, and such facts as that
the only voluntary "crusaders" against <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent> are from <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>
countries and the unconverted isolationists of <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> play up
strongly to the <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> minority, give us a basis in the Public
mind for a proper education.</p>

<p> It is therefore probable that there will not be the general
outcry against <ent type='GPE'>Rome</ent> that a man who has read the full evidence
would. expect. No other writer of influence has the courage and
honesty to warn the public, as <ent type='ORG'>Wells</ent> does, that instead of having
been reconciled with the modern spirit <ent type='ORG'>the Church</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>Rome</ent> is as
dangerous an enemy of civilization as ever. One thing only would
cause <ent type='ORG'>the Church</ent> the deepest alarm: if the victory of democracy
were to put <ent type='ORG'>Communism</ent> and Socialism back in the places they
occupied years ago. Will this happen?</p>

<p> It depends very largely upon <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>. When the war is over the
isolationists will be amongst the loudest to demand that <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>
shall have a leading voice in the settlement of Europe and <ent type='GPE'>China</ent>.
Every sensible man will welcome the aid of <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> in such a
restoration of Europe that, instead of sowing the dragon's teeth as
we did at Versailles at the close of the last war, we have every
guarantee that is humanly possible of a lasting peace. But the
terms of settlement that have been so far announced are ominously
vague, and we know only too well what "stability" means on the lips
of these folk.</p>

<p> You will find, when the time comes, that the Vatican will make
a brazen attempt to secure a voice as one of the great stabilizing
forces. You will find <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>s everywhere combining with the
reactionaries who want to plan the new Europe. They will want
<ent type='PERSON'>Leo</ent>pold restored, men like <ent type='PERSON'>Bonnet</ent> put in power in <ent type='GPE'>France</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Franco</ent>
firmly established in <ent type='GPE'>Spain</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Salazar</ent> in <ent type='GPE'>Portugal</ent>, the royal
family propped on the throne of <ent type='GPE'>Italy</ent>, and so on. By hook or crook
they will try to get <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>, which will have won the war in Europe,
excluded from the settlement. They will insist that religion be
"strengthened," knowing that <ent type='NORP'>Roman</ent>ism,, Buddhism, and <ent type='ORG'>Islam</ent> have
worked on the side of our enemies, and that <ent type='ORG'>Communism</ent> be taken at
the Pope's valuation. If the present generation tolerates these
things and does not insist on the guilt of every party being
stamped upon the mind of the world they will deserve their future.
The struggle for the rights of man which has reddened Europe with
blood for a century and a half will enter upon a new phase.</p>

<div> **** ****</div>

<p> Reproducible <ent type='ORG'>Electronic Publishing</ent> can defeat censorship.</p>

<div> **** ****</div>

<p> Bank of Wisdom
Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
28
</p></xml>