<xml><p> 27 page printout
Reproducible Electronic Publishing can defeat censorship.</p>

<p> This file, its printout, or copies of either
are to be copied and given away, but NOT sold.</p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>Bank</ent> of Wisdom, Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
**** ****</p>

<p>Edited by E. <ent type='PERSON'>Haldeman</ent>-<ent type='PERSON'>Julius</ent></p>

<p>THE BLACK INTERNATIONAL No. 3</p>

<p> HOW THE <ent type='ORG'>CROSS</ent> COURTED THE <ent type='ORG'>SWASTIKA</ent>
FOR EIGHT YEARS</p>

<p> by Joseph McCabe</p>

<p> HALDEMAN-JULIUS PUBLICATION
GIRARD -- : -- KANSAS
**** ****</p>

<p> Chapter I</p>

<p> SOCIALISM EMPTIES THE CHURCHES</p>

<p> The aim of <ent type='ORG'>the Black International</ent> is to protect and augment
the power and wealth of the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>. Since however, the clergy do
not share their power, much less their wealth, with the laity, we
may define this aim more sharply. It is to protect and augment
their own wealth and power, especially that of the higher clergy
and the <ent type='PERSON'>Pope</ent> and his Court. History compels us to add that in
pursuing this aim <ent type='ORG'>the Black International</ent> is not restrained by any
considerations or sentiments which are not strictly ecclesiastical.</p>

<p> That statement, a <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> may object, may be formally correct
but it is malicious. The <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>, he holds -- because in this
respect the priests have taken him into their confidence wants
wealth and power only in order that it may more effectively promote
the spiritual interests and eternal welfare of men. So we
understood; and we understood also that that is why the priest
must, whenever it is necessary, ignore all ordinary human emotions
and interests. What are the things of time compared with those of
eternity? It is a nice formula. The sufferings of 100000000
<ent type='NORP'>Chinese</ent> under the red hooves of the <ent type='NORP'>Japanese</ent> are doubtless sad to
contemplate but the spiritual welfare of all <ent type='LOC'>Asia</ent> requires that the
<ent type='PERSON'>Pope</ent> shall not say so to his friend the <ent type='ORG'>Mikado</ent>. The first of
<ent type='PERSON'>Pacelli</ent>-Pius's famous Five Peace Principles, which won the
admiration of the world, is "the right to life and freedom of all
nations, big and small, powerful and weak. But the spiritual
welfare of the <ent type='NORP'>Abyssinians</ent> (and the <ent type='NORP'>Spaniards</ent>, <ent type='NORP'>Albanians</ent>, <ent type='NORP'>Greeks</ent>,
<ent type='NORP'>Serbs</ent>, etc.) is much more important than life or freedom so he had
no harsh words for his friend <ent type='PERSON'>Mussolini</ent>.</p>

<p> We might, indeed, if we had leisure to go into these matters,
inquire whether the enormous accession of wealth and power to the
<ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> after the conversion of <ent type='PERSON'>Constantine</ent> in the fourth century
and again during the <ent type='ORG'>Renaissance</ent> was really followed by a great
spiritual uplift or by a remarkable corruption of both people and
<ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>. But we have not time for these digressions. Here we have to
consider contemporary events.</p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>Bank</ent> of Wisdom
Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
1
.
HOW THE <ent type='ORG'>CROSS</ent> COURTED THE <ent type='ORG'>SWASTIKA</ent></p>

<p> Now we saw in the first booklet of this series that the need
of <ent type='ORG'>the Black International</ent> to protect its wealth and power was
never greater than it is today. In my Decay of the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>Rome</ent>
(1909) I proved to the satisfaction of everybody except Catholic's,
who have a short way of differing from me without reading me, that
in the course of the nineteenth century the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> lost, in actual
seceders and descendants of seceders, about 100000000 followers.
It lost almost if not quite as many during the next 35 years, or
between 1900 and 1935. The leakage steadily continued, even
increased in all countries except those, such as <ent type='GPE'>Ireland</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Poland</ent>
in which the priests could keep then people in blinkers. The
progress of Socialism, against which the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> had declared war to
the death, made the leakage worse, and after the <ent type='NORP'>Russian</ent> Revolution
it became a flood. In <ent type='GPE'>Spain</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Italy</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Austria</ent>, and <ent type='LOC'><ent type='NORP'>Latin</ent> <ent type='GPE'>America</ent></ent> we
have the decisive evidence of electoral statistics, which show a
world-loss of at least 60000000 since the last war. Even for a
small country like <ent type='GPE'>Czecho</ent>-<ent type='GPE'>Slovakia</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>s, we shall see, admit
a loss of about 2000000 in fifteen years, and the drift continued
in <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Britain</ent>. Nor was it only a question of the
humiliation of losing so many members. The <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> in <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> was
estimated to have a wealth of $20000000000, and it was melting
away.</p>

<p> These spectacular losses are the key to the policy which
<ent type='PERSON'>Pacelli</ent> followed, first as Secretary of State and then as <ent type='PERSON'>Pope</ent> Pius
XII. When you know of these indisputable losses, which are not
obtruded upon public notice, you see that the line followed by the
Black International was quite inevitable in view of its primary
aim. It is the folk who do not know of the losses who are puzzled
by the plain evidence of the <ent type='NORP'>Italian</ent> Church's enthusiastic support
of <ent type='PERSON'>Mussolini</ent> in all his crimes, <ent type='ORG'>the Vatican</ent>'s open alliance with
<ent type='GPE'>Japan</ent>, or the Pope's strident call upon various governments to
cooperate with him in the extinction, by war, of <ent type='NORP'>Bolshevism</ent> in
<ent type='GPE'>Spain</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>China</ent>, and <ent type='GPE'>Mexico</ent>. Therefore in dealing with each
country in which we trace the action of <ent type='ORG'>the Black International</ent> I
give definite evidence from electoral statistics or <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>
admissions of the enormous losses of the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>. In the last book
I showed this in the case of <ent type='GPE'>Italy</ent> and South <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>.</p>

<p> It is vitally necessary in the case of <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent>. References to
the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> in that country suggests to the reader at one moment
that it is tremendously wealthy and powerful -- a good third of the
nation -- and the next day represent it as cowering powerlessly
under the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> lash. The <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n public his been particularly
puzzled by Cardinal <ent type='PERSON'>Mundelein</ent> making himself the chief spokesman of
the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>. Here was a great <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>man, praised in the highest
terms by the <ent type='PERSON'>Pope</ent> and the warmest friend of <ent type='PERSON'>Pacelli</ent> when he visited
<ent type='GPE'>America</ent>, scourging the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>s at a time when no statesman in the
world ventured to warn his people of the coming evil.</p>

<p> The human side of these consecrated movements is always
interesting. <ent type='PERSON'>Mundelein</ent> sent larger sums to the Papal treasury than
any other cardinal in the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> and promised even vaster funds
when prosperity returned to <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>. So <ent type='ORG'>the Vatican</ent> courageously
refused to condemn him when requested by <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> to do so. Besides,
it was convenient to have a rather muddle-headed enthusiast
assuring <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> that these charges of vice against <ent type='ORG'>the holy</ent> monks </p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>Bank</ent> of Wisdom
Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
2
.
HOW THE <ent type='ORG'>CROSS</ent> COURTED THE <ent type='ORG'>SWASTIKA</ent></p>

<p>of <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> were wicked <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> fabrications to cover a
persecution of the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>. It was not necessary to tell <ent type='PERSON'>Mundelein</ent>
that, as we shall see presently, the <ent type='PERSON'>Pope</ent> had already suppressed
the whole body of these <ent type='NORP'>Franciscan</ent> monks in <ent type='GPE'>Westphalia</ent> for
comprehensive corruption -- they were all in jail Anyway -- and
that the <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> bishop of <ent type='GPE'>Berlin</ent> had told <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> in a published
letter that the bishops of <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> admitted that there was a large
amount of "moral perversity" in the monastic world. How could
<ent type='PERSON'>Mundelein</ent> know that <ent type='ORG'>the Vatican</ent> and the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> hierarchy were still
pressing <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> to be friends? He had sworn to exterminate
<ent type='NORP'>Bolshevism</ent>, after a kiss of betrayal, and there was nothing in the
whole world that <ent type='ORG'>the Vatican</ent> more fiercely desired than the
destruction of <ent type='NORP'>Bolshevism</ent>, by hook or by crook, in every country.</p>

<p> When the <ent type='PERSON'>Pope</ent>, who would presently so solemnly assert "the
right to life and freedom of all nations," was asked to condemn the
invasion of <ent type='GPE'>Norway</ent>, the beginning of Hitler's monstrous enslavement
of Europe, he objected that there were only 2000 <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>s in
<ent type='GPE'>Norway</ent> and he had to think of the consequences for the "30000000
<ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>s of <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent>." What he meant was that, since the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> of
<ent type='GPE'>Rome</ent> does not admit that a man can quit it when his reason or his
conscience demands this, there were in <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> some 30000000 men
and women and their children who had received <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> baptism. In
1905 the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> claimed to have 25000000 members. Taking into
account the beautiful fertility of <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> parents these ought by
1940 to have grown to at least 35000000. In point of fact it is
easy to show that there were at the latter date not more than
15000000 <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>s, probably not more than 10000000.
This implies a loss in the present generation of at least
15000000, probably 20000000; and this loss is not so much due
to the action of the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>s as to the rapid growth of Socialism and
Communism since 1918. It implies also a proportionate loss of
wealth.</p>

<p> The new world-conditions which led to the disintegration of
the medieval <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> everywhere -- the advance of culture, universal
free education, cheap literature and free libraries, the growth of
urban and industrial populations, etc, -- had had at least as
devastating an effect in <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> as in <ent type='GPE'>Britain</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>. Think
of the huge circulation of such writers as <ent type='PERSON'>Nietzsche</ent> and Haeckel.
In cities like <ent type='GPE'>Berlin</ent> hardly a fifth of the inhabitants went to
church. But in <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> the <ent type='NORP'>Roman</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> had special conditions.
<ent type='PERSON'>Bismarck</ent> had switched off his attack on <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>ism from 1872 to
1881 and directed it to the Socialists, and he now had the
enthusiastic alliance of the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>. Some say that Socialism is a
crime, and some that it is folly, but the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> said that it is a
sin; which, of course, is much more likely to got men to avoid it.
The <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>s organized politically in a <ent type='ORG'>Center Party</ent> and a
<ent type='ORG'>Bavarian People</ent>'s Party, and there was a very sharp line of
division between. <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> votes and those of the sinful Socialists
and even worse <ent type='NORP'>Communists</ent>. Thirty years ago the Social Democratic
Federation dropped its official opposition to all <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>es, on the
painfully familiar plea of Socialist leaders that this would
shorten the path to power, but this did not affect the
irreconcilable hostility between Socialists and <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>s. In fact,
when Communism in turn became a powerful force, as it did in
<ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent>, and in <ent type='ORG'>the Vatican</ent> policy Socialists and <ent type='NORP'>Communists</ent> were
lumped together as <ent type='NORP'>Bolsheviks</ent>, the mutual antagonism was increased.</p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>Bank</ent> of Wisdom
Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
3
.
HOW THE <ent type='ORG'>CROSS</ent> COURTED THE <ent type='ORG'>SWASTIKA</ent></p>

<p> I have earlier explained that in the very promising new phase
of <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> life between 1924 and 1930 the <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>s and Socialists
cooperated politically, and when <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>sm grew they had another link
in hatred of their common enemy. <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>s for the first time rose
to the highest offices in the state. But the bishops knew, and
<ent type='PERSON'>Pacelli</ent> who lived in <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> from 1917 to 1929 saw, that the
leakage from the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> was now disastrous. Before the 1914-1918
war the <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> vote had already fallen, in spite of the high
<ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> birth rate. from one-fifth to one-sixth of the total
electorate, whereas <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> writers like the <ent type='NORP'>Jesuit</ent> Father <ent type='PERSON'>Krose</ent>
had estimated that by superior birth rate alone <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>s would
raise their percentage of the population by one percent every
decade. After the war their percentage, instead of rising, fell
steeply, though the masses of <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> peasants and farmers
continued to have large families while the masses of non-<ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>
urban workers increasingly practiced birth control. It is enough to
quote the figures at the last <ent type='NORP'>democratic</ent> elections. In November
1932, when the last entirely free election was held, the combined
<ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> vote was 5326583 in a total of 35000000 votes or not
much more than one-seventh. In March, 1933, when <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> was
Chancellor and there was a good deal of trickery and intimidation
-- but, we shall see, complete freedom for the <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>s -- the
<ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> vote was 5496054 in 39316873, or less than one-seventh. <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>s who were represented in <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n literature as
one-third of the population could not in this supreme crisis get
one-seventh of the adult community. Their proportion would have
been even less if they had not had the energetic support of the
<ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> against <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent>, as the <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Emil Ritter</ent> shows in his work
<ent type='PERSON'>Der Weg des Politischen Katholizismus</ent> (1934). The <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> were ordered
by their rabbis to vote with the <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>s, and in <ent type='GPE'>Berlin</ent> the
<ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>s ran a <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> candidate.</p>

<p> Now turn to the other side, At the time when the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> began
to fight the Socialists the latter could poll only 349000 votes.
By 1907 the Socialist vote had risen to 3010800. The total number
of voters had doubled: the Socialist vote had increased ten-fold:
the <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> vote had, taking into account the growth of
population, considerably decreased. But again it will be enough to
quote the final figures, just before the sun of freedom sank below
the horizon. In November, 1932, the Socialists and <ent type='NORP'>Communists</ent>
polled 13712292 votes, or much more than a third of the adult
community, Before the March election Goering's men had fired the
<ent type='GPE'>Reichstag</ent> to raise the <ent type='NORP'>Communist</ent> scare and, as <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> was
Chancellor, Socialists and <ent type='NORP'>Communists</ent> were forbidden to hold
meetings and their papers suppressed, so the <ent type='NORP'>Communist</ent> vote fell
considerably and the Socialist vote slightly. Yet the two parties
still cast 12321684 votes, or moire than twice as many as the
combined (and free) <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> parties and nearly a third of the
whole. The <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>s, I may add, even in the final election, with the
help of the <ent type='NORP'>Communist</ent> scare, the Pope's blessing -- as we shall see
-- and corrupt tactics, did not get one-half of the total vote
(17265823 votes out of 39316873). <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> never voluntarily
accepted <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent>. His party took power because it was the largest of
ten.</p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>Bank</ent> of Wisdom
Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
4
.
HOW THE <ent type='ORG'>CROSS</ent> COURTED THE <ent type='ORG'>SWASTIKA</ent></p>

<p> The glibness with which works of reference continue year after
year to say that <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>s in <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> are one-third of the
population, or 25000000 out of 75000.000, make the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> puzzle
worse than ever for most people. How could a group of men who set
out upon one of the most colossal aggressive enterprises in history
begin by defying and persecuting one-third of the nation in
addition to a savage repression of the still larger body of
Socialists and <ent type='NORP'>Communists</ent>? Why are all our experts (or oracles)
convinced that the overwhelming majority of the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> people
support <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> yet pay respectful attention to the shrieks of men
like the late Cardinal <ent type='PERSON'>Mundelein</ent> that the <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> third of the
nation is bitterly persecuted?</p>

<p> The truth is plainly shown in the above figures. As late as
the November election of 1932 -- we shall see presently what
happened after it -- the <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> hierarchy was violently opposed
to Socialism and Communism as well as to <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> and insisted on
<ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>s voting for <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> candidates. This was easy in <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent>,
where the main body of the <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>s is found in certain provinces
where they form the great majority of the community. On this
occasion, moreover, the appeal of the bishop to their flocks was
the most urgent and solemn since <ent type='PERSON'>Bismarck</ent> had fought the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> 60
years earlier. Is it seriously suggested that any large proportion
of genuine <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>s voted, in so grave a crisis, either for the
Socialists or for the bunch of apostates who, their leaders said,
were just as anxious as the Socialists to abolish the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>? If
you want to make an allowance for invalids and other possibilities
remember that on the other hand the <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>s had the support of
half a million <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, who were too scattered to have their own
candidates. In the circumstance's the voting figures give us a much
safer indication of the truth than any statements of writers.</p>

<p> These figures show that in 1932 <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>s were 13 percent, not
33 percent, of the adult community. A desperate apologist might
suggest that in <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent>, differently from in other countries, the
young are more religious than the older folk and this would give
the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> a larger total than the election figure's suggest. Such
an apologist would have to be very ignorant of <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> conditions.
In Great <ent type='GPE'>Briton</ent>, priests publicly admit that in many towns 50
percent of the boys quit the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> when they leave the school. And
in <ent type='GPE'>Britain</ent> the atmosphere is not quite as poisonous for the young,
from the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> angle, as in <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent>. You have heard of the
Strength through Joy movement, but you may not have heard how
youths have a song with the refrain, "On the heath and in the
meadows I lose my Strength through Joy," how working girls sing on
the streets a hymn to <ent type='PERSON'>Mary</ent> which suggests -- I forget the exact
words -- that her name was probably <ent type='PERSON'>Cohen</ent> and her baby was born on
the wrong side of the blanket. But suppose we take a generous view.
Thirteen percent of the nation in 1932 meant about 12000000
<ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>s. Make what allowance you like for absenteeism from the
polls (though every possible voter was whipped up) or other
factors, but you cannot raise that figure to 15000000, which is
only half what the <ent type='PERSON'>Pope</ent> claims.</p>

<p> And it is admitted that since 1932 the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> has suffered
further and catastrophic losses. The organization which held the
<ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> body together is torn to shreds. Think of the numerous </p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>Bank</ent> of Wisdom
Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
5
.
HOW THE <ent type='ORG'>CROSS</ent> COURTED THE <ent type='ORG'>SWASTIKA</ent></p>

<p>societies (<ent type='ORG'>Knights</ent> of Columbus, Daughters of <ent type='PERSON'>Mary</ent>, etc.) which in
<ent type='GPE'>America</ent> are extremely important in keeping the faithful loyal and
docile to the clergy. They are all suppressed in <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent>. The two
political parties are dissolved. The <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> press, the supreme
instrument of the clergy, is ruined. "All that remains of the one-time great <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> press of <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent>," said <ent type='ORG'>the Vatican</ent> Radio in
March (1941), "are a few parish magazines, and even these have to
be edited with the greatest care." All <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> schools in the
<ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> provinces have been closed and all the charitable and
other institutions which were one of the chief advertisements of
the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> have been taken over. All religious brothers, nuns,
etc., have been ignominiously expelled from education and every
<ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> child knows from its <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> playmates that this is said to
be on account of a discovery of a plague of some kind of shameful
wickedness amongst them. A ghastly reproach has been put upon the
whole by jailing thousands of them for moral turpitude and
seduction of the young. Then there is the economic pressure, as
good jobs must be got from <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> bosses, the social pressure, and so
on. There cannot be more than 10000000 <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>s in <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent>
today, and that means a loss of at least 15000000, if not
20000000. The <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> author of a special article in <ent type='ORG'>the London</ent>
Daily Express (November 15, 1939) the most widely circulated paper
in the world said that by 1936 priests in the <ent type='GPE'>Rhineland</ent> admitted
that they had lost half their flocks and added that "if the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>s
remain in power another decade <ent type='NORP'>Roman</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>ism may be obliterated
from <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent>." That is stronger language than I have used.</p>

<p> Any man who finds this difficult to understand may reflect on
the following experience. A friend of mine, a person of high
character and a <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> by baptism, went in 1937 to pay a
prolonged visit to relatives and friends in the <ent type='GPE'>Rhineland</ent>, his old
home. Everywhere he found the <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>s speaking with genial
disdain both of the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>s and the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>. It was a mainly <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>
district, and when my friend asked what they thought of the charges
of vice against the monks they laughingly replied that they had
always had a suspicion about life in those institutions. <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>
belief, in other words, was never so deep amongst them as <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>
writers pretend. They just wanted to be left alone to drink and
feed and smoke in the way of their fathers. How are such folk
likely to have fared under the pressure of the last five years?</p>

<p> However that may be, stupendous losses are, as I said,
admitted. And these losses are the key to <ent type='ORG'>the Vatican</ent> policy in
<ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent>. It is to check them and to recover ground that, in spite
of one deception after another, <ent type='ORG'>the Vatican</ent> has ordered <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>
<ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>s to submit and has tried year after year to enter into
alliance with <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent>. That is why the <ent type='PERSON'>Pope</ent> in spite of his discreet
letters of sympathy to Queen <ent type='PERSON'>Wilhelmina</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>King Leopold</ent> and his
protests against the ghastly attempts to annihilate the <ent type='NORP'>Poles</ent> after
they had been conquered, never uttered one word of straight moral
condemnation of any one of the long series of cynical breaches of
treaties, ruthless aggressions, and foul treatment of subject
peoples by which the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> government has roused against itself the
anger and disgust of the whole free world except its <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>
allies. That terrible indictment I will proceed to justify point by
point.</p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>Bank</ent> of Wisdom
Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
6
.
HOW THE <ent type='ORG'>CROSS</ent> COURTED THE <ent type='ORG'>SWASTIKA</ent></p>

<p> Chapter 11</p>

<p> THE POPE JOINS THE GANG</p>

<p> We saw that two grave dilemmas confronted <ent type='PERSON'>Pacelli</ent> when, in
1930, he became Secretary of State to the late <ent type='PERSON'>Pope</ent> and took over
<ent type='ORG'>the supreme control</ent> of the international policy of <ent type='ORG'>the Vatican</ent>.
There was an acrid quarrel with <ent type='PERSON'>Mussolini</ent> over the terms of the
Treaty and Concordat he had signed and a request from <ent type='GPE'>Japan</ent> that
the <ent type='ORG'>Papacy</ent> should recognize its annexation of <ent type='GPE'>Manchuria</ent>, which the
conscience of the civilized world condemned. We saw how he resolved
these dilemmas. He linked the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> firmly to two partners of the
criminal Conspiracy; which would come to be known as the <ent type='ORG'>Axis</ent>. He
had hardly accomplished this, when the third problem arose. <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent>,
doubtless encouraged by <ent type='ORG'>the holy</ent> alliance with <ent type='GPE'>Italy</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Japan</ent>,
sent an emissary to ask for recognition of his share in the brewing
plot against civilization. He got it. <ent type='ORG'>The Black International</ent>
joined the gang.</p>

<p> When you sum up events in this bold fashion many folk shake
their heads skeptically, so, although in the mad rush of life in
our time it seems almost to be ancient history -- it is less than
ten years old -- I must briefly repeat the evidence of what
happened in 1932. Remember that <ent type='PERSON'>Pacelli</ent> knew <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> thoroughly. He
had left it, after twelve years close observation of its life, in
1929, and his new office as Secretary of State compelled him to
watch carefully the critical course of events in that country.</p>

<p> Bitterly as he hated Socialism, because he expected it
everywhere sooner or later to turn to the <ent type='NORP'>Russian</ent> model and declare
religion "the opium of the people," he was fully aware that in face
of the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> threat and in view of the distress which the world-slump and the sudden cessation of loans had brought upon the
country the <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>s were cooperating with the Socialists under a
<ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> Chancellor, <ent type='ORG'>Bruning</ent>, and later the <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> General von
Schleicher. <ent type='ORG'>Bruning</ent> was a shrewd opportunist who leaned to the
Right or the Left as occasion required, but he was a good
statesman. As long as he held together the coalition of <ent type='NORP'>Liberals</ent>,
<ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>s, <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, Socialists, and <ent type='NORP'>Communist</ent> the Nazi's had no chance
of success. It was in very large part <ent type='ORG'>the Vatican</ent> that ruined this
defense and the leadership of <ent type='ORG'>Bruning</ent> by forcing him away from the
Socialists and patronizing the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>s.</p>

<p> That <ent type='PERSON'>Pacelli</ent> was guilty of a criminal blunder must be
admitted. He knew that <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> had already given proof of his
duplicity and of his infamous intentions but like <ent type='PERSON'>Mussolini</ent>, he
gambled on the success of <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> militarism and the spinelessness of
the democracies. All the world now knows how first the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>
industrialists, headed by <ent type='ORG'>Thyssen</ent> and <ent type='NORP'>Hagenberg</ent>, brought their
millions to the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> treasury and used every means in their power
to influence their <ent type='ORG'>Liberal and</ent> Radical workers in Hitler's favor.
The new <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> Party emerged from as slimy a mess of intrigue and
deception as one can imagine. <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> had won a large body of the
workers -- the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> group had started as a semi-Socialist working-class movement, pure and simple -- by promising to improve their </p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>Bank</ent> of Wisdom
Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
7
.
HOW THE <ent type='ORG'>CROSS</ent> COURTED THE <ent type='ORG'>SWASTIKA</ent></p>

<p>condition at the expense of "the bloated capitalist." By 1931
<ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> welcomed the gold of the capitalist -- and any other gold
that came along -- and sold his semi-Socialism. Ambassador <ent type='PERSON'>Dodd</ent>,
who was then in <ent type='GPE'>Berlin</ent>, describes in his Diary how he saw the
<ent type='NORP'>royalists</ent> and land-owners as well as the industrialists buzzing
round the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> headquarters.</p>

<p> <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> double-crossed them all. He took their money and rose
in November, 1932, to the electoral strength which I have
described. In 1930 the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> vote had been one-sixth of the whole.
In 1932 it was one-third. But they had used up all their resources
and were very dejected. They could get no more from the <ent type='NORP'>Liberals</ent>
and <ent type='NORP'>Conservatives</ent> and they could not approach the Socialists and
<ent type='NORP'>Communists</ent>, however ready they were to sell what soul they had to
the devil. What about the <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>s?</p>

<p> <ent type='PERSON'>Von Papen</ent> was the queerest figure in the bunch of <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>
leaders. His <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> standing was such that he received a high
decoration from <ent type='ORG'>the Vatican</ent> -- he is a Chamberlain of the Papal
Court -- and he was a friend of the very conservative President
<ent type='GPE'>Hindenburg</ent> and the <ent type='NORP'>Prussian</ent> aristocrats. In the summer of 1932 he
had, through his influence with <ent type='GPE'>Hindenburg</ent>, got the Chancellorship
away from <ent type='ORG'>Bruning</ent>, though he had in turn soon lost it to the
<ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> General <ent type='PERSON'>von Schleicher</ent>. Note carefully that <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> thus
had three <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> Chancellors (Premiers) in succession, an honor
of which they had not hitherto dreamed, under the Liberal-Socialist
coalition, which <ent type='PERSON'>Pacelli</ent> helped to destroy in favor of the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>s.
<ent type='PERSON'>Von Schleicher</ent>, in close touch with the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> hierarchy, adopted
an even more pronounced policy of cooperation with the Socialists
against the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>s than <ent type='ORG'>Bruning</ent> had followed. With their support he
dared to publish the fact that the aristocratic <ent type='NORP'>Prussian</ent> land-owners had shamelessly dipped into the public funds, and <ent type='PERSON'>Von Papen</ent>
easily persuaded <ent type='GPE'>Hindenburg</ent> to protect their noble caste by
dismissing <ent type='PERSON'>Von Schleicher</ent> and making <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> Chancellor. He would
now control the next election; and the greasy <ent type='PERSON'>Goering</ent> would do
dirty work in the country for him.</p>

<p> About the same time, the beginning of 1933, <ent type='PERSON'>Von Papen</ent> was sent
to <ent type='GPE'>Rome</ent> to propose an alliance with <ent type='ORG'>the Vatican</ent>. It is quite stupid
to affect to dispute these statements because <ent type='PERSON'>Von Papen</ent> in a
published speech (Der 12 November, 1933, p. 7), which I have read,
actually boasts of his work. On November 9, 1933, he made this
speech to a very large audience of <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> working men at <ent type='GPE'>Cologne</ent>,
speaking as one <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> to others and rousing them to support
<ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent>. He said, unctuously: "Providence destined me to render an
essential service in the birth of the government of the national
regeneration." As his bosom friends, <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Goebbels</ent>, were
apostates and half the secondary leaders were notoriously
sodomists, I do not wonder that folk find this chapter of <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>
history perplexing, but that <ent type='PERSON'>Von Papen</ent> did in fact propose to
<ent type='PERSON'>Pacelli</ent>, in Hitler's name, that he should order the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>
<ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>s to drop their hostility to the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>s in return for, when
they attained power, a favorable Concordat with the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> --
during his twelve years in <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Pacelli</ent> had tried in vain to get
this -- and that <ent type='PERSON'>Pacelli</ent> accepted is abundantly proved, and most
clearly by the subsequent course of events.</p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>Bank</ent> of Wisdom
Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
8
.
HOW THE <ent type='ORG'>CROSS</ent> COURTED THE <ent type='ORG'>SWASTIKA</ent></p>

<p> Early in 1933 the statement was widely repeated. in the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>
Press that the bishops, meeting at <ent type='ORG'>Fulda</ent>, had received instructions
from <ent type='GPE'>Rome</ent> to abandon the hostility to <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> and had passed these
on to the clergy. It is further stated in all histories of the time
that in preparation for the March election only <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>s and <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>s
were allowed to organize and appeal to the country. See, in
particular, the account, which will certainly not be accused of
anti-<ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> bias, in <ent type='PERSON'>Seldes</ent> (The Vatican). He adds that one of
the <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> clerical leaders, Msgr. <ent type='ORG'>Kaas</ent>, was sent to <ent type='GPE'>Rome</ent> to
advise <ent type='PERSON'>Pacelli</ent> to agree and that he said of <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent>: "This man, the
bearer of high ideal's, will do all that is necessary to save the
nation from catastrophe."</p>

<p> I gather that there were already some in the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> who
were in favor of alliance with <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent>. A few years later one of the
most important priests in <ent type='GPE'>Munich</ent> died and his funeral was
officially honored by the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> government; and in the heat of the
later struggle, when many <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>s blamed Cardinal
<ent type='PERSON'>Faulhaber</ent>, head of their <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>, the <ent type='ORG'>Valerist</ent> paper, the Irish
Independent (August 13, 1938), which was in close touch with the
clergy, said that "Cardinal <ent type='PERSON'>Faulhaber</ent> was very friendly to National
Socialism in the beginning" -- in other words, until <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> double-crossed <ent type='ORG'>the Vatican</ent>. <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> had by this time begun to wash out any
suspicion that he would, if returned to power, injure the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>.
In one of his first speeches in the <ent type='GPE'>Reichstag</ent>, on March 23, 1933,
he said that "as we see in <ent type='NORP'>Christianity</ent> the unshakable foundation
of the moral life so it is our duty to continue to cultivate
friendly relations with the Holy See and to develop them."</p>

<p> The great majority in the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> could not so easily reconcile
themselves to cooperation with a disreputable bunch of apostates
and sodomists, and there were many complaints in the <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> press
when the bishops circulated the Papal order to observe at least
benevolent neutrality. The terms of the order are, of course, not
known but we may gather them from the result. <ent type='ORG'>The Annual Register</ent>
for 1933, says, in recording Hitler's triumph at the election: "The
gigantic swing-over of the <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> middle-class in <ent type='LOC'>West</ent> and South
<ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> to the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> Party broke the power of the old middle-class
<ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> parties, <ent type='ORG'>the Center</ent> and the <ent type='ORG'>Bavarian People</ent>'s Party" (p.
169). The word "gigantic" will seem misplaced if you look back upon
the electoral statistics I have given. The <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> vote fell but
not so heavily. But note that the writer is referring only to the
middle class, and it is significant that the <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> vote fell
even by 20000 when every party feverishly whipped all its
supporters to the poll.</p>

<p> It is, at all events, another witness to the change of
attitude of the <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>s under ecclesiastical direction, and a
fourth, and still more important witness, is a <ent type='NORP'>French</ent> priest
writing later in the <ent type='NORP'>French</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> fortnightly, the Revue des
Deux Mondes (January 15, 1935, article "Le catholicisme et la
politique mondiale") and boasting of it as one of the diplomatic
triumphs of <ent type='ORG'>the Vatican</ent>.</p>

<p> But surely these witnesses are superfluous in view of the
acknowledged fact that on July 20, 1933, <ent type='PERSON'>Pacelli</ent> proudly signed the
Concordat he had arranged with the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>s. Does anybody suppose that</p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>Bank</ent> of Wisdom
Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
9
.
HOW THE <ent type='ORG'>CROSS</ent> COURTED THE <ent type='ORG'>SWASTIKA</ent></p>

<p>the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>s' who are now represented as from the start a horde of
irreligious blackguards, went out of their way after they had won
their triumph, to promise <ent type='GPE'>Rome</ent> that they would respect rights which
it claimed and that were drastically opposed to their principles?
The man who writes history on suspicions and assumptions, cannot
complain if his readers are skeptical, but the apologist who
suggests such things as this must have readers who are incapable of
ordinary judgment. Hitler's aim was to form a totalitarian state in
the most literal sense: a state in which every implement of
instruction or mind-forming should be used by <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> officials to
instil racial pride and a readiness for aggressive war. Yet the
first thing he does after securing power is to promise a <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>
which he hates that it shall control the education of millions of
children, continue to have a press that is pledged to
internationalism and peace, and draft its members into societies
and fraternities for the cult of a <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> Bible and a Gospel of
Peace. He was carrying out a bargain; but one that he never had the
least intention of honoring in practice.</p>

<p> We no more say that <ent type='ORG'>the Black International</ent> put <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> in
power than we say that it caused the war. We will not even linger
to consider how much influence the Papal policy had amongst the
various corrupt factors that put him in power. The point is that
the <ent type='ORG'>Cross</ent> embraced the Swastika: the <ent type='PERSON'>Pope</ent> joined the Gang. The
Vatican sold its position as international moral censor as
shamefully as it had sold it to the other partners of the <ent type='ORG'>Axis</ent>.
Incredible? Then let the apologist quote any Papal condemnations of
the appalling crimes against humanity and civilization that have
been committed every year since <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> seized power. I decline to
count mild protests against actions which injured the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>.</p>

<p> The world, bemused by a press which could see nothing in the
future except "the menace of <ent type='NORP'>Bolshevism</ent>," took little notice of
this at the time. But let it not now be suggested that perhaps
<ent type='PERSON'>Pacelli</ent> himself understood <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>sm no more than the majority of
folk. After twelve years in <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> for the single purpose of
studying developments! A few years later editors began to profess
that they wished they could penetrate the secret of <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> policy. It
was tragicomic. The substantial part of Hitler's program -- it was
expanded when he saw the criminal sluggishness of Fiance and
<ent type='GPE'>Britain</ent> -- had been for years in <ent type='PERSON'>Mein Kampf</ent>. In 1938 I put in the
form of a program, in Hitler's own words, statements of his aims
which are scattered over, and often repeated in, that immense flood
of twaddle. It will be of use if I reproduce the main part of it
here.</p>

<p> "We must see that the strength of our people has, its roots,
not in colonies, but in land of our own in Europe (p. 754). The
regaining of our lost provinces cannot be achieved by solemn
appeals to God as pious hopes but only by force of arms (708). The
South Tyrol and our lost provinces can be won back only by a bloody
struggle (708). The most sacred right in the world is the right to
land that you can till yourself and the holiest sacrifice is the
blood you shed for it (755). Our policy in the East [<ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>] must
be that we will win more land for the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> people. Since we need
strength for this, yet the mortal enemy of our people, <ent type='GPE'>France</ent>,
strangles us mercilessly, we must make every sacrifice that is </p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>Bank</ent> of Wisdom
Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
10
.
HOW THE <ent type='ORG'>CROSS</ent> COURTED THE <ent type='ORG'>SWASTIKA</ent></p>

<p>necessary to destroy the position of <ent type='GPE'>France</ent> in Europe (757). This
policy can be carried out only by an alliance with <ent type='GPE'>England</ent> (689).
There, is no English, <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n, or <ent type='NORP'>Italian</ent> statesman who was ever
pro-<ent type='NORP'>German</ent>. Any man who says that we can form alliances with
foreign nations in virtue of a pro-<ent type='NORP'>German</ent> spirit in the leading
statesmen of those countries is either an ass or a liar (698). The
alliance with <ent type='GPE'>England</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Italy</ent> will enable <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> to make its
case, under the shelter of such a coalition, all the preparations
that are needed for a final settlement with <ent type='GPE'>France</ent> (755)."</p>

<p> There, written nearly twenty years ago, is the whole program
of duplicity, callousness, and aggression. As the current
"translation" of <ent type='PERSON'>Mein Kampf</ent>, subsidized by the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> government, was
grossly fraudulent. I translated these sentences, which are
expanded and justified at great length in the work, from the 1935
(mature) edition, and sent them to two editors of radical <ent type='GPE'>London</ent>
papers, with a circulation of about 4000000 copies, who professed
to be puzzled about Hitler's intentions. Both refused to print my
article, and <ent type='GPE'>Britain</ent> slumbered and blundered on.</p>

<p> If any man supposes that <ent type='PERSON'>Pacelli</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>the Vatican</ent> did not know
the contents of <ent type='PERSON'>Mein Kampf</ent>, which already circulated by the
million, he must have a singularly low estimate of the ability with
which their work is conducted. Before <ent type='PERSON'>Pacelli</ent> put his pen to
parchment the Day of the Long Knife, about which <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> youth's had
sung chants all over <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> for two years, occurred. More than
100000 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, <ent type='NORP'>Communists</ent>, Socialists, <ent type='NORP'>Pacifists</ent>, etc., were
barbarously treated and robbed of their possessions and in many
cases their lives. <ent type='PERSON'>Pacelli</ent> amiably continued to work out the
details of his compact with the devil, and the church bells rang
when it was signed. And the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> bishops deputed Cardinal Bertram
to assure <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> that they were "glad to express as soon as
possible" their joy at the agreement and their "sincere readiness
to cooperate to their best ability with the new government" (the
<ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> Universe, August 18, 1933). Hitler's followers, especially
the notorious pervert <ent type='PERSON'>Roehm</ent> and his friends, scorned the concordat
and insulted the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>, and infringements of the agreement began
at once. But when <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> writers say that Cardinal <ent type='PERSON'>Faulhaber</ent> at
once took a firm stand against the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> they gravely mislead their
reader's.</p>

<p> The sermons which <ent type='PERSON'>Faulhaber</ent> delivered can be read in an
English translation <ent type='NORP'>Judaism</ent>, <ent type='NORP'>Christianity</ent>, and <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent>, 1933). They
are a painful exhibition of moral cowardice and sycophancy. I have
already quoted the <ent type='ORG'>Valerist</ent> organ saying that <ent type='PERSON'>Faulhaber</ent> was
favorable to <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>sm "in the beginning." It adds that "the fact that
he found it impossible later not to oppose certain elements of
their policy, hurt us as well as annoyed them." What were these
elements? Did he, as a <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> prelate professes to regard as his
duty, censure <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> for his perjury in violating his solemn oath
to preserve the Constitution? Did he denounce the brutality of the
attack on <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> and Socialists? Not a word. His attack was purely
theological. The Anti-Semitic language of the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>s was opposed to
the <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> doctrine that the Old Testament was inspired and that
<ent type='PERSON'>Jehovah</ent> was the God of <ent type='NORP'>Christianity</ent> and was incarnated in the Jew
Jesus. The <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>s laughed at him. <ent type='PERSON'>Rosenberg</ent>, who had at that time
some idea that because I admired pre-<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> I could be won to
support them, sent me a copy of his drastic reply.</p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>Bank</ent> of Wisdom
Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
11
.
HOW THE <ent type='ORG'>CROSS</ent> COURTED THE <ent type='ORG'>SWASTIKA</ent></p>

<p> In the preceding book I said that <ent type='PERSON'>Pacelli</ent> at this time wrote
the most severe attack on <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> that ever carne from a Papal
source. He was engaged in his mission -- not a "good will" mission
but arranging a bloody <ent type='NORP'>Fascist</ent> reaction -- in South <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>. From
there he sent to Cardinal Schulte at <ent type='GPE'>Cologne</ent> a letter in which he
roused <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>s against the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> leaders. "When in Satanic
pride, false prophets arise, pretending to be the bearers of a new
creed," he said, it behooved the faithful to stir themselves, I
cannot trace that the Cardinal passed on the warning to his flock
but, in any case, what was the point of the attack?</p>

<p> In June (1934) <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> had surpassed his record of outrage to
date by the infamous Blood Purge in which <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> leaders like
General <ent type='PERSON'>von Schleicher</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Strasser</ent> were murdered together with
<ent type='PERSON'>Roehm</ent> and other notorious perverts. The excuse was a confused plea
that the party had to be morally purified and that there was a Plot
against <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent>. But whereas in the <ent type='NORP'>Russian</ent> executions, about which
the world press poured out streams of indignation, the conspiracy
was proved in open court after trials which distinguished foreign
lawyers declared unassailable, there was no pretense of a trial in
<ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent>. <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent>, already under the influence of the semi-insane
egoism that developed after his success, shouted "I am the law and
justice in <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent>", and the men -- hundreds of them -- were shot
down in their houses or their cells! Was this what <ent type='PERSON'>Pacelli</ent>
condemned? Not at all. He had heard that the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>s were helping
<ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>s who favored them to found in <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> a National <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>
<ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>, acknowledging no obedience to <ent type='GPE'>Rome</ent> and finding room for
<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> doctrines. Notice carefully that <ent type='PERSON'>Pacelli</ent> denounces the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>s
as "pretending to be the bearers of a new creed". So it was with
the protests of the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> bishops which are quoted. They
protested against the increasing violations of the Concordat by
interference with their schools and their <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> organizations.</p>

<p> Chapter III</p>

<p> HOW HE HELPED HITLER IN AUSTRIA</p>

<p> We shall resume presently the revolting story of how the <ent type='PERSON'>Pope</ent>,
with <ent type='PERSON'>Pacelli</ent> at his elbow, helped <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> to consolidate his power
in <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> but at this point it is necessary to turn aside and
consider what was happening in <ent type='GPE'>Austria</ent>. <ent type='GPE'>Bavaria</ent> is a sister-state
of <ent type='GPE'>Austria</ent> rather than of <ent type='GPE'>Prussia</ent>, and from <ent type='GPE'>Munich</ent>, its capitol,
<ent type='PERSON'>Pacelli</ent> had watched very closely the development in the southern
<ent type='GPE'>Republic</ent>. It was of absorbing interest from the ecclesiastical
angle. <ent type='GPE'>Austria</ent> was the only country in the world where a <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>
priest, Msgr. <ent type='PERSON'>Seipel</ent>, a man of intense loyalty to <ent type='ORG'>the Vatican</ent>, had
<ent type='ORG'>supreme power</ent>. During fourteen year's after the war <ent type='PERSON'>Seipel</ent>, a
professor of moral theology and a leader of the <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> Socialist
movement, was either himself Chancellor (President) or the power
behind the Chancellor. He represented the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>, for it at once
transpired that there was as much Socialism in <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> Socialism
as there is science in <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> Science.</p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>Bank</ent> of Wisdom
Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
12
.
HOW THE <ent type='ORG'>CROSS</ent> COURTED THE <ent type='ORG'>SWASTIKA</ent></p>

<p> The state was thus a theocracy, the only one in the world
except <ent type='ORG'>Thibet</ent>, and as such of profound interest to every Vatican
official. This interest was all the greater from the fact that,
while the state was <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>, its capitol, <ent type='GPE'>Vienna</ent>, was Socialist
and Atheistic. Socialism and Communism had made the same progress
in <ent type='GPE'>Austria</ent> after the war and the expulsion of the emperor as they
had made in <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent>. In <ent type='GPE'>Vienna</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Linz</ent>, and other industrial towns
the Socialists had outvoted the <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>s and <ent type='NORP'>Liberals</ent> in the
municipal elections and had won control and carried out their
principles in a civic policy. Two features of their rule must be
noted.</p>

<p> The first is that the <ent type='GPE'>Austria</ent>n Socialists were emphatically
anti-<ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>. The well-known amiability (<ent type='ORG'>Gutmuthlichkeit</ent>) of the
<ent type='GPE'>Austria</ent>n character saved them from the worst libels of <ent type='NORP'>Bolsheviks</ent>
that were served upon the world-press, but the fierce hostility to
them of the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>, which made fruitless constitutional efforts to
capture <ent type='GPE'>Vienna</ent>, hardened their attitude to it. Here every vote cast
for Socialist or a <ent type='NORP'>Communist</ent> was sternly pronounced a vote against
the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>. "Even to this day," says C.A. <ent type='PERSON'>Macartney</ent>, a
distinguished and conservative scholar of <ent type='ORG'>Rambridge University</ent>,
"the real battle of <ent type='GPE'>Austria</ent>n Socialism is directed against the
<ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>" (The Social Revolution in <ent type='GPE'>Austria</ent>, 1926, p. 54). And the
Socialists continued to win, large numbers from the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> year
after year and to gain ground in the country. At the 1927 election
they polled 830000 votes outside <ent type='GPE'>Vienna</ent> and increased their vote
in <ent type='GPE'>Vienna</ent> by 120000. Is it a mere coincidence that in that year
the <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> Socialist government began to resort to persecution
and violence?</p>

<p> The second feature was of no interest at all to churchmen but
ought to have been -- and was not -- frankly described in the
press. It is that while <ent type='GPE'>Austria</ent> as a whole under its clerical
'statesmen' was so badly administered that <ent type='ORG'>the League</ent> of Nations
had to step in periodically to save it from bankruptcy, <ent type='GPE'>Vienna</ent>, in
spite of the heavy depression caused by the mutilation of the
country at <ent type='GPE'>Versailles</ent>, effected a very remarkable social
improvement. I was in <ent type='GPE'>Vienna</ent> when it took 500 <ent type='GPE'>Kronen</ent> -- a <ent type='ORG'>Krone</ent>
used to be worth 50c -- to buy a small apple, and a very small
cake, or the cheapest postage stamp, and half the workers were so
near "starving" that, the police told me, civil war was feared. Yet
after years of this, and still seriously crippled economically,
<ent type='GPE'>Vienna</ent> made extraordinary progress in education, housing, and other
social reforms. I have described it elsewhere and need say here
only that every impartial social student in Europe acknowledged it.
<ent type='PERSON'>Macartriey</ent> says that in a few months the Socialist Municipal
Council "did more to better the condition of the masses than had
previous decades of legislation from above": <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> legislation,
you understand, A <ent type='GPE'>London</ent> daily which is opposed to Socialism said
of this Socialist administration after the <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>s had
treacherously destroyed it that it had been "a model of <ent type='NORP'>democratic</ent>
government, as close to the ideal platonic <ent type='GPE'>Republic</ent> as the world
has ever seen" (News-Chronicle, February 12, 1935).</p>

<p> The <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> editor was wrong on one point. <ent type='GPE'>Vienna</ent> was not
closer to the ideal <ent type='GPE'>Republic</ent> than <ent type='GPE'>Moscow</ent>, and <ent type='GPE'>Madrid</ent> and (with
reserves on account of the mass of illiteracy) <ent type='GPE'>Mexico</ent> City were </p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>Bank</ent> of Wisdom
Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
13
.
HOW THE <ent type='ORG'>CROSS</ent> COURTED THE <ent type='ORG'>SWASTIKA</ent></p>

<p>approaching it under Socialist rule. If it seems rash to claim that
this was of no interest from the ecclesiastical angle you have only
to reflect on the facts. Had <ent type='ORG'>the Vatican</ent>, indeed in this case
<ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>s throughout the world, given any consideration to the
actual social fruits of <ent type='NORP'>Bolshevism</ent> when from 1935 onward they
shrieked for its extinction in <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Spain</ent>, and <ent type='GPE'>Mexico</ent>? The laity
were obviously ignorant of the truth. Their <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> press never
mentioned countries or cities under Socialist rule except to repeat
the most venomous libels about their social condition. Were the
higher clergy equally ignorant? If you can suppose that they were,
you have to conclude that they were blind to every issue but one --
the wealth and power of <ent type='ORG'>the Black International</ent>.</p>

<p> As I have written at length elsewhere, particularly in the
Appeal to Reason Library No. 5., on the development in <ent type='GPE'>Austria</ent> I
sum up the events briefly, with the addition of a few details that
have since transpired. The most important of these additions is
that we have now to review all these events since 1930 in the light
of Pacelli's scheme to have Socialism destroyed by alliance with
anti-Socialist powers, however criminal and unsavory they might be.
In 1934 his plan was not fully developed. He saw Socialism spread
in <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> but the destructive power was still almost below the
political horizon when he left the country. He saw it spread, with
devastating consequences to the <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> missions, in <ent type='GPE'>China</ent>, and he
linked the <ent type='ORG'>Papacy</ent> with <ent type='GPE'>Japan</ent>. He saw it in South <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> and went
there to bring the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> and the wealthy to a practical agreement.
He saw it in <ent type='GPE'>Mexico</ent> but, for lack of definite evidence, we do not
say that in his visit to the States he encouraged the idea of a
beautiful <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>-Wall-Street alliance. He saw it in <ent type='GPE'>Spain</ent> and
promoted the slowly maturing plot to destroy it. He saw it in
<ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>, but until 1936 he still dreamed of a friendly alliance with
the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> authorities, and it was only when he definitely
abandoned this hope that he gave the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> the slogan: Extinguish
<ent type='NORP'>Bolshevism</ent> in <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>China</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Mexico</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Spain</ent>. It was already
extinct, with his assistance, in <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Italy</ent>.</p>

<p> In 1933 his plans were still piecemeal, and <ent type='GPE'>Austria</ent> was the
next obvious, province for his intrigues. By this time it was
evident that in a field of fair propaganda and free discussion the
Socialists won every time, and it could not plausibly be said in
the case of <ent type='GPE'>Austria</ent>, as it was lyingly said of <ent type='GPE'>Italy</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent>,
that Socialism led to distress and disorder. The only serious
criticism I have seen of the fine social work done in <ent type='GPE'>Vienna</ent> is
that it was financed by foreign loan's which were advanced for a
different purpose. That is false The city council at <ent type='GPE'>Vienna</ent> never
received any part of the advances. They went to the <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent>
Socialist government, which means in large part to the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>.
<ent type='GPE'>Vienna</ent> paid its way by taxes and a financial system of great
ability.</p>

<p> There was a special difficulty in the case of <ent type='GPE'>Austria</ent>: the
mutual jealousy of <ent type='PERSON'>Mussolini</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent>, who still hated and
distrusted each other and each wanted control of <ent type='GPE'>Austria</ent>. The
Vatican favored <ent type='GPE'>Italy</ent>, especially as before the end of 1933 <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent>
betrayed his duplicity and <ent type='GPE'>Austria</ent> was predominantly <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>. In
1931 the <ent type='PERSON'>Pope</ent>, assisted by <ent type='PERSON'>Pacelli</ent>, had issued an Encyclical to the
effect that the <ent type='NORP'>Italian</ent> corporative state was (especially as it </p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>Bank</ent> of Wisdom
Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
14
.
HOW THE <ent type='ORG'>CROSS</ent> COURTED THE <ent type='ORG'>SWASTIKA</ent></p>

<p>bowed to Canon Law, put education under the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>, and heavily
subsidized the clergy) the model for <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> countries. The
corporative state meant, of course, the destruction of Socialism
and Trade Unions, the workers being drafted into corporations under
the firm hand of <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> and State, and the recognition of the
capitalists right of private property (or all the wealth he could
make) with a right of the state to conscript such of the wealth as
it needed. <ent type='GPE'>Portugal</ent> had adopted the scheme, as <ent type='GPE'>France</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Spain</ent>
have since done.</p>

<p> <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent>, though he affected to despise the <ent type='GPE'>Austria</ent>ns, was by no
means willing to see it pass under <ent type='NORP'>Italian</ent> influence or, as the
<ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>s wanted, restore the imperial rule, but he was not yet in
a position to force a bargain upon <ent type='PERSON'>Mussolini</ent>. As I quoted, he had
written long before this in <ent type='PERSON'>Mein Kampf</ent> that <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>s must win back
by force of arms even <ent type='GPE'>the South Tyrol</ent> from <ent type='GPE'>Italy</ent>, which had been
awarded it, at <ent type='GPE'>Versailles</ent>. This meant the annexation of <ent type='GPE'>Austria</ent>. He
cynically watched the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> coquetting in <ent type='GPE'>Austria</ent> with <ent type='NORP'>Italian</ent>
Fascism. If they chose to destroy Socialism for him, so much the
better. And Socialism was, in spite of its steady progress, doomed
from 1927. It not only mocked the financial ineptness of the
national government but it brought to light a series of grave
scandals in connection with the government and its supporters.
<ent type='PERSON'>Seipel</ent> rallied to his support all the industrialists and landowners
and looked round for a knight in shining armor like <ent type='PERSON'>Mussolini</ent> or
<ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent>.</p>

<p> Prince <ent type='GPE'>Starhemberg</ent>, a conceited puppy of the type of <ent type='ORG'>Ciano</ent> or
<ent type='LOC'>Suner</ent>, but a wealthy noble, chose himself for the part. By Seipel's
treacherous connivance and with <ent type='NORP'>Italian</ent> assistance he was allowed
to create a private <ent type='NORP'>Fascist</ent> army, the <ent type='ORG'>Heimwehr</ent> -- "created in its
final form by <ent type='PERSON'>Seipel</ent>," says the Annual Register, and <ent type='PERSON'>Seipel</ent> did
nothing independently of <ent type='ORG'>the Vatican</ent> -- which very obviously
intended to attack the Socialists and <ent type='NORP'>Communists</ent>. In fact,
<ent type='GPE'>Starhemberg</ent> provoked a clash prematurely, but the <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>
government had so small a majority in the <ent type='ORG'>Reichsrath</ent> that it was
beaten. <ent type='PERSON'>Seipel</ent> was driven from the Chancellorship and streams of
<ent type='GPE'>Austria</ent>ns quitted the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> (1933).</p>

<p> <ent type='PERSON'>Seipel</ent> and the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> put into the Chancellorship a priest-ridden little man of peasant extraction and no particular ability
whom the <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n press came to glorify as "gallant little
<ent type='PERSON'>Dollfuss</ent>." You may remember how he "stood up to <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent>"; though it
was not clearly explained at the time that in resisting <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>sm he
was defending Fascism. In his first budget as Chancellor he
admitted a deficit of $70000000, a colossal sum for so small a
state and after all the loans, and he rarely had a majority of more
than one in <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>. The railway-men, who were very largely
Socialists, disclosed the fact that, against international
agreement, he was allowing <ent type='GPE'>Italy</ent> to use <ent type='GPE'>Austria</ent>n railroads to send
arms secretly into Hungary; which also <ent type='GPE'>Italy</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>the Vatican</ent> wanted
to make <ent type='NORP'>Fascist</ent> and allied to <ent type='GPE'>Italy</ent>. <ent type='PERSON'>Dollfuss</ent> solemnly assured
<ent type='GPE'>France</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Britain</ent> that the traffic should cease, but he secretly
maintained it, and the Socialists again exposed it. So "the
Socialist watch-dog had to be destroyed." That is the language of
the Annual Register in its impartial summary of the events of 1933.</p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>Bank</ent> of Wisdom
Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
15
.
HOW THE <ent type='ORG'>CROSS</ent> COURTED THE <ent type='ORG'>SWASTIKA</ent></p>

<p> <ent type='PERSON'>Dollfuss</ent> went to <ent type='GPE'>Rome</ent> and had long talks with <ent type='PERSON'>Mussolini</ent> and
<ent type='PERSON'>Pacelli</ent>; with, incidentally, a talk to the Almighty in St. Peters.
You will, of course, not for a moment suspect that he discussed
with <ent type='PERSON'>Pacelli</ent> the plot to destroy <ent type='GPE'>Austria</ent>n Socialism. The <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>
never interferes in polities. But the course of the events that
followed the return of <ent type='PERSON'>Dollfuss</ent> to <ent type='GPE'>Vienna</ent> clearly shows that this
second step in Hitler's march to world-domination was facilitated,
like the first, by <ent type='ORG'>the Black International</ent>. And in order to avoid
all suspicion of the use of tainted sources I will give a short
summary of these events as they are described, objectively, in the
Annual Rdgister, which certainly does not lean to Socialism or
Atheism.</p>

<p> Before he had set out for <ent type='GPE'>Rome</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Dollfuss</ent> had given a solemn
engagement (his second) to <ent type='GPE'>France</ent> that he would take no action
against the Socialists for disclosing the Hungarian-<ent type='NORP'>Italian</ent>
traffic. <ent type='GPE'>France</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Britain</ent> feared Civil war in <ent type='GPE'>Austria</ent> and were
assured that all parties would be forbidden to store arms. They
were probably aware that both parties were collecting arms, but
while the <ent type='NORP'>Fascist</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Heimwehr</ent> was encouraged and made no secret of its
armament, the government took every measure to hamper the
Socialists, who had to store arms very secretly in their model
tenement-blocks. On his return, however, <ent type='PERSON'>Dollfuss</ent>, the idol of the
clergy, disowned his solemn engagements and assumed dictatorial
powers. <ent type='PERSON'>Mussolini</ent> had promised to see him through.</p>

<p> He closed the <ent type='ORG'>Reichsrath</ent> (<ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>) and announced that <ent type='GPE'>Austria</ent>
was to be "a corporative authoritative state." He suspended the
Mayor of <ent type='GPE'>Vienna</ent> and abolished the municipal government or paralyzed
it by cutting off its financial resources. He allowed Starhemberg's
army to take over provincial towns and to show itself openly in
<ent type='GPE'>Vienna</ent>. There is, in fact, evidence that agents of the <ent type='ORG'>Heimwehr</ent>
offered to sell pieces of artillery to the Socialists in order to
encourage them to rebel. It wits obvious that they were very
seriously threatened with extinction, but the prospect of success
against the government and the <ent type='ORG'>Heimwehr</ent> (which had artillery), with
<ent type='PERSON'>Mussolini</ent> in the background, was so poor that there was no
agreement on a plan of revolt when the <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Fascist</ent>s put into
circulation a report that they were in a few days going to enter
the blocks of workers tenements in search of the hidden arms and
<ent type='PERSON'>Dollfuss</ent> publicly supported the <ent type='ORG'>Heimwehr</ent>, large numbers of the
Socialists and the <ent type='NORP'>Communists</ent> decided to fight. <ent type='PERSON'>Dollfuss</ent> lied to
the world about the struggle he had provoked. He announced that 137
men, women, and children were killed. The number was at least 1500.
Eleven of the leaders were executed and 1188 men and women were
imprisoned; and many of these prisoners testified in court that
they were tortured in jail in the traditional and almost invariable
fashion of clerical counter-revolutions. So sordid was this chapter
of <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> history from beginning to end that the impartial writer
in the Annual Register (1934, p. 194) concludes his account in
these ironic words:</p>

<p> "At the cost of hundreds if not thousands of lives . . . the
Heimwebr <ent type='NORP'>Fascist</ent> movement, which was created in its final form by
the late Chancellor Msgr. Ignaz <ent type='PERSON'>Seipel</ent>, achieved in 1934 its oft-proclaimed aim of the destruction of the Social Democratic Party,
their violent ejection from the control of <ent type='GPE'>Vienna</ent> to which two-</p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>Bank</ent> of Wisdom
Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
16
.
HOW THE <ent type='ORG'>CROSS</ent> COURTED THE <ent type='ORG'>SWASTIKA</ent></p>

<p>thirds of the people had elected them, and the sweeping away of
parliamentary government in <ent type='GPE'>Austria</ent>. Thus culminated the anti-Socialist policy inaugurated by the late Msgr. <ent type='PERSON'>Seipel</ent> in 1926."</p>

<p> <ent type='PERSON'>Seipel</ent> had died in 1922, and "gallant little <ent type='PERSON'>Dollfuss</ent>" had,
after a visit to <ent type='ORG'>the Vatican</ent>, carried his policy to its logical
conclusion. Whatever difficulty we may have in some cases in
tracing the intrigues of <ent type='ORG'>the Black International</ent> there is none
here. The struggle was ecclesiastical. It was directed by priests
and aimed at restoring the power of the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> from beginning to
end. <ent type='PERSON'>Pacelli</ent> had won his first campaign in his war for the
extinction of <ent type='NORP'>Bolshevism</ent>.</p>

<p> The Socialists had taken the chief part in the revolution of
1919 against <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> and State. It had been, a Socialist historian
says, "the most peaceful and the most humane of all revolutions,"
for the successful <ent type='NORP'>republicans</ent> "had not hurt a hair of anybody's
head." The only error of this writer is his claim that it was a
unique revolution in its humanity. Five <ent type='NORP'>democratic</ent> revolutions in
<ent type='GPE'>Spain</ent> during the nineteenth century. several in <ent type='GPE'>Italy</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Portugal</ent>,
and all the revolutions of 1848 had had the same character; and the
<ent type='GPE'>Spanish</ent> revolution of 1932 had lived up to the <ent type='NORP'>democratic</ent>
tradition. And the treachery and truculence of the clerical
counter-revolution of 1934 had followed the model of all such
movements. Yet journalists and essayists everywhere continued to
speak of the <ent type='ORG'>Reds</ent> as dangerously prone to violence and the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>
as the world's noblest guardian of peace, humanity, and justice.
Who are the real <ent type='ORG'>Reds</ent>?</p>

<p> The <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> followed up its victory with the customary
inhumanity. All funds and buildings belonging to the workers were
confiscated, and the arbitrary arrests of Socialists continued. By
the beginning of 1937 there were 24000 political prisoners,
largely men and women who had had no trial, in the jails of
<ent type='GPE'>Austria</ent>. In that year Miss <ent type='PERSON'>Margery Fry</ent>, a very sane and respected
<ent type='NORP'>British</ent> prison-reformer, Wm. Rackham of <ent type='ORG'>Cambridge University</ent>, and
Professor <ent type='PERSON'>Kimberg</ent>, a high authority on prisons, traveled over
Europe on a tour of inspection. They were not permitted in any
country to see how political prisoners were treated, and were not
allowed to visit any jails in <ent type='GPE'>Austria</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Italy</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent>, and
<ent type='GPE'>Portugal</ent>. But they brought back and told in the <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> press a
horrible story of overcrowded jails in Hungary, <ent type='GPE'>Rumania</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Bulgaria</ent>,
and <ent type='GPE'>Yugo</ent>-<ent type='NORP'>Slavia</ent>, of the use of torture and brutality by jailers and
police, of semi-starvation and cruel conditions, of tens of
thousands who had never had any sort of trial. On the very day on
which I write this a cautious Liberal <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> paper (News
Chronicle, September 25, 1941), describes just such brutality in
<ent type='GPE'>Spanish</ent> jails today. And the world-press still refused to see in
these things the shadow of things to come.</p>

<p> That was the new situation in <ent type='GPE'>Austria</ent>: overcrowded jails,
refusal of trials, torture, and brutality by <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> jailers. And
over it all the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> waved its blessing. Cardinal <ent type='PERSON'>Innitzer</ent> issued
a special address to the workers, saying that their Holy Mother the
<ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> affectionately welcomed them back to the fold. There was not
much tenderness about the process, for the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> at once set up an
intolerable tyranny. Every government employee must attend church </p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>Bank</ent> of Wisdom
Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
17
.
HOW THE <ent type='ORG'>CROSS</ent> COURTED THE <ent type='ORG'>SWASTIKA</ent></p>

<p>regularly or be fired. Every teacher must go to confession at least
once in three weeks. The splendid system of education which, to the
admiration of the educational world, the Socialists had created was
destroyed and text books of the most mendacious <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> type were
substituted. Socialist efficiency was replaced by <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>-<ent type='NORP'>Fascist</ent>
inefficiency. Though the worst of the world-depression had now
passed. <ent type='GPE'>Austria</ent> fell into a condition of semi-famine, and the
priests used even this for their purposes. <ent type='ORG'>The Annual Register</ent>
tells us that the priests at first refused all foreign aid so as to
"force those in distress to apply to <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> organizations", and
two Englishmen were arrested for giving money to starving people.
Fifty out of sixty seats on the State Cultural Council were
allotted to <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>s.</p>

<p> How <ent type='PERSON'>Pacelli</ent> must have rubbed his hands! So did <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent>. On the
ruins of the Socialist-<ent type='NORP'>Communist</ent> movement the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>s of <ent type='GPE'>Austria</ent>
quickly grew in power. They murdered <ent type='PERSON'>Dollfuss</ent>, whom the priests
replaced with the unhappy and purblind <ent type='PERSON'>Schuschnigg</ent>. <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> drew
nearer to <ent type='PERSON'>Mussolini</ent> and bought off his interest in <ent type='GPE'>Austria</ent> by
promising him, with his usual brazen dishonesty, that be should not
only have <ent type='ORG'>Savoy</ent>, Coisica, and <ent type='GPE'>Tunis</ent> from <ent type='GPE'>France</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Dalmatia</ent> from
<ent type='GPE'>Yugo</ent>-<ent type='NORP'>Slavia</ent> but he should continue to be the dominant power in
Hungary and in all countries south of the <ent type='ORG'>Danube</ent>. That suited
<ent type='PERSON'>Pacelli</ent>. The <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>s of <ent type='GPE'>Austria</ent> added to the <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>s of <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent>
would give <ent type='ORG'>the Vatican</ent> a stronger hand in its new deals with the
<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>s, and there might be a glorious bloc of <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> powers from
<ent type='GPE'>Portugal</ent> (when the new revolution was accomplished in <ent type='GPE'>Spain</ent>) to
<ent type='GPE'>Bulgar</ent>. If I were a man of pinity I should be disposed to quote the
old <ent type='NORP'>Latin</ent> adage: Those whom God wishe's to destroy he first makes
mad. The destruction of Socialism in <ent type='GPE'>Austria</ent> and enslavement of the
whole country to Cardinal <ent type='PERSON'>Innitzer</ent> was a most beneficent removal of
obstacles to Hitler's annexation of the country. To this and the
share of <ent type='ORG'>the Black International</ent> in it we will return later.</p>

<p> Chapter IV</p>

<p> HITLER EXPOSES THE SHAME OF THE CHURCH</p>

<p> <ent type='PERSON'>Pacelli</ent> had soon repented of the hasty attack on <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> which
he had sent from South <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> to Cardinal Schulte. Apart from weak
complaints that the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>s did not observe the Concordat and a
sharper note when he saw the <ent type='ORG'>Gestapo</ent> men annihilating his treasured
<ent type='NORP'>Polish</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> by castration and other gentle <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> methods, he has
never condemned <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent>. Certainly he has never condemned <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> crime
and bestiality as such, though all the world recognizes that he had
a magnificent field for moral censorship. And his restraint, if you
like to call it that, was not due to any better observance of the
Concordat in <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent>. On the contrary, <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> schools and
associations were disappearing. But to challenge <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> would lead
at once to more drastic treatment of the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> and he must try to
win a compromise.</p>

<div> </div>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>Bank</ent> of Wisdom
Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
18
.
HOW THE <ent type='ORG'>CROSS</ent> COURTED THE <ent type='ORG'>SWASTIKA</ent></p>

<p> An opportunity occurred in 1935. The rich <ent type='ORG'>Saar</ent> province had at
the <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>Versailles</ent> been entrusted to <ent type='ORG'>the League</ent> of Nations
-- really to the exploitation of <ent type='NORP'>French</ent> industrialists -- for 15
years, and the time had now expired. The inhabitants were to vote
whether or no they would return to <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent>. They were
overwhelmingly <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> so that an issue that was of the greatest
possible importance to <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> was to be decided by the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>; for
it would be preposterous to suggest that in so delicate a matter
the local hierarchy would act without instructions from the
Vatican. On January 6 the bishops of <ent type='PERSON'>Speier</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Trier</ent>, the heads of
the local <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>, Issued a letter of instruction that was to be
read in every <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> of the province. Whether or no you
call this interfering in politics they ordered their people to vote
for <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent>. "As <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>s," they said, "it is out duty to
uphold the greatness, the <ent type='ORG'>Welfare</ent>, and the peace of our
<ent type='ORG'>Fatherland</ent>." On the following <ent type='LOC'>Sunday</ent>, 13th, the voting day, special
prayers were said after <ent type='PERSON'>Mass</ent> for a victory for <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> (<ent type='GPE'>London</ent>
Times, January 18). On the same day (18th) the <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> Times
boasted that <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> owed his triumph to the <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>s of the <ent type='ORG'>Saar</ent>,
and it remained to be seen how grateful he would prove. The bells
rang in every <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> when the overwhelming vote in favor
of <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> was announced; just as they had rung in every <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> of
<ent type='GPE'>Italy</ent> for the triumph of <ent type='PERSON'>Mussolini</ent>.</p>

<p> <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> made no change in his policy of ignoring the Concordat.
More <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> schools and associations were closed, and Cardinal
<ent type='PERSON'>Faulhaber</ent> vaguely threatened in one of his sermons to excommunicate
the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> leaders: not for their crimes, of course, but for
interfering with <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> education. <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> had directed that
<ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> parents in <ent type='GPE'>Munich</ent> should vote whether they wanted to send
their children to <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> or to national schools. As a result of
the vote the pupils attending <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> schools fell from 36464 to
19266, and the pupil's of <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> schools rose from 33 to 65 percent
of the whole. Every priest knew that this meant further enormous
leakage from the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>.</p>

<p> It must have put <ent type='PERSON'>Pacelli</ent> in a painful dilemma when, soon after
this, <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> demanded a vote of confidence from the entire country.
He had just, in defiance of <ent type='GPE'>France</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>the League</ent> of Nations, taken
a very serious step in the realization of his aggressive plan. He
had sent troops to occupy the <ent type='GPE'>Rhine</ent> provinces which by the terms of
the Treaty were to remain demilitarized. The <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> people were to
pronounce upon his entire policy: his crimes to date and the
aggressive campaign of which, as everybody knew, the defiance of
<ent type='GPE'>Versailles</ent> was the first clause.</p>

<p> One would have thought that here was a fine opportunity to
take refuge in the worn cliche that the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> never interferes in
politic's, but the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> hierarchy composed a letter that was to
be read in every <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> before the vote was taken. It is one of the
many clerical masterpieces of improper advice masquerading as
evasion, which the last ten years have produced. The bishops
recognized the painful dilemma of the faithful. If they voted for
<ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> they might seem to approve of various "measures antagonistic
to the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>" which he had ordered. So they are free to vote as
they will. But if any of them care to vote for <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> they could do
so with a clear conscience by saying to themselves: "We give our </p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>Bank</ent> of Wisdom
Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
19
.
HOW THE <ent type='ORG'>CROSS</ent> COURTED THE <ent type='ORG'>SWASTIKA</ent></p>

<p>vote to the <ent type='ORG'>Fatherland</ent> but that does not signify approval of
matters for which we could not conscientiously be held responsible"
(<ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> Times, March 27, 1936). In other words, Vote for <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent>.
We recognize the accents of <ent type='PERSON'>Pacelli</ent>-Pius.</p>

<p> The vote of confidence was a farce as such. The point of
interest is that <ent type='ORG'>the Black International</ent> which had helped to put
<ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> in the saddle in 1933 still supported him in spite of all
his outrages and his open menace to the world's peace. This was in
gratitude for favors to come, and it is one of the most acute
ironies of the time that while the priests were instructing the
<ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> laity in the moral acrobatics by which they could vote for
<ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> that most brazen of adventurers since Caesar <ent type='PERSON'>Borgia</ent> was
actually at work on a measure that would deal the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> and
the <ent type='ORG'>Papacy</ent> the most terrible blow they had suffered since <ent type='PERSON'>Luther</ent>
had nailed his theses to the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> door at <ent type='PERSON'>Wittenberg</ent>.</p>

<p> This was the revelation that monasteries which were
represented in <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> literature -- even in works that circulated
in <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> -- as fragrant gardens of piety and virtue were
cesspools of moral perversity and that the vice was widespread
amongst the parochial clergy. I have given an account of the early
stages of this exposure in the <ent type='PERSON'>Haldeman</ent>-<ent type='PERSON'>Julius</ent> booklet Vice in
<ent type='NORP'>German</ent> Monasteries (1937), which is, as far as I can ascertain, the
only lengthy account in the English language. Had so spectacular an
exposure, on so vast a scale, been made in regard to any other body
or <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> than the <ent type='NORP'>Roman</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> the press would have erupted into
its largest scare-type and its warmest moral indignation. Such is
the backstairs influence of <ent type='ORG'>the Black International</ent> in <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> and
<ent type='GPE'>Britain</ent> that journalists had to suppress, or publish lies about
the greatest sensation of the year 1936. Here let me round off the
story and set it in the light of later disclosures.</p>

<p> All that the great majority of <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>ns knew about the matter
was that Cardinal <ent type='PERSON'>Mundelein</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>, as part of his indictment
of the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>s for persecuting the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> -- which was itself
conducting a far worse persecution in <ent type='GPE'>Poland</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Austria</ent> and soon
would be in <ent type='GPE'>Spain</ent> -- charged them with fabricating an atrocious
libel against the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> clergy and said that of the 25635 priests
of <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> only 58, or a quarter of 1 percent, had been arrested on
a vice-charge. This was a statement (which no one in <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> could
cheek) made by the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> bishops, and it was an audacious evasion,
if not untruth. The B.U.P. and <ent type='PERSON'>Reuter</ent> message which conveyed the
words of the bishops added, significantly, that "eleven <ent type='NORP'>Roman</ent>
<ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> priests were arrested in <ent type='GPE'>Munich</ent> this week-end" and told of
two other arrests for assaults on little girls a few days later.
The figure is preposterous but the implication is worse. The
"thousands" of offenders of whom the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>s spoke were not priests.
They were monks or what the <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> calls lay brothers.</p>

<p> The difference is important. Priests in <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> as in <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>
have parochial duties, an important part of which is visiting homes
in the husband's absence and being visited by girls and women, like
ministers of other denominations. All of them have female domestic
servants in their houses. When they are disposed to violate their
vow of chastity they have ample opportunities, and of this sort of
indulgence the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> law takes no more cognizance than the </p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>Bank</ent> of Wisdom
Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
20
.
HOW THE <ent type='ORG'>CROSS</ent> COURTED THE <ent type='ORG'>SWASTIKA</ent></p>

<p><ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n law does, as long as they do not seduce minors under their
charge. Their circumstances do not particularly incline them to
sodomy. It is in the monastic communings, especially of lay (or
non-priest) brothers, who are devoted to teaching and the care of
the sick, mentally feeble, etc., that the pretense of special
holiness breaks down. The word "monk" is not a technical but
popular word, and it is applied to these in <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> literature.
The large communities and work of charity are particularly
recommended in <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> literature as proof of the Church's
inspiration, and they and the nuns number, or numbered, ten's of
thousands in <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent>. Those of the <ent type='NORP'>Franciscan</ent> Order were
particularly praised, and the largest community of them, at
<ent type='ORG'>Waldbreitbach</ent>, in <ent type='GPE'>Westphalia</ent>, were described as a holy institution
to which no other religion could show a parallel.</p>

<p> It was just here, at Waldbreitbaeb and other <ent type='NORP'>Franciscan</ent>
communities, that the police were busy gathering evidence at the
very time when the bishops were telling <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>s to vote for
<ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent>, and proof was accumulating that these holy places were not
only comprehensively but revoltingly corrupt. Father-confessors
seduced for years the young novices who came in. <ent type='NORP'>Monks</ent> confessed in
the witness-box how on the holiest days (when all monks feed and
drink most) they reeled along the corridors to the chapel and
halted in dark corners I have told all that from their own
confessions in court. There is nothing like it in <ent type='PERSON'>Boccaccio</ent> or
Rabelais; and it had been going on for an indefinite time. There
had been prosecutions early in the century, but in those days one
quickly let the <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> curtain fall again if it revealed anything
nasty.</p>

<p> One point only must be repeated here. The charge that the
trials of the monks were travesties of justice, on a level with the
<ent type='GPE'>Berlin</ent> trial of the <ent type='NORP'>Communists</ent> for the burning of the <ent type='GPE'>Reichstag</ent>, is
entirely false. The public is apt to assume this, since the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>
variety of justice is notorious and the plain man has no means of
checking statements about <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent>. But men like <ent type='PERSON'>Mundelein</ent> or the
<ent type='NORP'>German</ent>-<ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n priests who assisted him must have known better.
One such priest visited <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> to ascertain "the truth" in 1938
and lingering in <ent type='GPE'>Britain</ent> to communicate this personally ascertained
"truth" to the <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> press -- and <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>s, as usual, got
replies to him excluded from the press -- he returned in triumph to
<ent type='GPE'>America</ent>. His verdict was just what <ent type='PERSON'>Mundelein</ent> said: Less than 60
priests in <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> had been prosecuted, and the rest was <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>
fabrication. This priest knew that the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> bishops from whom he
got his figure admitted the depravity in monasteries's of religious
brothers, that <ent type='ORG'>the Vatican</ent> also admitted it by suppressing whole
provinces of them for irregularity of conduct, and that the
<ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>s of <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> fully admitted it.</p>

<p> There can be very little doubt that <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> directed the
prosecution. He knew that he had in this epidemic of vice a ground
that would go very far even in the eyes of <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>s to justify his
refusal to honor the terms of the Concordat he had signed. But he
also knew that he would give the bishops a means to stir the
<ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> body bitterly against him instead of winning its support
unless such charges were proved beyond cavil. He took care that
this was done.</p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>Bank</ent> of Wisdom
Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
21
.
HOW THE <ent type='ORG'>CROSS</ent> COURTED THE <ent type='ORG'>SWASTIKA</ent></p>

<p> The arrests and trial's were, in the first place, almost
entirely in the <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> provinces where these communities are most
numerous and, as it proved, most vicious; as the small communities
in Protestant provinces are as critically watched as in <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> and
<ent type='GPE'>Britain</ent>. All the police-officials charged with the preliminary
inquiries and the arrests were <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>s and the courts
predominantly <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>. Every witness against the monks was a
<ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>, and nearly every one of the accused pleaded guilty,
blaming the morbid conditions of the life and the drunkenness that
was permitted. The trials were held, in the normal form, in the
high courts of the capitals of these <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> provinces (mostly
<ent type='GPE'>Cologne</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Bonn</ent>, Coblentz, and <ent type='GPE'>Munich</ent>) and were reported daily in the
chief papers of the provinces, which have three <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> reader's
to one non-<ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>; and these papers fully sustained the verdicts
and admitted the guilt.</p>

<p> Are these just <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> allegations? Not at all. During 1936 and
1937 I followed the trials in these papers -- effectively, <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>
papers -- chiefly <ent type='ORG'>the Koinische Zeitung</ent> and the <ent type='LOC'>West</ent>falische Kurier
checked by <ent type='GPE'>Berlin</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Munich</ent> papers, and got the details from them.
They even sometimes rapped their own prelates on the knuckle's for
trying to gloss over or deny the ugly facts. I read fairly lengthy
reports of scores of individual trials of monks, priests (sometimes
of high rank), and even a nun (for seducing boy-pupils). Nine out
of ten of the monks were convicted of sodomy, as were most of the
priests, though some were charged with indecent relations with
young girls (down to 12 or 13) and were proved by their
parishioners to have done this over a period of many years.</p>

<p> The charge was generally sodomy, and this, as I said, fully
explains why there were, comparatively, so few priests. Fornication
is not an offence in law, and so the priests do not as a rule come
under the notice of the police. There were a few arrests of zealous
priests for attacking the government (over the Concordat) in
sermons and many prosecution for smuggling currency out of <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent>.
The police found that the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> used demure looking nuns and
venerable friars, their holy costumes stuffed with notes, to make
a profit in the sternly forbidden exchange-transactions or to
smuggle money to <ent type='GPE'>Rome</ent>. But in the overwhelming majority of cases
the charge was sodomy, and the next most frequent charge the
corruption of young girls. The World Almanac for 1939 says (p.
236):</p>

<p> "Up to October, 1938, more than 8000 <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> monks and lay
brothers had been arrested by <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> officials, approximately 50
percent of the 16000 members of <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> monasteries, on various
charges, including immorality, sedition, breaches of exchange laws,
abuse of the pulpit, collecting fund's without government
permission, or failure to fly the Swastika flag on national
monuments. Forty-five monks, 176 lay-brothers, and 21 monastery
employees were sentenced on immorality charges: 188 priests were
acquitted or released without trial."</p>

<p> It is pleasant to find that an <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n publication had the
courage to print so much -- no <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> publication had, and I
failed to get a publisher for a book -- but the details are
misleading. "Arrested by <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> officials" does not mean the <ent type='ORG'>Gestapo</ent>,</p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>Bank</ent> of Wisdom
Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
22
.
HOW THE <ent type='ORG'>CROSS</ent> COURTED THE <ent type='ORG'>SWASTIKA</ent></p>

<p>but, generally, <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> policemen and officers. The list of
charges is misleading because sodomy far outnumbered the others;
and the last sentence is particularly unfortunate. Over the period
of nearly two years in which I followed the trials 90 percent were
for vice, and very few of the accused escaped, and then only in
virtue of an earlier amnesty. Many of these were priest-monks,
though of the 400 <ent type='NORP'>Franciscan</ent> monks of the <ent type='GPE'>Westphalia</ent>n province, who
were the first to be arraigned, 61 (mostly the directing priests
and superiors) got secret warning and fled the country (many to
<ent type='GPE'>Rome</ent>), which left a disproportion of priests to monks in the 276
who were arrested. The province was found to be wholly corrupt and
the <ent type='PERSON'>Pope</ent> abolished it after a few trials. The non-monastic priests
who were arrested were scattered over <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> and only casually
mentioned in the press, but of the cases I collected nine-tenths
again were for vice (boys and little girls), hardly one in ten was
acquitted. Later there were more numerous arrests for "sedition" or
criticism of the "persecution of the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>".</p>

<p> Chapter V</p>

<p> THE POPE CONTINUES TO COURT HITLER</p>

<p> <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> is a rotten speaker: raucous in voice, graceless in
gesture, and loose in the composition of his speeches. It is not
"personal magnetism" that makes him a power with the young -- the
older are mostly driven to his gatherings -- but a belief in his
genius that is artificially created by years of the most elaborate
and most persistent boosting. The most effective speech he ever
made was on January 1, 1939, when he replied to <ent type='ORG'>the Vatican</ent> and
world-complaint that he persecuted the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>. There was, of
course, a fallacy in his argument. Unquestionably he wanted to
change the <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> in <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> in a sense which <ent type='ORG'>the Vatican</ent>
could not possibly accept and of this he said nothing, but his
direct reply to the charge of persecution of religion was
effective.</p>

<p> The <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> government has always subsidized the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>es but
<ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> had more than trebled the subsidy. Between 1933, when he
took office, and 1938 it rose from 150000000 <ent type='ORG'>Marks</ent> to
500000000 a year. What was your subsidy to the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>es, he
asked of <ent type='GPE'>France</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Britain</ent>, an <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>? He had never closed a church,
and he left the <ent type='NORP'>Roman</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> the richest land-owner in south and
west <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent>. It drew 1500000000 <ent type='ORG'>Marks</ent> a year from its property
alone. (<ent type='NORP'>German</ent> papers give its wealth as $20000000000). All that
he asked was that priests should behave themselves as respectably
as other citizens. "<ent type='ORG'>Paederasty</ent> and the corruption of children," he
said, "are punished by law like other crimes in this state." The
roars of applause in this case expressed the sentiment of
practically the whole of <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent>.</p>

<p> And <ent type='ORG'>the Black International</ent> knew it. In foreign countries they
dare not stake their case on the question whether the vice-trials
were or were not genuine. An impartial press-inquiry would soon
settle that. They preferred to use their censorship of the press to</p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>Bank</ent> of Wisdom
Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
23
.
HOW THE <ent type='ORG'>CROSS</ent> COURTED THE <ent type='ORG'>SWASTIKA</ent></p>

<p>prevent any mention of them or to confuse the public with a vague
charge of persecution and talk about smuggling currency and
criticizing the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>s. I cannot speak for the <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n press but as
far as I could ascertain no <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> paper even mentioned the
Sensational trials that were spread over 1936 to 1938 and then
extended to <ent type='GPE'>Austria</ent>. Was there ever such self-denial on the part of
newspaper men? You know why.</p>

<p> At <ent type='ORG'>the Vatican</ent> and in <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> this was clearly recognized. The
trials had begun at the end of May (1936). After ten trials the
<ent type='PERSON'>Pope</ent> suppressed the <ent type='GPE'>Westphalia</ent>n province of the <ent type='NORP'>Franciscan</ent> Order,
its largest and richest province, for irregularity: a step without
precedent in modern times and so grave that only a desperate hope
of disarming <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> can have prompted it. But the trials went on
until the influx of foreigners for <ent type='EVENT'>the Olympic Games</ent> made it
advisable to suspend them. Some of these foreigners might be able
to read <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> and learn how monks of pure <ent type='NORP'>Aryan</ent> blood talked
indecency to children under ten on the steps of their houses, raped
helpless youths in their hospitals . . . In the period of
suspension, with 260 friars still in prison awaiting trial, the
bishops, who probably knew how far the search for culprits would
reach -- for evidence had been given in court that youths had
reported the matter to ecclesiastical authorities and been silenced
-- approached <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent>. The <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> press reported in August that
they had conferred with <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> on the "currency-charges" against
priests and monks. There were then few currency-charges but
hundreds of vice-charges, so we know what they wanted; especially
as there was nothing to protest against in the fines for smuggling
currency.</p>

<p> Next month the bishops, now clearly under Pacelli's orders,
made a fresh attempt. On September 12, 1936, the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>onale Zeitung
published a copy of a letter from the bishops to the faithful which
was to be read in all the <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>es of <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> next day. It
trusted that <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> would bury the past and admit <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>s to
cooperate with him in the fight against the ever-increasing threat
of world-<ent type='NORP'>Bolshevism</ent> which shows its sinister hand in <ent type='GPE'>Spain</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>
and <ent type='GPE'>Mexico</ent>. As they added that "guns are not enough to fight the
<ent type='NORP'>Bolshevik</ent> danger -- a sound lead is necessary to secure victory,"
they very clearly wanted <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> to crush <ent type='NORP'>Bolshevism</ent> in <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent> by
war and so consecrated his program of aggression. And as these
words of theirs are an echo of words that the <ent type='PERSON'>Pope</ent> had used a few
weeks earlier it is obvious that <ent type='PERSON'>Pacelli</ent> was the author. He had at
last, in the summer of 1936, matured his program and found his
slogan: the extinction of <ent type='NORP'>Bolshevism</ent> in <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Spain</ent>, and <ent type='GPE'>Mexico</ent>.
Sometimes to give respectability to his <ent type='NORP'>Japanese</ent> alliance, he added
-- <ent type='GPE'>China</ent>. As I have earlier said, the A.F.L. defeated his plan to
get <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> to attack <ent type='GPE'>Mexico</ent>, but it remains true that he wanted
the war. The rest of his slogan stands. He was pledged to support
the plans of aggressive war of <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Italy</ent>, and <ent type='GPE'>Japan</ent>, the
foulest nations on earth.</p>

<p> <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> ignored the bishops, but <ent type='PERSON'>Pacelli</ent> still pressed. On
November 4 the Times reported that <ent type='PERSON'>Mussolini</ent> was pressing <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> to
come to terms with <ent type='ORG'>the Vatican</ent>, as this would not only give him
more weight in the "clerical state" which <ent type='PERSON'>Franco</ent> was to set up in
<ent type='GPE'>Spain</ent> but would help him in his designs on <ent type='GPE'>Austria</ent>: a hint at the </p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>Bank</ent> of Wisdom
Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
24
.
HOW THE <ent type='ORG'>CROSS</ent> COURTED THE <ent type='ORG'>SWASTIKA</ent></p>

<p>part the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> would play when the time came to annex that
country. <ent type='PERSON'>Mussolini</ent> was at this time a practicing <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> once
more. Also he had begun, with the enthusiastic support of the Black
International his brutal campaign in <ent type='GPE'>Abyssinia</ent> and his hypocritical
action in <ent type='GPE'>Spain</ent>.</p>

<p> A week later (Times, November 13, 1936) <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> had a request
for an interview from Cardinal <ent type='PERSON'>Faulhaber</ent>. He received him
grudgingly and more or less secretly, and when the Cardinal put
before him the request of the bishops and asked in return for the
control of <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> education by the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>, the Minister of
Education, whom, <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> had invited to be present, advised him to
refuse. The <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>es were, he insisted, negligible allies, as they
had lost their power over men's minds in many part of the world."
The offer of the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> was refused, and the destruction of
<ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> schools, as new vice-trials of the religious teachers gave
a pretext, and associations continued.</p>

<p> Nevertheless <ent type='ORG'>the Vatican</ent> remained on such terms with <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent>
that when, in March, 1937, there was a mild rebuke of breaches of
the Concordat in a new encyclical and <ent type='PERSON'>Mundelein</ent> continued his
violent campaign in <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>, the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> government sent a complaint
to <ent type='GPE'>Rome</ent>. <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>s boasted that <ent type='ORG'>the Vatican</ent> refused to listen, but
there was no breach. Indeed, a month later Count Preysing, the
aristocratic <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> bishop of <ent type='GPE'>Berlin</ent>, addressed another appeal to
<ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> (Times, July 3, 1937). It is in this that we get the
admission of monastic corruption. It said that the bishop's "do not
deny that in certain orders of lay brothers many members had been
drawn into a sphere of serious moral perversities." Perhaps one
could not expect a more strongly worded admission from such a
source, but the shifting of responsibility from the priests to the
lay brothers is very misleading. These lay brothers of the
<ent type='NORP'>Franciscan</ent> Order, of whom nearly 300 in one province were arrested
for sodomy, were under the direct authority of the clerical heads
of the Order, were periodically examined by representatives of
those authorities and were in each monastery ruled by a number of
priest-monks. Evidence was given by the brothers in the trials that
the epidemic of vice had been reported to the authorities in these
periodical examinations which are (of the most intimate character)
and no notice had been taken.</p>

<p> There was no modification of the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> policy. In December the
<ent type='PERSON'>Pope</ent> feebly complained to his cardinals, when they came to him with
their Christmas greetings, of the persecution in <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent>. The
excuse was, he said, that the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> interfered in polities. Even
the cardinals must have smiled when the aged and not very clear-headed <ent type='PERSON'>Pope</ent> went on to say that "no fair-minded man" could Say that
the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> ever interfered in politics. A few month's earlier he
had summoned the powers to crush by war the kind of government
which the people of <ent type='GPE'>Spain</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Mexico</ent> had freely chosen and
supported at every election: the form of government which, whatever
its beginning, had won the support of the entire <ent type='NORP'>Russian</ent> people, as
all the world now realizes. At that very moment <ent type='ORG'>the Vatican</ent> was
working with its murderous allies to change the political form of
<ent type='GPE'>Spain</ent>, had mercilessly intervened in polities in <ent type='GPE'>Austria</ent> for years,
had given, its blessing to the enslavement of the <ent type='GPE'>Abyssinia</ent>n
people, and had helped to establish Fascism in South <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>.</p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>Bank</ent> of Wisdom
Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
25
.
HOW THE <ent type='ORG'>CROSS</ent> COURTED THE <ent type='ORG'>SWASTIKA</ent></p>

<p> One might have expected that in these circumstances the <ent type='ORG'>Papacy</ent>
would assert what was left of its moral dignity and abandon the
dishonoring opportunism that had characterized its relations with
the brutal <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>s since 1932. On the pretty theory of the <ent type='ORG'>Papacy</ent>
which is put before the world its duty was to denounce the crimes
of <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> and the menace to the world of its naked ambition
and let <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>s take such punishment from the criminals as
<ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>s are supposed to endure with heroism rather than bow the
knee to iniquity.</p>

<p> It may be objected that at the most we can accuse <ent type='PERSON'>Pacelli</ent>, who
was entirely responsible for the policy of the senile Pontiff, of
an error of judgment in a grave dilemma. That would be a
misrepresentation of the position. He clung to his <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>, <ent type='NORP'>Italian</ent>,
and <ent type='NORP'>Japanese</ent> allies, not singly to avert persecution from <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>s
in their dominions -- and we must remember that even in this the
real concern of <ent type='ORG'>the Black International</ent> is the loss of members
under the strain -- but because his policy coincided with theirs.
When the time comes for <ent type='GPE'>China</ent> to recover its territory, as it
surely must come if the poison is to be got out of the veins of the
world, <ent type='NORP'>Roman</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> influence in <ent type='LOC'>the Far East</ent> will be very justly
restricted. The Vatican has irretrievably pledged itself to the
<ent type='NORP'>Japanese</ent> bully. in <ent type='GPE'>Italy</ent> it is not less firmly pledged to the
support of <ent type='PERSON'>Mussolini</ent>. What Cardinal <ent type='ORG'>Hinsley</ent> said, that if <ent type='PERSON'>Mussolini</ent>
falls the "cause of God" - of <ent type='ORG'>the Black International</ent> -- falls,
remains true. Socialism would get control of <ent type='GPE'>Italy</ent>, and the time
has gone by for triumphant <ent type='NORP'>democrats</ent> to handle with kid gloves the
reactionary elements that have shed blood whenever they temporarily
recovered power; besides that <ent type='NORP'>Fascist</ent> <ent type='GPE'>Italy</ent> is indispensable to the
Pope's fantastic plan of a great bloc of <ent type='NORP'>Fascist</ent>-<ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> powers to
offset the influence of the democracies, or their rich <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>
minorities, in the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>.</p>

<p> And beyond all this is the Church's indispensable need of a
<ent type='NORP'>Fascist</ent> atmosphere in any state in which it is to flourish. As I
have shown, the apparent progress of the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> in such democracies
as <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Britain</ent> is a fallacy. Not only does it lose instead
of advancing if the birth rate is taken into account, but migration
from backward <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> countries is the adequate explanation of the
apparent progress. In <ent type='GPE'>France</ent>, where there has been no such
immigration on a large scale, the membership of the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> fell in
30 years from 30000000 to about 5000000 when (in 1871) the
country became a democracy; and it was the same in <ent type='GPE'>Italy</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Spain</ent>
as long as they were democracies. There is not a single exception
to the law that free discussion is fatal to the <ent type='NORP'>Roman</ent> system. Its
effect is merely modified in <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Britain</ent> by the conspiracy
of <ent type='ORG'>the Black International</ent> to intimidate editors, publishers,
booksellers, librarians, etc., and the drastic law that. <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>s
shall not read critics of the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>.</p>

<p> Hence in <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> a policy that is purely ecclesiastical and
takes no account of moral and social considerations has to cling at
all cost and in spite of all rebuffs to the hope of disarming the
hostility of the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>s and helping to maintain them in power. Both
the rebuffs and the policy of appeasement continued. On October 15,
1938, the <ent type='PERSON'>Volkischer Beobachter</ent>, a recognized <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> organ, said: "We
are armed to continue the battle against <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>ism to the point </p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>Bank</ent> of Wisdom
Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
26
.
HOW THE <ent type='ORG'>CROSS</ent> COURTED THE <ent type='ORG'>SWASTIKA</ent></p>

<p>of total annihilation." Vice-prosecutions multiplied, and the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>s
called for, and would presently obtain, the suppression of all
<ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> schools in <ent type='GPE'>Bavaria</ent>. And remember that while <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent>
influence in <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> could, by getting the essential facts
concealed from the <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n public, represent this as a piece of
wanton persecution of religion, every <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> knew that it was done
on the ground judicially established in hundreds of cases, that the
most respecter <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> teachers, the brothers who were vowed to
chastity and asceticism, were corrupt and corruptors. The
philanthropic institutions-schools, orphanages, infirmaries, etc.,
of which the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> had been so proud were taken over by the
authorities and entrusted to laymen.</p>

<p> I am in this booklet confining myself to <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> so that the
reader may get a clear view of the strange situation in that
country insofar as it concerns the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>. It must, however be
understood that the humiliation of the proud <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent> in 1938 was far
greater than we realize if we restrict our attention to <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent>. In
<ent type='GPE'>Spain</ent> <ent type='ORG'>the Vatican</ent> and the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>s were actually cooperating in that
holy war for the extinction of <ent type='NORP'>Bolshevism</ent>, which was now Pacelli's
ruling passion. In <ent type='GPE'>Austria</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Czecho</ent>-<ent type='GPE'>Slovakia</ent> the Black
International rendered even more useful service than cooperation.
It prepared the way for those bloodies's triumphs of the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>s
which history will record to the deep shame of the western
democracies; the triumphs of lying by which <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> preserved his
armies for the attack on <ent type='GPE'>France</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Britain</ent>, and <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent> and gradually
pressed all the rest of Europe into the position of bleeding slaves
in his war-galley. How <ent type='ORG'>the Vatican</ent> helped him to do this, and how
<ent type='PERSON'>Pacelli</ent> became <ent type='PERSON'>Pope</ent> in 1939 and contemplated the ghastly
consequences of his policy yet persisted in it while the whole
civilized and free world was filled with moral indignation will be
told in a later book.</p>

<div> **** ****</div>

<p> Reproducible Electronic Publishing can defeat censorship.</p>

<p> The <ent type='ORG'>Bank</ent> of Wisdom is a collection of the most thoughtful,
scholarly and factual books. These computer books are reprints of
suppressed books and will cover <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n and world history; the
<ent type='ORG'>Biographies</ent> and writings of famous persons, and especially of our
nations Founding Fathers. They will include philosophy and
religion. all these subjects, and more, will be made available to
the public in electronic form, easily copied and distributed, so
that <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> can again become what its Founders intended --</p>

<p> The Free Market-Place of Ideas.</p>

<p> The <ent type='ORG'>Bank</ent> of Wisdom is always looking for more of these old,
hidden, suppressed and forgotten books that contain needed facts
and information for today. If you have such books please contact
us, we need to give them back to <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>.</p>

<div> **** ****</div>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>Bank</ent> of Wisdom
Box 926, <ent type='GPE'>Louisville</ent>, KY 40201
27
</p></xml>