<xml><p><ent type='EVENT'>The War</ent> On Privacy Hits You In The Pocket Book!</p>

<p>COPYRIGHT (C) 1991 BY FULL DISCLOSURE. ALL RIGHTS RESERVED.</p>

<p>Why does the <ent type='ORG'>FBI</ent> and other select government agencies pay over $4000 for a
pocket tape recorder? One of the most important elements in an electronic
surveillance operation is the tape recorder. Whether hidden in one's pocket
or recording information from a wiretap or bug, the tape recorder can be the
key to success or failure.</p>

<p>The <ent type='ORG'>FBI</ent> had a need for a specialized recorder, so they contracted with the
U.S. subsidiary of a <ent type='NORP'>Swiss</ent> company, <ent type='ORG'>Nagra Magnetics</ent>, Inc. to design a
recorder that met their needs. The result being the <ent type='ORG'>Nagra</ent> <ent type='ORG'>JBR</ent> subminiature
recorder and PS-1 playback system.</p>

<p>When asked whether the unit was named after <ent type='PERSON'>Jim</ent> B. Reames, an <ent type='ORG'>FBI</ent> employee
who helped design the recorder, a <ent type='ORG'>Nagra</ent> spokeswomen refused to say, but
pointed out that the initials were in fact the same.</p>

<p>The design and manufacture of the recorder has been so secret and important
to the <ent type='ORG'>FBI</ent> (and two other unnamed government agencies who are supposedly the
sole users of the recorder) that any public availability of information on
the recorder would "make the machine extinct,'' according to an employee of
<ent type='ORG'>Narga</ent> who refused to provide any details on the recorder in a telephone
interview.</p>

<p>It is also interesting to note that in the literature obtained by Full
Disclosure from the <ent type='ORG'>NATIA</ent> show, several of the companies made mention of
<ent type='ORG'>Narga</ent> tape recorders, but not the <ent type='ORG'>JBR</ent> model.</p>

<p>A freelance reporter who contacted <ent type='ORG'>Nagra</ent> in August, 1990, was informed that
someone from the Justice Department had just visited to express the
government's desire to keep the public ignorant about the <ent type='ORG'>JBR</ent> recorder.</p>

<p>Full Disclosure contacted <ent type='ORG'>Nagra</ent> on September 24, 1990 and was informed that
they received a letter from the <ent type='ORG'>Government</ent> "last week'' informing them that
they couldn't give out any information on the <ent type='ORG'>JBR</ent> recorder. <ent type='ORG'>Nagra</ent> refused to
disclose what agency sent the letter.</p>

<p>The company spokeswomen, also stated that they are not allowed to advertise
the unit anywhere, and if they did they would "lose all government
contracts.'' She further stated that they wanted to advertise it in
<special>N</special>Law and Order and could not.</p>

<p>Marketing is done by word of mouth and narcotics trade shows, she said. This
seemed a little contrary to the first spokesman who said that there were only
three customers for the <ent type='ORG'>JBR</ent> recorder.</p>

<p>Full Disclosure's investigative reporting team, was able to obtain complete
specifications on both the recorder and playback unit.</p>

<p>Because of the secrecy around the recorder and its specifications, the unit
is sole-sourced from <ent type='ORG'>Nagra</ent>. Inevitability when a product is available from a
single source, there is no price competition.</p>

<p>The following public disclosure of the <ent type='ORG'>JBR</ent> specifications should serve two
purposes:</p>

<p>1) to open a competitive market for this type of recorder, and</p>

<p>2) to give the <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> public more information on the tools the government
uses to spy upon. Thereby increasing the public's ability to participate in
political process as it relates to oversight and domestic use of spy
technology.</p>

<p>@SUBHEAD = <ent type='ORG'>JBR</ent> RECORDER</p>

<p>"The recorder is stereophonic, with two totally independent channels. A
third central track records a reference signal of 5461 Hz. This signal is
used later on in the playback system as a reference, in order to correct for
speed variations.</p>

<p>"The recording speed is 15/16 <ent type='ORG'>ips</ent>. This speed is stabilized by an optical
encoder system. In order to save energy and to reduce radiation as much as
possible, no erasing head is provided. For basically the same reasons, and to
ensure that the tapes remain genuine, there is also no playback facility
provided on the recorder.</p>

<p>"Special <ent type='PERSON'>Kudelski</ent> cassettes are used to provide two hours non stop recording
autonomy. A set of three "N'' size batteries are used allowing ten hours of
operation.</p>

<p>"Even though the <ent type='ORG'>detectablility</ent> is minimal, the bias frequency is of 32KHz
and has thus the same radiation as a quartz watch. The recorder weight is
less than 200 grams, includes its cassette and batteries, and is really
pocket size with cover: 110.2 x 62.6 x 20.8 mm (4.34: x 2.46" x 0.82").
Miniature microphone and remote controls are available with different length
cables.</p>

<p>So-called tape recorder detectors normally detect the presence of the "bias
oscillator'' in tape recorders. By using a non-standard and one that is also
commonly used by other common devices makes detection by such a means more
difficult.</p>

<p>@SUBHEAD = <ent type='ORG'>JBR</ent> Specifications:</p>

<p>SIZE (L x W x H): 110.2 x 62.6 x 20.8mm, with cover: 4.34" x 2.46" x 0.82"</p>

<p>with cover &amp; plugs: 110.2 x 64.3 x 20.8mm / 4.34" x 2.53" x 0.82"</p>

<p>Weight: Recorder with cover: 143 g, Cassette with 2 hr tape: 22 g, Batteries,
3 pcs: 29 g, Microphones including 4' cable, 2 pcs: 30 g, Remote control, 3'
cable:18 g. Total weight: 242 g.</p>

<p>Environment: Operating position: Any, Temperature: 0 C to 40 C (32 F to
104F). Humidity: 20% to 95% non-condensing.</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>Power Supply</ent>: Supply voltage: 2.7 to 5V DC, nominal 4.5 V. "Batt OK''
indicator threshold: 3.4V. Battery standard type: <ent type='ORG'>ASA</ent> ''N'', ANSI "L20'',
IEC "LR1''. Current consumption - start of tape: 40mA typical, - end of
tape: 50ma typical.</p>

<p>TAPE: Tape transport: without <ent type='GPE'>capstan</ent>, constant speed. Tape type: chromium
dioxide in special <ent type='ORG'>JBR</ent> cassette. Tape width: 3.81 mm (0.150"). Tape Thickness
(total): 9u (0.35mil) 120 min. 12u (0.48mil) 90 min. <ent type='PERSON'>Max</ent> recording time: 2
hours. Audio tracks: 1.20mm x 2. Control tract (center): 0.40 mm. Track
spacing: 0.50 mm. Nominal tape speed: 2.38 cm/s (15/16<ent type='ORG'>ips</ent>). Tape speed
accuracy: better than +/- 2%. Wow and flutter: typ. 2.5% peak-to-peak, <ent type='ORG'>NAB</ent> (=
<ent type='ORG'>DIN</ent> 45507) weighted. Start time: less than 4 seconds</p>

<p>Inputs: 2 microphone inputs. <ent type='PERSON'>Max</ent>imum input level: 60 mV RMS. Audio indicator
threshold: 30 mV RMS input -3 dB on tape. Input impedance: 80 K. Microphone
sensitivity: 10 mV/PA (1 Pa=10 ubar). <ent type='PERSON'>Max</ent>imum SPL: 110 dB (0 dB SPL = 20
uPa). <ent type='ORG'>Signal</ent> to noise ratio, unexpanded: better than 51 dB <ent type='ORG'>ASA</ent> A weighted.
Frequency response: 170 Hz to 4.5 kHz +/- 3dB. Total harmonic distortion:
less than 3%. Compression ratio: 2:1 in dB. Compressor operating range: 80 dB </p>

<p>The above is reprinted from Full Disclosure Newspaper. Subscribe today and
get interesting articles like the above, plus more... pictures, graphics,
advertisement, and more articles. Full Disclosure is your source for
information on the leading edge of surveillance technology. Print the
following form, or supply the information on a plain piece of paper:</p>

<div>----</div>

<p>Please start my subscription to Full Disclosure for:</p>

<p>[ ] Sample issue, $2.00</p>

<p>[ ] 12 issue subscription, $18.00</p>

<p>[ ] 24 issue subscription, $29.95
With 24 issue susbcription include free one of the following:
[ ] Directory of Electronic Surveillance Equipment Suppliers
[ ] Citizen's Guide on How to Use the Freedom of Info/Privacy Acts
[ ] <ent type='PERSON'>Max</ent>imizing PC Performance</p>

<p>Also available separately:</p>

<p>[ ] Directory of Electronic Surveillance Equipment Suppliers, $6.00</p>

<p>[ ] Citizen's Guide on How to Use the Freedom of Info/Privacy Acts, $5.00</p>

<p>[ ] <ent type='PERSON'>Max</ent>imizing PC Performance, $6.00</p>

<p> <ent type='GPE'>Illinois</ent> residences, add 6.5% sales tax on above 3 items.</p>

<p>Enclosed is payment in the form of:</p>

<p>[ ] Check/Money order, [ ] Visa, [ ] Mastercard</p>

<p>Card no:___________________________________ Exp date:_______</p>

<p>Signature:__________________________________________________</p>

<p>Phone:______________________________________________________
(required for credit card orders)</p>

<p>My name/address:</p>

<p>Name:_______________________________________________________</p>

<p>Street:_____________________________________________________</p>

<p>City/State/Zip:_____________________________________________</p>

<p>Return to: Full Disclosure, Box 903, <ent type='GPE'>Libertyville</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Illinois</ent> 60048

</p></xml>