<xml><p>The following are excerpts from original <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> documents, relating
directly to the extermination of <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> and others which was carried
out by the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>s during WW2. The purpose of this collection is both
to present such documents in an easily accessible form, and to
point out more complete references.</p>

<p>Naturally, in preparing a collection like this, one has to decide
which documents to use; the amount of material is enormous. I have
tried to choose a small set of representative ones, which touch
as many aspects as possible. Many of these documents are very long,
so I have restricted myself to short excerpts. </p>

<p>My remarks are inside square [...] brackets.</p>

<p>-<ent type='PERSON'>Daniel Keren</ent> (dk@lems.brown.edu).</p>

<p>The organization of this collection is as follows:</p>

<p>1) STATMENTS BY LEADING <ent type='ORG'>NAZIS</ent>
2) GAS CHAMBERS AND GASSING VANS (See also "<ent type='ORG'>AUSCHWITZ</ent>")
3) DOCUMENTS ABOUT MASS MURDER (see also the "<ent type='ORG'>Jager Report</ent>",
in the "MISC" topic).
4) THE EXTERMINATION OF THE INSANE
5) <ent type='EVENT'>MEDICAL EXPERIMENTS</ent> I: MASS STERILIZATION
6) <ent type='EVENT'>MEDICAL EXPERIMENTS</ent> II: FREEZING, LOW PRESSURE AND OTHERS
7) THE ECONOMIC PLUNDER
8) <ent type='ORG'>AUSCHWITZ</ent>
9) <ent type='EVENT'>KRISTALLNACHT</ent>
10) VERDICT OF SS-COURT
11) MISC - includes the following:
a. Prosecution of a <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> woman for selling her mother milk
to feed <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> babies.
b. Some of the court proceedings from a case in which the death
sentence was imposed on a <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent> for allegedly having sex with
a <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> woman.
c. Various excerpts from anti-<ent type='NORP'>semitic</ent> publications (mostly,
"<ent type='PERSON'>Der Stuermer</ent>").
d. Letter about transporting to <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y "racially valuable
children" whose parents were slain by the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>s.
e. Order to hang any <ent type='LOC'>Pole</ent> who has sex with a <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> woman.
f. <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent>sfuehrer-SS <ent type='ORG'>Himmler</ent> describing <ent type='NORP'>Russians</ent> and <ent type='NORP'>Slavs</ent> as
"human animals" to be used for work.
g. <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> plans for plundering <ent type='GPE'>Poland</ent>.
h. Order by <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent>sfuehrer-SS <ent type='ORG'>Himmler</ent> to kill and destroy
everything in <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> occupied <ent type='GPE'>Ukraine</ent> before evacuating it.
i. A long and very detailed report about mass executions in
the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> occupied Baltics (the "Jager report").</p>

<p>STATMENTS BY LEADING <ent type='ORG'>NAZIS</ent>
**************************</p>

<p>Speech by <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent>, January 31, 1939
[Trials of War Criminals Before the <ent type='GPE'>Nuernberg</ent> Military Tribunals -
<ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, U.S Govt. Print. Off., 1949-1953, Vol XIII, p. 131]
---------------------------------------------------------------
Today I will once more be a prophet: If the international <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> financiers
in and outside Europe should succeed in plunging the nations once more into
a world war, then the result will not be the bolshevization of the earth,
and thus the victory of <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ry, but the annihilation of the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> race in
Europe!</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Adolph Hitler</ent> speaking to a crowd at the Sports Palace in <ent type='GPE'>Berlin</ent>,
30 January 1942. Quoted in "The <ent type='EVENT'>Holocaust</ent>", by <ent type='PERSON'>Martin Gilbert</ent>,
Holt, Rinehart and Winston, NY, 1985, p. 285. Text as monitored by the
Foreign Broadcast Monitoring Service, <ent type='ORG'>Federal Communications Commission</ent>.
---------------------------------------------------------------------
And we say that the war will not end as the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> imagine it
will, namely with the uprooting of the <ent type='NORP'>Aryans</ent>, but the result of
this war will be the complete annihilation of the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>.</p>

<p>Excerpts from the meeting between <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> and the <ent type='ORG'>Mufti</ent>,
<ent type='PERSON'>Haj Amin Husseini</ent>, on 28 November 1941. The notes were taken by
Dr. <ent type='PERSON'>Paul Otto Schmidt</ent> and are quoted in Fleming's "<ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> and the
Final Solution", p. 101-104. Also geheime <ent type='ORG'>Reichssache</ent> 57 a/41, Records
Dept. Foreign and <ent type='ORG'>Commonwealth Office</ent> Pa/2.
---------------------------------------------------------------------
The <ent type='PERSON'>Fuehrer</ent> then made the following declaration, requesting
the <ent type='ORG'>Mufti</ent> to lock it deep in his heart:</p>

<p>1) He (the <ent type='PERSON'>Fuehrer</ent>) would carry on the fight until the last
traces of the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent>-<ent type='NORP'>Communist</ent> European hegemony had been
obliterated.</p>

<p>2) In the course of this fight, the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> army would - at a
time that could not yet be specified, but in any case in
the clearly foreseeable future - gain the southern exit of
<ent type='NORP'>Caucasus</ent>.</p>

<p>3) As soon as this breakthrough was made, the <ent type='PERSON'>Fuehrer</ent> would
offer the <ent type='NORP'>Arab</ent> world his personal assurance that the hour
of liberation had struck. Thereafter, <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y's only
remaining objective in the region would be limited to the
annihilation of the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> living under <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> protection
in <ent type='NORP'>Arab</ent> lands.</p>

<p>Adolf <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent>, quoted in "<ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent>", by <ent type='PERSON'>Joachim Fest</ent>, Vintage
Books Edition, 1974, p. 679-680:
---------------------------------------------------------------
Nature is cruel; therefore we are also entitled to be cruel. When I
send the flower of <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> youth into the steel hail of the next war
without feeling the slightest regret over the precious <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> blood
that is being spilled, should I not also have the right to eliminate
millions of an inferior race that multiplies like vermin?</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Speechs</ent> by <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent>sfuehrer-SS <ent type='ORG'>Himmler</ent> before senior SS officers in <ent type='GPE'>Poznan</ent>,
October 4 and 6, 1943
[Trials of War Criminals Before the <ent type='GPE'>Nuernberg</ent> Military Tribunals -
<ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, U.S Govt. Print. Off., 1949-1953, Vol. XIII, p. 323, and
<ent type='ORG'>Himmler</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent>sfuehrer-SS - P. Padfield, <ent type='PERSON'>Henry Holt</ent> and Co, NY, 1990,
p. 469]
----------------------------------------------------------------------
I mean the evacuation of the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, the extermination of the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent>
race. It's one of those things it is easy to talk about, "the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent>
race is being exterminated", says one party member, "that's quite
clear, it's in our program, elimination of the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, and we're doing
it, exterminating them". And then they come, 80 million worthy
<ent type='NORP'>German</ent>s, and each one has his decent <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>. Of course the others are
vermin, but this one is an A-1 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>. Not one of those who talk this way
has watched it, not one of them has gone through it. Most of you know
what it means when 100 corpses are lying side by side, or 500, or
1000. To have stuck it out and at the same time - apart from
exceptions caused by human weakness - to have remained decent fellows,
that is what has made us hard. This is a page of glory in our history
which has never been written and is never to be written.</p>

<p>I ask of you that what I say in this circle you really only hear and
never speak of. We come to the question: how is it with the women and
the children? I have resolved even here on a completely clear
solution. That is to say I do not consider myself justified in
eradicating the men - so to speak killing or ordering them killed -
and allowing the avengers in the shape of the children to grow up for
our sons and grandsons. The difficult decision has to be taken, to
cause this <ent type='PERSON'>Volk</ent> [people] to disappear from the earth.</p>

<p>[This speech was recorded; the magnetic tapes are in the national
archives in <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, DC]</p>

<p>
Speech by <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent>sfuehrer-SS <ent type='ORG'>Himmler</ent> at <ent type='GPE'>Kharkow</ent>, April 1943
[<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> Conspiracy and Aggression - <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, U.S Govt. Print.
Off., 1946, Vol. IV, p. 572-574]
----------------------------------------------------------
We have - I would say, as very consistent National Socialists,
taken the question of blood as our starting point. We were the
first really to solve the problem of blood by action, and in
this connection, by problem of blood, we of course do not
mean antisemitism. Antisemitism is exactly the same as delousing.
Getting rid of lice is not a question of ideology. It is a
matter of cleanliness.</p>

<p>The <ent type='PERSON'>Goebbels</ent> [<ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent> propaganda Minister] Diaries, February 14 1942
[The <ent type='PERSON'>Goebbels</ent> Diaries 1942-1943 - L.P. Lochner, Doubleday &amp; Co., 1948,
p. 86]
----------------------------------------------------------------
World <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ry will suffer a great catastrophe at the same time as
<ent type='NORP'>Bolshevism</ent>. The <ent type='PERSON'>Fuehrer</ent> once more expressed his determination to
clean up the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> in Europe pitilessly. There must be no squeamish
sentimentalism about it. The <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> have deserved the catastrophe that
has now overtaken them. Their destruction will now go hand in hand
with the destruction of our enemies. We must hasten this process
with cold ruthlessness.</p>

<p>The <ent type='PERSON'>Goebbels</ent> [<ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent> propaganda Minister] diaries, March 27, 1942:
[The <ent type='PERSON'>Goebbels</ent> Diaries 1942-1943 - L.P. Lochner, Doubleday &amp; Co., 1948,
p. 147-148]
-----------------------------------------------------------
Beginning with <ent type='GPE'>Lublin</ent>, the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> in <ent type='ORG'>the General Government</ent>
[<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> occupied <ent type='GPE'>Poland</ent>] are now being evacuated eastward. The procedure
is a pretty barbaric one and not to be described here more definitely.
Not much will remain of the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>. On the whole it can be said that about
60 per cent of them will have to be liquidated whereas only 40 per cent
can be used for forced labor.</p>

<p>Speech by <ent type='PERSON'>Frank</ent> [Governor of occupied <ent type='GPE'>Poland</ent>], to <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> soldiers
in <ent type='GPE'>Poland</ent>, urging them to write home
[<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> Conspiracy and Aggression - <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, U.S Govt. Print.
Off., 1946, Vol. II, p. 633-634]
----------------------------------------------------------------------
In all these weeks, they [i.e., your families] will be thinking
of you, saying to themselves: my God, there he sits in
<ent type='GPE'>Poland</ent> where there are so many lice and <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, perhaps he is
hungry and cold, perhaps he is afraid to write.
It would not be a bad idea to send our dear ones back home a
picture, and tell them: well now, there are not so many
lice and <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> any more, and conditions here in the General
Government have changed and improved somewhat already. Of
course, I could not eliminate all lice and <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> in only one
year's time. But in the course of time, and above all, if you
help me, this end will be attained. After all, it is not
necessary for us to accomplish everything within a year and
right away, for what would otherwise be left for those who
follow us to do?</p>

<p>Speech by <ent type='PERSON'>Frank</ent> [Governor of occupied <ent type='GPE'>Poland</ent>], December 16 1941
[Documents on the <ent type='EVENT'>Holocaust</ent> - Edited by Y. Arad, Y. Gutman, A. <ent type='GPE'>Margaliot</ent>,
NY, Ktav Pub. House in Association with Yad-Vashem, 1981, p. 247, <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>
Conspiracy and Aggression - <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, U.S Govt. Print.
Off., 1946 Vol. II p. 634]
---------------------------------------------------------------
One way or another -- I will tell you quite openly -- we must finish
off the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>. The <ent type='PERSON'>Fuehrer</ent> put it into words once: should united <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ry
again succeed in setting off a world war, then the blood sacrifice
shall not be made only by the peoples driven into war, but then the
<ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent> of Europe will have met his end....</p>

<p>But what should be done with the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>? Can you believe that they will
be accommodated in settlements in the <ent type='GPE'>Ostland</ent>? In <ent type='GPE'>Berlin</ent> we were told:
why are you making all this trouble? We don't want them either, not in
<ent type='GPE'>Ostland</ent> nor in the <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent>skommissariat; liquidate them yourselves!
Gentlemen, I must ask you to steel yourselves against all
considerations of compassion. We must destroy the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> wherever we
find them, and wherever it is at all possible, in order to maintain
the whole structure of the <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent>...</p>

<p>The <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> represent for us also extraordinary malignant gluttons. We
have now approximately 2500000 of them in <ent type='ORG'>the General Government</ent>
[<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> occupied <ent type='GPE'>Poland</ent>], perhaps with the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> mixtures and
everything that goes with it, 3500000 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>. We cannot shoot or
poison those 3500000 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, but we shall nevertheless be able to take
measures which will lead somehow to their annihilation, and this in
connection with the gigantic measures to be determined in discussions
with the <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent>.</p>

<p>Letter from <ent type='PERSON'>Hoppner</ent>, higher SS and Police leader in the <ent type='ORG'>Warthegau</ent>, to
SS-Obersturmbannfuehrer Eichmann, July 16 1941
[Documents of Destruction - R. Hilberg, <ent type='ORG'>Quadrangle Books</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>, 1971, p. 87]
-------------------------------------------------------------------
Enclosed is a memorandum on the results of various discussions held
locally in the office of the <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent> Governor...</p>

<p>Subject: Solution of the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> question
.
.</p>

<p>4) This winter there is a danger that not all of the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> can be fed
anymore. One might weigh honestly, if the most humane solution
might not be to finish off those of the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> who are not employable
by means of some quick-working device. At any rate, that would be
more pleasant than to let them starve to death.
5) For the rest, the proposal was made that in this camp all the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent>
women, from whom one could still expect children, should be
sterilized so that the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> problem may actually be solved
completely with this generation.</p>

<p>Extracts from the minutes of the Wannsee conference, January 20
1942, regarding the "Final Solution of the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> Question"
[Trials of War Criminals Before the <ent type='GPE'>Nuernberg</ent> Military Tribunals -
<ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, U.S Govt. Print. Off., 1949-1953, Vol. XIII, p. 210-216]
---------------------------------------------------------------
.
.
II. At the beginning of the meeting the Chief of the <ent type='ORG'>Security</ent>
Police and the SD, SS Lieutenant General <ent type='PERSON'>Heydrich</ent>, reported his
appointment by the <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent> Marshal [<ent type='PERSON'>Goering</ent>] to service as
Commissioner for the preparation of the Final Solution of the
European <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> Problem....</p>

<p>In the course of this final solution of the European <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent>
Problem, approximately 11 million <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> are involved. They are
distributed among individual countries as follows:</p>

<p>A. Original <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent> Territory [<ent type='GPE'>Altreich</ent>] 131800
<ent type='GPE'>Austria</ent> 43700
<ent type='LOC'>East</ent>ern territories 420000
Government General [<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> occupied <ent type='GPE'>Poland</ent>] 2284000
.
.
.
The Netherlands 160800
.
.
<ent type='GPE'>Rumania</ent>, including <ent type='GPE'>Bessarabia</ent> 342000
.
.
Hungary 742800
<ent type='GPE'>USSR</ent> 5000000
.
.
White <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>, excluding <ent type='PERSON'>Bialystok</ent> 446484</p>

<p>[Many countries deleted for brevity]</p>

<p> TOTAL over 11000000
.
.</p>

<p>Under proper direction the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> should now in the course of the
Final Solution be brought to the <ent type='LOC'>East</ent> in a suitable way for use
as labor. In big labor gangs, with separation of the sexes, the
<ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> capable of work are brought to these areas and employed in
road building, in which task undoubtedly a great part will fall
out through natural diminution.</p>

<p>The remnant that finally is able to survive all this - since this
is undoubtedly the part with the strongest resistance - must
be treated accordingly since these people, representing a natural
selection, are to be regarded as the germ cell of a new <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent>
development. (See the experience of history).</p>

<p>In the program of the practical execution of the Final Solution,
Europe is combed through from the <ent type='LOC'>West</ent> to the <ent type='LOC'>East</ent>...
.
.
In the course of the final solution plans, the <ent type='GPE'>Nuernberg</ent> laws
are in a certain degree to form the basis, and accordingly the
complete settlement of the problem is to include also the
solution of the mixed marriage and the <ent type='PERSON'>Mischling</ent> [people partly
of <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> descent]...</p>

<p>The first degree <ent type='PERSON'>Mischling</ent> excepted from the evacuation is to
be sterilized in order to prevent any offspring and to settle
the <ent type='PERSON'>Mischling</ent> problem once and for all...</p>

<p>Excerpted from a memorandum dated 27 April, 1942 by Dr. Erhard
Wetzel (a lawyer), who was serving as desk officer in the <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent>
Ministry for the <ent type='LOC'>East</ent>ern Territories
["<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>sm: A History in Documents and Eyewitness Accounts, 1919-1945",
Volume II, J.Noakes and G.Pridham, editors. <ent type='ORG'>Schocken Books</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent>,
(c)1988 by <ent type='ORG'>the Dept</ent>. of History and Archeology, University of Exeter.
ISBN 0-8053-0973-5 (vol. 1), 0-8052-0972-7 (vol. 2). Document #690 on
p.979]
-----------------------------------------------------------------------
Re: the Solution of the <ent type='NORP'>Polish</ent> Question </p>

<p> ...It should be obvious that one cannot solve the <ent type='NORP'>Polish</ent> problem by
liquidating the <ent type='LOC'>Pole</ent>s in the same way as the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>. Such a solution
to the <ent type='NORP'>Polish</ent> problem would burden the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> people with guilt for
years to come and lose us the sympathies of people everywhere,
particularly since our neighbors would be bound to reckon that
they would be treated in the same way when the time came. </p>

<p>A letter to <ent type='PERSON'>Rosenberg</ent> enclosing reports from <ent type='ORG'>Generalkommisar</ent> for
white <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Kube</ent>, about the extermination of <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> in the east,
June 18 1943
[<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> Conspiracy and Aggression - <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, U.S Govt. Print.
Off., 1946, Vol I, p. 1001]
------------------------------------------------------------------
...The fact that <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> receive special treatment requires no further
discussion. However, it appears hardly believable that this is done
in the way described in the report of the General Commissioner of
1 June 1943. What is <ent type='PERSON'>Katyn</ent> against that? Imagine only that these
occurrences would become known to the other side and exploited by them!
Most likely such propaganda would have no effect only because
people who hear who hear and read about it simply would not be ready
to believe it.</p>

<p>["Special treatment" and "resettlement" mean extermination, as is
obvious from many such documents; consider, for instance, the
following]</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>Memorandum</ent> of <ent type='ORG'>Gestapo Headquarters</ent>, 15 June 1944
[Trials of War Criminals Before the <ent type='GPE'>Nuernberg</ent> Military Tribunals -
<ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, U.S Govt. Print. Off., 1949-1953, Vol. IV, p. 1166]
--------------------------------------------------------------------------
In amending my directive of June 20 1944, I request that those people
subject to special treatment be sent to a crematorium to be cremated
if possible.</p>

<p>GAS CHAMBERS AND GASSING VANS (See also "<ent type='ORG'>AUSCHWITZ</ent>")
****************************************************</p>

<p>Letter from Dr. <ent type='PERSON'>Erhard Wetzel</ent> to <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent>skommissar Lohse, October 25, 1941
[<ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> and the Final Solution - G. <ent type='ORG'>Fleming</ent>, University of California
Press, 1984, p. 70]
------------------------------------------------------------------------
With regard to my letter of 18 October 1941, please be informed that
Oberdiensleiter [Chief Executive Officer] Brack from the Fuehrer's
Chancellory has stated his readiness to assist in the construction of
the necessary accommodations and gassing apparatuses, so they must
first be constructed. Brack's view is that, since construction of the
apparatuses within the <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent> would present far greater difficulties
than on-site production, the most expedient course of action is to
send his people directly to <ent type='GPE'>Riga</ent>, in particular his chemist Dr.
<ent type='PERSON'>Kallmeyer</ent>, who will take the necessary steps from there.
Oberdiensleiter Brack further points out that the procedure in
question is not without its hazards, and that therefore special safety
precautions are needed. Under these circumstances, I ask you to
contact Oberdiensleiter Brack in the Fuehrer's Chancellory through
your higher SS and Police leader. Please request from him the
dispatching of the chemist Dr. <ent type='PERSON'>Kallmeyer</ent> and any further assistants
that are needed. I might further point out that Sturmbannfuehrer
Eichmann, the adviser on <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> affairs in the <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent> main security
office, is in complete accord with this procedure. According to the
information received here from <ent type='PERSON'>Sturmbannfuehrer Eichmann</ent>, camps for
<ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> will be set up in <ent type='GPE'>Riga</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Minsk</ent>, where <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> from the <ent type='GPE'>Altreich</ent>
[<ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y proper] might also be sent. <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> are currently being
evacuated from the <ent type='GPE'>Altreich</ent> to <ent type='GPE'>Lodz</ent> and other camps, from which those
fit for work will be transferred to work forces in the east. Given the
present situation, <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> who are not fit for work can be eliminated
without qualms through use of the Brack device. Incidents such as
those that took place during the shootings of <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> in <ent type='GPE'>Vilna</ent>, according
to a report I have on my desk, can hardly be sanctioned, keeping in
mind that the executions were undertaken openly, and the new
procedures assure that such incidents will no longer be possible. <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>
fit for work, on the other hand, will be transported to work forces in
the east. That the men and women in this latter group must be kept
apart from each other goes without saying. Please keep me informed as
to any further measures you take.</p>

<p>Letter from Dr August <ent type='PERSON'>Becker</ent> to SS-Obersturmbannfuehrer Rauff, 16 May 1942
[<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> Conspiracy and Aggression - <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, U.S Govt. Print.
Off., 1946, Vol III, p. 418]
----------------------------------------------------------------------
I ordered the vans of group D to be camouflaged as house trailers by
putting one set of window shutters on each side of the small van and
two on each side of the large vans, such as one often sees on farm
houses in the country. The vans became so well known, that not only
the authorities but also the civilian population called the van "death
van", as soon as one of these vehicles appeared. It is my opinion the
van cannot be kept secret for any length of time, not even
camouflaged...</p>

<p>Besides that, I ordered that during application of gas all the men
were to be kept as far away from the vans as possible, so they should
not suffer damage to their health by the gas which eventually would
escape. I should like to take this opportunity to bring the following
to your attention: several commands have had the unloading after the
application of gas done by their own men. I brought to the attention
of those S.K [Special Kommando] concerned the immense psychological
injuries and damages involved to their health that this work can have
for those men, even if not immediately, at least later on. The men
complained to me about head-aches which appeared after each unloading.
Nevertheless they don't want to change the orders, because they are
afraid prisoners called for that work could use an opportune moment to
flee. To protect the men from these damages, I request orders to be
issued accordingly.</p>

<p>The application of the gas is not undertaken correctly. In order to
come to an end as fast as possible, the driver presses the accelerator
to the fullest extent. By doing that the persons to be executed suffer
death from suffocation and not death by dozing off as was planned. My
directions have now proved that by correct adjustment of the levers
death comes faster and the prisoners fall asleep peacefully. Distorted
faces and excretions, such as could be seen before, are no longer
noticed.</p>

<p>Letter from <ent type='PERSON'>Willy</ent> Just to SS-Obersturmbannfuehrer <ent type='PERSON'>Walter Rauff</ent>, 5 June 1942
["<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>sm: A History in Documents and Eyewitness Accounts, 1919-1945",
Volume II, J.Noakes and G.Pridham, editors. <ent type='ORG'>Schocken Books</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent>,
(c)1988 by <ent type='ORG'>the Dept</ent>. of History and Archeology, University of Exeter.
ISBN 0-8053-0973-5 (vol. 1), 0-8052-0972-7 (vol. 2). Document #913]</p>

<p>["<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>sm: A History in Documents and Eye Witness Accounts, 191-1945" vol. 2,
document 913]
----------------------------------------------------------------------
RE: Technical alterations to the special vehicles already in operation
and those in production.</p>

<p>Since December 1941, for example, 97000 have been processed using
three vans without any faults developing in the vehicles. The
well-known explosion in <ent type='ORG'>Kulmhof</ent> (<ent type='PERSON'>Chelmno</ent>) must be treated as a special
case. It was caused by faulty practice. Special instructions have been
given to the relevant offices in order to avoid such accidents. The
instructions were such as to ensure a considerable increase in the
degree of security.</p>

<p>Further operational experience hitherto indicates that the following
technical alterations are appropriate....</p>

<p> 2) The vans are normally loaded with 9-10 people per square meter.
With the large <ent type='ORG'>Saurer</ent> special vans this is not possible because
although they do not become overloaded their maneuverability is much
impaired. A reduction in the load area appears desirable. It can be
achieved by reducing the size of the van by c. 1 meter. The difficulty
referred to cannot be overcome by reducing the size of the load. For a
reduction in the numbers will necessitate a longer period of operation
because the free spaces will have to be filled with CO. By contrast, a
smaller load area which is completely full requires a much sorter
period of operation since there are no free spaces.....</p>

<p> 3) The connecting hoses between the exhaust and the van frequently
rust through because they are corroded inside by the liquids which
fall on them. To prevent this the connecting piece must be moved so
that the gas is fed from the top downwards. This will prevent liquids
flowing in.....</p>

<p> 6) The lighting must be better protected against damage than
hitherto....It has been suggested that lighting should be dispensed
with since they are allegedly never used. However, experience shows
that when the rear door is closed and therefore when it becomes dark,
the cargo presses hard towards the door....It makes it difficult to
latch the door. Furthermore, it has been observed that the noise
always begins when the doors are shut presumably because of fear
brought on by the darkness.</p>

<p>Letter from SS-<ent type='PERSON'>Hauptsturmfuehrer Truehe</ent> to <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent> security office, room 2D3A
[<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> Conspiracy and Aggression - <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, U.S Govt. Print.
Off., 1946, Vol. I, p. 1001]
------------------------------------------------------------------------
A transport of <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, which has to be treated in a special way, arrives
weekly at the office of the commandant of <ent type='ORG'>the Security Police</ent> and the
<ent type='ORG'>Security</ent> Service of white <ent type='GPE'>Ruthenia</ent>. The three S-vans which are there
are not sufficient for that purpose. I request assignment of another
S-van (five tons). At the same time I request the shipment of twenty
gas hoses for the three S-vans on hand since the ones on hand are leaky
already.</p>

<p>DOCUMENTS ABOUT MASS MURDER (See also "THE JAGER REPORT", in "MISC")
************************************************************************</p>

<p>Regulations for the chief of <ent type='ORG'>the Security Police</ent> and of the
<ent type='ORG'>Security</ent> service, 17 July 1941
[<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> Conspiracy and Aggression - <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, U.S Govt. Print.
Off., 1946, Vol. III, p. 422-425]
-------------------------------------------------------------
...By use of such informers and by use of all other existing
possibilities, the discovery of all elements to be eliminated
among the prisoners, must succeed step by step at once. The
commandos must learn for themselves, in every case, by short
questioning of the informers and eventual questioning of other
prisoners.</p>

<p>The information of one informer is nor sufficient to designate
a camp inmate to be a suspect, without further proof; it must
be confirmed in some way if possible.</p>

<p>Above all, the following must be discovered:</p>

<p>All important functionaries of state and party, especially
professional revolutionaries.</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>Functionaries</ent> of the Komintren.</p>

<p>All policy forming party functionaries of the <ent type='ORG'>KPDSU</ent> and its fellow
organizations in the central committees, in the regional and
district committees.</p>

<p>All Peoples-Commissars and their deputies.</p>

<p>All former <ent type='ORG'>Political Commissars</ent> in <ent type='ORG'>the Red Army</ent>.</p>

<p>Leading personalities of the state authorities of central and
middle regions.</p>

<p>The leading personalities in the business world.</p>

<p>Members of the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent>-<ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>n intelligence.</p>

<p>All <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>.</p>

<p>All persons, who are found to be agitators of fanatical <ent type='NORP'>communists</ent>.</p>

<p>Letter from <ent type='ORG'>Generalkommisar</ent> for white <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Kube</ent>, to <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent>kommisar
for the <ent type='GPE'>Ostland</ent>, Lohse, 31 July 1942
['The Good Old Days' - E. Klee, W. Dressen, V. <ent type='PERSON'>Riess</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>The Free Press</ent>,
NY, 1988, p. 180-181]
--------------------------------------------------------------------
During the course of extensive discussions with SS-Brigadefuehrer Zenner
and the very competent <ent type='PERSON'>Leiter</ent> of the SD, SS-Obersturmbannfuehrer Dr.
<ent type='PERSON'>Strauch</ent>, it was established that we have liquidated about 55000 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>
in the past ten weeks...</p>

<p>Naturally the SD and I would prefer to eliminate the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> in the
Generalbezirk of white <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent> once and for all as soon as the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>
are no longer needed by the <ent type='NORP'>Wehrmacht</ent> for economic reasons. For the time
being, the Wehrmacht's requirements, as the principle employer of
<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> labor, are being taken into account.</p>

<p>Report No. 51 of <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent>sfuehrer-SS <ent type='ORG'>Himmler</ent> to <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> about mass
executions in the east, 1942
[Trials of War Criminals Before the <ent type='GPE'>Nuernberg</ent> Military Tribunals -
<ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, U.S Govt. Print. Off., 1949-1953, Vol. XIII, p. 269-272]
----------------------------------------------------------------
August September October November </p>

<p>Prisoners executed
after interrogation 2100 1400 1596 2731
.
.
Accomplices of guerrilla and
guerrilla suspects executed 1198 3020 6333 3706
.
.
<ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> executed 31246 165282 95735 70948
.
.
Villages and localities
Burned down or destroyed 35 12 20 92</p>

<p>Letter from SS Major-General <ent type='PERSON'>Stahlecker</ent> to SS General <ent type='PERSON'>Heydrich</ent>,
January 31, 1942
[The Final Solution: The Attempt to Exterminate the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> of Europe,
1939-1945 - G. Reitlinger, <ent type='GPE'>South Brunswick</ent>, T. Yosellof, 1968, p. 233]
--------------------------------------------------------------------
The complete removal of <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ry from the eastern territories has been
substantially attained, with the exception of white <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>, as a result
of the execution up to the present time of 229052 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>.</p>

<p>Daily situation report of the <ent type='PERSON'>Einsatzgruppen</ent> (special task forces)
in <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>, No. 124, October 25th, 1941
[The Final Solution: The Attempt to Exterminate the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> of Europe,
1939-1945 - G. Reitlinger, <ent type='GPE'>South Brunswick</ent>, T. Yosellof, 1968, p. 133]
--------------------------------------------------------------------
A second action consisted in applying special treatment to 812
men and women, all persons without interest from the racial and
intellectual point of view.</p>

<p>Order by <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent>skommissar Lohse to halt the killing of <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> skilled
workers, December 2 1941
[Documents on the <ent type='EVENT'>Holocaust</ent> - Edited by Y. Arad, Y. Gutman, A. <ent type='GPE'>Margaliot</ent>,
NY, Ktav Pub. House in Association with Yad-Vashem, 1981, p. 396]
-----------------------------------------------------------------------
<ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent>skommissar for <ent type='GPE'>Ostland</ent> <ent type='GPE'>Riga</ent>, December 2 1941
IIa diary No. 220/41g</p>

<p>The Chief Quartermaster (Chiefintendant) of the <ent type='NORP'>Wehrmacht</ent> Command in
<ent type='GPE'>Ostland</ent> has lodged a complaint that armament plants and repair
workshops have been deprived of <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> skilled workers through
their liquidation, and that they cannot be replaced there at the
present time.</p>

<p>I request most emphatically that the liquidation of <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> employed
as skilled workers in armament plants and repair workshops of the
<ent type='NORP'>Wehrmacht</ent> who cannot be replaced by local personnel be prevented.</p>

<p>Ereignismeldung UdSSR, No. 101, October 2 1941
['The Good Old Days' - E. Klee, W. Dressen, V. <ent type='PERSON'>Riess</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>The Free Press</ent>,
NY, 1988, p. 67]
---------------------------------------------------------------------
<ent type='PERSON'>Einsatzgruppen</ent> C
Standort <ent type='GPE'>Kiev</ent></p>

<p>In collaboration with the group staff and two <ent type='ORG'>Kommandos</ent> of Police
Regiment South, on 29 and 30 September 1941, <ent type='ORG'>Sonderkommando</ent> 4a
executed 33771 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> in <ent type='GPE'>Kiev</ent>.</p>

<p>Ereignismlrdung UdSSR, No. 128, November 3 1941
['The Good Old Days' - E. Klee, W. Dressen, V. <ent type='PERSON'>Riess</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>The Free Press</ent>,
NY, 1988, p. 68]
----------------------------------------------------------------------
In <ent type='GPE'>Kiev</ent>, difficulties that arose during the execution of a major action
of this type - particularly with regard to registration - were overcome
by the use of posters announcing that all <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> were to report for
resettlement. Although it was initially thought that the action would
only involve 5000 to 6000 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, more than 30000 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> reported, who
as a result of extremely efficient organization still believed they
were going to be resettled right up until the time they were executed.</p>

<p>Despite that fact that up to now a total of some 75000 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> have been
liquidated in this way, it has nevertheless become apparent that this
method will not provide a solution to the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> problem.</p>

<p>Report from chief of <ent type='ORG'>Security</ent> Police and SD, June 17 1942
[<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> Conspiracy and Aggression - <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, U.S Govt. Print.
Off., 1946, Supplement A, p. 661]
------------------------------------------------------------
The <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> in the <ent type='GPE'>Crimea</ent>.
.
.
Already in 1939, out of 65000 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> in the <ent type='GPE'>Crimea</ent>, 44000 (that
is almost 70 percent) live in the cities of <ent type='GPE'>Simferopol</ent>, Sevastopol,
Kertch, <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>patoria, Yalta, and <ent type='LOC'>Feodosia</ent> alone...
.
.
Of the <ent type='GPE'>Krimtschaks</ent> (approx. 6000) who were generally counted to
be <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, about half lived for the greater part in <ent type='GPE'>Simferopol</ent>
(2500) and in <ent type='ORG'>Karasubarsar</ent>. Their annihilation together with
that of the real <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> and the <ent type='ORG'>Gypsies</ent> in the <ent type='GPE'>Crimea</ent> took part
place essentially until the beginning of December 1941.</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>Weekly</ent> report from Frank's [Governor of occupied <ent type='GPE'>Poland</ent>] propaganda
department, October 26, 1942
[The Final Solution: The Attempt to Exterminate the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> of Europe,
1939-1945 - G. Reitlinger, <ent type='GPE'>South Brunswick</ent>, T. Yosellof, 1968, p. 283]
---------------------------------------------------------------
The resettlement of <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> (which partly assumes forms not worthy of
a cultured people) directly provokes comparison of the methods of
the <ent type='ORG'>Gestapo</ent> with those of the <ent type='ORG'>GPU</ent>. The railway wagons are said to
be in such a bad state that it is impossible to prevent <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> breaking
out. The result is that at wayside stations there occur wild shootings
and regular man-hunts. It is also reported that corpses of shot <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>
lie on the streets for days. Although the <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent> <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>s, as well as
the foreign population, are convinced of the necessity of liquidating
all <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, it would still be more appropriate to carry this out in
a manner that causes less sensation and offense.</p>

<p>Order of Boehme, Commanding General <ent type='GPE'>Serbia</ent>, October 10 1941,
Regarding Executions of Hostages
[Trials of War Criminals Before the <ent type='GPE'>Nuernberg</ent> Military Tribunals -
<ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, U.S Govt. Print. Off., 1949-1953, Vol. XI, p. 977]
-------------------------------------------------------------
2. In all garrison towns in <ent type='GPE'>Serbia</ent> all <ent type='NORP'>Communists</ent>, male residents
suspected as such, all <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, a certain number of nationalistic and
democratically inclined residents are to be arrested as hostages,
by means of sudden action...</p>

<p> 3. If losses of <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> soldiers or ethnic <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>s occur, the
territorially competent commanders up to the regimental commanders
are to decree the shooting of arrestees according to the
following quotas:</p>

<p> a. For each killed or murdered <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> soldier or ethnic <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> (man,
woman or child) 100 prisoners or hostages.</p>

<p> b. For each wounded <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> soldier or ethnic <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>, 50 prisoners
or hostages.</p>

<p>The shootings are to be carried out by the troops.</p>

<p>Order of Commanding General in <ent type='GPE'>Serbia</ent>, October 4 1941, ordering mass
execution of concentration camp inmates for the killing of 21 <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>
Soldiers
[Trials of War Criminals Before the <ent type='GPE'>Nuernberg</ent> Military Tribunals -
<ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, U.S Govt. Print. Off., 1949-1953, Vol. XI, p. 976]
--------------------------------------------------------------------
Twenty-one soldiers were tortured to death by <ent type='NORP'>Communist</ent> bandits
in a bestial manner on 2 October in a surprise attack units of
the signal regiment between <ent type='GPE'>Belgrade</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Obrenovac</ent>. As reprisal
and retaliation, 100 <ent type='GPE'>Serbia</ent>n prisoners are to be shot at once
for each murdered <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> soldier. The Chief of the Military
administration is requested to pick out 2100 inmates in the
concentration camp <ent type='ORG'>Sabac</ent> in <ent type='GPE'>Belgrade</ent> (primarily <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> and
<ent type='NORP'>Communists</ent>) and to fix the time and place as well as burial place.</p>

<p>THE EXTERMINATION OF THE INSANE
*******************************</p>

<p>Letter from chief of institution for feeble-minded in <ent type='GPE'>Stetten</ent> to
<ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent> Minister of justice Dr. <ent type='PERSON'>Frank</ent>, September 6 1940
[Trials of War Criminals Before the <ent type='GPE'>Nuernberg</ent> Military Tribunals -
<ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, U.S Govt. Print. Off., 1949-1953, Vol. I, p. 854]
-----------------------------------------------------------------
Dear <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent> Minister,</p>

<p>The measure being taken at present with mental patients of all
kinds have caused a complete lack of confidence in justice among
large groups of people. Without the consent of relatives and
guardians, such patients are being transferred to different
institutions. After a short time they are notified that the
person concerned has died of some disease...</p>

<p>If the state really wants to carry out the extermination of these
or at least of some mental patients, shouldn't a law be
promulgated, which can be justified before the people - a law
that would give everyone the assurance od careful examination
as to whether he is due to die or entitled to live and which
would also give the relatives a chance to be heard, in a
similar way, as provided by the law for the prevention of
Hereditarily affected Progeny?</p>

<p>Letter from Dr. Wurm, of <ent type='ORG'>the Wuerttemberg Evangelical</ent> Provincial Church,
to <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent> Minister of interior Dr. <ent type='PERSON'>Frick</ent>, September 5 1940
[<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> Conspiracy and Aggression - <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, U.S Govt. Print.
Off., 1946, Supp. A, p. 1223]
-----------------------------------------------------------------------
Dear <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent> Minister,</p>

<p>On July 19th I sent you a letter about the systematic extermination
of lunatics, feeble-minded and epileptic persons. Since then this
practice has reached tremendous proportions: recently the inmates of
old-age homes have also been included. The basis for this practice
seems to be that in an efficient nation there should be no room
for weak and frail people. It is evident from the many reports which
we are receiving that the people's feelings are being badly hurt
by the measures ordered and that the feeling of legal insecurity
is spreading which is regrettable from the point of view of national
and state interest.</p>

<p>Letter from Dr. <ent type='NORP'>Hilfrich</ent>, Bishop of <ent type='GPE'>Limburg</ent>, to the <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent> Minister of
Justice, August 13 1941
[Trials of War Criminals Before the <ent type='GPE'>Nuernberg</ent> Military Tribunals -
<ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, U.S Govt. Print. Off., 1949-1953, Vol. I, p. 845-846]
---------------------------------------------------------------------
Regarding the report submitted on July 16 by the Chairman of the <ent type='ORG'>Fulda</ent>
Bishops' conference, Cardinal Dr. <ent type='PERSON'>Bertram</ent>, I consider it my duty to
present the following as a concrete illustration of destruction of
so-called "useless life".</p>

<p>About 8 Kilometers from <ent type='GPE'>Limburg</ent> in the little town of <ent type='PERSON'>Hadamar</ent>, on a
hill overlooking the town, there is an institution which had formerly
served various purposes and of late had been used as a nursing home.
This institution was renovated and furnished as a place in which, by
consensus of opinion, the above mentioned Euthanasia has been
systematically practiced for months-approximately since February
1941. This fact is, of course, known beyond the administrative
district of <ent type='GPE'>Wiesbaden</ent>...</p>

<p>Several times a week buses arrive in <ent type='PERSON'>Hadamar</ent>d with a considerable
number of such victims. School children of the vicinity know this
vehicle and say "here comes the murder-box again". After the arrival
of the vehicle, the citizens of <ent type='PERSON'>Hadamar</ent> watch the smoke rise out of
the chimney...</p>

<p>The effect of the principles at work here that children call each
other names and say "you're crazy; you'll be sent to the baking oven
in <ent type='PERSON'>Hadamar</ent>"...</p>

<p>All God-fearing man consider this destruction of helpless beings a
crass injustice...</p>

<p>Officials of the State Police, it is said, are trying to suppress
discussions of the <ent type='PERSON'>Hadamar</ent> occurrences by means of severe threats...</p>

<p>I beg you most humbly, Herr <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent> Minister, in the sense of the report
of the Episcopate of 16 July of this year, to prevent further
transgressions of the Fifth Commandment of God.</p>

<p>Letter from <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent>sfuehrer-SS <ent type='ORG'>Himmler</ent> to SS-<ent type='PERSON'>Oberfuehrer Brack</ent>,
19 December 1940
[Trials of War Criminals Before the <ent type='GPE'>Nuernberg</ent> Military Tribunals -
<ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, U.S Govt. Print. Off., 1949-1953, Vol. I, p. 856]
-----------------------------------------------------------------
Dear Brack,</p>

<p>I hear there is great excitement on the <ent type='ORG'>Alb</ent> because of the Grafeneck
Institution.
The population recognizes the gray automobiles of the SS and think they
know what is going on at the constantly smoking crematory. What happens
there is a secret and yet is no longer one. Thus the worst feeling has
arisen there, and in my opinion there remains only one thing, to
discontinue the use of the institution in this place and in any event
disseminate information in a clever and sensible manner by showing motion
pictures on the subject of inherited and mental diseases in just that
locality.
May I ask for a report as to how the difficult problem is solved?</p>

<p>Extract from the Diary of General <ent type='PERSON'>Halder</ent>, September-November 1941
[Trials of War Criminals Before the <ent type='GPE'>Nuernberg</ent> Military Tribunals -
<ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, U.S Govt. Print. Off., 1949-1953, Vol. X, p. 1195-1196]
-----------------------------------------------------------------
26 September 1941:
.
.
h. Mental institutions in <ent type='ORG'>Army Group</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>North</ent>. <ent type='NORP'>Russians</ent> regards the
feebleminded as sacred beings. Killing them is necessary,
nontheless.</p>

<p><ent type='EVENT'>MEDICAL EXPERIMENTS</ent> I: MASS STERILIZATION
*****************************************</p>

<p>Letter from SS-<ent type='PERSON'>Oberfuehrer Brack</ent> to <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent>sfuehrer-SS <ent type='ORG'>Himmler</ent>, June 23, 1942
[Documents on the <ent type='EVENT'>Holocaust</ent> - Edited by Y. Arad, Y. Gutman, A. <ent type='GPE'>Margaliot</ent>,
NY, Ktav Pub. House in Association with Yad-Vashem, 1981, p. 272]
--------------------------------------------------------------------
Honorable Mr. <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent>sfuehrer!</p>

<p>On instruction from <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent>sleiter Bouhler I placed a part of my men at
the disposal of Brigadefuehrer Globocnik some considerable time ago
for his special task. Following a further request from him, I have
now made available more personnel. On this occasion Brigadefuehrer
Globocnik pressed the view that the whole action against the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>
should be carried out as quickly as it is in any way possible, so
that we will not some day be stuck in the middle should any kind
of difficulty make it necessary to stop the action. you yourself,
Mr. <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent>sfuehrer, expressed the view to me at an earlier time that
one must work as fast as possible, if only for reasons of concealment.
Both views are more than justified according to my own experience,
and basically they produce the same results. Nevertheless I beg to
be permitted to present the following consideration of my own in
this connection:</p>

<p>According to my impression there are at least 2-3 million men and
women well fit for work among the approx. 10 million European
<ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>. In consideration of the exceptional difficulties posed for
us by the question of labor, I am of the opinion that these 2-3
million should in any case be taken out and kept alive. Of course
this can only be done if they are in the same time rendered
incapable of reproduction. I reported to you about a year ago that
persons under my instruction have completed the necessary experiments
for this purpose. I wish to bring up these facts again. The type
of sterilization which is normally carried out on persons with
genetic disease is out of the question in this case, as it takes
too much time and is expensive. Castration by means of X-rays,
however, is not only relatively cheap, but can be carried out on
many thousands in a very short time. I believe that it has become
unimportant at the present time whether those affected will then
in the course of a few weeks or months realize by the effects that
they are castrated.</p>

<p>In the event, Mr. <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent>sfuehrer, that you decide to choose these
means in the interest of maintaining labor-material, <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent>sleiter
Bouhler will be ready to provide the doctors and other personnel
needed to carry out this work. He also instructed me to inform you
that I should then order the required equipment as quickly as
possible.</p>

<p>Letter from Dr. Pokorny to <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent>sfuehrer-SS <ent type='ORG'>Himmler</ent>, October 1941
[<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> Conspiracy and Aggression - <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, U.S Govt. Print.
Off., 1946, Supp. A, p. 1279]
-----------------------------------------------------------------
Prompted by the thought that the enemy must not only be conquered but
exterminated, I feel obliged to submit the following to you as the
<ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent> Plenipotentiary for the Consolidation of <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> Folkdom:</p>

<p>Dr. <ent type='GPE'>Madous</ent> is publishing the results of his research into sterilization
by medicaments (I enclose both works). In reading this article, I was
struck by the enormous importance of this medicament in the present
struggle of our people. Should it be possible to produce as soon as
possible, as a result of this research, a medicament which, after a
comparatively brief period, would cause an unnoticed sterilization
in individuals, we would have in our disposal a new and very effective
weapon. The thought alone that the 3 million <ent type='NORP'>Bolsheviks</ent> now in <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>
captivity could be sterilized, so that they would be available for
work but precluded from propagation, opens up the most far-reaching
perspectives.</p>

<p>Letter from SS-Oberfuehrer Gund to <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent>sfuehrer-SS <ent type='ORG'>Himmler</ent>,
August 24, 1942
[Trials of War Criminals Before the <ent type='GPE'>Nuernberg</ent> Military Tribunals -
<ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, U.S Govt. Print. Off., 1949-1953, Vol. I, p. 717]
------------------------------------------------------------------
At the orders of <ent type='NORP'>Gauleiter</ent> Dr. Jury, his staff have hitherto busied
themselves especially with the problems of population, racial policy,
and antisocial elements. Since the prevenation of reproduction by
the congenitally unfit and racially inferior belongs to the duties
of our National Socialist racial and demographic policy, the present
director of <ent type='ORG'>the District Office for</ent> Racial Policy, Gauhauptstellenleiter
Dr. Fehringer, has examined the question of sterilization and found
that the methods so far available, castration and sterilization, are
not sufficient in themselves to meet expectations. Consequently, the
obvious question occurred to him whether impotence and sterility in
could not be produced in men and women by the administration of medicine
or injections...</p>

<p>The director of my race policy office points out that the necessary
research and human experiments could be undertaken by by an
appropriately selected medical staff, basing their work on the
<ent type='ORG'>Madaus</ent> animal experiments in cooperation with the pharmacological
institute of <ent type='ORG'>the Faculty</ent> of Medicine of <ent type='GPE'>Vienna</ent>, on the persons of
of the inmates of the <ent type='NORP'>Gypsy</ent> camp of <ent type='GPE'>Lackenbach</ent> in Lower Danube.</p>

<p>Letter from <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent>sfuehrer-SS <ent type='ORG'>Himmler</ent> to SS-<ent type='PERSON'>Oberfuehrer Brack</ent>, 11 August
1942
[Trials of War Criminals Before the <ent type='GPE'>Nuernberg</ent> Military Tribunals -
<ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, U.S Govt. Print. Off., 1949-1953, Vol. I, p. 722]
-----------------------------------------------------------
Dear Brack,</p>

<p>It is only today that I have the opportunity of acknowledging the
receipt of your letter of June 23. I am positively interested in
seeing the sterilization by X-rays tried out at least once in one camp
in a series of experiments.</p>

<p>Letter from <ent type='GPE'>Blankenburg</ent> to <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent>sfuehrer-SS <ent type='ORG'>Himmler</ent>, 29 April 1944
[Trials of War Criminals Before the <ent type='GPE'>Nuernberg</ent> Military Tribunals -
<ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, U.S Govt. Print. Off., 1949-1953, Vol. I, 723]
------------------------------------------------------------------------
By order of <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent>sleiter Bouhler I submit to you as an enclosure a work
of Dr. <ent type='PERSON'>Horst Schumann</ent> on the influence of X-rays on human genital glands.</p>

<p>Previously you have asked <ent type='PERSON'>Oberfuehrer Brack</ent> to perform this work, and
you supported it by providing the adequate material in the concentration
camp Auschwitz. I point especially to the second part of this work,
which shows that by those means castration of males is almost impossible
or requires an effort which does not pay. As I have convinced myself,
operative castration requires not more than 6 to 7 minutes, and therefore
can be performed more reliably and quicker than castration by X-rays.</p>

<p>Soon I will be able to submit a continuation of this work to you.</p>

<p>Letter from SS-Obersturmbannfuehrer <ent type='PERSON'>Brandt</ent> to Prof. <ent type='PERSON'>Clauberg</ent>, 10 July 1942
[Trials of War Criminals Before the <ent type='GPE'>Nuernberg</ent> Military Tribunals -
<ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, U.S Govt. Print. Off., 1949-1953, Vol. I, p. 729]
--------------------------------------------------------------------
Today the <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent> Leader SS charged me with transmitting to you his wish
that you go to <ent type='ORG'>Ravensbrueck</ent> after you have had another talk with
SS-<ent type='PERSON'>Obergruppenfuehrer Pohl</ent> and the camp physician of the women's
concentration camp <ent type='ORG'>Ravensbrueck</ent>, in order to perform the sterilization
of <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses according to your method...</p>

<p>Thorough experiments should be conducted to investigate the effect of
the sterilization largely in a way that you find out after a certain
time, which you would have to fix, perhaps by X-rays, what kind of
changes have taken place. In some cases a practical experiment might
be arranged by locking up a <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ess and a <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent> together for a certain
period and then seeing what results are achieved.</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>Memorandum</ent> of SS-Obersturmbannfuehrer <ent type='PERSON'>Brandt</ent> on discussion between
<ent type='ORG'>Himmler</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Gebhart</ent>, Gluecks, and <ent type='PERSON'>Clauberg</ent> concerning sterilization
experiments conducted on <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses
[Trials of War Criminals Before the <ent type='GPE'>Nuernberg</ent> Military Tribunals -
<ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, U.S Govt. Print. Off., 1949-1953, Vol. I, p. 728]
------------------------------------------------------------------
<ent type='PERSON'>Fuehrer</ent> Headquarters, July 1942</p>

<p>On 7 July 1942 a discussion took place between the <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent> Leader SS,
SS-Brigadefuehrer Professor Dr. <ent type='PERSON'>Gebhart</ent>, SS-Brigadefuehrer Gluecks,
and SS-Brigadefuehrer <ent type='PERSON'>Clauberg</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Koenigshette</ent>. The topic of the
discussion was the sterilization of <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses. The <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent> Leader
SS has promised Brigadefuehrer Professor <ent type='PERSON'>Clauberg</ent> that Auschwitz
concentration camp will be at his disposal for his experiments on
human beings and animals. By means of some fundamental experiments,
a method should be found which would lead to sterilization of persons
without their knowledge. The <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent> Leader SS wanted to get another
report as soon as the result of these experiments was known, so
that the sterilization of <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses could then be carried out in
actuality.</p>

<p>It should also be examined, preferably in cooperation with Professor
Dr. Hohlfelder, an X-ray specialist in <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y, what way sterilization
of men could be achieved by X-ray treatment.</p>

<p>The <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent> Leader SS called the special attention of all gentlemen
present to the fact that the matter involved was most secret and
should be discussed only with the officers in charge and that
the persons present at the experiments had to pledge secrecy.</p>

<p>Letter from Professor <ent type='PERSON'>Clauberg</ent> to <ent type='ORG'>Himmler</ent>, June 7 1943, on his
research concerning sterilization of women
[Trials of War Criminals Before the <ent type='GPE'>Nuernberg</ent> Military Tribunals -
<ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, U.S Govt. Print. Off., 1949-1953, Vol 1, p. 730]
----------------------------------------------------------------
Dear <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent> Leader,</p>

<p>Today I am fulfilling my obligation to report to you from time to
time about the state of my research work...</p>

<p>The method I contrived to achieve the sterilization of the female
organism without operation is as good as perfected. It can be
performed by a single injection made through the entrance of
the uterus in the course of the customary gynecological
examination known to every physician. If I say that the
method is "as good as perfected" this means:</p>

<p>1. Still to be worked out are only minor improvements of the method.</p>

<p>2. Already today it could be put to practical use in the course
of our regular eugenic sterilization and could thus replace
the operation.</p>

<p>As to the question which you, <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent> Leader, asked me almost a
one year ago, i.e., how much time would probably be required
to sterilize 1000 women by using this method. Today I can
answer you with regard to the future as follows:</p>

<p>If my researches continue to have the same results as up to
now - and there is no reason to doubt that - then the moment is
not far off when I can say:</p>

<p>"One adequately trained physician in one adequately equipped
place, with perhaps 10 assistants (the number of assistants in
conformity with the speed desired) will most likely be able to
deal with several hundred, if not even 1000 per day".</p>

<p><ent type='EVENT'>MEDICAL EXPERIMENTS</ent> II: FREEZING, LOW PRESSURE AND OTHERS
*********************************************************</p>

<p>Letter from SS-Standartenfuehrer Sievers to SS-Obersturmbannfuehrer
Dr. <ent type='PERSON'>Brandt</ent>, November 2 1942
[Trial of <ent type='EVENT'>the Major War Criminals Before</ent> the International Military
Tribunal, Vol. XX, p. 520]
-------------------------------------------------------------------
Dear Comarade <ent type='PERSON'>Brandt</ent>,</p>

<p>As you know, the <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent>sfuehrer-SS has directed that
SS-Hauptsturmfuehrer Prof. Dr. Hirt be supplied with everything
needed for his research work. For certain anthropological
researches - I already reported to the <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent>sfuehrer-SS on
them - 150 skeletons of prisoners, or rather <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, are
required, which are to be supplied by the KL Auschwitz.</p>

<p>Letter from <ent type='PERSON'>Graum</ent> to <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent>sfuehrer-SS <ent type='ORG'>Himmler</ent>, June 1 1943
[<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> Conspiracy and Aggression - <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, U.S Govt. Print.
Off., 1946, Supp. A, p. 1273]
------------------------------------------------------------------
Dear <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent>sfuehrer,</p>

<p>The fuehrer's Commissioner-General, SS Brigadefuehrer Professor Dr. <ent type='PERSON'>Brandt</ent>,
called me with the request that I should assist him by placing prisoners
at his disposal for research work into the cause of contagious
jaundice (Hepatitis epidemica) which he was furthering considerably.</p>

<p>The work has been carried out up to now by a medical captain, Dr. Dohmen,
within the framework of the research place of the army medical inspectorate,
with the participation of the <ent type='PERSON'>Robert Koch</ent> institute. It has up to now led
to the result, in agreement with the result of other <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> research
workers, that contagious jaundice is not carried by bacteria but by a
virus. In order to increase our knowledge, which is based up to now
only on vaccination experiments from men to animals, the reverse way
is now necessary, namely the vaccination of the cultivated virus germ
into humans. One must reckon on cases of death.</p>

<p>Letter to SS-<ent type='PERSON'>Obergruppenfuehrer Pohl</ent>, 19 May 1944
[<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> Conspiracy and Aggression - <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, U.S Govt. Print.
Off., 1946, Supp. A, p. 1270-1271]
-------------------------------------------------------------------
Dear <ent type='PERSON'>Obergruppenfuehrer</ent>,</p>

<p>Following our application of 30.9.43, you gave me your authorization on the
25.10.43 for the carrying out of experiments with a view to producing a
new kind of spotted fever serum and transferred 100 suitable prisoners
to <ent type='PERSON'>Natzweiler</ent> for this purpose. It has been possible to carry out the
experiments very satisfactorily so far with the help of the chief of
<ent type='ORG'>Department</ent> D III, SS Standartenfuehrer Dr. Dolling commissioned by you.</p>

<p>Letter from SS-Sturmbannfuehrer <ent type='PERSON'>Brandt</ent> to SS-Obersturmbannfuehrer Sievers,
21 March 1942
[Trials of War Criminals Before the <ent type='GPE'>Nuernberg</ent> Military Tribunals -
<ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, U.S Govt. Print. Off., 1949-1953, Vol. I, p. 144]
------------------------------------------------------------------------
Reference is made to the subatmospheric pressure experiments which are
being carried out on concentration camp inmates in the <ent type='LOC'>Dachau</ent> camp by
the air force. The <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent> Leader-SS has approved the experiments under
the conditions that SS-Untersturmfuehrer Dr. <ent type='PERSON'>Rascher</ent> who is an
<ent type='NORP'>Obersturmfuehrer</ent> in the air-force, will take part in them.</p>

<p>Letter from SS-Untersturmfuehrer <ent type='PERSON'>Rascher</ent> to <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent>sfuehrer-SS <ent type='ORG'>Himmler</ent>,
5 April 1942
[Trials of War Criminals Before the <ent type='GPE'>Nuernberg</ent> Military Tribunals -
<ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, U.S Govt. Print. Off., 1949-1953, Vol. I, p. 144-147]
------------------------------------------------------------------------
Highly esteemed <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent> Leader:</p>

<p>Enclosed is an interim report on the low-pressure experiments so far
conducted in the concentration camp of <ent type='LOC'>Dachau</ent>...</p>

<p>Only continuous experiments at altitudes higher than 10.5 Km resulted
in death. These experiments showed that breathing stopped after about
30 minutes, while in two cases the electrocardiographically charted
action of the heart continued for another 20 minutes.</p>

<p>The third experiment of this type took such an extraordinary course
that I called an SS physician of the camp as a witness, since I had
worked on these experiments all by myself. It was a continuous
experiment without oxygen at a height of 12 Km. conducted on a 37-year
old <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent> in good general condition. Breathing continued up to 30
minutes. After 4 minutes the experimental subject began to perspire
and to wiggle his head, after 5 minutes cramps occurred, between 6
and 10 minutes breathing increased in speed and the experimental
subject became unconscious; from 11 to 30 minutes breathing slowed
down to three breaths per minute, finally stopping altogether. </p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>Severest</ent> cyanosis developed in between and foam appeared at the mouth...</p>

<p> Autopsy report
~~~~~~~~~~~~</p>

<p>One hour later after breathing had stopped, the spinal marrow was
completely severed and the brain was removed. Thereupon the action
of the auricle stopped for 40 seconds. In then renewed its action,
coming to a complete standstill 8 minutes later. A heavy subarchnoid
oedema was found in the brain. In the veins and arteries of the brain
a considerable quantity of air was discovered.</p>

<p>Letter from SS-Untersturmfuehrer <ent type='PERSON'>Rascher</ent> to <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent>sfuehrer-SS <ent type='ORG'>Himmler</ent>,
11 May 1942
[Trials of War Criminals Before the <ent type='GPE'>Nuernberg</ent> Military Tribunals -
<ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, U.S Govt. Print. Off., 1949-1953, Vol. I, p. 152-155]
-------------------------------------------------------------------
Highly esteemed <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent> Leader,</p>

<p>Enclosed I am forwarding a short summary on the principle experiments
conducted up to date...</p>

<p>For the following experiments <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> professional criminals who had
committed race pollution were used. The question of the formation of
embolism was investigated in 10 cases. Some of the experimental subjects
died during a continued high-altitude experiment; for instance, after
one-half hour at the height of 12 Km. After the skull had been opened
under water an ample amount of air embolism was found in the brain
vessels and, in part, free air in the brain ventricles.</p>

<p>To find out whether the severe psychic and physical effects, as
mentioned under No. 3, are due to the formation of embolism, the
following was done: After relative recuperation from such a
parachute descending test had taken place, however, before regaining
consciousness, some experimental subjects were kept under water
until they died. When the skull and the cavities of the breast and
of the abdomen had been opened under water, an enormous amount of
air embolism was found in the vessels of the brain, the coronary
vessels, and vessels of the liver and the intestines, etc.</p>

<p>It was also proved by experiments that air embolism occurs in
practically all vessels even while pure oxygen is being inhaled.
One experimental subject was made to breathe pure oxygen for
2.5 hours before the experiment started. After 6 minutes at a
height of 20 Km, he died and at dissection also showed ample
air embolism, as was the case in all other experiments.</p>

<p>Report by SS-Untersturmfuehrer <ent type='PERSON'>Rascher</ent> about intense cooling experiments
in <ent type='LOC'>Dachau</ent> concentration camps, 10 September 1942
[Trials of War Criminals Before the <ent type='GPE'>Nuernberg</ent> Military Tribunals -
<ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, U.S Govt. Print. Off., 1949-1953, Vol. I, p. 220]
-----------------------------------------------------------------------
The experimental subjects were placed in the water, dressed in complete
flying uniform, winter or summer combination, and with an aviator's
helmet. A life jacket made out of rubber kapok was to prevent
submerging. The experiments were carried out at water temperatures
varying from from 2.5 to 12 Centigrade. In one experimental series,
the <ent type='ORG'>occiput</ent> (brain stem) protruded above the water, while in another
series of experiments the <ent type='ORG'>occiput</ent> (brain stem) and back of the head
were submerged in water.</p>

<p>Electrical measurements gave low temperature readings of 26.4 in the
stomach and 26.5 in the rectum. Fatalities occurred only when the
brain stem and the back of the head were also chilled. Autopsies of
of such fatal cases always revealed large amounts of free blood, up
to one-half litter, in the cranial cavity.</p>

<p>Report by Prof. Dr. Holzloehner, Dr. <ent type='PERSON'>Rascher</ent>, and Dr. <ent type='PERSON'>Finke</ent>, regarding
cooling experiments, 10 October 1942
[Trials of War Criminals Before the <ent type='GPE'>Nuernberg</ent> Military Tribunals -
<ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, U.S Govt. Print. Off., 1949-1953, Vol. I, p. 226-243]
--------------------------------------------------------------------
If the experimental subject was placed in the water under narcosis,
one observed a certain arousing effect. The subject began to groan
and made some defensive movements. In a few cases a state of excitation
developed. This was especially severe in the cooling of head and
neck. But never was a complete cessation of the narcosis observed.
The defensive movements ceased after about 5 minutes. There
followed a progressive rigor, which developed especially strongly
in the arm musculature; the arms were strongly flexed and pressed to
the body. The rigor increased with the continuation of the cooling,
now and then interrupted by tonic-clonic twitchings. With still more
marked sinking of the body temperature it suddenly ceased. These
cases ended fatally, without any successful results from resuscitation
efforts.</p>

<p>Letter from SS-Untersturmfuehrer Dr. <ent type='PERSON'>Rascher</ent> to SS-Sturmbannfuehrer
Rudolph <ent type='PERSON'>Brandt</ent>, October 3 1942
[Trials of War Criminals Before the <ent type='GPE'>Nuernberg</ent> Military Tribunals -
<ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, U.S Govt. Print. Off., 1949-1953, Vol. I, p. 221-222]
----------------------------------------------------------------------
The <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent> leader SS wants to be informed of the state of the
experiments. I can announce that the experiments have been
concluded, with the exception of those on warming with body
heat. The final report will be ready in about 5 days. Prof.
Holzloehner, for reasons I cannot fathom, does not himself
want to make the report to the <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent> Leader <ent type='ORG'>Himmler</ent> and has
asked me to attend to it. This report must be made before
20 October, because the great <ent type='ORG'>Luftwaffe</ent> [<ent type='NORP'>German</ent> air-force]
conference on freezing takes place on <ent type='GPE'>Nuernberg</ent> on 25 October.
The report on the results of our research must be made there,
to assure that they be used in time for the troops. May I ask
you to arrange for a decision from the <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent> Leader regarding
the final report to him, and the submission to him of the
relevant material? </p>

<p>Today I received your letter of 22 September 1942, in which the
<ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent> Leader orders that the experiments on warming through
body heat must absolutely be conducted. Because of incomplete
address it was delayed. Today I asked Obersturmbannfuehrer
Sievers to send a telegram to the camp commander immediately,
to the effect that four <ent type='NORP'>Gypsy</ent> women be procured at once
from another camp. Moreover, I asked SS Obersturmbannfuehrer
Sievers to take steps to have the low pressure chamber ready
for use.</p>

<p>THE ECONOMIC PLUNDER
*********************</p>

<p>Letter from SS-Brigadefuehrer <ent type='PERSON'>Frank</ent> to chief of administration of
Auschwitz, concerning the utilization and distribution of "evacuated"
<ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 26 September 1942
[Trials of War Criminals Before the <ent type='GPE'>Nuernberg</ent> Military Tribunals -
<ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, U.S Govt. Print. Off., 1949-1953, Vol. XIII, p. 256-258]
---------------------------------------------------------------------
e) Women's clothing and women underwear including footwear, children's
clothing and children's underwear including footwear have to be handed
over to the <ent type='PERSON'>Volk</ent>sdeutsche Mittelstelle against payment...</p>

<p>f) Featherbeads, quilts, woolen blankets, cloth for suits, shawls,
umbrellas, walking sticks, thermos flasks, earflaps, baby carriages,
combs, handbags, leather belts, shopping baskets, tobacco pipes,
sun glasses, mirrors, table knives, forks and spoons, knapsacks, and
suitcases made from leather or artificial material are to be delivered
to the <ent type='PERSON'>Volk</ent>sdeutsche Mittelstelle. The question of payment will be
decided later...</p>

<p>h) Spectacles and eyeglasses of every kind are to be handed in to
the medical office for utilization. (Spectacles with golden frames
have to be handed in without glasses together with the rare metals).</p>

<p>Letter from prison warden <ent type='PERSON'>Guenther</ent> to the general commissar of white
<ent type='GPE'>Ruthenia</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Minsk</ent>, 31 May 1943
[<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> Conspiracy and Aggression - <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, U.S Govt. Print.
Off., 1946, Vol. VIII, p. 208]
-----------------------------------------------------------------------
Since that time all <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>n <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> who were turned to us,
had their golden bridgework, crowns and fillings pulled or broken
out. This happens 1 to 2 hours before the respective action.</p>

<p>Since April 13 1943, 516 <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>n <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> have been finished
off. On the basis of a definitive investigation, gold was taken
only in two actions, on 14 April 1943 from 172, and on 27 April
1943 from 164 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>. About 50% of the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> had gold teeth, bridgework
or fillings. <ent type='PERSON'>Hauptscharfuehrer Ruebe</ent> of the security police was always
personally present and he took the gold along too.</p>

<p>Letter from SS-<ent type='PERSON'>Gruppenfuehrer Katzmann</ent> to SS-<ent type='PERSON'>Obergruppenfuehrer</ent> Kruger,
regarding the "solution of the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> problem in Galicia", and giving
a breakdown of property taken from the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, June 30, 1943
[Documents on the <ent type='EVENT'>Holocaust</ent> - Edited by Y. Arad, Y. Gutman, A. <ent type='GPE'>Margaliot</ent>,
NY, Ktav Pub. House in Association with Yad-Vashem, 1981, p. 335-341]
-------------------------------------------------------------------
Valuables were secured and handed over to the special staff
"<ent type='PERSON'>Reinhard</ent>". Apart from furniture and large quantities of textile,
etc., the following were confiscated and delivered to special staff
"<ent type='PERSON'>Reinhard</ent>":</p>

<p>As of June 30, 1943:
.
.
20.952 Kg - wedding rings - gold
22.740 Kg - pearls
11.730 Kg - gold teeth
.
.</p>

<p>Report by SS-<ent type='PERSON'>Obergruppenfuehrer Pohl</ent> to Himmler's office, February
6 1943, listing items plundered from <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> victims and delivered
to various <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> organizations
[Trials of War Criminals Before the <ent type='GPE'>Nuernberg</ent> Military Tribunals -
<ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, U.S Govt. Print. Off., 1949-1953, Vol. V, p. 699-703]
-----------------------------------------------------------------
Report on the realization of textile-salvage from the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent>
resettlement up to the present date...</p>

<p>1. <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent> ministry of economics</p>

<p>Men's old clothing without underwear 97000 sets
Women's old clothing without underwear 76000 sets
women's silk underwear 89000 sets
Total 34 cars
<ent type='ORG'>Rags</ent> - 400 cars, 2700000 Kg
Bed feathers - 130 cars, 270000 Kg
Women's hair - 1 car, 3000 Kg
Scrap material - 5 cars, 19000 Kg</p>

<p>2. Office for <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>ization</p>

<p>Men's clothing:</p>

<p>Pants - 62000
Shirts - 132000
.
.
Shoes - 31000 pairs</p>

<p>Women's clothing:</p>

<p>Coats - 155000
Dresses - 119000
.
.
Panties - 60000
Brassiers - 25000
Underwear - 22000
Kerchiefs - 85000
Shoes - 111000
.
.
211 cars
[Many more organizations and items cited]</p>

<p> Grand Total 825 cars</p>

<p>Report by SS-<ent type='PERSON'>Grupenfuehrer Globocnik</ent> listing items plundered
from the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> victims of "Operation <ent type='PERSON'>Reinhard</ent>" and delivered to
various <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> organizations. Attached is a detailed list, prepared
by SS-<ent type='PERSON'>Sturmbannfuehrer Wippern</ent> on February 27, 1943.
[Trials of War Criminals Before the <ent type='GPE'>Nuernberg</ent> Military Tribunals -
<ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, U.S Govt. Print. Off., 1949-1953, Vol. V, p. 704-709]
-----------------------------------------------------------------
Valuation of <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> belongings delivered up to 3 February 1943</p>

<p>1. cash - RM 15931722.01
Delivery SS Econ. <ent type='GPE'>Krakow</ent> - RM 31500000.00
SS WVHA <ent type='GPE'>Berlin</ent> - RM 5581411.50
----------------
RM 53013133.51</p>

<p>[At that time, 2.5 RM were equal to 1 US Dollar].</p>

<p>2. Foreign currency, notes

[Long list] total RM 1452904.65
.
.
.

5. Other Valuables
.
.
2894 gold gentlemen's pocket watches
.
.
7313 gold ladies' wrist watches
.
.
13455 gentlemen's pocket watches
.
.
22324 spectacles
.
.
7000 fountain pens
.
.
51370 watches to be repaired
.
.
230 clinical thermometers</p>

<p>[many items deleted]</p>

<p> Total RM 26089800.00</p>

<p>6. Textiles</p>

<p>462 boxcars rags
253 boxcars feathers for bedding
317 boxcars clothes and linen</p>

<p> Total RM 13294400.00</p>

<p> Summary</p>

<p>1. Delivered cash and cash on hand RM 53013133.51
2. Foreign currency, notes RM 1452904.65
3. Foreign currency, minted gold RM 843802.75
4. Precious metals RM 5353943.00
5. Other items RM 26089800.00
6. Textiles RM 13294400.00</p>

<p>Total RM 100047983.91</p>

<p>[In April 8, 1945, an immense amount of SS loot was discovered hidden in
a salt mine in <ent type='ORG'>Merkers</ent>, <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y. Among other items, it contained
369.6. lbs of rings and 385 lbs of gold and silver teeth feeling. This
is reported in Trials of War Criminals Before the <ent type='GPE'>Nuernberg</ent> Military
Tribunals - <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, U.S Govt. Print. Off., 1949-1953, Vol. XIII,
p. 376].</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>AUSCHWITZ</ent>
*********</p>

<p>Report entitled "Resettlement of <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>" written by SS-Sturmbannfuehrer
Gricksch for SS-Col. von Herff and <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent>sfuehrer-SS <ent type='ORG'>Himmler</ent>, after
inspection of Auschwitz camp on 14-16 May 1943.
[<ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> and the Final Solution - G. <ent type='ORG'>Fleming</ent>, University of California
Press, 1984, p. 142-143]
------------------------------------------------------------------
The Auschwitz camp plays a special role in the resolution of the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent>
question. The most advance methods permit the execution of the
<ent type='PERSON'>Fuehrer</ent>-order in the shortest possible time and without arousing much
attention. The so-called "resettlement action" runs the following
course: The <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> arrive in special trains (freight cars) toward
evening and are driven on special tracks to areas of the camp
specifically set aside for this purpose. There the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> are unloaded
and examined for their fitness to work by a team of doctors, in the
presence of the camp commandant and several SS officers. At this point
anyone who can somehow be incorporated into the work program is put in
a special camp. <ent type='ORG'>The curably ill</ent> are sent straight to a medical camp
and are restored to health through a special diet. The basic principle
behind everything is: conserve all manpower for work. The previous
type of "resettlement action" has been thoroughly rejected, since it
is too costly to destroy precious work energy on a continual basis.</p>

<p>The unfit go to cellars in a large house which are entered from
outside. They go down five or six steps into a fairly long,
well-constructed and well-ventilated cellar area, which is lined with
benches to the left and right. It is brightly lit, and the benches are
numbered. The prisoners are told that they are to be cleansed and
disinfected for their new assignments. They must therefore completely
undress to be bathed. To avoid panic and to prevent disturbances of
any kind, they are instructed to arrange their clothing neatly under
their respective numbers, so that they will be able to find their
things again after their bath. Everything proceeds in a perfectly
orderly fashion. Then they pass through a small corridor and enter a
large cellar room which resembles a shower bath. In this room are
three large pillars, into which certain materials can be lowered from
outside the cellar room. When three-to four-hundred people have been
herded into this room, the doors are shut, and containers filled with
the substances are dropped down into the pillars. As soon as the
containers touch the base of the pillars, they release particular
substances that put the people to sleep in one minute. A few minutes
later, the door opens on the other side, where the elevator is
located. The hair of the corpses is cut off, and their teeth are
extracted (gold-filled teeth) by specialists (<ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>). It has been
discovered that <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> were hiding pieces of <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>elry, gold, platinum
etc., in hollow teeth. Then the corpses are loaded into elevators and
brought up to the first floor, where ten large crematoria are located.
(Because fresh corpses burn particularly well, only 50-100 lbs. of
coke are needed for the whole process.) The job itself is performed
by <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> prisoners, who never step outside this camp again.</p>

<p>The results of this "resettlement action" to date: 500000 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>.
Current capacity of the "resettlement action" ovens: 10000 in 24
hours.</p>

<p>Notes From Diary of SS-Doctor <ent type='PERSON'>Kremer</ent>, while in Auschwitz
['The Good Old Days' - E. Klee, W. Dressen, V. <ent type='PERSON'>Riess</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>The Free Press</ent>,
NY, 1988, p. 256-268]
----------------------------------------------------------------
2 September 1942</p>

<p>3.00 a.m. attended my first Sonderaktion. Dante's Inferno seems to
me almost a comedy compared to this. They don't call Auschwitz the
extermination camp for nothing!</p>

<p>[Sonderaktion = special action, meaning extermination; in this case,
gassing. See, for instance, two following document].</p>

<p>5 September 1942</p>

<p>In the morning attended a Sonderaktion from the women's concentration
camp (<ent type='NORP'>Muslims</ent>); the most dreadful of horrors. <ent type='GPE'>Hschf</ent>. Thilo -- army
doctor -- was right when he said to me this is the 'anus mundi'. In
the evening towards 8.00 attended another Sonderaktion from
<ent type='GPE'>Holland</ent>.</p>

<p>['<ent type='NORP'>Muslims</ent>' does not mean "practicing <ent type='ORG'>Islam</ent>"; this is the way the SS
referred to emaciated people].</p>

<p>10 October 1942</p>

<p>Extracted and fixed fresh live material from liver, spleen and
pancreas...</p>

<p>11 October 1942</p>

<p>Today, <ent type='LOC'>Sunday</ent>, there was roast hare for lunch -- a real fat leg -- with
dumplings and red cabbage for 1.25 RM.</p>

<p>12 October 1942</p>

<p>Second inoculation against typhus, later on in the evening severe
generalized reaction (fever). Despite this in the night attended a
further Sonderaktion from <ent type='GPE'>Holland</ent> (1600 persons). Ghastly scenes in
front of the last bunker! That was the 10th Sonderaktion.</p>

<p>13 November 1942</p>

<p>Extracted fresh live material (liver, spleen and pancreas) from a
previously photographed, severely atrophied <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> prisoner aged
eighteen. Fixed as always, liver and spleen in <ent type='LOC'>Carnoy</ent> and pancreas in
<ent type='PERSON'>Zenker</ent> (Prisoner No. 68030).</p>

<p>Letter from SS-Obersturmbannfuehrer Rodl to the inspector of
concentration camps, SS-Obersturmbannfuehrer <ent type='ORG'>Liebehenschel</ent>, 14
November 1941
[<ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> and the Final Solution - G. <ent type='ORG'>Fleming</ent>, University of California
Press, 1984, p. 99]
--------------------------------------------------------------------
The Commandant's office has submitted to date two lists recommending
the conferment of the Kreigverdienstkreuz [war service cross]. In
both of these appear SS personnel who participated in executions. We
herewith request confirmation as to whether these names should be
listed once again in the roll currently under preparation. Further
requested is information as to whether in the recommendation lists
under "reasons and comments of immediate superior" there should be
specified "execution, i.e., special action" or whether a general,
routine reason should be given.</p>

<p>Letter from <ent type='PERSON'>Bischoff</ent>, head of construction management at Auschwitz, to
the SS economic and administrative head office in <ent type='GPE'>Berlin</ent>, regarding
construction at Auschwitz, 13 October 1942
[Auschwitz: Technique and operation of the gas chambers - J.C Pressac,
the <ent type='ORG'>Beate Klarsfeld</ent> Foundation, NY, 1989, p. 198]
--------------------------------------------------------------------
As regards the construction of the new crematorium building, it was
necessary to start immediately in July 1942 because of the situation
caused by the special actions.</p>

<p>Letter from SS-Sturmbannfuehrer <ent type='PERSON'>Bischoff</ent>, of the Auschwitz construction
department, to SS General <ent type='PERSON'>Kammler</ent>, January 29, 1943
[The Final Solution: The Attempt to Exterminate the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> of Europe,
1939-1945 - G. Reitlinger, <ent type='GPE'>South Brunswick</ent>, T. Yosellof, 1968, p. 158-159]
--------------------------------------------------------------------
Crematorium No. 2. The completed furnaces have been started up in
the presence of Engineer Prufer from Messers. <ent type='ORG'>Topf</ent> (of <ent type='GPE'>Erfurt</ent>). The
planks cannot yet be moved from the ceiling of the mortuary cellar
on account of frost, but this is not important, as the gassing
cellar can be used for that purpose. The ventilation plant has
been held up by restrictions on rail transport, but the installation
should be ready by February 20th.</p>

<p>Letter from SS-Sturmbannfuehrer <ent type='PERSON'>Bischoff</ent>, March 6 1943
[Auschwitz: Technique and operation of the gas chambers - J.C Pressac,
the <ent type='ORG'>Beate Klarsfeld</ent> Foundation, NY, 1989, p. 434]
-----------------------------------------------------------------
... order of 6/3/1943 concerning the delivery of a gas tight door
100 x 192 cm for cellar I of <ent type='ORG'>Krematorium III</ent>, to be produced to
the identical pattern and dimensions as the cellar door of
Krematorium II which is situated opposite, with peephole of
double 8 mm glass, with rubber sealing strip and frame.</p>

<p>Letter from SS-<ent type='PERSON'>Sturmbannfuehrer Jahrling</ent> to SS-General <ent type='PERSON'>Kammler</ent>
estimating the number of corpses that can be disposed off in 24 hours
in the Auschwitz crematoriums, June 25 1943
[Auschwitz: Technique and operation of the gas chambers - J.C Pressac,
the <ent type='ORG'>Beate Klarsfeld</ent> Foundation, NY, 1989, p. 247]
-------------------------------------------------------------------
1.) Crematorium I
~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~
3 x 2 muffles 340 persons</p>

<p> 2.) Crematorium II
~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~
5 x 3 muffles 1440 persons</p>

<p> 3.) Crematorium III
~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~
5 x 3 muffles 1440 persons </p>

<p> 4.) Crematorium IV
~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~
8 muffles 768 persons</p>

<p> 5.) Crematorium V
~~~~~~~~~~~~~~~
8 muffles 768 persons</p>

<div> </div>

<p>A letter asking for a truck to bring Zyklon-B to Auschwitz; uses the
standard camouflage term "resettlement of <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>" to refer to
extermination. Another such document asks for "material for special
treatment" - another term used to disguise extermination.
[Auschwitz: Technique and operation of the gas chambers - J.C Pressac,
the <ent type='ORG'>Beate Klarsfeld</ent> Foundation, NY, 1989, p. 557]
---------------------------------------------------------------------
Radio message 13
SS Garrison Radio Station Auschwitz
Origin WVHA [SS economic administration head office]</p>

<p>Received 2nd October 1942 in <ent type='ORG'>the Kommandantur</ent> of Auschwitz
Concentration camp</p>

<p>The movement authorization for one 5 Ton truck with trailer to
<ent type='PERSON'>Dessau</ent> and back in order to pick up material for the resettlement
of the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, is hereby accorded.
The authorization is to be given to the driver.</p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>Liebehenschel</ent>
SS Lieutenant Colonel
Permanent representative of the head
of the service with the rank of <ent type='NORP'>Waffen</ent> SS
Lieutenant General</p>

<p>For file</p>

<p>Head of the radio station</p>

<p>Letter from SS-<ent type='PERSON'>Sturmbannfuehrer Jahrling</ent> to <ent type='ORG'>Topf</ent> &amp; Sons, March 6 1943
[Auschwitz: Technique and operation of the gas chambers - J.C Pressac,
the <ent type='ORG'>Beate Klarsfeld</ent> Foundation, NY, 1989, p. 221]
---------------------------------------------------------------------
[This document is interesting for two reasons: first, it demonstrates
that the underground cellars in the crematoriums could not have possibly
been morgues, as morgues are never heated; heating, however, does
facilitate the evaporation of Zyklon-B. Also, the document - like
many others - makes reference to an "undressing room", and there is
no reason for a morgue to have one near by. Pressac contains numerous
other documents attesting to the design and use of the Auschwitz gas
chambers. Even the fake shower heads are mentioned].</p>

<p>Subject: KL Auschwitz Krematorien II and III</p>

<p>In accordance with your suggestion, the service agrees that cellar 1
should be preheated with the air coming from the rooms of the 3
forced draught installations. The supply and installation of the
ductwork and blowers necessary to this end are to be effected as soon
as possible. As you point out in your above-mentioned letter,
execution should commence this week. We would ask you to send in
triplicate detailed quote for supply and installation.</p>

<p>At the same time, we would ask you to send an additional quotation
for the modification of the air-extraction installation in the
undressing room.</p>

<p><ent type='EVENT'>KRISTALLNACHT</ent>
*************</p>

<p>Message from SS-Grupenfuehrer <ent type='PERSON'>Heydrich</ent> to all State Police Main
Offices and Field Offices, November 10 1938 (before "<ent type='ORG'>Kristallnacht</ent>",
the "night of broken glass", the first large scale pogrom
against the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>)
[<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> Conspiracy and Aggression - <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, U.S Govt. Print.
Off., 1946, Vol. III, p. 545-547]
----------------------------------------------------------------
Regards: Measures against <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> tonight.
.
.
.

a) Only such measures may be taken which do not jeopardize
<ent type='NORP'>German</ent> life or property (for instance, burning of synagogues
only if there is no danger of fires for the neighbourhoods).</p>

<p>b) Business establishments and homes of <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> may be destroyed but
not looted. The police have been instructed to supervise the
execution of these directives and to arrest looters.</p>

<p>c) In Business streets special care is to be taken that non-<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent>
establishments will be safeguarded at all cost against damage.
.
.
.</p>

<p>As soon as the events of this night permit the use of the designated
officers, as many <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, particularly wealthy ones, as the local
jails will hold, are to be arrested in all districts. Initially
only healthy male <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, not too old, are to be arrested. After
the arrests have been carried out the appropriate concentration
camp is to be contacted immediately with a view to a quick
transfer of the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> to the camps...</p>

<p>VERDICT OF SS-COURT
*******************</p>

<p>Excerpts from Verdict of the SS Court in <ent type='GPE'>Munich</ent>, against
SS-Untersturmfuehrer <ent type='PERSON'>Max Taubner</ent>, 24 of May 1943
['The Good Old Days' - E. Klee, W. Dressen, V. <ent type='PERSON'>Riess</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>The Free Press</ent>,
NY, 1988, p, 196-207]
-----------------------------------------------------------------</p>

<p>1. The accused shall not be punished because of the actions against
the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> as such. The <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> have to be exterminated and none of the
<ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> that were killed is any great loss. Although the accused should
have recognized that the extermination of the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> was the duty of
<ent type='ORG'>Kommandos</ent> which were set up especially for this purpose, he should
be excused for considering himself to have the authority to take
part in the extermination of <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ry himself. Real hatred of the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>
was the driving motivation for the accused. In the process he let
himself be drawn into committing cruel actions in <ent type='ORG'>Alexandriya</ent> which
are unworthy of a <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> man and an SS-officer. These excesses cannot
be justified, either, as the accused would like to, as retaliation
for the pain that the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> have caused the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> people. It is not
the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> way to apply <ent type='PERSON'>Bolshevic</ent> methods during the necessary
extermination of the worst enemy of our people. In so doing the
conduct of the accused gives rise to considerable concern. The
accused allowed his men to act with such vicious brutality that
they conducted themselves under his command like a savage horde...</p>

<p>2. By taking photographs of the incidents or having photographs
taken, by having these developed in photographic shops and showing
them to his wife and friends, the accused is guilty of disobedience.
Such pictures could pose the gravest risks to the security of the
<ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent> if they fell into the wrong hands...</p>

<p>Dismissal of the case against the remaining parties, 1 June 1943</p>

<p>The following has been established on the basis of the main trial
of SS-Untersturmfuehrer <ent type='PERSON'>Max Taubner</ent>...
The following men were party to the punishable acts committed or
ordered by SS-Untersturmfuehrer <ent type='PERSON'>Max Taubner</ent>:</p>

<p>1. SS-Unterscharfuehrer Walter Muller particularly stood out during
the shootings of <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> with the brutality with which he tore small
<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> children from their mothers. He held these children in
front of him with his left hand and then, with his right hand,
shot them with a pistol.</p>

<p> .
. [three more SS-personnel accused]
.</p>

<p>Allowances have been made for the fact that the accused were, without
exception, acting on the orders of and under the responsibility
of Untersturmfuehrer <ent type='PERSON'>Max Taubner</ent>. In this respect, their own
culpability may be described as slight...</p>

<p>The cases against these accused have therefore been dismissed.</p>

<p>MISC
****</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>Memorandum</ent> from <ent type='ORG'>the Ministry</ent> of Justice to <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent>, regarding prosecution
of a <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ess for selling her mother milk to a <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> pediatrician
[Trials of War Criminals Before the <ent type='GPE'>Nuernberg</ent> Military Tribunals -
<ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, U.S Govt. Print. Off., 1949-1953, Vol. III, p. 701-702]
--------------------------------------------------------------------
After the birth of her child, a full-blooded <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ess sold her mother
milk to a pediatrician and concealed that she was a <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ess. With
this milk babies of <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> blood were fed in a nursing home for
children. The accused will be charged with deception. The buyers of
the milk have suffered damage, for mother's milk from a <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ess
cannot be regarded as food for <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> children. The impudent behavior
of the accused is an insult as well. Relevant charges, however, have
not been applied for, so that the parents, who are unaware of the
true facts, need not subsequently be worried.</p>

<p>I shall discuss with the <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent> health leader the racial hygienic
aspect of the case.</p>

<p> R. Rothenberger.</p>

<p>Death to the "Race Defiler":
Excerpts from Opinion and Sentence of the <ent type='GPE'>Nuernberg</ent> Special Court in
the <ent type='PERSON'>Katzenberger</ent> Case
[Trials of War Criminals Before the <ent type='GPE'>Nuernberg</ent> Military Tribunals -
<ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, U.S Govt. Print. Off., 1949-1953, Vol. III, 653-663]
--------------------------------------------------------------------
Findings:</p>

<p>1. The defendant <ent type='PERSON'>Katzenberger</ent> is fully <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> and a <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> national; he
is a member of the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> religious community...</p>

<p>2. Irene <ent type='PERSON'>Seiler</ent> is a <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> citizen of <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> blood...</p>

<p>[Testimonies about the relationship between <ent type='PERSON'>Katzenberger</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Seiler</ent> deleted]</p>

<p>The court is therefore convinced that <ent type='PERSON'>Katzenberger</ent>, after the <ent type='GPE'>Nuernberg</ent> laws
had come into effect, had repeated sexual intercourse with <ent type='PERSON'>Seiler</ent>, up to
March 1940...</p>

<p>The conduct to which the defendants admitted and which in the case of
<ent type='PERSON'>Katzenberger</ent> and consisted in drawing <ent type='PERSON'>Seiler</ent> close to him, kissing
her, patting and caressing her thighs over her clothes, makes it clear
that in a crude manner <ent type='PERSON'>Katzenberger</ent> did to <ent type='PERSON'>Seiler</ent> what is popularly
called "<ent type='PERSON'>Abschmieren</ent>" [petting]. It is obvious that such actions
are motivated only by sexual impulses. Even if the <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent> had only done
these so-called "<ent type='ORG'>Ersatzhandlungen</ent>" [sexual acts in lieu of actual
intercourse] to <ent type='PERSON'>Seiler</ent>, it would have been sufficient to charge him
with racial pollution in the full sense of the law...</p>

<p>He is therefore guilty of a continuous crime of racial pollution
according to sections 2 and 5, paragraph 11 of the Law for
Protection of <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> Blood and <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> Honor of 15 September 1935...</p>

<p>As the only feasible answer to the frivolous conduct of the defendant,
the court therefore deems it necessary to pronounce the death sentence
as the heaviest punishment provided by section 4 of the decree
against public enemies...</p>

<p>Various excerpts from anti-<ent type='NORP'>semitic</ent> publications
[All taken from <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> Conspiracy and Aggression - <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>,
U.S Govt. Print. Off., 1946, Vol. VIII]
--------------------------------------------------------------
p. 4:
[Speech by <ent type='PERSON'>Julius Streicher</ent>, September 5 1937, reported in the
Fraenkische Tageszeitung]</p>

<p>The <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent> no longer shows himself among us openly as he used to. But it would
be wrong to say that victory is ours. Full and final victory will have
been achieved only when the whole world has been rid of the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>.</p>

<p>p. 7:
[Leading article by <ent type='PERSON'>Streicher</ent> from "<ent type='PERSON'>Der Stuermer</ent>" No. 39, September 1936]</p>

<p>The continued work of the "<ent type='ORG'>Stuermer</ent>" will help to ensure that every <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>
down to the last man will, with heart and hand, join the ranks of those
whose aim is to crush the head of the serpent Pan-Juda beneath their
heels. He who helps to bring this about helps to eliminate the devil.
And this devil is the <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>.</p>

<p>p. 11:
[Streicher's speech in <ent type='GPE'>Nuernberg</ent>, April 3 1925, taken from "Kampf dem
Weltfeind", p. 42]</p>

<p>Let us make a new beginning today so that we can annihilate the <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>.</p>

<p>p. 12:
[Deutche <ent type='PERSON'>Volk</ent>sgesundheit aus Blut und Boden, New Year's issue 1935]</p>

<p>One single cohabitation of a <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent> with an <ent type='NORP'>Aryan</ent> woman is sufficient to
poison her blood forever. Together with the alien albumen she has
absorbed the alien soul. Never again will she be able to bear purely
<ent type='NORP'>Aryan</ent> children, even when married to an <ent type='NORP'>Aryan</ent>. They will all be
bastards, with a dual soul and the body of a mixed breed.</p>

<p>p. 19:
[Article signed by <ent type='PERSON'>Streicher</ent> in "<ent type='PERSON'>Der Stuermer</ent>", No, 12, March 19
1942, pages 1 and 2]</p>

<p>There were two ways which might have led to a liberation of Europe
from the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>: Expulsion or extermination! Both methods have been
tried in the course of the centuries, but they were never carried
to a conclusion...</p>

<p>The teaching of <ent type='NORP'>Christianity</ent> has stood in the way of a radical
solution of the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> problem in Europe...</p>

<p>Fate has decreed that it was finally left to the 20th century to see
the total solution of the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> problem. Just how this solution
will be achieved has been made known to the European nations and
to entire non-<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> humanity in a proclamation read out by the
<ent type='PERSON'>Fuehrer</ent> of the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> people on the 24th February 1942:</p>

<p>Today the ideas of our Nationalsocialists and those of the <ent type='NORP'>Fascist</ent>
revolution have conquered large and mighty nations and my
prophecy will find its fulfillment, that in this war not the
<ent type='NORP'>Aryan</ent> race will be destroyed, but the <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent> will be exterminated.
What ever else this struggle may lead to, or however long it
may endure, this will be the final result.</p>

<p>p. 29:</p>

<p> Report of Streicher's address to 2000 children at <ent type='GPE'>Nuernberg</ent>,
Christmas 1936, from Fraenkische Tegeszeitung, 22nd
December 1936</p>

<p>Two thousand children rejoiced with <ent type='PERSON'>Julius Streicher</ent>...</p>

<p>The <ent type='NORP'>Gauleiter</ent> [<ent type='PERSON'>Streicher</ent>] told the little ones about the terrible times
after the war, when the <ent type='PERSON'>Devil</ent> dominated mankind. "Do you know who the
<ent type='PERSON'>Devil</ent> is", he asked his breathlessly listening audience. "The <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>, the
<ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>", resounded from a thousand children's voices.</p>

<p>Letter from the Minister of State for the Protectorate of Bohemia
and <ent type='GPE'>Moravia</ent> to Rudolph <ent type='PERSON'>Brandt</ent>, June 13 1944, Concerning Children
of Executed <ent type='NORP'>Czechs</ent>
[Trials of War Criminals Before the <ent type='GPE'>Nuernberg</ent> Military Tribunals -
<ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, U.S Govt. Print. Off., 1949-1953, Vol. IV, p. 1030-1032]
-----------------------------------------------------------------
Dear comarade <ent type='PERSON'>Brandt</ent>,</p>

<p>Concerning the matter "children of executed <ent type='NORP'>Czechs</ent>" I wish to
reply to your letter as directed to SS-Lieutenant General <ent type='PERSON'>Frank</ent>,
date 6 February of this year, diary index No. 26/2/44 g Bra/H,
that the conversation between SS-Lieutenant General <ent type='PERSON'>Frank</ent> and
SS Colonel <ent type='PERSON'>Sollmann</ent> took place on 2 July of last year in <ent type='GPE'>Prague</ent>.
Colonel <ent type='PERSON'>Sollmann</ent> stated during this conversation that racially
valuable children up to six years would be considered eligible
by the "<ent type='PERSON'>Lebensborn</ent>"...</p>

<p>It was intended, to have children up to six years and suitable
for <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>ization brought into <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> families through the
"<ent type='PERSON'>Lebensborn</ent>"...</p>

<p>It is intended to have the racially acceptable elements of the
collectively housed children transferred through the "<ent type='PERSON'>Lebensborn</ent>"
to <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> families or to a children's home whereas the
children over 16 years are to be sent to a concentration camp.</p>

<p>Extract from Himmler's address to party comrades, September 7 1940
[Trials of War Criminals Before the <ent type='GPE'>Nuernberg</ent> Military Tribunals -
<ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, U.S Govt. Print. Off., Vol. IV, p. 1140]
------------------------------------------------------------------
If any <ent type='LOC'>Pole</ent> has any sexual dealing with a <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> woman, and by this
I mean sexual intercourse, then the man will be hanged right in
front of his camp. Then the others will not do it. Besides,
provisions will be made that a sufficient number of <ent type='NORP'>Polish</ent> women
and girls will come along as well so that a necessity of this
kind is out of the question.</p>

<p>The women will be brought before the courts without mercy, and
where the facts are not sufficiently proved - such borderline
cases always happen - they will be sent to a concentration camp.
This we must do, unless these one million <ent type='LOC'>Pole</ent>s and those
hundreds of thousands of workers of alien blood are to inflict
untold damage on the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> blood. Philosophizing is of no avail
in this case. It would be better if we did not have them at all -
we all know that - but we need them.</p>

<p>From the speech of <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent>sfuehrer-SS <ent type='ORG'>Himmler</ent>, speaking to SS
Major-Generals, <ent type='GPE'>Poznan</ent>, October 4 1943
[<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> Conspiracy and Aggression - <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, U.S Govt. Print.
Off., 1946, Vol. IV, p. 559]
-------------------------------------------------------------------
One basic principal must be the absolute rule for the SS man: we
must be honest, decent, loyal, and comradely to members of our own
blood and to nobody else. What happens to a <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>n, to a <ent type='NORP'>Czech</ent>,
does not interest me in the slightest. What the nations can offer
in good blood of our type, we will take, if necessary by kidnapping
their children and raising them with us. Whether nations live in
prosperity or starve to death interests me only in so far as we
need them as slaves for our culture; otherwise, it is of no interest
to me. Whether 10000 <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>n females fall down from exhaustion
while digging an anti-tank ditch interest me only in so far as
the anti-tank ditch for <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y is finished. We shall never be rough
and heartless when it is not necessary, that is clear. We <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>s,
who are the only people in the world who have a decent attitude
towards animals, will also assume a decent attitude towards these
human animals. But it is a crime against our own blood to worry
about them and give them ideals, thus causing our sons and
grandsons to have a more difficult time with them. When someone
comes to me and says, "I cannot dig the anti-tank ditch with women
and children, it is inhuman, for it will kill them", then I
would have to say, "you are a murderer of your own blood because
if the anti-tank ditch is not dug, <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> soldiers will die, and
they are the sons of <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> mothers. They are our own blood".</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Frank</ent>, Governor of <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> occupied <ent type='GPE'>Poland</ent>, in an interview, October 3
1939
[<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> Conspiracy and Aggression - <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, U.S Govt. Print.
Off., 1946, Vol. II, p. 632]
------------------------------------------------------------------
<ent type='GPE'>Poland</ent> can only be administered by utilizing the country through
means of ruthless exploitation, deportation of all supplies, raw
materials, machines, factory installations etc., which are
important for the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> war economy, availability of all workers
for work within <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y, reduction of the entire <ent type='NORP'>Polish</ent> economy
to absolute minimum necessary for bare existence of the population,
closing of all educational institutions, especially technical
schools and colleges in order to prevent the growth of a new
<ent type='NORP'>Polish</ent> intelligentsia. <ent type='GPE'>Poland</ent> shall be treated as a colony. the
<ent type='LOC'>Pole</ent>s shall be the slaves of the Greater <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> World Empire.</p>

<p>Letter from <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent>sfuehrer-SS <ent type='ORG'>Himmler</ent> to <ent type='ORG'>the Higher</ent> SS and Police
Chief in the <ent type='GPE'>Ukraine</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Kiev</ent>, September 7 1943
[<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> Conspiracy and Aggression - <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, U.S Govt. Print.
Off., 1946, Supp. A, p. 1270]
---------------------------------------------------------------------
Dear Pruetzmann,</p>

<p>Infantry general staff has special orders with regard to the <ent type='PERSON'>Donetz</ent>
area. Get in touch with him immediately. I order you to cooperate as
much as you can. The aim to be achieved is that when areas in the
<ent type='GPE'>Ukraine</ent> are evacuated, not a human being, not a single head of cattle,
not a hundredweight of cereals and not a railway line remain behind;
that not a house remain standing, not a mine is available which is
not destroyed for years to come, that there is not a well which is
not poisoned. The enemy must really find completely burned and destroyed
land. Discuss these things with <ent type='PERSON'>Stampf</ent> straight away and do your
absolute best.</p>

<p>Detailed report by SS-<ent type='PERSON'>Standartenfuehrer Jager</ent> about mass killings
in <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> occupied <ent type='GPE'>USSR</ent>, July-November 1941
['The Good Old Days' - E. Klee, W. Dressen, V. <ent type='PERSON'>Riess</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>The Free Press</ent>,
NY, 1988, p. 46-58].
------------------------------------------------------------------
[The "Jager report" was written by a commander of one of the
"<ent type='PERSON'>Einsatzgruppen</ent>" (special task forces) which were in charge of
liquidating <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, communist leaders, partisans and others in the
<ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> Union.</p>

<p>To understand the magnitude of the massacres, note the total number
of victims - 137346. This is for one <ent type='PERSON'>Einsatzgruppen</ent>, in a five month
period, in one area. This report reflects very clearly on the plan
to kill all the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, except those which were needed for working
purposes; those were, as the report notes, "only" to be sterilized;
Jager goes on to state that "if despite sterilization a <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ess becomes
pregnant she will be liquidated".</p>

<p>There are many documents about the <ent type='PERSON'>Einsatzgruppen</ent> massacres in the
<ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> Union, but the "Jager report" is one of the most chillingly
detailed of them].</p>

<p>The Commander of
the security police and
the SD
<ent type='ORG'>Einsatzkommando</ent> 3 Kauen [Kaunas], 1 December 1941</p>

<p>--------------------------
|Secret <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent> Business! | 5 copies
-------------------------- 4th copy</p>

<p> Complete list of executions carried out in the EK 3 area
up to 1 December 1941</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>Security</ent> police duties in <ent type='GPE'>Lithuania</ent> taken over by <ent type='ORG'>Einsatzkommando</ent> 3 on
2 July 1941.
(The <ent type='PERSON'>Wilna</ent> [Vilnius] area was taken over by EK 3 on 9 Aug. 1941, the
<ent type='ORG'>Schaulen</ent> area on 2 Oct. 1941. Up until these dates EK 9 operated in
<ent type='PERSON'>Wilna</ent> and EK 2 in <ent type='ORG'>Schaulen</ent>.)
On my instructions and orders the following executions were conducted by
<ent type='GPE'>Lithuania</ent>n partisans:</p>

<p>4.7.41 Kauen-Fort VII 416 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 47 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses 463
6.7.41 Kauen-Fort VII <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> 2514</p>

<p>Following the formation of a raiding squad under the command of
SS-Obersturmfuherer Hamman and 8-10 reliable men from the
<ent type='ORG'>Einsatzkommando</ent>. the following actions were conducted in cooperation
with <ent type='GPE'>Lithuania</ent>n partisans:</p>

<p>7.7.41 Mariampole <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> 32
8.7.41 Mariampole 14 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 5 Comm. officials 19
8.7.41 <ent type='PERSON'>Girkalinei Comm</ent>. officials 6
9.7.41 <ent type='PERSON'>Wendziogala</ent> 32 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 2 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses, 1 <ent type='GPE'>Lithuania</ent>n
(f.), 2 <ent type='GPE'>Lithuania</ent>n Comm., 1
<ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>n Comm. 38
9.7.41 Kauen-Fort VII 21 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 3 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses 24
14.7.41 Mariampole 21 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 1 <ent type='PERSON'>Russ</ent>., 9 Lith. Comm. 31
17.7.41 Babtei 8 Comm. officials (incl. 6 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>) 8
18.7.41 Mariampole 39 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 14 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses 53
19.7.41 Kauen-Fort VII 17 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 2 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses, 4 Lith.
Comm., 2 Comm. <ent type='GPE'>Lithuania</ent>ns (f.),
1 <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> Comm. 26
21.7.41 <ent type='GPE'>Panevezys</ent> 59 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 11 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses, 1
<ent type='GPE'>Lithuania</ent>n (f.), 1 <ent type='LOC'>Pole</ent>, 22 Lith.
Comm., 9 <ent type='PERSON'>Russ</ent>. Comm. 103
22.7.41 <ent type='GPE'>Panevezys</ent> 1 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent> 1
23.7.41 Kedainiai 83 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 12 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses, 14 <ent type='PERSON'>Russ</ent>.
Comm., 15 Lith. Comm., 1 <ent type='PERSON'>Russ</ent>.
O-Politruk 125
25.7.41 Mariampole 90 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 13 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses 103
28.7.41 <ent type='GPE'>Panevezys</ent> 234 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 15 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses, 19 <ent type='PERSON'>Russ</ent>.
Comm., 20 Lith. Comm. 288</p>

<p> Total carried forward 3384</p>

<p>Sheet 2
Total carried over 3384</p>

<p>29.7.41 <ent type='NORP'>Rasainiai</ent> 254 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 3 Lith. Comm. 257
30.7.41 <ent type='PERSON'>Agriogala</ent> 27 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 11 Lith. Comm. 38
31.7.41 <ent type='ORG'>Utena</ent> 235 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 16 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses, 4 Lith.
Comm., 1 robber/murderer 256
31.7.41 <ent type='PERSON'>Wendziogala</ent> 13 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 2 murderers 15
1.8.41 <ent type='GPE'>Ukmerge</ent> 254 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 42 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses, 1 Pol.
Comm., 2 Lith. NKVD agents, 1
mayor of <ent type='PERSON'>Jonava</ent> who gave order
to set fire to <ent type='PERSON'>Jonava</ent> 300
2.8.41 Kauen-Fort IV 170 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 1 US <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ess, 33 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses,
4 Lith. Comm. 209
4.8.41 <ent type='GPE'>Panevezys</ent> 362 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 41 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses, 5 <ent type='PERSON'>Russ</ent>. Comm.,
14 Lith. Comm. 422
5.8.41 <ent type='NORP'>Rasainiai</ent> 213 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 66 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses 279
7.8.41 <ent type='ORG'>Utena</ent> 483 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 87 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses, 1 <ent type='GPE'>Lithuania</ent>n
(robber of corpses of <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> soldiers)571
8.8.41 <ent type='GPE'>Ukmerge</ent> 620 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 82 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses 702
9.8.41 Kauen-Fort IV 484 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 50 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses 534
11.8.41 <ent type='GPE'>Panevezys</ent> 450 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 48 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses, 1 Lith. 1 <ent type='PERSON'>Russ</ent>.500
13.8.41 <ent type='ORG'>Alytus</ent> 617 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 100 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses, 1 criminal 719
14.8.41 <ent type='PERSON'>Jonava</ent> 497 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 55 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses 552
15-16.8.41 <ent type='GPE'>Rokiskis</ent> 3200 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses, and J. Children,
5 Lith. Comm., 1 <ent type='LOC'>Pole</ent>, 1 partisan 3207
9-16.8.41 <ent type='NORP'>Rasainiai</ent> 294 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses, 4 <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> children 298
27.6-14.8.41 <ent type='GPE'>Rokiskis</ent> 493 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 432 <ent type='NORP'>Russians</ent>, 56 <ent type='GPE'>Lithuania</ent>ns
(all active <ent type='NORP'>communists</ent>) 981
18.8.41 Kauen-Fort IV 689 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 402 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses, 1 <ent type='LOC'>Pole</ent> (f.),
711 <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> intellectuals from Ghetto
in reprisal for sabotage action 1812
19.8.41 <ent type='GPE'>Ukmerge</ent> 298 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 255 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses, 1 Politruk,
88 <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> children, 1 <ent type='PERSON'>Russ</ent>. Comm. 645
22.8.41 <ent type='GPE'>Dunanburg</ent> 3 <ent type='PERSON'>Russ</ent>. Comm., 5 <ent type='NORP'>Latvian</ent>, incl. 1
murderer, 1 <ent type='PERSON'>Russ</ent>. Guardsman, 3 <ent type='LOC'>Pole</ent>s,
3 gypsies (m.), 1 gypsy (f.), 1 gypsy
child, 1 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>, 1 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ess, 1 <ent type='NORP'>Armenian</ent>
(m.), 2 Politruks (prison inspection
in <ent type='GPE'>Dunanburg</ent> 21</p>

<p> Total carried forward 16152</p>

<p>Sheet 3
Total carried forward 16152</p>

<p>22.8.41 <ent type='PERSON'>Aglona</ent> Mentally sick: 269 men, 227 women,
48 children 544
23.8.41 <ent type='GPE'>Panevezys</ent> 1312 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 4602 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses, 1609
<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> children 7523
18-22.8.41 Kreis <ent type='NORP'>Rasainiai</ent> 466 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 440 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses, 1020
<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> children 1926
25.8.41 <ent type='PERSON'>Obeliai</ent> 112 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 627 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses, 421
<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> children 1160
25-26.8.41 Seduva 230 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 275 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses, 159
<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> children 664
26.8.41 <ent type='PERSON'>Zarasai</ent> 767 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 1113 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses, 1 Lith.
Comm., 687 <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> children, 1 <ent type='PERSON'>Russ</ent>.
Comm. (f.) 2569
28.8.41 <ent type='PERSON'>Pasvalys</ent> 402 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 738 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses, 209
<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> children 1349
26.8.41 <ent type='PERSON'>Kaisiadorys</ent> All <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses, and <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent>
children 1911
27.8.41 Prienai All <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses, and <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent>
Children 1078
27.8.41 Dagda and 212 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 4 <ent type='PERSON'>Russ</ent>. POW's 216
<ent type='GPE'>Kraslawa</ent>
27.8.41 <ent type='GPE'>Joniskia</ent> 47 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 165 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses, 143
<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> children 355
28.8.41 <ent type='NORP'>Wilkia</ent> 76 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 192 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses, 134
<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> children 402
28.8.41 Kedainiai 710 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 767 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses, 599
<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> children 2076
29.8.41 <ent type='ORG'>Rumsiskis</ent> and 20 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 567 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses, 197
Ziezmariai <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> children 784
29.8.41 <ent type='ORG'>Utena</ent> and 582 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 1731 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses, 1469
<ent type='PERSON'>Moletai</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> children 3782
13-31.8.41 <ent type='ORG'>Alytus</ent> and
environs 233 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> 233</p>

<p>1.9.41 Mariampole 1763 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 1812 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses, 1404
<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> children, 109 mentally sick,
1 <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> subject (f.), married to a
<ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>, 1 <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>n (f.) 5090</p>

<p> Total carried over 47814</p>

<p>Sheet 4
Total carried over 47814</p>

<p>28.8-2.9.41 Darsuniskis 10 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 69 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses, 20
<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> children 99
<ent type='GPE'>Carliava</ent> 73 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 113 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses, 61
<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> children 247
<ent type='PERSON'>Jonava</ent> 112 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 1200 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses, 244
<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> children 1556
<ent type='ORG'>Petrasiunai</ent> 30 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 72 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses, 23
<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> children 125
<ent type='GPE'>Jesuas</ent> 26 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 72 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses, 46
<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> children 144
<ent type='PERSON'>Agriogala</ent> 207 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 260 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses, 195
<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> children 662
Jasvainai 86 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 110 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses, 86
<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> children 282
Babtei 20 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 41 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses, 22
<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> children 83
<ent type='PERSON'>Wendziogala</ent> 42 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 113 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses, 97
<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> children 252
<ent type='PERSON'>Krakes</ent> 448 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 476 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses, 97
<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> children 1125
4.9.41 <ent type='NORP'>Pravenischkis</ent> 247 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 6 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses 253
<ent type='ORG'>Cekiske</ent> 22 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 64 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses, 60
<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> children 146
<ent type='GPE'>Seredsius</ent> 6 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 61 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses, 126
<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> children 193
<ent type='PERSON'>Velinona</ent> 2 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 71 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses, 86
<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> children 159
Zapiskis 47 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 118 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses, 13
<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> children 178
5.9.41 <ent type='GPE'>Ukmerge</ent> 1123 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 1849 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses, 1737
<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> children 4709
25.8-6.9.41 Mopping up in: 16 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 412 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses, 415
<ent type='NORP'>Rasainiai</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> children 843
<ent type='GPE'>Georgenburg</ent> all <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, all <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses, all
<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> children 412
9.9.41 <ent type='ORG'>Alytus</ent> 287 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 640 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses, 352
<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> children 1279
9.9.41 <ent type='PERSON'>Butrimonys</ent> 67 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 370 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses, 303
<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> children 740
10.9.41 <ent type='PERSON'>Merkine</ent> 223 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 640 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses, 276
<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> children 854
10.9.41 <ent type='PERSON'>Varena</ent> 541 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 141 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses, 149
<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> children 831
11.9.41 <ent type='NORP'>Leipalingis</ent> 60 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 70 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses, 25
<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> children 155
11.9.41 <ent type='PERSON'>Seirijai</ent> 229 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 384 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses, 340
<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> children 953
12.9.41 <ent type='PERSON'>Simnas</ent> 68 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 197 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses, 149
<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> children 414
11-12.9.41 <ent type='PERSON'>Uzusalis Reprisal</ent> against inhabitants who
fed <ent type='PERSON'>Russ</ent>. partisans; some in
possession of weapons 43
26.9.41 Kauen-F.IV 412 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 615 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses, 581
<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> children (sick and
suspected epidemic cases) 1608</p>

<p> Total carries over 66159</p>

<p>Sheet 5
Total carried over 66159</p>

<p>2.10.41 <ent type='ORG'>Zagare</ent> 633 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 1107 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses, 496
<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> children (as these <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> were
being led away a mutiny rose, which
was however immediately put down;
150 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> were shot immediately; 7
partisans wounded) 2236
4.10.41 Kauen-F.IX 315 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 712 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses, 818
<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> children (reprisal after
<ent type='NORP'>German</ent> police officer shot in ghetto) 1845
29.10.41 Kauen-F.IX 2007 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 2920 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses, 4273
<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> children (mopping up ghetto
of superfluous <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>) 9200
3.11.41 Lazdijai 485 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 511 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses, 539
<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> children 1535
15.11.41 <ent type='PERSON'>Wilkowiski</ent> 36 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 48 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses, 31
<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> children 115
25.11.41 Kauen-F.IX 1159 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 1600 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses, 175
<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> children (resettlers from
<ent type='GPE'>Berlin</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Munich</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Frank</ent>furt am main) 2934
29.11.41 Kauen-F.IX 693 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 1155 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses, 152
<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> children (resettlers from
from <ent type='GPE'>Vienna</ent> and Breslau) 2000
29.11.41 Kauen-F.IX 17 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 1 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ess, for contravention
of ghetto law, 1 <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent>s <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> who
converted to the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> faith and
attended rabbinical school, then 15
terrorists from the <ent type='PERSON'>Kalinin</ent> group 34</p>

<p>EK 3 detachment in <ent type='GPE'>Dunanburg</ent>
in the period 13.7-21.8.41: 9012 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses and <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent>
children, 573 active Comm. 9585</p>

<p>EK 3 detachment in <ent type='PERSON'>Wilna</ent>:
12.8-1.9.41 City of <ent type='PERSON'>Wilna</ent> 425 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 19 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses, 8 Comm. (m.),
9 Comm. (f.) 461
2.9.41 City of <ent type='PERSON'>Wilna</ent> 864 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 2019 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses, 817
<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> children (sonderaktion because
<ent type='NORP'>German</ent> soldiers shot at by <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>) 3700</p>

<p> Total carried forward 99084</p>

<p>sheet 6</p>

<p> Total carried forward 99804</p>

<p>12.9.41 City of <ent type='PERSON'>Wilna</ent> 993 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 1670 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses, 771
<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> children 3334
17.9.41 City of <ent type='PERSON'>Wilna</ent> 337 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 687 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses, 247
<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> children and 4 Lith. Comm. 1271
20.9.41 Nemencing 128 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 176 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses, 99
<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> children 403
22.9.41 Novo-Wilejka 468 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 495 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses, 196
<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> children 1159
24.9.41 <ent type='PERSON'>Riess</ent> 512 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 744 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses, 511
<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> children 1767
25.9.41 <ent type='ORG'>Jahiunai</ent> 215 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 229 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses, 131
<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> children 575
27.9.41 <ent type='PERSON'>Eysisky</ent> 989 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 1636 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses, 821
<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> children 3446
30.9.41 <ent type='PERSON'>Trakai</ent> 366 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 483 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses, 597
<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> children 1446
4.10.41 City of <ent type='PERSON'>Wilna</ent> 432 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 1115 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses, 436
<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> children 1983
6.10.41 <ent type='NORP'>Semiliski</ent> 213 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 359 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses, 390
<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> children 962
9.10.41 Svenciany 1169 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 1840 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses, 717
<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> children 3726
16.10.41 City of <ent type='PERSON'>Wilna</ent> 382 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 507 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses, 257
<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> children 1146
21.10.41 City of <ent type='PERSON'>Wilna</ent> 718 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 1063 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses, 586
<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> children 2367
25.10.41 City of <ent type='PERSON'>Wilna</ent> 1776 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses, 812 <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> children 2578
27.10.41 City of <ent type='PERSON'>Wilna</ent> 946 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 184 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses, 73
<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> children 1203
30.10.41 City of <ent type='PERSON'>Wilna</ent> 382 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 789 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses, 362
<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> children 1553
6.11.41 City of <ent type='PERSON'>Wilna</ent> 340 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 749 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses, 252
<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> children 1341
19.11.41 City of <ent type='PERSON'>Wilna</ent> 76 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 77 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses, 18
<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> children 171
19.11.41 City of <ent type='PERSON'>Wilna</ent> 6 POW's, 8 <ent type='LOC'>Pole</ent>s 14
20.11.41 City of <ent type='PERSON'>Wilna</ent> 3 POW's 3
25.11.41 City of <ent type='PERSON'>Wilna</ent> 9 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 46 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses, 8 <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent>
children, 1 <ent type='LOC'>Pole</ent> for possession of arms
and other military equipment 64</p>

<p>EK 3 detachment in <ent type='GPE'>Minsk</ent> from
28.9-17.10.41:</p>

<p> <ent type='PERSON'>Pleschnitza</ent> 620 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 1285 <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses,
<ent type='GPE'>Bischolin</ent> 1126 <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> children and 19
<ent type='ORG'>Scak Comm</ent>.
Bober
Uzda 3050
--------
133346
Prior to EK 3 taking over security police duties, <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> liquidated
by pogroms and executions (including partisans) 4000
-----------
Total 137346</p>

<p>Today I can confirm that our objective, to solve the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> problem for
<ent type='GPE'>Lithuania</ent>, has been achieved by EK 3. In <ent type='GPE'>Lithuania</ent> there are no more
<ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, apart from <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> workers and their families.</p>

<div> .
.
.</div>

<p>The distance between from the assembly point to the graves was on average
4 to 5 Km.</p>

<div> .
.
.</div>

<p>I consider the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> action more or less terminated as far as
<ent type='ORG'>Einsatzkommando</ent> 3 is concerned. Those working <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> and <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>esses still
available are needed urgently and I can envisage that after the winter
this workforce will be required even more urgently. I am of the view
that the sterilization program of the male worker <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> should be
started immediately so that reproduction is prevented. If despite
sterilization a <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ess becomes pregnant she will be liquidated.</p>

<div> .
.
.</div>

<p>(signed) Jager
SS-Standartenfuehrer</p>

<p> @@@@@@@@
@@@ @@@
@@@ ANOTHER @@@
@@@ FILE BROUGHT TO @@@
@@@ YOU BY @@@
@@@ THE <ent type='ORG'>QUARTO</ent> MUNDISTA BBS @@@
@@@ THE FOURTH WORLD BBS SYSTEM @@@
@@@ FIDONET 1:352/333 206-786-9629 14.4 v32b @@@
@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@@</p>

</xml>