<xml><p>Newsgroups: alt.politics.org.nsa,talk.politics.crypto
From: grady@netcom.com (<ent type='PERSON'>Grady Ward</ent>)
Subject: <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent> employee's security manual
<ent type='ORG'>Organization</ent>: Moby lexical databases

<ent type='ORG'>Security Guidelines</ent>

This handbook is designed to introduce you to some of the basic
security principles and procedures with which all <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent> employees must
comply. It highlights some of your security responsibilities, and
provides guidelines for answering questions you may be asked
concerning your association with this <ent type='ORG'>Agency</ent>. Although you will be
busy during the forthcoming weeks learning your job, meeting
co-workers, and becoming accustomed to a new work environment, you
are urged to become familiar with the security information contained
in this handbook. Please note that a listing of telephone numbers is
provided at the end of this handbook should you have any questions or
concerns.

Introduction

In joining <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent> you have been given an opportunity to participate in
the activities of one of the most important intelligence
organizations of <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States Government. At the same time, you
have also assumed a trust which carries with it a most important
individual responsibility--the safeguarding of sensitive information
vital to the security of our nation.

While it is impossible to estimate in actual dollars and cents the
value of the work being conducted by this <ent type='ORG'>Agency</ent>, the information to
which you will have access at <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent> is without question critically
important to the defense of <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States. Since this
information may be useful only if it is kept secret, it requires a
very special measure of protection. The specific nature of this
protection is set forth in various <ent type='ORG'>Agency</ent> security regulations and
directives. The total <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Security</ent> Program, however, extends beyond
these regulations. It is based upon the concept that security begins
as a state of mind. The program is designed to develop an
appreciation of the need to protect information vital to the national
defense, and to foster the development of a level of awareness which
will make security more than routine compliance with regulations.

At times, security practices and procedures cause personal
inconvenience. They take time and effort and on occasion may make it
necessary for you to voluntarily forego some of your usual personal
perogatives. But your compensation for the inconvenience is the
knowledge that the work you are accomplishing at <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent>, within a
framework of sound security practices, contributes significantly to
the defense and continued security of <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States of America.

I extend to you my very best wishes as you enter upon your chosen
career or assignment with <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent>.

Philip T. Pease
Director of <ent type='ORG'>Security</ent>


INITIAL SECURITY RESPONSIBILITIES

Anonymity

Perhaps one of the first security practices with which new <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent>
personnel should become acquainted is the practice of anonymity. In
an open society such as ours, this practice is necessary because
information which is generally available to the public is available
also to hostile intelligence. Therefore, the <ent type='ORG'>Agency</ent> mission is best
accomplished apart from public attention. Basically, anonymity means
that <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent> personnel are encouraged not to draw attention to themselves
nor to their association with this <ent type='ORG'>Agency</ent>. <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent> personnel are also
cautioned neither to confirm nor deny any specific questions about
<ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent> activities directed to them by individuals not affiliated with
the <ent type='ORG'>Agency</ent>.

The ramifications of the practice of anonymity are rather far
reaching, and its success depends on the cooperation of all <ent type='ORG'>Agency</ent>
personnel. Described below you will find some examples of situations
that you may encounter concerning your employment and how you should
cope with them. Beyond the situations cited, your judgement and
discretion will become the deciding factors in how you respond to
questions about your employment.

Answering Questions About Your Employment

Certainly, you may tell your family and friends that you are employed
at or assigned to the National <ent type='ORG'>Security</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Agency</ent>. There is no valid reason
to deny them this information. However, you may not disclose to them
any information concerning specific aspects of the Agency's mission,
activities, and organization. You should also ask them not to
publicize your association with <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent>.

Should strangers or casual acquaintances question you about your
place of employment, an appropriate reply would be that you work for
<ent type='ORG'>the Department</ent> of Defense. If questioned further as to where you are
employed within <ent type='ORG'>the Department</ent> of Defense, you may reply, "<ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent>."
When you inform someone that you work for <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent> (or <ent type='ORG'>the Department</ent> of
Defense) you may expect that the next question will be, "What do you
do?" It is a good idea to anticipate this question and to formulate
an appropriate answer. Do not act mysteriously about your
employment, as that would only succeed in drawing more attention to
yourself.

If you are employed as a secretary, engineer, computer scientist, or
in a clerical, administrative, technical, or other capacity
identifiable by a general title which in no way indicates how your
talents are being applied to the mission of the <ent type='ORG'>Agency</ent>, it is
suggested that you state this general title. If you are employed as
a linguist, you may say that you are a linguist, if necessary.
However, you should not indicate the specific language(s) with which
you are involved.

The use of service specialty titles which tend to suggest or reveal
the nature of the Agency's mission or specific aspects of their
work. These professional titles, such as cryptanalyst, signals
collection officer, and intelligence research analyst, if given
verbatim to an outsider, would likely generate further questions
which may touch upon the classified aspects of your work. Therefore,
in conversation with outsiders, it is suggested that such job titles
be generalized. For example, you might indicate that you are a
"research analyst." You may not, however, discuss the specific
nature of your analytic work.

Answering Questions About Your <ent type='ORG'>Agency</ent> Training

During your career or assignment at <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent>, there is a good chance that
you will receive some type of job-related training. In many
instances the nature of the training is not classified. However, in
some situations the specialized training you receive will relate
directly to sensitive <ent type='ORG'>Agency</ent> functions. In such cases, the nature of
this training may not be discussed with persons outside of this
<ent type='ORG'>Agency</ent>.

If your training at the <ent type='ORG'>Agency</ent> includes language training, your
explanation for the source of your linguistic knowledge should be
that you obtained it while working for <ent type='ORG'>the Department</ent> of Defense.

You Should not draw undue attention to your language abilities, and
you may not discuss how you apply your language skill at the <ent type='ORG'>Agency</ent>.

If you are considering part-time employment which requires the use of
language or technical skills similar to those required for the
performance of your <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent> assigned duties, you must report (in advance)
the anticipated part-time work through your Staff <ent type='ORG'>Security</ent> Officer
(<ent type='ORG'>SSO</ent>) to <ent type='ORG'>the Office</ent> of Security's Clearance Division (M55).

Verifying Your Employment

On occasion, personnel must provide information concerning their
employment to credit institutions in connection with various types of
applications for credit. In such situations you may state, if you are
a civilian employee, that you are employed by <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent> and indicate your
pay grade or salary. Once again, generalize your job title. If any
further information is desired by persons or firms with whom you may
be dealing, instruct them to request such information by
correspondence addressed to: Director of <ent type='ORG'>Civilian Personnel</ent>,
National <ent type='ORG'>Security</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Agency</ent>, Fort George G. <ent type='GPE'>Meade</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Maryland</ent> 20755-6000.
Military personnel should use their support group designator and
address when indicating their current assignment.

If you contemplate leaving <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent> for employment elsewhere, you may be
required to submit a resume/job application, or to participate in
extensive employment interviews. In such circumstances, you should
have your resume reviewed by the
<ent type='ORG'>Classification Advisory</ent> Officer (<ent type='ORG'>CAO</ent>) assigned to your organization.
Your <ent type='ORG'>CAO</ent> will ensure that any classified operational details of your
duties have been excluded and will provide you with an unclassified
job description. Should you leave the <ent type='ORG'>Agency</ent> before preparing such a
resume, you may develop one and send it by registered mail to the
<ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent>/CSS Information Policy Division (Q43) for review. Remember, your
obligation to protect sensitive <ent type='ORG'>Agency</ent> information extends beyond
your employment at <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent>.

The <ent type='ORG'>Agency</ent> And Public News Media

From time to time you may find that the agency is the topic of
reports or articles appearing in public news media--newspapers,
magazines, books, radio and TV. The <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent>/CSS Information Policy
Division (Q43) represents the <ent type='ORG'>Agency</ent> in matters involving the press
and other media. This office serves at the Agency's official media
center and is the Director's liaison office for public relations,
both in the community and with other government agencies. The
Information Policy Division must approve the release of all
information for and about <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent>, its mission, activities, and
personnel. In order to protect the aspects of <ent type='ORG'>Agency</ent> operations, <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent>
personnel must refrain from either confirming or denying any
information concerning the <ent type='ORG'>Agency</ent> or its activities which may appear
in the public media. If you are asked about the activities of <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent>,
the best response is "no comment." You should the notify Q43 of the
attempted inquiry. For the most part, public references to <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent> are
based upon educated guesses. The <ent type='ORG'>Agency</ent> does not normally make a
practice of issuing public statements about its activities.

GENERAL RESPONSIBILITIES

Espionage And Terrorism

During your security indoctrination and throughout your <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent> career
you will become increasingly aware of the espionage and terrorist
threat to <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States. Your vigilance is the best single
defense in protecting <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent> information, operations, facilities and
people. Any information that comes to your attention that suggests
to you the existence of, or potential for, espionage or terrorism
against the U.S. or its allies must be promptly reported by you to
<ent type='ORG'>the Office</ent> of <ent type='ORG'>Security</ent>.

There should be no doubt in your mind about the reality of the
threats. You are now affiliated with the most sensitive agency in
government and are expected to exercise vigilance and common sense to
protect <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent> against these threats.

Classification

Originators of correspondence, communications, equipment, or
documents within the <ent type='ORG'>Agency</ent> are responsible for ensuring that the
proper classification, downgrading information and, when appropriate,
proper caveat notations are assigned to such material. (This
includes any handwritten notes which contain classified information).
The three levels of classification are Confidential, Secret and Top
Secret. The <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent> Classification Manual should be used as guidance in
determining proper classification. If after review of this document
you need assistance, contact the <ent type='ORG'>Classification Advisory</ent> Officer
(<ent type='ORG'>CAO</ent>) assigned to your organization, or the Information Policy
Division (Q43).

Need-To-Know

Classified information is disseminated only on a strict
"need-to-know" basis. The "need-to-know" policy means that classified
information will be disseminated only to those individuals who, in
addition to possessing a proper clearance, have a requirement to know
this information in order to perform their official duties
(need-to-know). No person is entitled to classified information
solely by virtue of office, position, rank, or security clearance.

All <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent> personnel have the responsibility to assert the
"need-to-know" policy as part of their responsibility to protect
sensitive information. Determination of "need-to-know" is a
supervisory responsibility. This means that if there is any doubt in
your mind as to an individual's "need-to-know," you should always
check with your supervisor before releasing any classified material
under your control.

For Official Use Only

Separate from classified information is information or material
marked "FOR
OFFICIAL USE ONLY" (such as this handbook). This designation is used
to identify that official information or material which, although
unclassified, is exempt from the requirement for public disclosure of
information concerning government activities and which, for a
significant reason, should not be given general circulation. Each
holder of "FOR OFFICAL USE ONLY" (FOUO) information or material is
authorized to disclose such information or material to persons in
other departments or agencies of the <ent type='ORG'>Executive</ent> and Judicial branches
when it is determined that the information or material is required to
carry our a government function. The recipient must be advised that
the information or material is not to be disclosed to the general
public. Material which bears the "FOR OFFICIAL USE ONLY" caveat does
not come under the regulations governing the protection of classified
information. The unauthorized disclosure of information marked "FOR
OFFICIAL USE ONLY" does not constitute an unauthorized disclosure of
classified defense information. However, Department of Defense and
<ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent> regulations prohibit the unauthorized disclosure of information
designated "FOR OFFICIAL USE ONLY." <ent type='ORG'>Appropriate</ent> administrative
action will be taken to determine responsibility and to apply
corrective and/or disciplinary measures in cases of unauthorized
disclosure of information which bears the "FOR OFFICIAL USE ONLY"
caveat. Reasonable care must be exercised in limiting the
dissemination of "FOR OFFICIAL USE ONLY" information. While you may
take this handbook home for further study, remember that is does
contain "FOR OFFICIAL USE ONLY" information which should be
protected.

Prepublication Review

All <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent> personnel (employees, military assignees, and contractors)
must submit for review any planned articles, books, speeches,
resumes, or public statements that may contain classified,
classifiable, <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent>-derived, or unclassified protected information,
e.g., information relating to the organization, mission, functions,
or activities of <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent>. Your obligation to protect this sensitive
information is a lifetime one. Even when you resign, retire, or
otherwise end your affiliation with <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent>, you must submit this type of
material for prepublication review. For additional details, contact
<ent type='ORG'>the Information Policy Division</ent> (Q43) for an explanation of
prepublication review procedures.

Personnel <ent type='ORG'>Security</ent> Responsibilities

Perhaps you an recall your initial impression upon entering an <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent>
facility. Like most people, you probably noticed the elaborate
physical security safeguards--fences, concrete barriers, <ent type='ORG'>Security</ent>
Protective Officers, identification badges, etc. While these
measures provide a substantial degree of protection for the
information housed within our buildings, they represent only a
portion of the overall <ent type='ORG'>Agency</ent> security program. In fact, vast
amounts of information leave our facilities daily in the minds of <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent>
personnel, and this is where our greatest vulnerability lies.
Experience has indicated that because of the vital information we
work with at <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Agency</ent> personnel may become potential targets for
hostile intelligence efforts. Special safeguards are therefore
necessary to protect our personnel.

Accordingly, the <ent type='ORG'>Agency</ent> has an extensive personnel security program
which establishes internal policies and guidelines governing employee
conduct and activities. These policies cover a variety of topics,
all of which are designed to protect both you and the sensitive
information you will gain through your work at <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent>.

Association With Foreign Nationals

As a member of the U.S. Intelligence Community and by virtue of your
access to sensitive information, you are a potential target for
hostile intelligence activities carried out by or on behalf of
citizens of foreign countries. A policy concerning association with
foreign nationals has been established by the <ent type='ORG'>Agency</ent> to minimize the
likelihood that its personnel might become subject to undue influence
or duress or targets of hostile activities through foreign
relationships.

As an <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent> affiliate, you are prohibited from initiating or
maintaining associations (regardless of the nature and degree) with
citizens or officials of <ent type='NORP'>communist</ent>-controlled, or other countries
which pose a significant threat to the security of <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States
and its interests. A comprehensive list of these designated
countries is available from your Staff <ent type='ORG'>Security</ent> Officer or the
<ent type='ORG'>Security Awareness Division</ent>. Any contact with citizens of these
countries, no matter how brief or seemingly innocuous, must be
reported as soon as possible to your Staff <ent type='ORG'>Security</ent> Officer (<ent type='ORG'>SSO</ent>).
(Individuals designated as <ent type='ORG'>Staff Security Officers</ent> are assigned to
every organization; a listing of <ent type='ORG'>Staff Security Officers</ent> can be found
at the back of this handbook).

Additionally, close and continuing associations with any non-U.S.
citizens which are characterized by ties of kinship, obligation, or
affection are prohibited. A waiver to this policy may be granted only
under the most exceptional circumstances when there is a truly
compelling need for an individual's services or skills and the
security risk is negligible.

In particular, a waiver must be granted in advance of a marriage to
or cohabitation with a foreign national in order to retain one's
access to <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent> information. Accordingly, any intent to cohabitate
with or marry a non-U.S. citizen must be reported immediately to your
Staff <ent type='ORG'>Security</ent> Officer. If a waiver is granted, future reassignments
both at headquarters and overseas may be affected.

The marriage or intended marriage of an immediate family member
(parents, siblings, children) to a foreign national must also be
reported through your <ent type='ORG'>SSO</ent> to the Clearance Division (M55).

Casual social associations with foreign nationals (other than those
of the designated countries mentioned above) which arise from normal
living and working arrangements in the community usually do not have
to be reported. During the course of these casual social
associations, you are encouraged to extend the usual social
amenities. Do not act mysteriously or draw attention to yourself
(and possibly to <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent>) by displaying an unusually wary attitude.

Naturally, your affiliation with the <ent type='ORG'>Agency</ent> and the nature of your
work should not be discussed. Again, you should be careful not to
allow these associations to become close and continuing to the extent
that they are characterized by ties of kinship, obligation, or
affection.

If at any time you feel that a "casual" association is in any way
suspicious, you should report this to your Staff <ent type='ORG'>Security</ent> Officer
immediately. Whenever any doubt exists as to whether or not a
situation should be reported or made a matter of record, you should
decided in favor of reporting it. In this way, the situation can be
evaluated on its own merits, and you can be advised as to your future
course of action.

Correspondence With Foreign Nationals

<ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent> personnel are discouraged from initiating correspondence with
individuals who are citizens of foreign countries. Correspondence
with citizens of <ent type='NORP'>communist</ent>-controlled or other designated countries
is prohibited. Casual social correspondence, including the "penpal"
variety, with other foreign acquaintances is acceptable and need not
be reported. If, however, this correspondence should escalate in its
frequency or nature, you should report that through your Staff
<ent type='ORG'>Security</ent> Officer to the Clearance Division (M55).

<ent type='ORG'>Embassy</ent> Visits

Since a significant percentage of all espionage activity is known to
be conducted through foreign embassies, consulates, etc., <ent type='ORG'>Agency</ent>
policy discourages visits to embassies, consulates or other official
establishments of a foreign government. Each case, however, must be
judged on the circumstances involved. Therefore, if you plan to
visit a foreign embassy for any reason (even to obtain a visa), you
must consult with, and obtain the prior approval of, your immediate
supervisor and <ent type='ORG'>the Security Awareness Division</ent> (M56).

Amateur Radio Activities

Amateur radio (ham radio) activities are known to be exploited by
hostile intelligence services to identify individuals with access to
classified
information; therefore, all licensed operators are expected to be
familiar with <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent>/CSS Regulation 100-1, "Operation of Amateur Radio
Stations" (23 October 1986). The specific limitations on contacts
with operators from <ent type='NORP'>communist</ent> and designated countries are of
particular importance. If you are an amateur radio operator you
should advise <ent type='ORG'>the Security Awareness Division</ent> (M56) of your amateur
radio activities so that detailed guidance may be furnished to you.

Unofficial Foreign Travel

In order to further protect sensitive information from possible
compromise resulting from terrorism, coercion, interrogation or
capture of <ent type='ORG'>Agency</ent> personnel by hostile nations and/or terrorist
groups, the <ent type='ORG'>Agency</ent> has established certain policies and procedures
concerning unofficial foreign travel.

All <ent type='ORG'>Agency</ent> personnel (civilian employees, military assignees, and
contractors) who are planning unofficial foreign travel must have
that travel approved by submitting a proposed itinerary to the
<ent type='ORG'>Security Awareness Division</ent> (M56) at least 30 working days prior to
their planned departure from <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States. Your itinerary should
be submitted on Form K2579 (Unofficial Foreign Travel Request). This
form provides space for noting the countries to be visited, mode of
travel, and dates of departure and return. Your immediate supervisor
must sign this form to indicate whether or not your proposed travel
poses a risk to the sensitive information, activities, or projects of
which you may have knowledge due to your current assignment.

After your supervisor's assessment is made, this form should be
forwarded to <ent type='ORG'>the Security</ent> Awareness Director (M56). Your itinerary
will then be reviewed in light of the existing situation in the
country or countries to be visited, and a decision for approval or
disapproval will be based on this assessment. The purpose of this
policy is to limit the risk of travel to areas of the world where a
threat may exist to you and to your knowledge of classified <ent type='ORG'>Agency</ent>
activities.

In this context, travel to <ent type='NORP'>communist</ent>-controlled and other hazardous
activity areas is prohibited. A listing of these hazardous activity
areas is prohibited. A listing of these hazardous activity areas can
be found in Annex A of <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent>/CSS Regulation No. 30-31, "<ent type='ORG'>Security</ent>
Requirements for Foreign Travel" (12 June 1987). From time to time,
travel may also be prohibited to certain areas where the threat from
hostile intelligence services, terrorism, criminal activity or
insurgency poses an unacceptable risk to <ent type='ORG'>Agency</ent> employees and to the
sensitive information they possess. Advance travel deposits made
without prior agency approval of the proposed travel may result in
financial losses by the employee should the travel be disapproved, so
it is important to obtain approval prior to committing yourself
financially. Questions regarding which areas of the world currently
pose a threat should be directed to <ent type='ORG'>the Security Awareness Division</ent>
(M56).

Unofficial foreign travel to <ent type='GPE'>Canada</ent>, the <ent type='GPE'>Bahamas</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Bermuda</ent>, and <ent type='GPE'>Mexico</ent>
does not require prior approval, however, this travel must still be
reported using Form K2579. Travel to these areas may be reported
after the fact.

While you do not have to report your foreign travel once you have
ended your affiliation with the <ent type='ORG'>Agency</ent>, you should be aware that the
risk incurred in travelling to certain areas, from a personal safety
and/or counterintelligence standpoint, remains high. The requirement
to protect the classified information to which you have had access is
a lifetime obligation.

Membership In <ent type='ORG'>Organization</ent>s

Within <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States there are numerous organizations with
memberships ranging from a few to tens of thousands. While you may
certainly participate in the activities of any reputable
organization, membership in any international club or professional
organization/activity with foreign members should be reported through
your Staff <ent type='ORG'>Security</ent> Officer to the Clearance Division (M55). In most
cases there are no security concerns or threats to our employees or
affiliates. However, <ent type='ORG'>the Office</ent> of <ent type='ORG'>Security</ent> needs the opportunity to
research
the organization and to assess any possible risk to you and the
information to which you have access.

In addition to exercising prudence in your choice of organizational
affiliations, you should endeavor to avoid participation in public
activities of a conspicuously controversial nature because such
activities could focus undesirable attention upon you and the <ent type='ORG'>Agency</ent>.
<ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent> employees may, however, participate in bona fide public affairs
such as local politics, so long as such activities do not violate the
provisions of the statutes and regulations which govern the political
activities of all federal employees. Additional information may be
obtained from your Personnel Representative.

Changes In Marital Status/Cohabitation/Names

All personnel, either employed by or assigned to <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent>, must advise the
Office of <ent type='ORG'>Security</ent> of any changes in their marital status (either
marriage or divorce), cohabitation arrangements, or legal name
changes. Such changes should be reported by completing <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent> Form
G1982 (Report of Marriage/Marital Status Change/Name Change), and
following the instructions printed on the form.

Use And Abuse Of Drugs

It is the policy of the National <ent type='ORG'>Security</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Agency</ent> to prevent and
eliminate the improper use of drugs by <ent type='ORG'>Agency</ent> employees and other
personnel associated with the <ent type='ORG'>Agency</ent>. The term "drugs" includes all
controlled drugs or substances identified and listed in the
Controlled Substances Act of 1970, as amended, which includes but is
not limited to: narcotics, depressants, stimulants, cocaine,
hallucinogens ad cannabis (marijuana, hashish, and hashish oil). The
use of illegal drugs or the abuse of prescription drugs by persons
employed by, assigned or detailed to the <ent type='ORG'>Agency</ent> may adversely affect
the national security; may have a serious damaging effect on the
safety and the safety of others; and may lead to criminal
prosecution. Such use of drugs either within or outside <ent type='ORG'>Agency</ent>
controlled facilities is prohibited.

<ent type='ORG'>Physical Security Policies</ent>

The physical security program at <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent> provides protection for
classified material and operations and ensures that only persons
authorized access to the Agency's spaces and classified material are
permitted such access. This program is concerned not only with the
Agency's physical plant and facilities, but also with the internal
and external procedures for safeguarding the Agency's classified
material and activities. Therefore, physical security safeguards
include <ent type='ORG'>Security</ent> Protective Officers, fences, concrete barriers,
access control points, identification badges, safes, and the
compartmentalization of physical spaces. While any one of these
safeguards represents only a delay factor against attempts to gain
unauthorized access to <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent> spaces and material, the total combination
of all these safeguards represents a formidable barrier against
physical penetration of <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent>. Working together with personnel
security policies, they provide "security in depth."

The physical security program depends on interlocking procedures.
The responsibility for carrying out many of these procedures rests
with the individual. This means you, and every person employed by,
assign, or detailed to the <ent type='ORG'>Agency</ent>, must assume the responsibility for
protecting classified material. Included in your responsibilities
are: challenging visitors in operational areas; determining
"need-to-know;" limiting classified conversations to approved areas;
following established locking and checking procedures; properly using
the secure and non-secure telephone systems; correctly wrapping and
packaging classified data for transmittal; and placing classified
waste in burn bags.

The <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent> Badge

Even before you enter an <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent> facility, you have a constant reminder
of security--the <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent> badge. Every person who enters an <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent>
installation is required to wear an authorized badge. To enter most
<ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent> facilities your badge must be inserted into an Access Control
Terminal at a building entrance and you must enter your Personal
Identification Number (<ent type='ORG'>PIN</ent>) on the terminal keyboard. In the absence
of an <ent type='ORG'>Access Control Terminal</ent>, or when passing an internal
security checkpoint, the badge should be held up for viewing by a
<ent type='ORG'>Security</ent> Protective Officer. The badge must be displayed at all
times while the individual remains within any <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent> installation.

<ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent> Badges must be clipped to a beaded neck chain. If necessary for
the safety of those working in the area of electrical equipment or
machinery, rubber tubing may be used to insulate the badge chain.
For those <ent type='ORG'>Agency</ent> personnel working in proximity to other machinery or
equipment, the clip may be used to attach the badge to the wearer's
clothing, but it must also remain attached to the chain.

After you leave an <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent> installation, remove your badge from public
view, thus avoiding publicizing your <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent> affiliation. Your badge
should be kept in a safe place which is convenient enough to ensure
that you will be reminded to bring it with you to work. A good rule
of thumb is to afford your badge the same protection you give your
wallet or your credit cards. DO NOT write your Personal
Identification Number on your badge.

If you plan to be away from the <ent type='ORG'>Agency</ent> for a period of more than 30
days, your badge should be left at the main <ent type='ORG'>Visitor Control Center</ent>
which services your facility.

Should you lose your badge, you must report the facts and
circumstances immediately to <ent type='ORG'>the Security</ent> Operations Center (<ent type='ORG'>SOC</ent>)
(963-3371s/688-6911b) so that your badge <ent type='ORG'>PIN</ent> can be deactivated in
the <ent type='ORG'>Access Control Terminal</ent>s. In the event that you forget your
badge when reporting for duty, you may obtain a "non-retention"
<ent type='ORG'>Temporary Badge</ent> at the main <ent type='ORG'>Visitor Control Center</ent> which serves your
facility after a co-worker personally identifies your and your
clearance has been verified.

Your badge is to be used as identification only within <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent> facilities
or other government installations where the <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent> badge is recognized.
Your badge should never be used outside of the <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent> or other
government facilities for the purpose of personal identification.
You should obtain a Department of Defense identification card from
<ent type='ORG'>the Civilian Welfare Fund</ent> (<ent type='ORG'>CWF</ent>) if you need to identify yourself as a
government employee when applying for "government discounts" offered
at various commercial establishments.

Your badge color indicates your particular affiliation with <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent> and
your level of clearance. Listed below are explanations of the badge
colors you are most likely to see:

Green (*) Fully cleared <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent> employees and certain
military assignees.

Orange (*) (or Gold) Fully cleared representative of
other government agencies.

Black (*) Fully cleared contractors or consultants.

<ent type='ORG'>Blue Employees</ent> who are cleared to the SECRET level
while awaiting completion of their processing for full (TS/SI)
clearance. These Limited Interim Clearance (<ent type='ORG'>LIC</ent>) employees are
restricted to certain activities while inside a secure area.

<ent type='ORG'>Red Clearance</ent> level is not specified, so assume
the holder is uncleared.

* - Fully cleared status means that the person has been cleared to
the Top Secret (TS) level and indoctrinated for Special Intelligence
(SI).

All badges with solid color backgrounds (permanent badges) are kept
by individuals until their <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent> employment or assignment ends.
Striped badges ("non-retention" badges) are generally issued to
visitors and are returned to <ent type='ORG'>the Security</ent> Protective Officer upon
departure from an <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent> facility.

<ent type='ORG'>Area Control</ent>

Within <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent> installations there are generally two types of areas,
Administrative and Secure. An <ent type='ORG'>Administrative Area</ent> is one in which
storage of classified information is not authorized, and in which
discussions of a classified nature are forbidden. This type of area
would include the corridors, restrooms, cafeterias, visitor control
areas, credit union, barber shop, and drugstore. Since uncleared,
non-<ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent> personnel are often present in these areas, all <ent type='ORG'>Agency</ent>
personnel must ensure that no classified information is
discussed in an <ent type='ORG'>Administrative Area</ent>.

Classified information being transported within <ent type='ORG'>Agency</ent> facilities
must be placed within envelopes, folders, briefcases, etc. to ensure
that its contents or classification markings are not disclosed to
unauthorized persons, or that materials are not inadvertently dropped
enroute.

The normal operational work spaces within an <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent> facility are
designated Secure Areas. These areas are approved for classified
discussions and for the storage of classified material. Escorts must
be provided if it is necessary for uncleared personnel (repairmen,
etc.) to enter Secure Areas, an all personnel within the areas must
be made aware of the presence of uncleared individuals. All unknown,
unescorted visitors to Secure Areas should be immediately challenged
by the personnel within the area, regardless of the visitors'
clearance level (as indicated by their badge color).

The corridor doors of these areas must be locked with a deadbolt and
all classified information in the area must be properly secured after
normal working hours or whenever the area is unoccupied. When
storing classified material, the most sensitive material must be
stored in the most secure containers. Deadbolt keys for doors to
these areas must be returned to the key desk at the end of the
workday.

For further information regarding Secure Areas, consult the Physical
<ent type='ORG'>Security</ent> Division (M51) or your staff <ent type='ORG'>Security</ent> Officer.

Items Treated As Classified

For purposes of transportation, storage and destruction, there are
certain types of items which must be treated as classified even
though they may not contain classified information. Such items
include carbon paper, vu-graphs, punched machine processing cards,
punched paper tape, magnetic tape, computer floppy disks, film, and
used typewriter ribbons. This special treatment is necessary since a
visual examination does not readily reveal whether the items contain
classified information.

Prohibited Items

Because of the potential security or safety hazards, certain items
are prohibited under normal circumstances from being brought into or
removed from any <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent> installation. These items have been groped into
two general classes. Class I prohibited items are those which
constitute a threat to the safety and security of <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent>/CSS personnel
and facilities. Items in this category include:

a. Firearms and ammunition b. Explosives, incendiary
substances, radioactive materials, highly volatile materials, or
other hazardous materials c. <ent type='ORG'>Contraband</ent> or other illegal substances
d. Personally owned photographic or electronic equipment including
microcomputers, reproduction or recording devices, televisions or
radios.

Prescribed electronic medical equipment is normally not prohibited,
but requires coordination with <ent type='ORG'>the Physical Security Division</ent> (M51)
prior to being brought into any <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent> building.

Class II prohibited items are those owned by the government or
contractors which constitute a threat to physical, technical, or
<ent type='ORG'>TEMPEST</ent> security. Approval by designated organizational officials is
required before these items can be brought into or removed from <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent>
facilities. Examples are:

a. <ent type='ORG'>Transmitting</ent> and receiving equipment b. Recording
equipment and media c. Telephone equipment and attachments d.
Computing devices and terminals e. Photographic equipment and film

A more detailed listing of examples of Prohibited Items may be
obtained from your Staff <ent type='ORG'>Security</ent> Officer or the Physical <ent type='ORG'>Security</ent>
Division (M51).

Additionally, you may realize that other seemingly innocuous items
are also restricted and should not be brought into any <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent> facility.
Some of these items pose a technical threat; others must be treated
as restricted since a visual inspection does not readily reveal
whether they are classified. These items include:

a. Negatives from processed film; slides; vu-graphs b.
Magnetic media such as floppy disks, cassette tapes, and VCR
videotapes c. Remote control devices for telephone
answering machines d. Pagers

Exit Inspection

As you depart <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent> facilities, you will note another physical security
safeguard--the inspection of the materials you are carrying. This
inspection of your materials, conducted by <ent type='ORG'>Security</ent> Protective
Officers, is designed to preclude the inadvertent removal of
classified material. It is limited to any articles that you are
carrying out of the facility and may include letters, briefcases,
newspapers, notebooks, magazines, gym bags, and other such items.
Although this practice may involve some inconvenience, it is
conducted in your best interest, as well as being a sound security
practice. The inconvenience can be considerably reduced if you keep
to a minimum the number of personal articles that you remove from the
<ent type='ORG'>Agency</ent>.

Removal Of Material From <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent> Spaces

The <ent type='ORG'>Agency</ent> maintains strict controls regarding the removal of
material from its installations, particularly in the case of
classified material.

Only under a very limited and official circumstances classified
material be removed from <ent type='ORG'>Agency</ent> spaces. When deemed necessary,
specific authorization is required to permit an individual to hand
carry classified material out of an <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent> building to another Secure
Area. Depending on the material and circumstances involved, there
are several ways to accomplish this.

A <ent type='ORG'>Courier Badge</ent> authorizes the wearer, for official purposes, to
transport classified material, magnetic media, or Class II prohibited
items between <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent> facilities. These badges, which are strictly
controlled, are made available by <ent type='ORG'>the Physical Security Division</ent>
(M51) only to those offices which have specific requirements
justifying their use.

An Annual <ent type='ORG'>Security</ent> Pass may be issued to individuals whose official
duties require that they transport printed classified materials,
information storage media, or Class II prohibited items to secure
locations within the local area. Materials carried by an individual
who displays this pass are subject to spot inspection by <ent type='ORG'>Security</ent>
Protective Officers or other personnel from <ent type='ORG'>the Office</ent> of <ent type='ORG'>Security</ent>.
It is not permissible to use an Annual <ent type='ORG'>Security</ent> Pass for personal
convenience to circumvent inspection of your personal property by
perimeter <ent type='ORG'>Security</ent> Protective Officers.

If you do not have access to a <ent type='ORG'>Courier Badge</ent> and you have not been
issued an Annual <ent type='ORG'>Security</ent> Pass, you may obtain a One-Time <ent type='ORG'>Security</ent>
Pass to remove classified materials/magnetic media or admit or remove
prohibited items from an <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent> installation. These passes may be
obtained from designated personnel in your work element who have been
given authority to issue them. The issuing official must also
contact <ent type='ORG'>the Security</ent> Operations Center (<ent type='ORG'>SOC</ent>) to obtain approval for
the admission or removal of a Class I prohibited item.

When there is an official need to remove government property which is
not magnetic media, or a prohibited or classified item, a One-Time
Property Pass is used. This type of pass (which is not a <ent type='ORG'>Security</ent>
Pass) may be obtained from your element custodial property officer.
A Property Pass is also to be used when an individual is removing
personal property which might be reasonably be mistaken for
unclassified Government property. This pass is surrendered to the
<ent type='ORG'>Security</ent> Protective Officer at the post where the material is being
removed. Use of this pass does not preclude inspection of the item at
the perimeter control point by <ent type='ORG'>the Security</ent> Protective Officer or
<ent type='ORG'>Security</ent> professionals to ensure that the pass is being used
correctly.

External Protection Of Classified Information

On those occasions when an individual must personally transport
classified material between locations outside of <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent> facilities, the
individual who is acting as the courier must ensure that the material
receives adequate protection. Protective measures must include double
wrapping and packaging of classified information, keeping the
material under constant control, ensuring the presence of a second
appropriately cleared person when necessary, and
delivering the material to authorized persons only. If you are
designated as a courier outside the local area, contact <ent type='ORG'>the Security</ent>
Awareness Division (M56) for your courier briefing.

Even more basic than these procedures is the individual security
responsibility to confine classified conversations to secure areas.
Your home, car pool, and public places are not authorized areas to
conduct classified discussions--even if everyone involved in he
discussion possesses a proper clearance and "need-to-know." The
possibility that a conversation could be overheard by unauthorized
persons dictates the need to guard against classified discussions in
non-secure areas.

Classified information acquired during the course of your career or
assignment to <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent> may not be mentioned directly, indirectly, or by
suggestion in personal diaries, records, or memoirs.

Reporting Loss Or Disclosure Of Classified Information

The extraordinary sensitivity of the <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent> mission requires the prompt
reporting of any known, suspected, or possible unauthorized
disclosure of classified information, or the discovery that
classified information may be lost, or is not being afforded proper
protection. Any information coming to your attention concerning the
loss or unauthorized disclosure of classified information should be
reported immediately to your supervisor, your Staff <ent type='ORG'>Security</ent> Officer,
or <ent type='ORG'>the Security</ent> Operations Center (<ent type='ORG'>SOC</ent>).

Use Of Secure And Non-Secure Telephones

Two separate telephone systems have been installed in <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent> facilities
for use in the conduct of official <ent type='ORG'>Agency</ent> business: the secure
telephone system (gray telephone) and the outside, non-secure
telephone system (black telephone). All <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent> personnel must ensure
that use of either telephone system does not jeopardize the security
of classified information.

The secure telephone system is authorized for discussion of
classified information. Personnel receiving calls on the secure
telephone may assume that the caller is authorized to use the system.
However, you must ensure that the caller has a "need-to-know" the
information you will be discussing.

The outside telephone system is only authorized for unclassified
official <ent type='ORG'>Agency</ent> business calls. The discussion of classified
information is not permitted on this system. Do not attempt to use
"double-talk" in order to discuss classified information over the
non-secure telephone system.

In order to guard against the inadvertent transmission of classified
information over a non-secure telephone, and individual using the
black telephone in an area where classified activities are being
conducted must caution other personnel in the area that the
non-secure telephone is in use. Likewise, you should avoid using the
non-secure telephone in the vicinity of a secure telephone which is
also in use.

HELPFUL INFORMATION

<ent type='ORG'>Security</ent> Resources

In the fulfillment of your security responsibilities, you should be
aware that there are many resources available to assist you. If you
have any questions or concerns regarding security at <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent> or your
individual security responsibilities, your supervisor should be
consulted. Additionally, <ent type='ORG'>Staff Security Officers</ent> are appointed to
the designated <ent type='ORG'>Agency</ent> elements to assist these organizations in
carrying out their security responsibilities. There is a Staff
<ent type='ORG'>Security</ent> Officer assigned to each organization; their phone numbers
are listed at the back of this handbook. <ent type='ORG'>Staff Security Officers</ent>
also provide guidance to and monitor the activities of <ent type='ORG'>Security</ent>
Coordinators and Advisors (individuals who, in addition to their
operational duties within their respective elements, assist element
supervisors or managers in discharging security responsibilities).

Within <ent type='ORG'>the Office</ent> of <ent type='ORG'>Security</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>the Physical Security Division</ent> (M51)
will offer you assistance in matters such as access control, security
passes, clearance verification, combination locks, keys,
identification badges, technical security, and <ent type='ORG'>the Security</ent>
Protective Force. The <ent type='ORG'>Security Awareness Division</ent> (M56) provides
security guidance and briefings regarding unofficial foreign
travel, couriers, special access, <ent type='ORG'>TDY</ent>/<ent type='ORG'>PCS</ent>, and amateur radio
activities. <ent type='ORG'>The Industrial and Field Security Division</ent> (M52) is
available to provide security guidance concerning <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent> contractor and
field site matters.

<ent type='ORG'>The Security</ent> Operations Center (<ent type='ORG'>SOC</ent>) is operated by two <ent type='ORG'>Security</ent> Duty
Officers (<ent type='ORG'>SDO</ent>s), 24 hours a day, 7 days a week. The <ent type='ORG'>SDO</ent>,
representing <ent type='ORG'>the Office</ent> of <ent type='ORG'>Security</ent>, provides a complete range of
security services to include direct communications with fire and
rescue personnel for all <ent type='ORG'>Agency</ent> area facilities. The <ent type='ORG'>SDO</ent> is available
to handle any physical or personnel problems that may arise, and if
necessary, can direct your to the appropriate security office that
can assist you. After normal business hours, weekends, and holidays,
the <ent type='ORG'>SOC</ent> is the focal point for all security matters for all <ent type='ORG'>Agency</ent>
personnel and facilities (to include <ent type='ORG'>Agency</ent> field sites and
contractors). The <ent type='ORG'>SOC</ent> is located in Room 2A0120, <ent type='ORG'>OPS</ent> 2A building and
the phone numbers are 688-6911(b), 963-3371(s).

However, keep in mind that you may contact any individual or any
division within <ent type='ORG'>the Office</ent> of <ent type='ORG'>Security</ent> directly. Do not hesitate to
report any information which may affect the security of the Agency's
mission, information, facilities or personnel.

<ent type='ORG'>Security</ent>-Related Services

In addition to Office of <ent type='ORG'>Security</ent> resources, there are a number of
professional, security-related services available for assistance in
answering your questions or providing the services which you require.

The Installations and Logistics <ent type='ORG'>Organization</ent> (L) maintains the system
for the collection and destruction of classified waste, and is also
responsible for the movement and scheduling of material via <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent>
couriers and <ent type='ORG'>the Defense Courier Service</ent> (<ent type='ORG'>DCS</ent>). Additionally, L
monitors the proper addressing, marking, and packaging of classified
material being transmitted outside of <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent>; maintains records
pertaining to receipt and transmission of controlled mail; and issues
property passes for the removal of unclassified property.

The <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent> Office of Medical Services (M7) has a staff of physicians,
clinical psychologists and an alcoholism counselor. All are well
trained to help individuals help themselves in dealing with their
problems. Counseling services, with referrals to private mental
health professionals when appropriate, are all available to <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent>
personnel. Appointments can be obtained by contacting M7 directly.
When an individual refers himself/herself, the information discussed
in the counseling sessions is regarded as privileged medical
information and is retained exclusively in M7 unless it pertains to
the national security.

Counselling interviews are conducted by <ent type='ORG'>the Office</ent> of Civilian
Personnel (M3) with any civilian employee regarding both on and
off-the-job problems. M3 is also available to assist all personnel
with the personal problems seriously affecting themselves or members
of their families. In cases of serious physical or emotional
illness, injury, hospitalization, or other personal emergencies, M3
informs concerned <ent type='ORG'>Agency</ent> elements and maintains liaison with family
members in order to provide possible assistance. Similar counselling
services are available to military assignees through Military
Personnel (M2).

GUIDE TO SECURITY

M51 PHYSICAL SECURITY 963-6651s/688-8293b (<ent type='ORG'>FMHQ</ent>) 968-8101s/859-6411b
(FANX)

CONFIRM and badges Prohibited Items
(963-6611s/688-7411b) Locks, keys, safes and alarms <ent type='ORG'>SOC</ent>
(963-3371s/688-6911b) <ent type='ORG'>Security</ent>/vehicle passes <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent> facility
protection and compliance <ent type='ORG'>Visitor Control Inspections Red</ent>/blue seal
areas New Construction Pass Clearances
(963-4780s/688-6759b)

M52 INDUSTRIAL AND FIELD SECURITY 982-7918s/859-6255b

<ent type='ORG'>Security</ent> at contractor field site facilities Verification of
classified mailing addresses for contractor facilities

M53 INVESTIGATIONS 982-7914s/859-6464b

Personnel Interview Program (PIP) Reinvestigations Military
Interview Program (<ent type='ORG'>MIP</ent>) Special investigations

M54 COUNTERINTELLIGENCE 982-7832s/859-6424b

<ent type='ORG'>Security</ent> counterintelligence analysis <ent type='ORG'>Security</ent> compromises
M55 CLEARANCES 982-7900s/859-4747b

Privacy Act Officer (For review of security files) Continued SCI access
Contractor/applicant processing Military access

M56 SECURITY AWARENESS 963-3273s/688-6535b

<ent type='ORG'>Security</ent> indoctrinations/debriefings <ent type='ORG'>Embassy</ent> visits
Associations with foreign nationals <ent type='ORG'>Briefings</ent> (foreign travel,
<ent type='ORG'>Security</ent> Week ham radio, courier,
<ent type='ORG'>Security</ent> posters, brochures, etc. <ent type='ORG'>LIC</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>PCS</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>TDY</ent>,
special access, etc.)
Foreign travel approval
Military contractor orientation
Special Access Office (963-5466s/688-6353b)

M57 POLYGRAPH 982-7844s/859-6363b

Polygraph interviews

M509 MANAGEMENT AND PO<ent type='ORG'>LIC</ent>Y STAFF 982-7885s/859-6350b

STAFF SECURITY OFFICERS (<ent type='ORG'>SSO</ent>s)

Element Room Secure/Non-Secure
A 2A0852B 963-4650/688-7044
B 3W099 963-4559/688-7141
D/Q/J/N/U 2B8066G 963-4496/688-6614
E/M D3B17 968-8050/859-6669
G 9A195 963-5033/688-7902
K 2B5136 963-1978/688-5052
L SAB4 977-7230/688-6194
P 2W091 963-5302/688-7303
R B6B710 968-4073/859-4736
S/V/Y/C/X C2A55 972-2144/688-7549
T 2B5040 963-4543/688-7364
W 1C181 963-5970/688-7061

GUIDE TO SECURITY-RELATED SERVICES

<ent type='ORG'>Agency</ent> Anonymity 968-8251/859-4381
<ent type='ORG'>Alcohol Rehabilitation</ent> Program 963-5420/688-7312
Cipher Lock Repair 963-1221/688-7119
Courier Schedules (local) 977-7197/688-7403
Defense Courier Service 977-7117/688-7826
Disposal of Classified Waste
- Paper only 972-2150/688-6593
- Plastics, Metal, Film, etc 963-4103/688-7062
Locksmith 963-3585/688-7233
Mail Dissemination and Packaging 977-7117/688-7826
Medical Center (Fort <ent type='GPE'>Meade</ent>) 963-5429/688-7263
(FANX) 968-8960/859-6667
(Airport Square) 982-7800/859-6155
<ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent>/CSS Information Policy Division 963-5825/688-6527
Personnel Assistance
- Civilian 982-7835/859-6577
- Air Force 963-3239/688-7980
- Army 963-3739/688-6393
- Navy 963-3439/688-7325
Property Passes (unclassified material) 977-7263/688-7800
<ent type='ORG'>Psychological Services</ent> 963-5429/688-7311

FREQUENTLY USED ACRONYMS/DESIGNATORS

ARFCOS Armed Forces Courier Service (now known as <ent type='ORG'>DCS</ent>)
AWOL Absent Without Leave
<ent type='ORG'>CAO</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Classification Advisory</ent> Officer
COB Close of Business
<ent type='ORG'>CWF</ent> Civilian Welfare Fund
<ent type='ORG'>DCS</ent> Defense Courier Service (formerly known as ARFCOS)
DoD Department of Defense
EOD Enter on Duty
FOUO For Official Use Only
M2 Office of <ent type='ORG'>Military Personnel</ent>
M3 Office of <ent type='ORG'>Civilian Personnel</ent>
M5 Office of <ent type='ORG'>Security</ent>
M7 Office of Medical Services
NCS National Cryptologic School
<ent type='ORG'>PCS</ent> Permanent Change of Station
<ent type='ORG'>PIN</ent> Personal Identification Number
Q43 Information Policy Division
<ent type='ORG'>SDO</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Security</ent> Duty Officer
<ent type='ORG'>SOC</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Security</ent> Operations Center
SPO <ent type='ORG'>Security</ent> Protective Officer
<ent type='ORG'>SSO</ent> Staff <ent type='ORG'>Security</ent> Officer
<ent type='ORG'>TDY</ent> Temporary Duty
UFT Unofficial Foreign Travel

A FINAL NOTE

The information you have just read is designed to serve as a guide to assist
you in the conduct of your security responsibilities. However, it by no means
describes the extent of your obligation to protect information vital to the
defense of our nation. Your knowledge of specific security regulations is part
of a continuing process of education and experience. This handbook is designed
to provide the foundation of this knowledge and serve as a guide to the
development of an attitude of security awareness.

In the final analysis, security is an individual responsibility. As a
participant in the activities of the National <ent type='ORG'>Security</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Agency</ent> organization, you
are urged to be always mindful of the importance of the work being accomplished
by <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent> and of the unique sensitivity of the Agency's operations.
</p></xml>