<xml>

<p> AN <ent type='ORG'>ILLUMINATI</ent> OUTLINE OF HISTORY</p>

<p>Alpha and <ent type='ORG'>Omega</ent> -- <ent type='GPE'>Immanentizing</ent> of the Eschaton.
20000000 BC -- Recent Epoch of geeology begins; Ice Age ends;
human beings spread to all parts of the world.
30000 -- First Illuminatus, Gruad, rules in Atlantis.
20000 -- Mythical Lloigor inhabit continent of Mu.
10000 -- Approximate beginning of agriculture. Estimated date of
inscriptions on stone disks by the <ent type='NORP'>Dropa</ent> tribe, a diminuative
people of the Bayan-Kara-Ula Mountains on the border of <ent type='GPE'>China</ent> and
<ent type='GPE'>Tibet</ent>; disks describe how the tribe came to earth in flying
machines; ancient <ent type='NORP'>Dropa</ent> graves contain human remains with huge
heads and small bodies. Earliest estimated date of carving of the
Crystal Skull found at <ent type='GPE'>Lubaantun</ent> in the <ent type='GPE'>Yucatan</ent>. Hyborian Age in
Europe.
9000 to 10000 -- Date of Plato's Atlantis.
6000 -- Picture writing develops.
5000 -- First alphabet begins to develop.
4000 -- Approximate date of discovery of metals, beginning of
cities, constellations of stars first recorded. <ent type='NORP'>Egyptians</ent> begin
placing small pieces of crystal on the forehead of deceased prior
to mummification.
3000 -- Approximate date of building of the <ent type='LOC'>Sphinx</ent> and Great
Pyramid at <ent type='GPE'>Giza</ent> and other pyramids elsewhere in <ent type='GPE'>Egypt</ent>. Indus
Valley civilization develops complex government, writing and well
planned cities. <ent type='NORP'>Minoan</ent> civilization flourishes in <ent type='GPE'>Crete</ent>.
Earliest parts of the Bible written. Beginning date of Olmec
calendar from <ent type='LOC'>Central America</ent>: 3113 BC. Trephination (cutting a
hole in the skull) practiced by people all over the world.
2500 -- <ent type='ORG'>Sarmoung Brotherhood</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>Babylonia</ent> flourish according to
Gurdjieff.
2100 -- <ent type='NORP'>Egyptians</ent> record star configurations on which the 24 hour
day is based.
2000 -- Stonehenge and other stone circles built in <ent type='GPE'>England</ent>.
1800 -- Huge Silbury Mound constructed near Stonehenge.
1700 -- <ent type='GPE'>Babylonia</ent>n Enuma <ent type='PERSON'>Anu Enlil</ent>, early roots of astrology
based on celestial phenomena.
1500 -- Approximate date of the destruction of Thera, on which
Atlantis legends are probably based. Early references to
<ent type='NORP'>Mithraism</ent> on cuneform astronomical tests. Quadrants of the moon
recorded in <ent type='GPE'>China</ent>.
1360 -- Akhenaton's monotheistic sun worship in <ent type='GPE'>Egypt</ent>.
1344 -- Tutankhamun, Akhenaton's successor who revived
polytheism, buried at <ent type='GPE'>Thebes</ent>; curse reading "Death comes on swift
wings to he who opens this tomb," written on tomb doorway.
1300 -- Approximate date "I Ching" written in <ent type='GPE'>China</ent>.
1184 -- End of <ent type='EVENT'>the Trojan War</ent>, Illium falls to the <ent type='NORP'>Greeks</ent>.
1000 to 2000 -- Legendary Thule civilization in the <ent type='LOC'>Gobi</ent> region
destroyed by a catastrophe, "possibly of an atomic nature,"
survivors migrating to <ent type='ORG'>Agarthi</ent> and Schamballah.
1000 -- Huge Sacrificial Table built at Mystery Hill near <ent type='PERSON'>North</ent>
Salem, <ent type='GPE'>New Hampshire</ent>.
950 -- Approximate date of building of Solomon's Temple in
<ent type='GPE'>Jerusalem</ent>, traditional origin of the <ent type='NORP'>Masonic</ent> fraternity; alleged
assassination of <ent type='ORG'>Temple master</ent>-mason Hiram for refusing to reveal
masonic secrets.
900 -- Approximate time settlers from Europe and <ent type='LOC'>the Middle East</ent>
established colonies in <ent type='PERSON'>North</ent> <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>.
800 -- Twenty-two "moon stations" in monthly lunar cycle
recognized in <ent type='GPE'>Babylonia</ent>, India and <ent type='GPE'>China</ent>.
753 -- Legendary founding of <ent type='GPE'>Rome</ent> by <ent type='NORP'>Romulus</ent>.
700 -- <ent type='NORP'>Jordanian</ent> city of <ent type='ORG'>Petra</ent> is carved out of sandstone by
unknown culture.
600 -- Approximate beginning of money with first coins in Lydia.
575 -- Nebuchadnezzar completes building Tower of Babel in
<ent type='GPE'>Babylon</ent>.
500 to 600 -- Time of Buddha, <ent type='PERSON'>Lao Tse</ent>, Confucius, Zarathustra,
Orpheus, Pythagoras, <ent type='PERSON'>Zachariah</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Daniel</ent>--an Illuminated century.
500 -- <ent type='LOC'>Sun</ent>-Tse's "Treatise on the Art of War," first intelligence
manual.
485 -- Execution of <ent type='PERSON'>Spurius Cassius</ent> in <ent type='GPE'>Rome</ent>.
450 -- Development of the 12 constellations of the zodiac in
<ent type='ORG'>Mesopotamia</ent>, recognizing the importance of the plane of the
elliptic through which the sun, moon and planets move.
440 -- Assassination of Spurius Maelius.
400 -- Druidism in <ent type='GPE'>England</ent>. Astrological ideas from Enuma Anu
Enlil transmitted to India.
390 -- Approximate date Plato's "The Republic" written, featuring
such <ent type='ORG'>Illuminoid</ent> images as the Philosopher Kings, <ent type='ORG'>the Divided Line</ent>
and the parable of the Cave.
355 -- Plato's "Timaios" and "<ent type='PERSON'>Kritias</ent>," earliest accounts of
Atlantis.
300 -- Invention of <ent type='NORP'>Mayan</ent> calendar in <ent type='GPE'>Yucatan</ent>, based on advanced
astronomy. <ent type='PERSON'>Fabius</ent> family of <ent type='GPE'>Rome</ent> reaches its greatest heights.
275 -- Approximate date <ent type='NORP'>Greek</ent> poet <ent type='PERSON'>Aratus</ent> makes first sytematic
record of star constellations in "<ent type='ORG'>Phaenomena</ent>."
273 to 232 -- Rule of Asoka, king of India who allegedly founded
the Nine Unknown.
212 -- Archimedes uses burning-glass to set fire to <ent type='NORP'>Roman</ent> fleet at
<ent type='ORG'>Syracuse</ent>, early use of lens as weapon.
133 -- Land reformer <ent type='PERSON'>Tiberius Gracchus</ent> murdered and hundreds of
his followers killed by followers of powerful <ent type='NORP'>Roman</ent> patricians;
death of Scripio <ent type='NORP'>Africanus</ent> a few years later.
121 -- Gaius <ent type='PERSON'>Gracchus</ent> and 3000 of his followers massacred by
patricians.
100 -- The Great Teacher of <ent type='ORG'>the Essenes</ent>. Essentials of modern
astrology worked out.
95 -- Approximate date of assassination of <ent type='LOC'>Saturninus</ent> and Glaucia.
92 -- Assassination of Rutilius Rufus.
91 -- Assassination of Livius Drufus.
73 -- Revolt of gladiators led by Spartacus.
44 -- Assassination of Julius Caesar.
4 -- Birth of <ent type='PERSON'>Jesus</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>Nazareth</ent>, accompanied by various <ent type='ORG'>Illuminoid</ent>
trappings: three early Men-In-Black disguised as the <ent type='ORG'>Wise Men</ent>;
strange lights in the sky; miracles such as visits from angels,
prohpecy and suspension of time are reported.
0 -- Carnation-Painted Eyebrows Society, Copper Horses, <ent type='PERSON'>Iron Shins</ent>
and other secret societies active in <ent type='GPE'>China</ent>.
AD 30 -- Assassination of the radical <ent type='PERSON'>Jesus</ent>, allegedly on
<ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent> orders; more <ent type='ORG'>Illuminoid</ent> trappings; an eclipse; an
earthquake; visitorsfrom the sky roll away the stone from the
sepulcher and liberate the crucified <ent type='PERSON'>Jesus</ent>.
100 -- Hero of <ent type='GPE'>Alexandria</ent> devises primitive steam-engine.
125 to 150 -- <ent type='PERSON'>Simon Magus</ent>, Menander, Valentinus and others develop
Gnostic religious doctrines of esoteric knowledge (illumination).
135 -- Approximate date Ptolemy records 1022 stars in "<ent type='ORG'>Almagest</ent>";
also recorded astrological ideas from Enuma <ent type='PERSON'>Anu Enlil</ent> in his
"<ent type='ORG'>Apotelesmatika</ent>."
150 -- <ent type='NORP'>Roman</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Mithraism</ent> competes with <ent type='NORP'>Christianity</ent>. Yellow Turban
Society subdues northern <ent type='GPE'>China</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Triad</ent> cult formed in opposition.
200 -- First book of the <ent type='ORG'>cabala</ent>, "<ent type='PERSON'>Sepher Yetzirah</ent>," compiled.
216 to 276 -- Life of Mani, the Illuminator, who founded
<ent type='NORP'>Manicheism</ent>, based on ideas from <ent type='NORP'>Judaism</ent>, <ent type='NORP'>Christianity</ent>,
Zoroasterism, Gnosticism, etc.
325 -- Council of Nicaea in which <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> begins to rigidify.
400 -- Estimated date of carving of stone statues found on Easter
Island.
500 -- <ent type='NORP'>Chinese</ent> use of gunpowder.
570 to 632 -- Life of <ent type='PERSON'>Muhammad</ent>, founder of Islam.
670 -- Callinicus invents <ent type='NORP'>Greek</ent> Fire, primitive incendiary bomb.
673 to 735 -- Life of the Venerable <ent type='PERSON'>Bede</ent>, the greatest scholar of
<ent type='NORP'>Saxon</ent> <ent type='GPE'>England</ent> whose "Ecclesiastical History of <ent type='GPE'>England</ent>" (731)
contained many occult and unexplained occurances.
700 -- Sufi mysticism begins.
730 -- "Al <ent type='PERSON'>Azif</ent>" written in <ent type='GPE'>Damascus</ent> by Abdul Alhazred.
772 -- <ent type='PERSON'>Charlemagne</ent> allegedly established <ent type='ORG'>Holy Secret Tribunal</ent>
which becomes the <ent type='PERSON'>Holy Vehm</ent>.
850 -- <ent type='NORP'>Ismaili</ent> and <ent type='NORP'>Fatimid</ent> missionaries throughout <ent type='GPE'>Islamic Empire</ent>
preach revolution against the ruling <ent type='LOC'>Sun</ent>ni order and <ent type='NORP'>Abbasid</ent>
state.
900 -- Beginning of the Bogomils of <ent type='GPE'>Bulgaria</ent>, a <ent type='PERSON'>Manicheian</ent> sect,
roots of <ent type='ORG'>Cathari</ent>.
909 -- First <ent type='NORP'>Fatimid</ent> caliph in <ent type='GPE'>Egypt</ent>.
920 to 1003 -- Life of Pope Sylvester II who allegedly visited the
Nine Unknown in India.
950 -- "Al <ent type='PERSON'>Azif</ent>" translated into <ent type='NORP'>Greek</ent> as "Necronomicon."
1000 -- Approximate founding of Yezidi cult by <ent type='PERSON'>Sufi Sheikh</ent> Adi in
<ent type='GPE'>Iraq</ent>. Abode of Learning active in <ent type='GPE'>Cairo</ent>. Spread of <ent type='ORG'>Cathari</ent>
<ent type='NORP'>Manicheism</ent> throughout Europe. <ent type='PERSON'>Leif Ericson</ent> explores <ent type='PERSON'>North</ent>
<ent type='GPE'>America</ent>.
1034 to 1124 -- Life of <ent type='PERSON'>Hasan</ent>-e Sabbah, founder of <ent type='ORG'>the Assassins</ent>
of <ent type='GPE'>Persia</ent>. Member of the <ent type='NORP'>Ismaili</ent> sect, <ent type='PERSON'>Hasan</ent> seized fortress of
<ent type='GPE'>Alamut</ent> in <ent type='GPE'>Daylam</ent> in 1090; split with <ent type='NORP'>Fatimid</ent> dynasty in 1094;
Assassins flourished for next several centuries.
1050 -- Approximate date of founding of the Order of Hospitallers
in <ent type='GPE'>Jerusalem</ent>.
1058 -- Member of <ent type='ORG'>the Abode</ent> of Learning sect gains temporary
control of <ent type='GPE'>Bagdad</ent>.
1092 -- Assassins murder <ent type='GPE'>Persia</ent>n minister Nizam al-Mulk.
1095 -- First Crusade.
1100 -- Approximate date <ent type='PERSON'>Sufi Gilani</ent> founds <ent type='NORP'>Arabic</ent> school of
<ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent>, Kadiri Order of Sebil-el-ward, in <ent type='GPE'>Bagdad</ent>. Assassins
infiltrate Thug cult of India. Bogomil leader <ent type='GPE'>Basil</ent> burned in
<ent type='GPE'>Constantinople</ent>. <ent type='GPE'>Albi</ent>gensian <ent type='ORG'>Cathari</ent> sect flourishes near <ent type='GPE'>Albi</ent>,
<ent type='GPE'>France</ent>. <ent type='ORG'>Avengers</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Beati Paoli</ent> active in <ent type='GPE'>Italy</ent>. Joachim of
Floris founds primitive <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> sect, <ent type='ORG'>Illuminated Ones</ent>. Robin
Hood active in <ent type='GPE'>England</ent>.
1119 -- <ent type='ORG'>Knights Templar</ent> founded in <ent type='GPE'>Palestine</ent>.
1123 -- Abode of Learning suppressed by <ent type='NORP'>Turkish</ent> Vizier Afdal.
1140 -- Rapid growth of <ent type='ORG'>Cathari</ent> sect begins.
1149 -- First <ent type='ORG'>Cathari</ent> bishop established.
1162 to 1227 -- Life of Genghis Khan, conquerer of <ent type='GPE'>China</ent> and
<ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>, invader of Europe and <ent type='GPE'>Islamic Empire</ent>, destroyer of
Assassin power. Approximate beginnings of the wandering of the
<ent type='ORG'>Gypsies</ent> of <ent type='PERSON'>North</ent> India.
1167 -- <ent type='ORG'>Cathari</ent> council near Toulouse.
1170 -- Assassination of Thomas a Becket.
1171 -- Last <ent type='NORP'>Fatimid</ent> caliph dies.
1176 -- <ent type='PERSON'>Peter Waldo</ent> founds <ent type='ORG'>the Poor Men</ent> of <ent type='PERSON'>Lyons</ent>. Sultan Saladin
invades Assassin territory, gains truce.
1184 -- <ent type='PERSON'>Waldenses</ent> excommunicated, suppressed.
1200 to 1300 -- <ent type='ORG'>House</ent> of Wisdom in <ent type='GPE'>Cairo</ent>, roots of the <ent type='NORP'>Afghan</ent>
Roshaniya. Origin of the <ent type='ORG'>Mafia</ent> in <ent type='GPE'>Sicily</ent>.
1208 -- <ent type='GPE'>Albi</ent>gensian Crusade begins suppression of <ent type='ORG'>Cathari</ent> heresy.
1212 -- The Children's Crusade. Genghis Khan invades <ent type='GPE'>China</ent>.
1233 -- Founding of the Inquisition to suppress <ent type='ORG'>Cathari</ent> and other
heresies.
1235 to 1315 -- Life of Dr. Illuminatus, <ent type='PERSON'>Ramon Llull</ent> (Raymond
Lully) in <ent type='GPE'>Spain</ent>.
1241 -- <ent type='NORP'>Mongols</ent> invade Europe through wise use of intelligence
information and strategy, introduce gunpowder from <ent type='LOC'>Asia</ent>.
1244 -- Massacre of <ent type='ORG'>Cathari</ent> at <ent type='GPE'>Montsegur</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>France</ent>.
1250s -- Approximate beginning of <ent type='PERSON'>Holy Vehm</ent> in <ent type='GPE'>Westphalia</ent>.
Approximate time of <ent type='PERSON'>Hulagu Khan</ent>'s defeat of <ent type='ORG'>the Assassins</ent>.
1254 to 1324 (?) -- Life of <ent type='PERSON'>Marco Polo</ent>, early European traveler in
<ent type='GPE'>China</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Persia</ent>.
1258 -- <ent type='PERSON'>Hulagu Khan</ent> destroys <ent type='GPE'>Bagdad</ent>; <ent type='NORP'>Mongols</ent> destroy <ent type='ORG'>Mesopotamia</ent>,
the mother of civilization.
1260 -- <ent type='NORP'>Mongol</ent> invasion of <ent type='GPE'>Islamic Empire</ent> turned back.
1270s -- <ent type='ORG'>Cathari</ent> hierarchy fades.
1275 -- <ent type='ORG'>Assembly</ent> of traveling <ent type='ORG'>mason guilds</ent> in <ent type='GPE'>Frankfort</ent>. "<ent type='PERSON'>Zohar</ent>,"
second book of the <ent type='ORG'>cabala</ent>, compiled by Moses de Leon in <ent type='GPE'>Spain</ent>.
1280 -- <ent type='PERSON'>Roger Bacon</ent>, deviser of early eyeglasses, independently
invents gunpowder.
1291 -- Hospitallers retreat to <ent type='GPE'>Cyprus</ent>.
1300 -- <ent type='ORG'>White Lotus Society</ent> founded in <ent type='GPE'>China</ent>. Inquisition begins
suppression of witches and other pagan groups.
1307 -- Philip IV of <ent type='GPE'>France</ent> suppresses <ent type='ORG'>Knights Templar</ent> for
witchcraft and heresies; de Molay imprisoned in the Temple in
<ent type='GPE'>Paris</ent>.
1308 -- Assassination of Holy <ent type='NORP'>Roman</ent> Emperor <ent type='PERSON'>Albert</ent> I.
1309 -- Hospitallers acquire the isle of <ent type='ORG'>Rhodes</ent>.
1313 -- <ent type='ORG'>Knights Templar</ent> dissolved by papal decree.
1314 -- De Molay and others burned in <ent type='GPE'>Paris</ent>.
1327 -- Assassination of King Edward II in <ent type='GPE'>England</ent>.
1329 -- First appearance of the Tarot in <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent>.
1360 -- Approximate date of the earliest known Satanic cults;
black masses celebrated in <ent type='GPE'>France</ent>.
1369 -- Timurlane becomes Great Khan.
1375 -- Another assembly of traveling <ent type='ORG'>mason guilds</ent> in <ent type='GPE'>Frankfort</ent>.
1379 to 1482 -- <ent type='ORG'>Alleged</ent> life of <ent type='NORP'>Christian</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Rosenkreuz</ent>, fictitious
founder of Rosicrucianism.
1390 -- <ent type='ORG'>Gypsies</ent> begin to appear in Europe.
1400s -- <ent type='ORG'>Cathari</ent> sect dies out. Concave lenses developed.
1404 -- King <ent type='PERSON'>Robert</ent> revises code of <ent type='PERSON'>Holy Vehm</ent>.
1410 -- Secret society formed in <ent type='GPE'>Italy</ent> which eventually joins with
Rosicrucianism.
1437 -- Assassination of King <ent type='PERSON'>James</ent> I of <ent type='GPE'>Scotland</ent>.
1456 -- Gutenberg Bible begins modern printing.
1458 -- Abramelin's "Book of Sacred Magic" translated from Hebrew
to <ent type='NORP'>french</ent> according to followers of the cult of the Guardian
Angel.
1471 -- Assassination of King Henry VI of <ent type='GPE'>England</ent>.
1472 -- University of Ingolstadt founded. <ent type='PERSON'>Fernando Poo</ent> discovers
<ent type='PERSON'>Fernando Poo</ent>.
1483 -- Assassination of King Edward V of <ent type='GPE'>England</ent>.
1492 -- <ent type='PERSON'>Rodrigo Borgia</ent>, head of the powerful <ent type='PERSON'>Borgia</ent> family,
becomes Pope Alexander VI. <ent type='GPE'>Columbus</ent> sails the ocean blue.
1493 to 1541 -- Life of Paracelsus, possible founder of
Roscrucianism; discover of zinc around 1530; model of the <ent type='PERSON'>Faust</ent>
legend.
1500 -- Approximate date of <ent type='PERSON'>Roshaiya</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Illuminated Ones</ent>, in
<ent type='GPE'>Afganistan</ent>. Beginning of <ent type='PERSON'>Alumbrados</ent> in <ent type='GPE'>Spain</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>Charcoal</ent>-Burners in <ent type='GPE'>Scotland</ent>. Cesare <ent type='PERSON'>Borgia</ent> has his brother-in-law
assassinated.
1502 -- Cesare <ent type='PERSON'>Borgia</ent> arrests and executes enemies who have
conspired against him.
1503 to 1566 -- Life of Nostradamus, visionary prophet.
1507 -- Fra Dolcino's version of Joachim's Illuminism suppressed
by the Bishop of Vercueil.
1510 -- Beginning of systematic importation of <ent type='NORP'>African</ent> slaves into
<ent type='GPE'>the West</ent> Indies.
1513 -- Machiavelli's "The Prince" published.
1519 -- <ent type='NORP'>Spanish</ent> conquest of <ent type='GPE'>Mexico</ent>, enslavement of Amerindians.
1522 -- Hospitallers lose <ent type='ORG'>Rhodes</ent> to the <ent type='NORP'>Turks</ent>.
1530 -- Hospitallers given Isle of <ent type='GPE'>Malta</ent> by <ent type='PERSON'>Charles</ent> V, become
Knights of <ent type='GPE'>Malta</ent>.
1537 -- Assassination of Alessandro de Medici, Duke of Florence.
1568 -- First Inquisition edict against the <ent type='PERSON'>Alumbrados</ent>.
1574 -- Second edict against <ent type='PERSON'>Alumbrados</ent>.
1575 -- Approximate date of founding of <ent type='ORG'>British Intelligence</ent>
services.
1575 to 1624 -- Life of <ent type='PERSON'>Jakob Bohme</ent>, visionary mystic, illuminated
one.
1584 -- Assassination of <ent type='PERSON'>William</ent> I of <ent type='NORP'>Orange</ent> in <ent type='GPE'>England</ent>.
1587 -- English colony established at <ent type='GPE'>Roanoke Island</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Virginia</ent>; no
trace of the "lost colony" was found when supply ships returned
three years later.
1589 -- Assassination of King Henry III of <ent type='GPE'>France</ent>.
1590 -- Janssen makes first compound microscope in Europe.
1597 -- Anonymous alchemist seeks to start Rosicrucian-like
society in Europe.
1605 -- Rosicrucian constitution published.
1607 -- <ent type='NORP'>Italian</ent> secrect society headed by Count Bernard of <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent>
merges with Rosicrucianism. First permanent English settlement in
<ent type='GPE'>America</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>James</ent>town, Virgina.
1608 -- Apprentice to <ent type='NORP'>Dutch</ent> spectacle-maker <ent type='PERSON'>Lippershey</ent> discovers
principle of focusing lenses; <ent type='PERSON'>Lippershey</ent> builds first telescope.
1609 -- Galileo independently builds telescope, begins study of
astonomy. <ent type='NORP'>Spanish</ent> settlement at Santa Fe, New <ent type='GPE'>Mexico</ent>, founded.
1610 -- Assassination of King Henty IV of <ent type='GPE'>France</ent>.
1614 -- "<ent type='PERSON'>Fama Fraternitatis</ent>" published, fictional story of
<ent type='PERSON'>Rosenkreuz</ent> by <ent type='PERSON'>Johann Valentin Andrea</ent>.
1619 -- First slave ship in <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>James</ent>town, <ent type='GPE'>Virginia</ent>.
1620 -- <ent type='GPE'>Plymouth Colony</ent>, second English settlement, arrives on
Mayflower.
1622 -- Posters appear in <ent type='GPE'>Paris</ent> warning that the Rosicrucians are
"amongst you...visibly and invisibly."
1623 -- Final papal edict against <ent type='PERSON'>Alumbrados</ent>; Guerinets appear in
<ent type='GPE'>France</ent>. First submarine built by <ent type='PERSON'>Cornelius van Drebbel</ent> in
<ent type='GPE'>England</ent>.
1638 -- <ent type='PERSON'>Milton</ent> meets Galileo.
1640 -- Beginning of subliminal persuasion when Rembrandt imbeds
the word "sex" in a painting.
1642 -- <ent type='EVENT'>Civil War</ent> in <ent type='GPE'>England</ent> between King <ent type='PERSON'>Charles</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>Parliament</ent>.
1646 -- Earliest known <ent type='NORP'>Masonic</ent> Lodge to allow non-professional or
"free" masons, in <ent type='GPE'>Warrington</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>England</ent>.
1647 -- <ent type='ORG'>Alleged</ent> correspondence between <ent type='ORG'>Cromwell</ent> and Ebeneezer
Pratt plotting the overthrow of King <ent type='PERSON'>Charles</ent>.
1649 -- King <ent type='PERSON'>Charles</ent> convicted and beheaded by <ent type='ORG'>Parliament</ent>.
1654 -- Illuminated Guerinets come to public notice in <ent type='GPE'>France</ent>.
1667 -- Milton's "Paradise Lost" published.
1675 -- <ent type='GPE'>Leeuwenhoek</ent> discovers "animalcules" through the
microscope.
1676 -- Sperm discovered by Leeuwenhoek's student Ham.
1680 -- Madame Le Voisin, innovator of modern Satanism, executed
in <ent type='GPE'>Paris</ent>.
1682 -- Tamanend, sachem and chief of the <ent type='ORG'>Lenni</ent>-<ent type='NORP'>Lenape</ent> tribe,
welcomes <ent type='PERSON'>William</ent> Penn to <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>, traditionally considered the
beginning of the Tammany Society.
1689 -- <ent type='PERSON'>William</ent> III of <ent type='NORP'>Orange</ent> becomes king of <ent type='GPE'>England</ent>, allegedly
through the plotting of the <ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent>.
1694 -- <ent type='ORG'>Bank</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>England</ent> founded.
1700 -- Quietism of Fenelon and others.
1701 -- Earliest record of "operative" or professional <ent type='NORP'>Masonic</ent>
Lodge in <ent type='GPE'>Alnwick</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>England</ent>.
1702 -- First daily newspaper in <ent type='GPE'>England</ent>.
1717 -- Founding of modern <ent type='NORP'>Freemasonry</ent> with <ent type='ORG'>the Grand Lodge</ent> of
<ent type='GPE'>London</ent> by <ent type='NORP'>Desaguliers</ent>. Voltaire imprisoned in the <ent type='GPE'>Bastille</ent>.
1721 -- <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> King George I cracks down on the flourishing Hell
Fire Clubs, popular <ent type='ORG'>Satanistic</ent> cults.
1723 -- Anderson's "Constitutions of the <ent type='NORP'>Freemasons</ent>" published.
"<ent type='PERSON'>Ebrietatis Enconium</ent>" and other early anti-<ent type='NORP'>Masonic</ent> works
published.
1724 -- Publication of the anti-<ent type='NORP'>Masonic</ent> "Grand Mysteries of the
<ent type='NORP'>Freemasons</ent> Discovered."
1731 -- <ent type='PERSON'><ent type='ORG'>Benjamin</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Franklin</ent></ent> initiated into <ent type='NORP'>Freemasonry</ent>.
1734 -- <ent type='ORG'>Franklin</ent> elected Grand Master of <ent type='GPE'>Pennsylvania</ent>.
1736 -- Death of the last leader of the <ent type='NORP'>Afghan</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Illuminated Ones</ent>.
1749 -- Rousseau's spontaneous "enlightenment" launches the
<ent type='NORP'>Roman</ent>tic Movement.
1750 -- Hell Fire Clubs continue to flourish in <ent type='GPE'>Dublin</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>London</ent>.
Fictional alchemist <ent type='PERSON'>Joseph Curwen</ent> writes letter stating "I laste
<ent type='NORP'>Nighte</ent> strucke on ye Wordes that bringe up <ent type='ORG'>Yooge</ent>-Sothothe,"
perhaps the real power behind the <ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent>.
1754 -- Six year old <ent type='PERSON'>Adam Weishaupt</ent> is orphaned and goes to live
with the Jesuits.
1757 -- First year of Swedenborg's "New Era."
1759 -- Voltaire's "Candide" published.
1760 -- St. Germain founds chemical dye factory in <ent type='GPE'>Holland</ent>, fore-runner of I.G. <ent type='ORG'>Farben</ent>; disappears with 100000 guilders. <ent type='ORG'>Franklin</ent>
invents bifocals.
1761 -- St. Germain discovered living in <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>. <ent type='NORP'>Chinese</ent> Emperor
issues edict against secret societies.
1762 -- <ent type='ORG'>Illumines</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>France</ent> founded. Sandwich invented.
1763 -- Swedenborg's "Doctrine of Life for the New <ent type='GPE'>Jerusalem</ent>"
published.
1764 -- Voltaire's "Philosophical Dictionary" published; he begins
a prodigious attack on dogmas of church and state.
1765 -- <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> Stamp Act imposed to help pay for the <ent type='NORP'>French</ent> and
<ent type='NORP'>Indian</ent> War debt. Sons of Liberty clubs formed to resist the tax.
1767 -- Townshend Revenue Act, another <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> tax on the
colonies. <ent type='GPE'>Kunta Kinte</ent> kidnapped into <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n slavery.
1768 -- Virginia's legislature dissolved for its opposition to the
Townshend Act. <ent type='PERSON'>Weishaupt</ent> graduates from <ent type='ORG'>the University</ent> of
Ingolstadt, becomes tutor and catechist. Macfarguhar, Ball and
<ent type='NORP'>Smelie</ent> begin compiling the "Encyclopaedia Britannica." Mesmer
commissions 12 year old Mozart's first opera, "<ent type='PERSON'>Bastien</ent> and
<ent type='PERSON'>Bastien</ent>ne."
1770 -- <ent type='GPE'>Boston</ent> Massacre: <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> troops fire into a crowd.
Townshend Act repealed.
1771 -- "Encyclopaedia Britannica" published.
1772 -- <ent type='PERSON'>Weishaupt</ent> becomes professor at University of Ingolstadt.
1773 -- <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> Tea Tax on colonies. <ent type='GPE'>Boston</ent> Tea Party in protest.
<ent type='PERSON'>Weishaupt</ent> marries. <ent type='ORG'>Alleged</ent> meeting of <ent type='PERSON'>Meyer Rothschild</ent> and others
to plan a world revolution. Suppression of the Jesuits.
Franklin's "Rule by Which a <ent type='GPE'>Great Empire</ent> May Be Reduced to a Small
One" published.
1774 -- Britain's "Intolerable Acts" designed to punish rebellious
colonies. <ent type='ORG'>First Continental Congress</ent>. <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent> begins training
troops. <ent type='PERSON'>Louis XVI</ent> becomes king of <ent type='GPE'>France</ent>. <ent type='ORG'>Casanova</ent> becomes
secret agent for the Inquisitors of <ent type='GPE'>Venice</ent>. Catherine II shuts
down satiric journals in <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>. Jefferson's "Summary View of the
Rights of <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>ns" published.
1775 -- <ent type='ORG'>Second Continental Congress</ent> authorizes naval warships,
sets up secret committee to procure weapons, names <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>
commander-in-chief of the new <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n Army. <ent type='PERSON'>George III</ent> proclaims
<ent type='GPE'>America</ent> in open rebellion. Initial battles of the Revolutionary
War: Lexington, Bunker Hill, Toconderoga. Bushnell's first
experimental submarine and torpedo tested. Prince Hall lodges
(for blacks) chartered by <ent type='ORG'>Grand Lodge</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>London</ent>, rejected by
<ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n lodges.
1776 -- <ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent> founded by <ent type='PERSON'>Weishaupt</ent>. <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n Declaration of
Independence, written by <ent type='GPE'>Jefferson</ent>, adopted by Continental
<ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>. Battles of <ent type='GPE'>Long Island</ent>, <ent type='LOC'>White Plains</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Trenton</ent>.
<ent type='PERSON'>Nathan Hale</ent> executed as spy by <ent type='NORP'>British</ent>. <ent type='ORG'>Franklin</ent> becomes
ambassador to <ent type='GPE'>France</ent>, is affiliated with <ent type='NORP'>French</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Masonic</ent> lodges.
Opening of <ent type='NORP'>Freemasons</ent>' Hall, permanent headquarters of English
Masonry. <ent type='PERSON'>Cagliostro</ent> initiated into Masonry. <ent type='GPE'>Saigon</ent> captured by
<ent type='PERSON'>Tay Son</ent> brothers. <ent type='PERSON'>Aaron Burr</ent> serves as assistant to Benedict
Arnold. <ent type='PERSON'>Thomas Paine</ent>'s "Common Sense" and "The Crisis" widely
read. <ent type='PERSON'>Adam Smith</ent>'s "Wealth of Nations" published.
1777 -- <ent type='PERSON'>Weishaupt</ent> joins <ent type='ORG'>Munich Lodge</ent> of the Order of Good Council.
Articles of Confederation adopted by <ent type='ORG'>Continental Congress</ent>.
Battles of <ent type='GPE'>Bennington</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Brandywine</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Germantown</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Princeton</ent> and
<ent type='GPE'>Saratoga</ent>. <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent> has his mystical vision of the future of the
United States while at Valley Forge. War of <ent type='NORP'>Bavarian</ent> Secession
begins.
1778 -- <ent type='GPE'>France</ent> recognizes <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n independence, signs treaty and
provides aid. <ent type='ORG'>Franklin</ent> assists in initiation of Voltaire into
<ent type='NORP'>Masonic</ent> Lodge of <ent type='GPE'>Paris</ent>. <ent type='NORP'>Masonic</ent> Convention in <ent type='PERSON'>Lyons</ent> organizes
Knights of Benficience.
1779 -- <ent type='PERSON'>John Paul Jones</ent> says "Damn the torpedos!" Benedict Arnold
becomes a traitor and spy for the <ent type='NORP'>British</ent>. War of <ent type='NORP'>Bavarian</ent>
Secession ends.
1780 -- <ent type='PERSON'>John Andre</ent>, <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> agent, captured with secret documents
from Arnold; Arnold escapes to join <ent type='NORP'>British</ent>; Andre hanged as spy.
Weishaupt's wife dies. <ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent> begins rapid growth. First use
of the title Odd Fellows. Order of the Brotherhood of <ent type='LOC'>Asia</ent>,
Rosicrucian off-shoot, founded.
1781 -- Battle of <ent type='ORG'>Guilford Court</ent> <ent type='ORG'>House</ent>, surrended of <ent type='GPE'>Cornwallis</ent> at
<ent type='GPE'>Yorktown</ent>. <ent type='PERSON'>John Hanson</ent> becomes first President of <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent>
States in <ent type='ORG'>Congress Assembled</ent>. <ent type='PERSON'>Weishaupt</ent> seeks abortion for his
sister-in-law while awaiting dispensation to marry her. United
<ent type='NORP'>Masonic</ent> Lodges of Hamburg headed by <ent type='ORG'>Fraximus</ent>, a secret
Rosicrucian. Kant's "Critique of Pure Reason" published.
1782 -- <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> cabinet agrees to recognize <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n independence,
preliminary agreement signed in <ent type='GPE'>Paris</ent>. <ent type='ORG'>Hanson</ent> commissions the
"Eye in the Pyramid" Great Seal, finishes term; Elias Boudinot
elected second President of <ent type='ORG'>Congress Assembled</ent>. <ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent>
dominate European Masonry. <ent type='ORG'>Casanova</ent> retires as secret agent.
1783 -- <ent type='ORG'>Treaty</ent> signed between <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>England</ent>. <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>
disbands army, resigns. <ent type='ORG'>Hanson</ent> dies. <ent type='PERSON'>Thomas Mifflin</ent> third
President of <ent type='ORG'>Congress Assembled</ent>. Ex-<ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent> Utschneider sends
letter denouncing the Order to monarch of <ent type='GPE'>Bavaria</ent>. Rite of
<ent type='ORG'>Swedenborg</ent> founded by Marquis de Throne. Eclectic Rite founded by
Baron <ent type='PERSON'>Knigge</ent> in <ent type='GPE'>Frankfort</ent>. Webster's "<ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n Spelling Book"
published.
1784 -- <ent type='ORG'>Treaty</ent> with <ent type='GPE'>England</ent> ratified by <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>. Richard Henry
Lee fourth President of <ent type='ORG'>Congress Assembled</ent>. <ent type='NORP'>Bavarian</ent> Monarch Carl
Theodore outlaws secret societies. <ent type='PERSON'>Cagliostro</ent> moves to <ent type='PERSON'>Lyons</ent> from
<ent type='GPE'>Bordeaux</ent> to found <ent type='ORG'>the Mother Lodge</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>Egypt</ent>ian Masonry. Royal
Commission in <ent type='GPE'>Paris</ent>, including <ent type='ORG'>Franklin</ent> and Guillotine as members,
investigates Mesmerism and returns a negative report.
1785 -- <ent type='PERSON'>Weishaupt</ent> flees to <ent type='ORG'>Gotha</ent>; new edict outlaws <ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent>;
High-ranking <ent type='PERSON'>Illuminatus Lanz</ent> killed by lightning and <ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent>
papers found on body by police. <ent type='NORP'>French</ent> "<ent type='PERSON'>Diamond</ent> Necklace" affair.
<ent type='GPE'>Napoleon</ent> graduates military school. <ent type='ORG'>Franklin</ent> returns to <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>;
<ent type='GPE'>Jefferson</ent> becomes <ent type='NORP'>French</ent> ambassador. Rosicrucian Order suppressed
in <ent type='GPE'>Austria</ent>. Anonymous pamphlet appears in <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> revealing
secrets of ancient <ent type='GPE'>Egypt</ent>ian ceremonies.
1786 -- <ent type='ORG'>Wisdom Lodge</ent> founded in <ent type='GPE'>Virginia</ent>. Secret congress in
<ent type='GPE'>Frankfort</ent> where <ent type='PERSON'>Louis XVI</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Gustavus III</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>Sweden</ent> condemned to
die by <ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent>. <ent type='NORP'>Italian</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Illuminatus Buonarroti</ent>'s library of
<ent type='NORP'>Masonic</ent> and subversive books confiscated by state authorities.
<ent type='PERSON'>Nathaniel Gorham</ent> fifth President of <ent type='ORG'>Congress Assembled</ent>. <ent type='GPE'>Napoleon</ent>
writes pamphlete defending <ent type='PERSON'>Rousseau</ent>.
1787 -- <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> authorities publish letter by <ent type='PERSON'>Weishaupt</ent> admitting
he sought abortion for his sister-in-law; <ent type='PERSON'>Weishaupt</ent> replies,
blaming "extenuating circumstances." <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> Union (extension of
outlawed <ent type='NORP'>Bavarian</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent>) founded by <ent type='GPE'>Bahrdt</ent>. <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>
elected President of Constitutional Convention in <ent type='GPE'>Philadelphia</ent>;
new constitution adopted by the convention. Arthur St. Clair
sixth President of <ent type='ORG'>Congress Assembled</ent>. <ent type='GPE'>Jefferson</ent> meets secretly
in <ent type='GPE'>Paris</ent> with <ent type='NORP'>Brazilian</ent> rebel to discuss <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n aid to
revolution in <ent type='GPE'>Brazil</ent>. Shay's Rebellion in <ent type='GPE'>Massachusetts</ent> to
protest unfair taxes. Goethe visits Cagliostro's family in
<ent type='GPE'>Palermo</ent>. <ent type='ORG'>Swedenborg</ent>ian Church founded in <ent type='GPE'>London</ent>. Society for the
Abolition of the <ent type='NORP'>African</ent> Slave-Trade founded in <ent type='GPE'>London</ent>.
1788 -- <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n Constitution ratified by the states. Individual
<ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n states begin to outlaw slavery. <ent type='PERSON'>Cyrus Griffen</ent> seventh
President of <ent type='ORG'>Congress Assembled</ent>. <ent type='PERSON'>Paine</ent> visits <ent type='GPE'>London</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Paris</ent>.
"The <ent type='NORP'>Federalist</ent>" essays published by <ent type='PERSON'>Hamilton</ent>, Madison and Jay.
1789 -- <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent> elected President of <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States; first
<ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent> under new Constitution. <ent type='GPE'>Jefferson</ent> returns to U.S. to
become first Secretary of State; <ent type='PERSON'>Hamilton</ent> becomes first Secretary
of the <ent type='ORG'>Treasury</ent>. <ent type='NORP'>French</ent> Revolution begins.
1790 -- Rebellion and massacre throughout <ent type='GPE'>France</ent>. <ent type='PERSON'>Cagliostro</ent>
arrested by Inquisition of <ent type='GPE'>Rome</ent>. <ent type='NORP'>Bavarian</ent> edict against Reading
Societies. Blake's "Marriage of Heaven and Hell" published.
1791 -- <ent type='GPE'>Napoleon</ent> joins the <ent type='ORG'>Jocobin Club</ent>. <ent type='ORG'>First Bank</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent>
States chartered. <ent type='ORG'>Burr</ent> begins converting Tammany Society into a
political machine. The anonymous "Vie de <ent type='PERSON'>Joseph Balsamo</ent>" (Joseph
Basalmo was Cagliostro's name before he joined the <ent type='ORG'>Masons</ent>), first
recorded link of the <ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent> and the <ent type='NORP'>French</ent> Revolution, appears
in several European countries. Mozart's "The Magic Flute,"
containing <ent type='NORP'>Masonic</ent> elements, performed.
1792 -- <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent> re-elected. War between <ent type='GPE'>France</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Austria</ent>.
<ent type='PERSON'>Louis XVI</ent> imprisoned in the Templars Temple tower. Massacres of
September, in which priests, bishops and others are killed.
Elections for the National Convention, a triumph for <ent type='PERSON'>Robespierre</ent>
and his followers. <ent type='GPE'>France</ent> declared a Republic. First
<ent type='ORG'>Swedenborg</ent>ian church in <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>. Catherine II outlaws Masonry in
<ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>. "Life of <ent type='PERSON'>Joseph Balsamo</ent>" translated into English in
<ent type='GPE'>Dublin</ent>. Assassination of Gustav III at the Stockholm opera.
1793 -- <ent type='EVENT'>Year One</ent> of the <ent type='NORP'>French</ent> Republic; the year of the Terror,
<ent type='PERSON'>Louis XVI</ent> found guilty of conspiracy, condemned to be executed.
<ent type='NORP'>French</ent> government kills thousands of its citizens. <ent type='GPE'>France</ent>
declares war on <ent type='GPE'>England</ent> and the <ent type='NORP'>Dutch</ent> United Provinces; war breaks
out with <ent type='GPE'>Spain</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Austria</ent>; <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Prussia</ent> begin partition of
<ent type='GPE'>Poland</ent>. <ent type='NORP'>French</ent> food riots.
1794 -- Year Two; <ent type='GPE'>France</ent> passes laws distributing confiscated
property to the poor, leads victorious battle against <ent type='GPE'>Austria</ent>ns.
Would-be assassin of <ent type='PERSON'>Robespierre</ent> fires on Collot d'Herbois
instead; the next day a young girl arrested as suspected assassin;
she and 40 others sent to guillotine. Other attempts of
Robespierre's life; his enemies accuse him of attempting to have
himself declared divine by <ent type='PERSON'>Catherine Theot</ent>, an old woman who
preached a mystery religion; <ent type='PERSON'>Robespierre</ent> guillotined. <ent type='PERSON'>Monroe</ent>
becomes minister to <ent type='GPE'>France</ent>. Whiskey rebellion in <ent type='GPE'>Pennsylvania</ent> to
protest liquor taxes.
1795 -- <ent type='GPE'>France</ent> makes peace with <ent type='GPE'>Prussia</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Spain</ent>, invades
<ent type='GPE'>Holland</ent>. <ent type='GPE'>Napoleon</ent> suppresses revolt in <ent type='GPE'>Paris</ent> and goes to <ent type='GPE'>Italy</ent> as
Commander-in-Chief. Yazoo land fraud: bribed <ent type='GPE'>Georgia</ent> legislators
sell Mississippi.
1796 -- Adams elected President. <ent type='PERSON'>Paine</ent> publishes letter critical
of <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>.
1798 -- <ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent> scare in New <ent type='GPE'>England</ent>. Knights of <ent type='GPE'>Malta</ent> lose
their island to <ent type='GPE'>Napoleon</ent>.
1800 -- Death of <ent type='PERSON'>Thomas Waley</ent>, one of the last Hell Fire Club
leaders. <ent type='GPE'>Napoleon</ent> comes to power, allegedly through <ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent>
manipulation.
1805 to 1881 -- Life of <ent type='PERSON'>Auguste Blanqui</ent>, <ent type='NORP'>French</ent> socialist, founder
of numerous secret societies modeled after <ent type='PERSON'>Buonarroti</ent>.
1815 -- Napoleon's Waterloo. Secret societies which eventually
become <ent type='ORG'>the Decembrist Movement</ent> formed in <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>n <ent type='NORP'>Masonic</ent> lodges.
1817 -- Suppression of the Lodge of Jupiter the Thunderer begins.
<ent type='NORP'>Irish</ent> immigrants force entry into Tammany Society, changing its
direction.
1818 -- Mar Shelley's "<ent type='PERSON'>Frankenstein</ent>" published.
1819 -- <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n Independent Order of Odd Fellows founded.
Founding of National <ent type='NORP'>Freemasonry</ent>, the most important of several
<ent type='NORP'>Polish</ent> secret societies devoted to ousting the <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>ns from
<ent type='GPE'>Poland</ent>. Liberation of <ent type='GPE'>Columbia</ent> by <ent type='GPE'>Bolivar</ent>.
1822 -- <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>n government suppresses Masonry. Equador liberated
by <ent type='GPE'>Bolivar</ent>.
1825 -- <ent type='GPE'>Decembrist</ent> movement suppressed in <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent> after brief
uprising. <ent type='GPE'>Bolivar</ent> liberates <ent type='GPE'>Bolivia</ent>. Founding of <ent type='GPE'>Vienna</ent> bank by
<ent type='PERSON'>Solmon Rothschild</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Naples</ent> bank by Carl <ent type='PERSON'>Rothschild</ent>.
1828 -- Tammany Society backs <ent type='PERSON'>Andrew Jackson</ent> for President. Anti-<ent type='NORP'>Masonic</ent> Party founded, first third-party in <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>. Attempted
assassination of <ent type='GPE'>Bolivar</ent>.
1829 -- <ent type='ORG'>Alleged</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent> meeting in <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent> decides to unite
<ent type='NORP'>Atheists</ent> and <ent type='NORP'>Nihilists</ent> into <ent type='NORP'>Communist</ent> movement.
1830 -- Anti-<ent type='NORP'>Masonic</ent> conventions in <ent type='GPE'>Massachusetts</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Vermont</ent> find
evidence linking Masonry with Illuminism. Book of <ent type='NORP'>Mormon</ent>
published. <ent type='PERSON'>Weishaupt</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Bolivar</ent> die.
1831 -- Anti-<ent type='NORP'>Masonic</ent> Party runs <ent type='PERSON'>Wirt</ent> for President, assuring that
Mason <ent type='PERSON'>Andrew Jackson</ent> would be re-elected. <ent type='PERSON'>Poe</ent> dismissed from West
Point.
1833 -- <ent type='PERSON'>Jackson</ent> orders U.S. funds withdrawn from <ent type='ORG'>Bank</ent> of the
United States, effectively killing the institution.
1835 -- The socialist League of the Just founded in <ent type='GPE'>Paris</ent>, later
becoming the Marxist <ent type='NORP'>Communist</ent> League. Attempted assassination of
<ent type='PERSON'>Jackson</ent> with two single shot pistols, both of which jammed.
<ent type='ORG'>Revolver</ent> invented.
1844 -- <ent type='PERSON'>Morse</ent> builds first practical telegraph. <ent type='ORG'>Bahai</ent> religion
begins when the Bab proclaims his mission in <ent type='GPE'>Persia</ent>.
1848 -- Fall of monarchy in <ent type='GPE'>France</ent>. Republic established in <ent type='GPE'>Rome</ent>.
Abdication of Ferdinand I in <ent type='GPE'>Austria</ent>. Revolts in <ent type='GPE'>Denmark</ent>,
<ent type='GPE'>Ireland</ent>, Lombardy, Schleswig-Holstein and <ent type='GPE'>Venice</ent>. <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> briefly
united in a parliament at <ent type='GPE'>Frankfort</ent>; unity destroyed by <ent type='PERSON'>the King</ent>
of <ent type='GPE'>Prussia</ent>. Marx and <ent type='GPE'>Engles</ent> publish the "<ent type='NORP'>Communist</ent> Manifesto"
(allegedly commissioned by the <ent type='ORG'>Illuminati</ent>) and travel in <ent type='GPE'>France</ent>
and <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> encouraging discontent with the Establishment.
Woman's Suffrage Movement gets underway in Seneca Falls, <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent>.
Spiritualism born in <ent type='GPE'>Wayne County</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent>, when the teenaged <ent type='ORG'>Fox</ent>
sisters communicate with poltergeists. Fortean tidbits: moon
turns "blood-red" during total eclipse; a great comet fails to
return at the time predicted; visions and "phantom soldiers" seen
in the skies of <ent type='GPE'>France</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Scotland</ent>; Captain M'Quahae of H.M.S.
Daedalus reports seeing a "huge, unknown creature" in the ocean.
Gold discovered in <ent type='GPE'>California</ent>.
1849 to 1936 -- Life of Sir <ent type='GPE'>Basil</ent> Zaharoff, "mystery man of
Europe," who made a fortune as an armaments dealer and financier,
selling weapons to both sides in <ent type='EVENT'>World War</ent> I and other conflicts.
1852 -- <ent type='ORG'>Benjamin</ent> becomes first professed <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent> elected to <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>.
1859 -- Oil wells invented. Darwin's "Origin of Species"
published.
1860 -- <ent type='ORG'>Lincoln</ent> elected. <ent type='ORG'>Electric</ent> storage battery invented.
1860s -- Attempts to suppress the <ent type='ORG'>Mafia</ent> in <ent type='GPE'>Sicily</ent> are
unsuccessful.
1861 -- Confederate states secede; elect <ent type='GPE'>Jefferson</ent> Davis
president; <ent type='ORG'>Benjamin</ent> appointed Confederate Attorney General, later
Secretary of War. <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n <ent type='EVENT'>Civil War</ent> begins. Emancipation of
serfs in <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>. <ent type='PERSON'>Jacolliot</ent> writes about the Nine Unknown in
<ent type='LOC'>Calcutta</ent>. Gatling gun patented.
1862 -- <ent type='ORG'>Benjamin</ent> appointed Confederate Secretary of State.
1863 -- Rockfeller builds his first refinery.
1865 -- Assassination of <ent type='ORG'>Lincoln</ent>; <ent type='PERSON'>Andrew Johnson</ent> becomes
president; "<ent type='PERSON'>Booth</ent>" killed; coded message found among his effects;
the code key later found in possession of <ent type='ORG'>Benjamin</ent>, alleged
<ent type='PERSON'>Rothschild</ent> agent. <ent type='EVENT'>Civil War</ent> ends. Thirteenth amendment abolishes
slavery.
1866 -- Ku <ent type='ORG'>Klux Klan</ent> founded as a social club in <ent type='GPE'>Pulaski</ent>,
<ent type='GPE'>Tennessee</ent>. <ent type='ORG'>Benjamin</ent> flees to <ent type='GPE'>England</ent>. Death of Phineas Quimby,
magnetic healer, founder of Free Thought movement, teacher of Mary
Baker Eddy.
1867 -- Ku <ent type='ORG'>Klux Klan</ent> reorganized along political and racial lines
near <ent type='GPE'>Nashville</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Tennessee</ent>.
1868 -- Assassination of Thomas D'Arcy McGee, first Canadian
political assassination.
1869 -- St. Germain allegedly completes 85 years in the <ent type='LOC'>Himalayas</ent>
after his "death." <ent type='PERSON'>Mendeleev</ent> composes first periodic table of the
elements in <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>. U.S. transcontinental railroad completed.
1870 -- <ent type='ORG'>Standard Oil Company</ent> incorporated.
1875 -- "Whiskey Ring" conspiracy of distillery owners revealed.
Madam <ent type='PERSON'>Blavatsky</ent> founds <ent type='ORG'>Theosophy Society</ent>. <ent type='PERSON'>Mary Baker Eddy</ent>'s
"<ent type='ORG'>Science and Health</ent>" published.
1875 to 1947 -- Life of <ent type='PERSON'>Aleister Crowley</ent>, the Great Beast, Golden
Dawn leader and occult figure.
1876 -- <ent type='PERSON'>Disraeli</ent> again warns about dangers of secret societies.
Battle of the Little Big Horn. <ent type='ORG'>Bell</ent> patents telephone. <ent type='PERSON'>Otto</ent>
builds four-cycle gasoline engine.
1877 -- First of seven wills in which Cecil <ent type='ORG'>Rhodes</ent> leaves his
money to establish a secret society to expand <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> rule
throughout the world.
1878 to 1945 -- Life of <ent type='PERSON'>Edgar Cayce</ent>, visionary, trance-channeler
who spoke of reincarnation, <ent type='GPE'>Egypt</ent>ian mysteries, and Atlantis.
1881 -- <ent type='PERSON'>Garfield</ent> assassinated. Czar Alexander II assassinated by
secret society. <ent type='PERSON'>Disraeli</ent> publishes "Lothair," a novel about
secret societies and European politics.
1884 -- <ent type='ORG'>Fabian Society</ent> founded in <ent type='GPE'>London</ent> by <ent type='PERSON'>Sidney</ent> and Beatrice
Webb and others.
1885 -- First practical horseless carriage built by Daimler.
1887 -- <ent type='LOC'>Golden Dawn</ent> founded in <ent type='GPE'>London</ent> by <ent type='PERSON'>Mathers</ent> and others.
Mitchelson-Morley experiement disproving ether theory.
1888 -- Unsolved murders of <ent type='GPE'>London</ent> prostitutes by "Jack the
Ripper," suspected of being one of those implicated in the
Cleveland Street Affair involving high-society <ent type='NORP'>Victorians</ent> and
their patronage of a brothel staffed by messenger boys.
1889 -- Second <ent type='NORP'>Communist</ent> International organized.
1890 -- Biologist <ent type='PERSON'>Yersin</ent> visits India, purportedly to recieve
plague and cholera serum from the Nine Unknown. Wounded Knee
massacre.
1891 -- <ent type='ORG'>Rhodes</ent> gains control of 90% of world's diamond supply.
The Round Tables, a secret society allegedly funded by <ent type='ORG'>Rhodes</ent> and
the <ent type='PERSON'>Rothschild</ent>s to gain financial and political power, founded in
the U.S., <ent type='GPE'>Canada</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Australia</ent>, India, <ent type='GPE'>South Africa</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>New Zealand</ent>.
<ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> grant founds University of Chicago. Nikola <ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent>
invents <ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent> coil, becomes U.S. citizen.
1892 -- <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> trust transferred to holding company: Standard
Oil of <ent type='GPE'>New Jersey</ent>.
1893 -- Assassination of Chicago Mayor Harrison.
1894 -- Assassination of President <ent type='PERSON'>Carnot</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>France</ent>.
1896 -- Maconi's patent No. 7777 for radio. First "flap year" for
<ent type='EVENT'>UFOs</ent>: wave of sightings of unidentified airships in U.S.
1897 -- Assassination of Premier <ent type='PERSON'>Canovas</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>Spain</ent>. <ent type='NORP'>Zionism</ent>
founded in <ent type='GPE'>Basil</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Switzerland</ent> by Theodore Herzl.
1898 -- Assassination of Empress <ent type='PERSON'>Elizabeth</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>Austria</ent>. Pavlov
begins study of conditioned reflex in dogs.
1899 -- <ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent> discovers terrestrial stationary waves which can
produce electricity; reports receiving signals from another
planet. <ent type='ORG'>Alleged</ent> meeting in <ent type='GPE'>England</ent> at which the Morgans,
<ent type='PERSON'>Rothschild</ent>s and <ent type='PERSON'>Warburgs</ent> become affiliated.
1900 -- Assassination of King Umberto I of <ent type='GPE'>Italy</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Kentucky</ent>
Governor-elect <ent type='PERSON'>William</ent> Goebel. <ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent> suggests alien beings might
be living "in the very midst of us." <ent type='ORG'>Boxer</ent> rebellion in <ent type='GPE'>China</ent>.
Approximate date <ent type='PERSON'>Adolf Lanz</ent> founded the Order of New Templars, a
fore-runner of the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> mentality.
1901 -- Assassination of McKinley and <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>n Education Minister
<ent type='GPE'>Bogolepov</ent>. <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> Institute for Medical Research
(<ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> University) founded in <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent>. First trans-<ent type='LOC'>Atlantic</ent> radio broadcast: <ent type='PERSON'>Marconi</ent> sends the letter S.
1902 -- Assassination of <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>n Minister of Interior Sipyagain.
Paul and <ent type='PERSON'>Felix Warburg</ent> immigrate from <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> to the U.S.
<ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> General Education Board founded.
1903 -- Assassination of Bogdanovich, Governor of <ent type='GPE'>Ufa</ent>. "Protocols
of Elders of Zion," alleged plan for <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ish world takeover,
published in <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>n newspaper.
1904 -- Assassination of <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>n Premier Vischelev von Plehev.
1905 -- Assassination of Grand Duke <ent type='PERSON'>Sergius</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Idaho</ent> Governor
<ent type='PERSON'>Steunenberg</ent>. Abortive revolution in <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>. Expanded version of
"Protocols of Zion" published.
1906 -- Assassination of <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>n General Dubrassov.
1907 -- Financial panic and depression allegedly caused by J.P.
Morgan to gain support for the central bank concept.
1908 -- Assassination of King Carl of <ent type='GPE'>Prussia</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Crown Prince</ent> of
<ent type='GPE'>Portugal</ent>. <ent type='ORG'>FBI</ent> founded. Founding of the Armanen Initiates, another
<ent type='ORG'>proro</ent>-<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> secret society.
1910 -- Attempted assassination of Mayor <ent type='PERSON'>Gaynor</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>NYC</ent>. Secret
meeting of bankers and politicians at <ent type='GPE'>Jekyll Island</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Georgia</ent>,
results in Federal Reserve Act.
1911 -- Assassination of Prime Minister <ent type='PERSON'>Staliapin</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent> by
police double agent. <ent type='ORG'>Standard Oil</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>New Jersey</ent> broken up as
illegal monopoly.
1912 -- Assassination of <ent type='PERSON'>Primier Canalegas</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>Spain</ent>. Attempted
assassination of <ent type='PERSON'>Teddy Roosevelt</ent>. Colonel E.M. <ent type='ORG'>House</ent>, adviser to
<ent type='PERSON'>Woodrow Wilson</ent>, publishes "<ent type='PERSON'>Philip Dru</ent>: Administrator," a political
romance which proposed modern social legislation. Founding of
<ent type='NORP'>German</ent>en Order, another pre-<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> secret society.
1913 -- Assassination of George I of <ent type='GPE'>Greece</ent>. <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent>
Foundation founded.
1914 -- Attempted assassination of Archduke Ferdinand of <ent type='GPE'>Austria</ent>
by <ent type='NORP'>Masonic</ent> agents, followed an hour later by successful
assassination; in <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Rasputin</ent> stabbed the same day. <ent type='EVENT'>World War</ent>
I begins.
1915 -- Sinking of the Lusitania by <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> submarine; allegedly
carrying secret munitions for the <ent type='ORG'>Allies</ent>, the ship supposedly
sacrificed by <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n authorities to drum up war
hysteria in U.S. <ent type='PERSON'>Alfred Wegener</ent> proposed theory of continental
drift, receives ridicule and contempt from his fellow scientists.
Ku <ent type='ORG'>Klux Klan</ent> revived.
1916 -- Assassination of <ent type='PERSON'>Rasputin</ent>.</p>

<p>From "The <ent type='ORG'>Illuminoid</ent>s" c. <ent type='PERSON'>Neil Wilgus</ent> &amp; various sources</p>

</xml>