<xml>

<p>Comments Concerning <ent type='ORG'>the Philadelphia</ent> Experiment</p>

<p>As I told the good DOCTOR long ago, <ent type='ORG'>the PHILADELPHIA EXPERIMENT</ent> was
a SUCCESFUL TEST of EINSTEIN'S unified FIELD equations. All matter and energy
are all manifestations of a COSMOLOGICAL influence mediated through the
<ent type='ORG'>MULTIPLEX</ent> SCALAR field. EINSTEIN wrote about his equations in 1932, BUT
he renounced his work because HE was AFRAID of the CONSEQUENCES that this
knowledge WOULD have on mankind. Do you know that the ATOMIC BOMB is a lie
that has been told to the public to keep us from knowing the TRUTH? The REAL
weapon is a multiplexed spatial howitzer that opens a SPACE-<ent type='ORG'>TIME</ent> gateway
between the core of the SUN and AS MANY AS 512 (in newer models) TARGET
points, causing COMPLETE DEVESTATION. Nuclear detonation was proved
impossible by N. TESLA in 1915; Nuclear POWER is a LIE, a retrograde form
of ENERGY caused by the accelerated NATURAL DECAY of matter. The real
principle of the <ent type='ORG'>MANHATTAN</ent> DEVICE (Named because it is buried underneath
the EMPIRE STATE BUILDING) designed by <ent type='PERSON'>ALBERT</ent> einstein which destroyed the
<ent type='GPE'>CITY</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>hiroshima</ent> would lead to unlimited 'free' energy -- Which could be
tapped off any hyperspatial TANGENT line, derived from the CONSTANT PROCESS
OF CREATION OF MATTER in the interstellar medium.</p>

<p>My <ent type='GPE'>COLLEGUE</ent> Dr. JOHN <ent type='ORG'>LEVINSON</ent> developed HIS solutions of the UNIFIED
FIELD EQUATIONS in 1939. As such, ROTATING MAGNETIC FIELDS can create a
local STREAMING of the space-time <ent type='GPE'>CONTINUM</ent>, which was tested in a secret
series of experiments done underneath the BERMUDA TRIANGLE in 1940. The
OTHER end of the TEMPORAL VORTEX that we created has SKIPPED in time from
1903 and will continue to do so until 2011. It TOSSED five <ent type='ORG'>AMERICAN BOMBERS</ent>,
killing the crew from the effects of <ent type='ORG'>TIME</ent> SHEAR forward in time from 1945 to
1989, when one was DISCOVERED underneath the <ent type='ORG'>OCEAN</ent>. Another was FOUND ON
THE MOON by <ent type='ORG'>apollo</ent> astronauts. The <ent type='PERSON'>Levinson</ent> <ent type='ORG'>TIME</ent> equations can be transformed
using the method invented by myself and DR. TOWNSEND BROWN to a set of SPACE
equations which allow for instanteous translation of MATTER through SPACE.
(<ent type='PERSON'>Gene Rodenberry</ent> DESIGNED the <ent type='ORG'>TRANSPORTER</ent> for the syndicated program STAR
<ent type='ORG'>TREK</ent> in order to PREPARE the public for the concept of INSTANTEOUS
TELEPORTATION that was first successfully tested on AN american <ent type='ORG'>DESTROYER</ent>
called the ELDRIDGE. More on that later) ALSO, using the result of EMILY
<ent type='PERSON'>NOETHER</ent>, instanteous translation is EQUIVALENT to reactionless propulsion;
which unfortunately creates a <ent type='ORG'>PROTATIONAL</ent> FIELD that KILLS humans. LIVING
matter cannot be carried on SUCH a <ent type='ORG'>VESSEL</ent>. AFTER too many DEATHS, we
decided to GIVE UP our CAMPAIGN of <ent type='EVENT'>UFO</ent> MOVIES and <ent type='EVENT'>UFO</ent> FLYOVERS when the
SOVIET UNION realized that we had solved and applied BROWNS space equations.
And when THIS technology was FOUND impossible to adapt for transportation
of LIVING MATTER. HOWEVER, <ent type='ORG'>TIME</ent> SHEAR effects can be REDUCED in the CASE
of INSTANTEOUS transport. HENCE, this technology is REAL. Buy shares in
the company TELEPAD that will be offered two months FROM NOW. THEY WILL
introduce a PRACTICAL transporter that the POLICE will be able to USE to
ARREST people anywhere in the world. IN <ent type='ORG'>TEN</ent> YEARS, this will become
availible to YOU from the PHONE COMPANY as a service that by dialing
*647351845###646412* will INSTANTLY transport any HARRASSING caller to
your <ent type='ORG'>FRONT</ent> DOOR.</p>

<p>&gt;that the <ent type='ORG'>Navy</ent> decided to classify after a successful test in 1940. Were</p>

<p>YES, as I said, the <ent type='ORG'>NAVY</ent> classified this result as BEING eighteen
security levels ABOVE TOP SECRET. The NAME is SO SECRET that I don't EVEN
KNOW what this security classification are.</p>

<p>&gt;some so-called <ent type='PERSON'>Levinson</ent> Time Equations successfully applied to your knowledge
&gt;in relation to I.A.S. work on July 22, 1943 or on August 12, 1943?</p>

<p>On July 22, 1943, the ELDRIDGE DEVICE was first ACTIVATED. It
successfully made the destroyer invisible, but it also ALTERED the crystal
structure of the metal, SHIFTING ALL IRON atoms to the ALPHA-S configuration,
making the ship HEAVIER THAN WATER: it sank to the bottom. When the power
system FAILED because of an ELECTRICAL SHORT caused by SALT WATER leakage,
the ship floated back to the surface, and the entire crew was DROWNED and
ELECTROCUTED. We did not see the effects of <ent type='ORG'>TIME</ent> SHEAR in this experiment,
but <ent type='ORG'>SPACIAL</ent> DISTORTION left as a residual effect eventually altered the
crystaline form of the IRON atoms to the OMEGA-PSI configuration which is
LIGHTER THAN AIR, and the ship blew away from our TEST DOCK and we had to
BLOW IT UP with the <ent type='ORG'>MANHATTAN</ent> DEVICE buried underneath the EMPIRE STATE
BUILDING (WHICH WAS in FACT the FIRST such test, predating the so-called
<ent type='ORG'>TRINITY</ent> test) before it would be seen by <ent type='NORP'>GERMAN</ent> spies, who would realize
that WE COULD NOW transform any <ent type='ORG'>BATTLESHIP</ent> into an INVINCIBLE BLIMP.</p>

<p>MOST PEOPLE think that the <ent type='ORG'>AUGUST</ent> 12 test of the <ent type='GPE'>PHILADELPHIA</ent> DEVICE
was conducted on the ELDRIDGE. This is NOT true. The real test ship was
a LARGE RUBBER RAFT. WE had DISCOVERED the <ent type='ORG'>CRYSTALLINE</ent> structure of metal
was altered by this kind of <ent type='ORG'>PARAGRAVITATIONAL</ent> field, so we allowed only
ORGANIC substances in the TEST ZONE. As it turns OUT, the presence of
a sailor's <ent type='GPE'>BELT</ent> BUCKLE started an ELECTROMAGNETIC REACTION that created an
INDUCED <ent type='ORG'>PROTATIONAL</ent> FIELD with resulting <ent type='ORG'>TIME</ent> SHEAR, which ONLY CREMATED
half the <ent type='ORG'>CREW</ent>. THEIR BODIES BURNED FOR 19 DAYS as we STOOD OUTSIDE the
field we created, unable to TURN OFF the now GROWING WARP IN THE STRUCTURE
OF REALITY.</p>

<p>Others were stuck in SLOW FREEZE and DEEP FREEZE for years. THEY
would just sit there, AND IF NOBODY TOUCHED THEM, THEY WOULD NOT MOVE
and soon would become INVISIBLE. Even at THIS PHASE, if you see a PERSON,
or see others LAYING HANDS UPON another, come and join them because this
man is THE MOST DESPERATE MAN IN THE WORLD. NONE of these <ent type='ORG'>SAILORS</ent> wants
to undego the horrors of being CAUGHT IN THE PUSH, the sensations just
BEFORE the DEEP FREEZE.</p>

<p>Four of our sailors entered a <ent type='ORG'>BAR</ent> after we FREED them from the
<ent type='ORG'>PROTATIONAL</ent> FIELD (which we accomplished with the help of Dr. Einstein
and Dr. <ent type='PERSON'>Levinson</ent> and using knowledge of neutrino interactions PASSED
BACKWARDS in <ent type='ORG'>TIME</ent> by researchers observing the 1997 SUPERNOVA of
<ent type='ORG'>ALPHA CENTAURI</ent>) and then went into SLOW FREEZE. CAUGHT IN THE PUSH,
they tryed to start a fight but they SUDDENLY TURNED INVISIBLE, and
then one of them WALKED RIGHT THROUGH A SOLID WALL IN ThE SIGHT OF
HUNDREDS OF PEOPLE, HE WAS NEVER SEEN AGAIN.</p>

<p>&gt;
&gt;Did anything unusual happen in physics in 1943, secret or otherwise?</p>

<p>NO -- WE Have BEEN advancing the REAL PHYSICS. (If your son is
TAKING what is called PHYSICS in college, talk him into taking BUSINESS
or POLITICAL SCIENCE instead. He will be MUCH happier and his <ent type='ORG'>SEX LIFE</ent>
will be FULFILLING. Only the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> teaches REAL PHYSICS; what is TAUGHT
in COLLEGE is a LIE) with the HELP of ALIEN VISITORS since 1922. 1943
Was JUST another YEAR in the advancement of OUR unified FIELD theory.</p></xml>