<xml><p> <ent type='PERSON'>RFK</ent>1.TXT</p>

<p>The following extract is submitted to resurrect long
forgotten material concerning the assassination of <ent type='PERSON'>Robert</ent> F,
<ent type='PERSON'>Kennedy</ent>. The evidence for conspiracy that it presents,
regarding the assassination, speaks for itself. I do not
necessarily agree that there was a second conspiracy to
cover it up, as does the cited source. I believe, rather,
that the obscurity of the material is a classic
manifestation of <ent type='ORG'>Collective Denial</ent>, resulting in the
seemingly irrational appearance of secondary suppression
suggested here. As an example of <ent type='ORG'>Collective Denial</ent> by
investigators, and the press, content versus coverage leaves
no other logical analysis. The evidence was Too Bad to be
True, and therefore "invisible" in the most literal sense.
The most important aspect of the article may well be its
demonstration of the power of clinical <ent type='ORG'>Collective Denial</ent>.
That there was something to Deny is clearly stated.</p>

<p> <ent type='PERSON'>Robert Sabaroff</ent>
712512445</p>

<p> EXTRACT FROM "COMPUTERS &amp; AUTOMATION
CONCERNING EVIDENCE IN THE <ent type='PERSON'>RFK</ent> ASSASSINATION</p>

<p> The following partial text is extracted verbatim from
the periodical, "COMPUTERS AND AUTOMATION; The magazine of
the design, applications, and implications of information
processing systems.", Vol. 19, No. 10, October, 1970. a
Editorial Offices; Berkeley Enterprises, Inc., 815
<ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent> Street, <ent type='GPE'>Newtonville</ent>, Mass. 02160. Advertising
contact, The Publisher (617) 332-5453. Circulation audited
by the Audit Bureau of Circulations.</p>

<p>From the Table of Contents;</p>

<p> "52 <ent type='ORG'>THE CONSPIRACY</ent> TO ASSASSINATE SENATOR ROBERT F.
KENNEDY AND THE SECOND CONSPIRACY TO COVER IT UP
By <ent type='PERSON'>Richard</ent> E. Sprague</p>

<p> "A summary of what researchers are uncovering in
their investigation of what appears to be not one
but two conspiracies relating to the assassina-tion of Senator <ent type='PERSON'>Robert</ent> F. <ent type='PERSON'>Kennedy</ent>.</p>

<p> "56 INDEX TO "SPECIAL UNIT SENATOR: The Investigation</p>

<p> of the Assassination of Senator <ent type='PERSON'>Robert</ent> F. <ent type='PERSON'>Kennedy</ent>"
An index is supplied for <ent type='ORG'>the Random House</ent> book
written by <ent type='PERSON'>Robert</ent> A. <ent type='GPE'>Houghton</ent>, of the <ent type='GPE'>Los Angeles</ent>
Police Department, about the investigation of the
assassination of Senator <ent type='PERSON'>Robert</ent> F. <ent type='PERSON'>Kennedy</ent>."</p>

<p>[The second listing is offered both for the benefit of
researchers and to give context to references to <ent type='GPE'>Houghton</ent> in
material excerpted from the p. 52 article, above].</p>

<p>[To assess the character of the publication, and a non-political, socially aware side of the nature of computer
research in the public sector in 1970, there also appears an
article, on P. 14, "COMPUTERS AND THE <ent type='ORG'>CONSUMER</ent>, by Ralph
Nader").</p>

<p>*[The following is not and never has been Classified, and
owning or showing it violates no section of the National
Security Act. It is not a criminal or subversive act to
view it or its contents].*</p>

<p> [P. 52]</p>

<p>[Boxed editorial preface at top of page]: "_Computers and
Automation_ believes that the possibility of conspiracies of
important <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> leaders in our times is of the utmost
significance to every <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> - and especially to computer
people, because computers can be used: to handle large
amounts of information easily; to correlate the information
rapidly; to prove or disprove or possibilities of
conspiracy; etc. Therefore, computer people can make a
unique and important contribution to society in this area.
Already a computerized of analysis of information regarding
the assassination of President <ent type='PERSON'>John</ent> F. <ent type='PERSON'>Kennedy</ent> in underway
in <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>.
"Accordingly, _Computers and Automation_ is publishing
from time to time articles and reports on investigations
into assassinations; the major evidence; and the application
of computers to the evidence. Our purpose is to present
important, useful, and authoritative information in order
to find out the truth. Since this subject is not receiving
adequate and comprehensive coverage anywhere else that we
know of, _Computers and Automation_ has taken the
responsibility to publish.
"No scientist, no honest man, ever refuses to consider
new evidence or to correct errors. If corrections are
needed or new evidence appears, _Computers and Animation_
will publish both.</p>

<p> "<ent type='ORG'>THE CONSPIRACY</ent> TO ASSASSINATE SENATOR
ROBERT F. KENNEDY AND THE SECOND CONSPIRACY
TO COVER IT UP</p>

<p> "<ent type='PERSON'>Richard</ent> E. Sprague,
Hartsdale, N.Y.</p>

<p> "In June 1970, a group action suit was filed in Los
Angeles on behalf of all the residents of the State of
<ent type='GPE'>California</ent> by <ent type='PERSON'>Theodore Charach</ent>, a free-lance journalist, to
force <ent type='ORG'>the Los Angeles Police Department</ent> to make public
additional information in their possession relating to a
possible conspiracy in the assassination of Senator <ent type='PERSON'>Robert</ent>
F. <ent type='PERSON'>Kennedy</ent> in June 1958...
"...The <ent type='PERSON'>Charach</ent> suit...claims that another man also fired
shots, and that it was likely that he, not <ent type='PERSON'>Sirhan</ent>, was the
killer. <ent type='PERSON'>Charach</ent>, and his lawyer, <ent type='PERSON'>Godfrey Isaac</ent>, held a
press conference on Thursday, June 4, 1970, in <ent type='GPE'>Los Angeles</ent>
to announce the filing of the suit and its withdrawal. The
withdrawal was made so that the defendants would have an
opportunity to assess all of Charach's findings.
"The only news organization apparently that this story
was the _<ent type='GPE'>Los Angeles</ent> Free Press_ (7813 Beverly Blvd., Los
Angeles, <ent type='GPE'>California</ent>, 90036 [in 1970] in their June 12-18,
1970, issue. The news of this suit was not published in
any other of the <ent type='GPE'>Los Angeles</ent> papers, nor distributed by the
Associated Press, <ent type='ORG'>United Press International</ent>, or <ent type='ORG'>Reuters</ent>,
nor published in the _New York Times_, nor published or
broadcast by many other important new media...</p>

<p> "STATEMENTS IN THE CHARACH SUIT</p>

<p> "The assassin that is suggested in the suit of Theodore
<ent type='PERSON'>Charach</ent> was a uniformed security guard employed on a
contract basis by <ent type='ORG'>the Ambassador Hotel</ent> to guard Senator
<ent type='PERSON'>Kennedy</ent>. His name is <ent type='PERSON'>Thane Eugene Cesar</ent>, a part time
employee, at the time, of <ent type='ORG'>the Ace Security Guard Service</ent> in
<ent type='GPE'>Los Angeles</ent>, and a known right-wing supporter of George
Wallace and hater of the <ent type='PERSON'>Kennedy</ent>s'.</p>

<p> "Cesar's name is mentioned in a book and in an article,
both by <ent type='PERSON'>Robert</ent> Blair Kaiser. The book is to be published in
the fall of 1970. The article was published in "LADIES HOME
JOURNAL" magazine in May 1970 and is entitled "<ent type='PERSON'>RFK</ent> Must
Die." <ent type='PERSON'>Cesar</ent> is quoted in the article as saying he did draw
his service revolver at the time <ent type='PERSON'>Kennedy</ent> was hit, but
replaced it in his holster because <ent type='PERSON'>Sirhan</ent> was by then under
control.</p>

<p> "Charach's suit says that <ent type='ORG'>District</ent> Attorney Evelle
Younger, Chief of Police Edward M. <ent type='PERSON'>Davis</ent>, and Deputy Chief
<ent type='PERSON'>Robert</ent> A. <ent type='GPE'>Houghton</ent> (also author of the book "Special Unit
Senator" on the assassination published 1970 by Random
House) have all purposely concealed from the people of
<ent type='GPE'>California</ent>, without the legal right to do so, the following
alleged facts:</p>

<p> "1. Senator <ent type='PERSON'>Robert</ent> F. <ent type='PERSON'>Kennedy</ent> was NOT killed by a
bullet from the gun of <ent type='PERSON'>Sirhan</ent> B. <ent type='PERSON'>Sirhan</ent>.</p>

<p> "2. Another gun was fired at <ent type='PERSON'>RFK</ent> at the same time.</p>

<p> "3. The fatal shot did not come from the direction
of Sirhan's position.</p>

<p> "4. A witness, <ent type='PERSON'>Donald Schulman</ent>, an employee of <ent type='ORG'>KNX</ent>-TV, SAW <ent type='PERSON'>Cesar</ent> fire his gun while standing directly
behind Senator <ent type='PERSON'>Kennedy</ent>. <ent type='ORG'>Schulman</ent> saw <ent type='PERSON'>Kennedy</ent> being hit
from behind by three bullets. <ent type='ORG'>Schulman</ent> was interviewed
about what he saw within minutes after the assassination;
but he was not called as a witness at Sirhan's trial; nor
was he mentioned in <ent type='ORG'>Evelle Younger</ent>'s report to the people
of <ent type='GPE'>California</ent>; nor was he mentioned in Houghton's book,
'Special Unit Senator.'...</p>

<p> "5. <ent type='PERSON'>Karl Uecker</ent>, the maitre d' who was escorting
Senator <ent type='PERSON'>Kennedy</ent> through the pantry where he was shot, saw
<ent type='PERSON'>Cesar</ent> with his drawn gun in his hand, immediately after
<ent type='ORG'>Uecker</ent> helped subdue <ent type='PERSON'>Sirhan</ent>. Younger, <ent type='PERSON'>Davis</ent>, and
<ent type='GPE'>Houghton</ent> (asserts <ent type='PERSON'>Charach</ent>) did not present this evidence
to the jury or at the <ent type='PERSON'>Sirhan</ent> trial.</p>

<p> "6. Cesar's presence in the pantry, his possession
of a gun, his drawing of the gun from his holster, and
his close proximity to Kennedy's back were all
suppressed. <ent type='PERSON'>Cesar</ent> was never called to testify before the
grand jury or at the trial. (Houghton's book even states
that there were NO security guards at the doors or in the
kitchen at the time of the shooting, and that NO persons
of right wing connections were in the pantry; this is
simply not true.)</p>

<p> "7. The facts determined at the autopsy by Dr.
Thomas T. <ent type='PERSON'>Noguchi</ent>, coroner, were glossed over, changed,
or not allowed to be presented before the grand jury or
at the trial.</p>

<p> "8. One of these facts was that the fatal wound was
caused by a bullet in the head, the trajectory of which
was back to front, right to left, and upward. <ent type='PERSON'>Sirhan</ent> WAS
NEVER in a position to have fired on that trajectory.
<ent type='PERSON'>Cesar</ent> WAS.</p>

<p> "9. A second of these facts was that the fatal
wound was inflicted from a distance of one inch to three
inches, while two other wounds fired from the rear were
inflicted from a distance of less than six inches away.
<ent type='PERSON'>Sirhan</ent> was never closer to <ent type='PERSON'>Kennedy</ent> than several feet
away. <ent type='PERSON'>Cesar</ent> was right behind him and to his right.</p>

<p> "10. Dr. <ent type='PERSON'>Noguchi</ent> started to testify about the
wounds at the <ent type='PERSON'>Sirhan</ent> trial, but was stopped by the judge.</p>

<p> "OTHER EVIDENCE</p>

<div> "....</div>

<p> "The Sounds of Three Shots Recorded on Tape</p>

<p> "Several TV and radio network microphones were open and
operating during the shooting. They were all in the
Ambassador Ballroom, quite a distance from the pantry. One
of these microphones, attached to an <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> Broadcasting
Corp. TV camera, produced a live and video tape recording of
the event. Researchers in <ent type='GPE'>New York City</ent> have examined this
tape and found that only THREE shots can be heard above the
noise of the crowd.
"The microphone was continuously open from the time
<ent type='PERSON'>Kennedy</ent> left the podium until all the shots had been fired
and for some time beyond that. The TV video tape with sound
shows that there were no breaks in either picture or
sound...
"Now, the fact that ONLY THREE shots can be heard
confirms the probability that more than one gun was being
fired, and that shots from a second gun are those recorded
on the tape. Sirhan's gun shots were apparently not loud
enough to be recorded. If they had been, all eight of his
shots should have been audible also."</p>

<p>(NOTE: <ent type='PERSON'>Sirhan</ent> was firing a .22. <ent type='PERSON'>Cesar</ent> had a service
revolver).</p>

<p> "SOUND TEST BY THE LOS ANGELES POLICE</p>

<p> "Confirmation of the evidence that Sirhan's gun could not
have been heard above the crowd noise from the position of
the <ent type='ORG'>ABC</ent> microphone is presented on pages 118-119 of "Special
Unit Senator," Houghton's book. Unwittingly, thus,
<ent type='GPE'>Houghton</ent> presents evidence of a second presents evidence of
a second gun, whereas he had intended the evidence to help
prove there was no conspiracy.
"The following is quoted from the book:</p>

<p> "The next day, June 20, Pena [L.A. Police Lt.
<ent type='PERSON'>Manny Pena</ent>] ordered sound level tests to be
conducted at the Ambassador to determine whether a
gun fired in the pantry could be heard by the stairs
outside the opposite end of the Embassy Room. The
two locations were approximately a hundred yards,
and many walls, drapes and doors apart.
"Officer DeWayne Wolfer conducted the sound
tests at the hotel between 11:30 a.m. and 1:30 p.m.
when...there was no talking, shouting, or music to
deaden the sounds of the shots... "</p>

<p>(Houghton's text, as quoted by COMPUTERS AND AUTOMATION,
goes on to give technical details of the test, how the
ammunition and firing position was duplicated, etc.,
particularly noting measurements taken at the location from
which <ent type='PERSON'>Sandra Serrano</ent>, a <ent type='PERSON'>Kennedy</ent> worker, claimed to have
heard the shots).</p>

<p> "...registered no greater change than one half
decibel during ANY of the tests. ...The minimum
change in noise level discernible for people with
normal hearing is two decibels...
"She [<ent type='PERSON'>Sandra Serrano</ent>] obviously thought, in the
furor of the moment, that she heard and saw certain
things which were not physically possible or did not
actually occur. It happens every day. ...People ...
hear something which cannot be detected by the most
sensitive electronic device.</p>

<p> "Now <ent type='GPE'>Houghton</ent> is right on one count; Miss <ent type='PERSON'>Serrano</ent> did not
hear the shots from Sirhan's gun... What she did hear,
however, was the sound of a second gun firing three shots...
"Also, the crowd noise was present. Nearly everyone in
the ballroom interviewed heard a few shoots. Why wouldn't
they, if the microphones 300 to 400 feet away on the podium
recorded the three shots?
"In this way, <ent type='GPE'>Houghton</ent>, in an effort to invalidate Miss
Serrano's report, unwittingly produced just the right test
to prove that a gun, not Sirhan's but a second gun, was
firing."</p>

<p> "SECRECY OVER THE <ent type='PERSON'>RFK</ent> AUTOPSY REPORT</p>

<p> "The reports on the autopsy of Senator <ent type='PERSON'>Robert</ent> F. <ent type='PERSON'>Kennedy</ent>
have been suppressed in three separate ways: first, by the
judge's ruling before the trial of <ent type='PERSON'>Sirhan</ent>; second, by
attempts to silence the coroner, Dr. <ent type='PERSON'>Thomas Noguchi</ent>, by
intimidation; and third, by passing a special <ent type='GPE'>California</ent> law
making the autopsy reports secret for 75 years.
"The attempts to intimidate Dr. <ent type='PERSON'>Noguchi</ent> are like a scene
out of the movie "Z". After he told in public the results of
the autopsy, he was accused of being insane and fired. He
took the issue to court and won a victory, when his lawyer,
<ent type='PERSON'>Godfrey Isaac</ent> threatened to subpoena the autopsy and
introduce it in court. Then the <ent type='GPE'>Los Angeles</ent> Police Dept.
rehired <ent type='PERSON'>Noguchi</ent>.</p>

<p> "SUMMARY</p>

<p> "To summarize, the officials of the <ent type='GPE'>Los Angeles</ent> Police
Department have been and still are suppressing important
evidence about the <ent type='PERSON'>RFK</ent> assassination. This evidence points
toward a conspiracy, with <ent type='PERSON'>Sirhan</ent> being a patsy, toward a
hotel security guard firing the three shots which hit
<ent type='PERSON'>RFK</ent>..."</p>

<div> -----------------</div>

</xml>