<xml>
<p> EXPOSE: <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> Syndicate - <ent type='ORG'>Secret Govt</ent> pt 1 (53K)</p>

<p>This text is being posted with the intent to EDUCATE those of you who
know not the silent and pervasive influence of your hidden masters. Some
have looked for shadows of the old illuminati; they look amiss, not seeing
that which is all around them. If you know not the "who" and the "why",
efforts will be mis-directed. This is NOT a "conspiracy"..nay, it is a
very cold and calculated NETWORK of individuals whose intent is nothing
short of implementation of a "<ent type='EVENT'>New World</ent> Order"; an oligarchic rein in which
*you* serve as little more that slaves in their "technocracy". This network
has every intention to implement a cashless society, for it is they who
control every aspect of finance and banking over the entire globe. They
have had about 100 years to perfect their plans and put them into practice.

Please understand that the <ent type='NORP'>Bilderbergers</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>the Council</ent> on Foreign Relations,
the Tri-lateral Commission,<ent type='ORG'>the Institute for Policy</ent> Studies, the <ent type='ORG'>Roundtables</ent>,
the "Club of Rome",etc are ALL bound by common denominators of long-standing
families ties, and interests and come together as a _single_ policy making
body that is known today as "<ent type='ORG'>The Committee</ent> of 300" . This has also been
known as "The <ent type='NORP'>Olympians</ent>", the "<ent type='ORG'>Policy Committee</ent>".

Don't be mis-led by labels such as "<ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent>" or "<ent type='PERSON'>Rothschild</ent>"; for these
are simply the families who have the mechanisms of control already set in
place,but of themselves are not the entire network; that being the
"Committee of 300". It is THEY who control the UN, who tell the heads of
nations "when to jump and how high", they who are behind the world's illicit
drug trade via the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> and the old <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> East India links. They who
manage the <ent type='ORG'>IMF</ent>,set policy at <ent type='ORG'>GATT</ent> conferences. It is they who ARE the
"<ent type='ORG'>Shadow Government</ent>". It is they who manage the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>,<ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent>,<ent type='ORG'>DIA</ent>..the same
group that took out <ent type='PERSON'>JFK</ent> and have MURDERED around 173 people in their efforts
to suppress the truth about all the links..they who were behind the
assassination of <ent type='PERSON'>RFK</ent>,<ent type='PERSON'>MLK</ent>..they who are behind the suppression of truth
regarding the MIA's; It is the same group behind E. Howard Hunt,
<ent type='PERSON'>John Singlaub</ent>, Ollie <ent type='PERSON'>North</ent>..the very same group who brought down Richard
Nixon in <ent type='EVENT'>Watergate</ent>..the same group behind the persecution of the <ent type='NORP'>Christic</ent>
Institute..the same people who were behind Nugan-Hand..the same group
that groomed <ent type='PERSON'>Jimmy Carter</ent> for the Presidency..the same group who ARE
the "Military-Industrial complex", the same group behind the total
militarization of <ent type='ORG'>NASA</ent>..the same group who ARE "MJ-12", were behind the
"<ent type='ORG'>Jason Group</ent>"..the same behind Project Blue Book, The Condon Committee,
the same who started up the <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent>..who are responsible for the MURDER of
<ent type='PERSON'>Danny Casalaro</ent>..the same group responsible for the world-wide DISINFO
campaign regarding the <ent type='ORG'>TRUTH</ent> of <ent type='EVENT'>UFO</ent> sightings and contacts. The very
SAME group who OWN THE ME<ent type='ORG'>DIA</ent>..ie..<ent type='ORG'>The Washington Post</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>NBC</ent> (General
Electric),<ent type='ORG'>ABC</ent>,<ent type='ORG'>CBS</ent>,<ent type='ORG'>The New York</ent> Times,etc. The same group behind the
the Warren Commission,ad nauseum..

I DO believe I could make a DIRECT connection here with just what
<ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>BASE says on <ent type='ORG'>WACKENHUT</ent> that also ties in the <ent type='ORG'>Shadow Government</ent>
with <ent type='EVENT'>UFO</ent> related installations; this is but *ONE* connection..there
are many,many more that can be and will be ferreted out for exposure.</p>

<p>===== Begin Included article =============================================</p>

<p>Message #6041 - INFO.PARANET
Date : 16-Jan-92 19:46
From : <ent type='PERSON'>Don</ent> Ecker
To : <ent type='PERSON'>John</ent> Galt
Subject : <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent>
<ent type='PERSON'>John</ent> Galt said:</p>

<p> &gt; <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> Corp., one of the nation's largest security firms, said Friday
&gt; it has bought the U.S. security operations of <ent type='ORG'>ISS International</ent> Service
&gt; System Inc. The purchase price was not disclosed. <ent type='ORG'>ISS International</ent>
&gt; has more than 700 employees in its U.S. security operations, primarily
&gt; in <ent type='GPE'>Jacksonville</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Los Angeles</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Dallas</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Atlanta</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Cleveland</ent> and
&gt; <ent type='GPE'>Chattanooga</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Tenn</ent>.</p>

<p>In several investigations that I am currently involved in for <ent type='EVENT'>UFO</ent> Magazine as
well as my radio show "<ent type='EVENT'>UFO</ent>s Tonite", I have come across the <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent>
connection. As many of you may know, <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> is responsible for outside
security around <ent type='LOC'>Area</ent> 51 and site S-4. Last year there was a helicopter crash
in <ent type='GPE'>Las Vegas</ent> that killed a number of <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> employees, plus they are
involved in the <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> scandel. At any rate much more than I can go into here.
However************</p>

<p>I checked <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>BASE and came up with the following. Incidently, all sources are
available for the following information if requested.</p>

<p>Read and contemplate.</p>

<div>*****************************************************************************</div>

<p><ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>BASE FILES
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------</p>

<p>CONFLICT, LI</p>

<p> PERU, 88-91 PRIVATE SECURITY CORPORATION FORMING IMPORTANT ROLE
IN LIC-DRUG OPERATIONS. FROM 1981-91, <ent type='ORG'>PERUVIAN SECURITY CORPORATIONS</ent>
INCREASED FROM 80 TO 350, PLUS 150 UNOFFI<ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>L ORGANIZATIONS. AMONG
THOSE IS <ent type='ORG'>WACKENHUT</ent> CORP, <ent type='ORG'>WHO</ent>SE EMPLOYEES CONSIST OF MANY EX-<ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>,
<ent type='ORG'>DEA</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>FBI</ent> MEMBERS. Z 11/90 87</p>

<p>DOMESTIC OP</p>

<p> <ent type='GPE'>CHILE</ent>, CUBA. <ent type='ORG'>WACKENHUT</ent> CORP OF CORAL <ent type='ORG'>GABLES</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>FLORIDA</ent>. PROVIDES
SECURITY SYSTEMS THRUOUT WORLD. <ent type='ORG'>INMAN</ent> WAS DIRECTOR OF CORP PLUS
OTHER INFLUENTIAL PERSONS IN 80 <ent type='ORG'>WACKENHUT</ent> WORKED CLOSELY WITH
S. CALIFORNIA'S CABAZON IN<ent type='ORG'>DIA</ent>NS AND THEIR TRIBAL ADMINISTRATOR
JOHN PHILIP NICHOLS. NICHOLS PER NEWS ARTICLE, BOASTED RE ATTEMPTED
ASSASSINATION <ent type='PERSON'>CASTRO</ent> AND SUCCESSFUL ASSASSINATION OF SALVADOR ALLENDE.
<ent type='ORG'>WACKENHUT</ent>/CABAZON CONNECTION OF PARTICULAR INTEREST TO D. CASOLARO
<ent type='ORG'>WHO</ent> DIED IN W.VIRGINIA IN 91 HE ALSO INVESTIGATING OCTOBER SURPRISE
AND INSLAW. MICHAEL <ent type='PERSON'>RICONOSCIUTO</ent> - A WEAPONS-SYSTEM DESIGNER AND
SOFTWARE SPE<ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>LIST - WAS DIR OF A RESEARCH PROJECT OF <ent type='ORG'>WACKENHUT</ent>/CABAZON
JOINT VENTURE. IN EARLY 80s <ent type='PERSON'>AFFIDAVIT</ent> SAID HE MODIFIED A STOLEN
PROMIS SOFTWARE FOR FOREIGN SALES. OTHER INFO ON <ent type='ORG'>WACKENHUT</ent>. <ent type='ORG'>ITT</ent>
9/24/81 4-5</p>

<p> FOR EIGHT YEARS INSLAW BATTLING JUSTICE DEPT FOR POSSESSION OF
PROMIS, A SOFT-WARE PROGRAM DEVELOPED BY COMPANY OWNER BILL <ent type='PERSON'>HAMILTON</ent>.
IN 91 INSLAW WENT PUBLIC AND <ent type='PERSON'>ALLEGED REAGAN</ent> JUSTICE DEPT, AFTER IT
HAD STOLEN PROMIS, TURNED IT OVER TO <ent type='PERSON'>EARL BRIAN</ent>. INSLAW ALLEGES
SOFTWARE GIVEN BRIAN AS PAYBACK FOR BRIAN'S HELP IN ARRANGING ARMS-FOR-HOSTAGE <ent type='ORG'>DEA</ent>L WITH <ent type='GPE'>IRAN</ent> IN 1980 (OCTOBER SURPRISE). PER <ent type='PERSON'>HAMILTON</ent>, BRIAN, <ent type='ORG'>WHO</ent>
RUNS UPI, <ent type='ORG'>ALLEGEDLY</ent> MARKETED PROMIS TO <ent type='ORG'>INTEL</ent> AGENCIES OF <ent type='GPE'>ISRAEL</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>JORDAN</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>IRAQ</ent>,
<ent type='GPE'>CANADA</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>SOUTH KOREA</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>LIBYA</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>ENGLAND</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>GERMANY</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>FRANCE</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>AUSTRALIA</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>THAILAND</ent>,
<ent type='GPE'>JAPAN</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>CHILE</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>GUATEMALA</ent>, AND <ent type='ORG'>BRAZIL</ent>. PER INSLAW, ONCE SOFTWARE USED BY FOREIGN
<ent type='ORG'>INTEL</ent> SERVICES, <ent type='ORG'>NATIONAL SECURITY AGENCY</ent> (<ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent>) ABLE INFILTRATE COMPUTERIZED
<ent type='ORG'>INTEL</ent> FILES THOSE COUNTRIES. MODIFICATIONS TO PROMIS <ent type='ORG'>ALLEGEDLY</ent> DONE BY
<ent type='ORG'>WACKENHUT</ent> CORP. OF CORAL <ent type='ORG'>GABLES</ent>, FL. HOUSE JUDI<ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>RY COMM<ent type='ORG'>ITT</ent>EE INVESTIGATING
SCANDAL SINCE 89. ATTORNEY GENERAL THORNBURG, UNDER SUPOENA, RELEASED
INSLAW-RELATED FILES - BUT 15 TO 20 FILES MISSING. <ent type='ORG'>ITT</ent> 9/10/91 4-5</p>

<p> STORY OF <ent type='PERSON'>DANNY CASOLARO</ent> - <ent type='ORG'>WHO</ent> HAD BEEN SORTING THRU THE S&amp;L DEBACLE,
<ent type='ORG'>BCCI</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>IRAN</ent>-CONTRA, CONTRA-CONNECTED <ent type='ORG'>WACKENHUT</ent> CORP., <ent type='ORG'>WACKENHUT</ent>-CONNECTED
INSLAW CASE AND INSLAW-CONNECTED "OCTOBER SURPRISE." <ent type='ORG'>ITT</ent> 9/10/91
4-5</p>

<p>LIAISON</p>

<p> INSLAW PRES BILL <ent type='PERSON'>HAMILTON</ent> SAYS HE HAS INFO THAT PROMIS ILLEGALLY
SOLD TO <ent type='GPE'>SOUTH KOREA</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>LIBYA</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>JORDAN</ent>, GREAT <ent type='GPE'>BRITAIN</ent> (<ent type='GPE'>ENGLAND</ent>), <ent type='GPE'>GERMANY</ent>,
<ent type='GPE'>FRANCE</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>AUSTRALIA</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>THAILAND</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>JAPAN</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>CHILE</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>GUATEMALA</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>BRAZIL</ent>, AND
<ent type='GPE'>CANADA</ent>. CANA<ent type='ORG'>DIA</ent>N COMPANY, COMMUNICATIONS <ent type='GPE'>CANADA</ent> - THE CANA<ent type='ORG'>DIA</ent>N
WORKPLACE AUTOMATION RESEARCH CENTER (CWARC) WROTE INSLAW A LETTER.
ROYAL CANA<ent type='ORG'>DIA</ent>N MOUNTED POLICE ARE OPERATING PROMIS IN 900 LOCATIONS.
MICHAEL <ent type='PERSON'>RICONOSCIUTO</ent> SWORE IN AN <ent type='PERSON'>AFFIDAVIT</ent> THAT WHEN HE DIRECTOR
OF <ent type='ORG'>WACKENHUT</ent> CORP OF CORAL <ent type='ORG'>GABLES</ent>, FL ONE OF HIS JOBS TO ADAPT
PROMIS SOFTWARE. <ent type='PERSON'>PETER VIDENIEKS</ent> AND EARL W. BRIAN WERE FREQUENT
VISITORS TO <ent type='ORG'>WACKENHUT</ent>. <ent type='PERSON'>RICONOSCIUTO</ent> SAID HE TO MODIFY PROMIS FOR
IMPLEMENTATION IN LAW ENFORCEMENT AND <ent type='ORG'>INTEL</ent> AGENCIES WORLDWIDE.
AFTER TESTIFYING BEFORE HOUSE JUDI<ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>RY COMM<ent type='ORG'>ITT</ent>EE INVESTIGATORS,
<ent type='PERSON'>RICONOSCIUTO</ent> ARRESTED AND CHARGED WITH SELLING MORE THAN 4 GRAMS
OF POTENT SPEED. <ent type='ORG'>ITT</ent> 6/11/91 11-13</p>

<p>END OF FILE ---------------------------
---------------------------------------------------</p>

<p>If you notice the name <ent type='ORG'>INMAN</ent> in the above, that is Adm. <ent type='PERSON'>Bobby Inman</ent> recently
mentioned in <ent type='PERSON'>Tim Good</ent>'s book "Alien Liason" and the subject of the January
1992 rebuttal of <ent type='PERSON'>Bob Oechsler</ent> in the M<ent type='EVENT'>UFO</ent>N Journel.</p>

<p>Best:</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Don</ent> Ecker
Director Research
<ent type='EVENT'>UFO</ent> Magazine</p>

<p>--- FD 1.99c
* Origin: ParaNet Alpha-Delta The Data Base (9:1012/3.0)</p>

<p>===End of included article=================================================</p>

<p>Also here's something from last year on the ultra secret <ent type='PERSON'>Bilderberg</ent>
meeting..what motivations and policies do you think that THEY
follow?</p>

<p>-----Begin included text---------------------------------------------------</p>

<p>From: <ent type='ORG'>campe</ent>@thor.uucp (<ent type='PERSON'>Gary Campe</ent> ext )
Newsgroups: alt.activism,talk.politics.misc,misc.headlines
Subject: BILDERBERG ANNUAL MEETING SCHEDULED
<info type="Message-ID"> 13155@fpssun</info>
Date: 22 Apr 91 17:56:38 GMT
References: The Spotlight
Sender: daemon@fpssun
Organization: FPS Computing, Beaverton, Oregon
Lines: 23</p>

<p>Ad as it appears in The Spotlight dated April 22, 1991:</p>

<p>JUNE 7-9 - <ent type='PERSON'>Bilderberg</ent> group meets secretly at Baden-Baden, <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent>.</p>

<p>Members will fly into <ent type='GPE'>Frankfurt</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> or <ent type='GPE'>Stasbourg</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>France</ent> to be taken
in government helicopters to a heavily guarded hotel near Baden-Baden, site
of secret meeting of world's elite. <ent type='ORG'>Agenda</ent> items include exploiting Middle
East oil and progress toward world government. For information, call
<ent type='PERSON'>David Rocefeller</ent> at (914) 631-1634 or his personal valet, Dr. Henry
Kissinger at (212) 759-7919.</p>

<div> ******************</div>

<p>Have any of you been invited?</p>

<p>--
RE-ELECT "Government is not reason, it is not eloquence - it
NO-ONE! is force. Like fire, it is a dangerous servant and
========== a fearful master" -- <ent type='PERSON'>George Washington</ent>.
Disclaimer: The opinions expressed are mine alone and not that of my employer.</p>

<div>------------------------------------------------------------------------------</div>

<p>From: <ent type='ORG'>campe</ent>@thor.uucp (<ent type='PERSON'>Gary Campe</ent> ext )
Newsgroups: misc.headlines,talk.politics.misc,alt.conspiracy
Subject: <ent type='PERSON'>Bilderberg</ent> Annual Meeting - What was said
<info type="Message-ID"> 14096@fpssun</info>
Date: 28 Jun 91 17:48:41 GMT
Sender: daemon@fps.com
Followup-To: misc.headlines
Distribution: usa
Organization: FPS Computing, Beaverton, Oregon
Lines: 42</p>

<p>This information was reported in the June 24, 1991 issue of "THE SPOTLIGHT".</p>

<p>This is not the entire article, only the highlights. If you would like to
read this article in its entirety please refer to the above publication.</p>

<div> ----------------------------</div>

<p>The word out of the <ent type='PERSON'>Bilderberg</ent> annual meeting is that there will be another
war within the next five years.</p>

<p>It was repeatedly stated at the <ent type='PERSON'>Bilderberg</ent> meeting that there will be
"other <ent type='PERSON'>Saddams</ent>" in the years ahead who must be dealt with swiftly and
efficiently.</p>

<p>The <ent type='PERSON'>Bilderberg</ent> group plans a global army at the disposal of <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent>
Nations. It is their hope that the U.N. will become the world government
by the year 2000.</p>

<p>"A U.N. army must be able to act immediately, anywhere in the world, without
delays involved in each country making its own decision whether to
participate, based on parochial considerations," said <ent type='PERSON'>Henry Kissinger</ent>.</p>

<p>If <ent type='NORP'>Americans</ent> can be persuaded to surrender warmaking decisions to the U.N.,
"parochial nationalism" in <ent type='GPE'>Briton</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>France</ent> and elsewhere will disappear,
<ent type='PERSON'>Bilderberg</ent> speakers said.</p>

<p>"The <ent type='LOC'>Persian Gulf</ent> venture has advanced the cause by years" one speaker said.</p>

<div> ----------------------------</div>

<p>So there you have it, the "One <ent type='PERSON'>Worlders</ent>" are still alive and well.</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Garry</ent></p>

<p>--
RE-ELECT "Government is not reason, it is not eloquence - it
NO-ONE! is force. Like fire, it is a dangerous servant and
========== a fearful master" -- <ent type='PERSON'>George Washington</ent>.
Disclaimer: The opinions expressed are mine alone and not that of my employer.</p>

<p>---End included text---------------------------------------------------------</p>

<p>The following is on the historical perspective of just the <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent>
and <ent type='PERSON'>Rothschild</ent> connections and in no way attempts to cover every
aspect, but will suffice to give you a basis on which to understand
how pervasive the Web of influence is and that it is a good deal MORE
than "merely a conspiracy". Just <ent type='ORG'>WHO</ent> makes up the ILLEGAL SHADOW
GOVERMNENT,YOUR HIDDEN MASTERS?</p>

<p>I ask no one to accept any of this at face value, and would heartily
encourage you to perform your own investigation. To that end,I've
provided an extensive list of reading materials at the end of this
text.

And lastly, I would include a very lucid assessment of our situation
by <ent type='PERSON'>John</ent> DiNardo, which in my opinion, is absolutely correct. There have
been MANY people who are posting such as <ent type='PERSON'>John</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Dave Radcliffe</ent>, Rich
Winkel and others who have been showing you just *<ent type='ORG'>WHO</ent>* the CANCER IS.</p>

<p>----------------------------------------------------------------------------
If the usurpers of our freedom, the plunderers of our life's earnings,
the despoilers of our planet <ent type='LOC'>Earth</ent>, the deluders of our TV-zombified
society, the desecrators of our Constitution can crush the <ent type='NORP'>Christic</ent>
Institute -- than what refuge is left for the few remaining
<ent type='NORP'>Christic</ent>-like organizations to shelter THEM from this Frankenstein
Monster government? What refuge is left for you and me, and for our
children who will necessarily find themselves forced to riot and
spill their blood in the streets during the twenty-first century?
It always degenerates to that, you know.</p>

<p> We <ent type='NORP'>Americans</ent> are a lazy, short-sighted bunch. We realize that if we
don't earn a living, we will be impoverished. We realize that if we
don't brush our teeth, our teeth will rot out of our mouths. We
realize that if we don't service our cars, they will fail to operate.
Yet, we don't realize -- or we're too lazy to admit -- that if we
don't supervise and participate in our system of government to ensure
that our Constitution is protected from the greedy, power-mad
neurotics whose ambitions drive them to seize the reins of power
and wealth vested in our <ent type='ORG'>Federal Government</ent>, then our libertarian
foundations will crumble beneath us, leaving us to fall into the
pit of subjugation that the corporate rulers have prepared for us.</p>

<p> As we witness our free-fall into the pit, we finally understand
that the law is slipping out of our hands; that we and our children
will have to resort to meeting in dark rooms and plotting to recover
our Constitutional freedoms which the usurpers have seized through
television, that great national <ent type='NORP'>Svengali</ent> -- that opiate of the masses
which they have so cleverly employed to sedate, delude and distract us
while quietly cuffing our ankles and wrists. How could we be so stupid
as to surrender our minds to Big Brother, never suspecting that
whenever someone offers you free entertainment, day after day and
year after year, it's got to be costing you. </p>

<p> Why shouldn't we be as vulnerable to totalitarianism as are
the peoples of most other societies around the world. More so,
considering the fact that totalitarianism originates from within the
military elite. And whose nation has the most savagely powerful
military force on the planet? What's worse is that it's not just the
military that's militating against our Constitutional freedoms.
It's the military-industrial complex. President <ent type='PERSON'>Eisenhower</ent> left office
a third of a century ago by warning us that the military-industrial
complex is the greatest threat to our freedom. That was as much of
a warning as he dared give, lest he meet the doom of his valiant
successor who tried to actually BE the President of <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States.</p>

<p> How knowledgeable was <ent type='ORG'>the General</ent> of the <ent type='ORG'>Army</ent> of the Second <ent type='EVENT'>World War</ent>,
Dwight <ent type='PERSON'>Eisenhower</ent>, in his fear of the military-industrial complex?
As knowledgeable as President <ent type='PERSON'>Kennedy</ent> is dead!</p>

<p> So you see, there really isn't much time left. If we prove to be too
lazy now to unite behind Constitutional upholders such as the
<ent type='NORP'>Christic</ent> Institute -- then our children in the twenty-first century
will NOT be too frightened to stand up against the bullets of the
<ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> Security Corporation of Coral Gables, <ent type='GPE'>Florida</ent>. Because
when the oppression becomes intolerable, you, I and anyone would
stand up to bullets, rather than go on living in unbearable agony.
Ask the <ent type='NORP'>Palestinian</ent> people who stand up to bullets every day --
or the <ent type='NORP'>Rumanian</ent> people, or the <ent type='NORP'>Guatemalan</ent> people, or the <ent type='NORP'>Filipino</ent>
people, or the <ent type='NORP'>Chinese</ent> people, or the <ent type='NORP'>Iranian</ent> people, or the
<ent type='NORP'>Tibetan</ent> people, or the <ent type='NORP'>Timorese</ent> people.</p>

<p> If we prove to be too lazy now, OUR generation may even see the day
when citizens will speak softly and listen intently for the footsteps
of the <ent type='ORG'>Gestapo</ent> who may finally come to kick down our front door and
arrest us for plotting to regain the Constitutional freedoms
that were once our heritage.</p>

<p> <ent type='PERSON'>John</ent> DiNardo</p>

<div>---------------------------------------------------------------------------</div>

<p> Excerpted from the book, "Rape of The Constitution; Death of Freedom" by
Gyeorgos C. Hatonn . </p>

<p> *** The <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> Syndicate ***</p>

<div> ========================================================================</div>

<p> Many <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> conservatives believe as a matter of faith that the
<ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent>s and <ent type='ORG'>the Council</ent> on Foreign Relations exercise absolute
control over the government and the people of the U.S. This thesis can
be accepted as a working formula if one remains conscious of the larger
issues. Two writers for whom the present writer (E.M) has great respect,
Dr. <ent type='PERSON'>Emanuel Josephson</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Morris Bealle</ent>, insisted on focusing on the
<ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent>s and excluding all other aspects of the World Order. This
severely limited the effect of their otherwise groundbreaking work on the
Medical Monopoly. This writer advanced a contrary view in "<ent type='ORG'>The World</ent>
Order," fixing upon the <ent type='PERSON'>Rothschild</ent> monetary power, which reached a point
of world control by 1885, and its <ent type='GPE'>London</ent> policy group, the Royal
Institute of International Affairs, as the policy makers for what has
essentially been, since 1900, a re-established colonial government,
functions primarily through <ent type='ORG'>the Council</ent> on Foreign Relations, but only as
the subsidiary of <ent type='ORG'>RIIA</ent> and through the <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> Foundation, which
controls government functions, the educational establishments, the media,
the religions and the state legislatures. </p>

<p> It is true that the <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> colonials have "free elections," in which
they have the absolute right to vote for one of two opposing candidates,
both of whom have been handpicked and financed by the <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent>
syndicate. This touching evidence of "democracy" serves to convince most
<ent type='NORP'>Americans</ent> that you are indeed a free people. You even have a cracked
<ent type='ORG'>Liberty Bell</ent> in <ent type='GPE'>Philadelphia</ent> to prove it. <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> youths have been free
since 1900 to be marched off to die in <ent type='NORP'>Hegelian</ent> wars in which both
combatants received their instructions from the World Order. You are free
to invest in a stock market in which the daily quantity,price and value
of the monetary unit is manipulated and controlled by a Federal Reserve
System which is answerable only to <ent type='ORG'>the Bank</ent> of England. It has maintained
its vaunted "independence" from your government control, but this is the
only independence it has ever had. </p>

<p> The realization that you do indeed live under the dictates of the
"<ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> Syndicate" can well be the starting point of the long road
back of a genuine struggle for <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> independence. In exposing "the
<ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent>s" as agents of a foreign power, which is not merely a foreign
power, but a genuine world government, you must realize that this is not
merely a group dedicated to making money, but a group which is committed
to maintaining the power of a colonial form of government over the
<ent type='NORP'>American</ent> people. Thus the ancient calumny of <ent type='PERSON'>John</ent> D. <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> as a
man obsessed by greed (a category in which he has plenty of company)
obscures the fact that from the day the <ent type='PERSON'>Rothschild</ent>s began to finance his
march towards a total oil monopoly in <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States from their
coffers at <ent type='ORG'>the National City Bank</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>Cleveland</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> was never an
independent power, nor does any department of the <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> Syndicate
operate as an independent power. You know that the <ent type='ORG'>Cosa Nostra</ent>, or
<ent type='ORG'>Mafia</ent>, with which the Syndicate is closely allied, has somewhat
autonomous power in the regions which have been assigned to that
particular "family" by the national directors, but this always implies
that that family remains under total control and answerable for
everything which occurs in its territory. </p>

<p> Similarly, the <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> Syndicate operates under clearly defined
spheres of influence. The "charitable" organizations, the business
companies and the policy groups, always meld into a working operation,
nor can any department of the Syndicate strike out on its own or
formulate an independent policy, no matter what may be its
justification. </p>

<p> The <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> Syndicate operates under the control of the world
financial structure, which means that on any given day, all of its assets
could be rendered close to worthless by adroit financial manipulation.
This is the final control, which ensures that no one can quit the
organization. Not only would he be stripped of all assets, but he would
be under contract for immediate assassination. <ent type='ORG'>The Department</ent> of Justice
is well aware that the only "terrorists" operating in <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States
are the agents of the World Order, but they prudently avoid any mention
of this fact. </p>

<p> The world financial structure, far from being an unknown or hidden
organization, is actually well known and well defined. It consists of
the major <ent type='NORP'>Swiss</ent> Banks; the survivors of the old <ent type='NORP'>Venetian</ent>-<ent type='NORP'>Genoese</ent> banking
axis; <ent type='ORG'>the Big Five</ent> of the world grain trade; the <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> combine,
centered in <ent type='ORG'>the Bank</ent> of England and its chartered merchant banks,
functioning through the <ent type='PERSON'>Rothschild</ent>s and the <ent type='ORG'>Oppenheimers</ent> and having
absolute control over their Canadian colony through <ent type='ORG'>the Royal Bank</ent> of
<ent type='GPE'>Canada</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>the Bank</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>Montreal</ent>, their Canadian lieutenants being the
Bronfmans, Belzbergs, Reichmanns and other financial operators; and the
colonial banking structure in the U.S., controlled by <ent type='ORG'>the Bank</ent> of England
through the <ent type='ORG'>Federal Reserve System</ent>; the <ent type='GPE'>Boston</ent> Brahmin families who made
their fortunes in the opium trade, including the <ent type='PERSON'>Delanos</ent> and others and
the <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> Bank, <ent type='ORG'>Chase Manhattan Bank</ent>, <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> Express, the present
form of the old <ent type='PERSON'>Rothschild</ent> representatives in the U.S., which includes
<ent type='ORG'>Kuhn</ent>,Loeb Company and <ent type='ORG'>Lehman Brothers</ent>. </p>

<p> It is notable that the <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> Syndicate is far down on the list of
the worlds financial structure. Why then is it of such importance?
Although it is not the crucial factor in financial decision in the
<ent type='LOC'>Western Hemisphere</ent>, it is the actual working control mechanism of the
<ent type='NORP'>American</ent> colony. The <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> family themselves,like the
Morgans,<ent type='PERSON'>Schiff</ent>s and <ent type='PERSON'>Warburgs</ent>, have faded into insignificance, but the
mechanism created in their name roars along at full power,still
maintaining all of the functions for which it was organized. Since he
set up the <ent type='ORG'>Trilateral Commission</ent>, David <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> has functioned as a
sort of international courier for the World Order, principally concerned
with delivering working instructions to the <ent type='NORP'>Communist</ent> bloc,either
directly, in <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent> or by traveling to the area. Laurence <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent>
is active in the operation of the Medical Monopoly, but his principal
interests are in operating various vacation spas in tropical areas. They
are the two survivors of the "Fortunate Five," the five sons of <ent type='PERSON'>John</ent> D.
<ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent>, Jr. and <ent type='PERSON'>Abby Aldrich</ent>. <ent type='PERSON'>John</ent> D. <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent>, Jr. died in an
institution in <ent type='GPE'>Tucson</ent>,<ent type='GPE'>Arizona</ent> and was hastily cremated. <ent type='PERSON'>John</ent> D.
<ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> III died in a mysterious accident on a <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent> Parkway near
his home. Nelson <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent>, named after his grandfather, died in the
arms of a TV journalist. It was later revealed that he had also been in
the arms of another TV journalist at the same time; the death was hushed
up for many hours. It was generally believed that he ran afoul of his
<ent type='GPE'>Columbian</ent> drug connection, the disagreement hardly being trivial; it
involved several billion dollars in drug profits which had not been
properly apportioned. <ent type='PERSON'>Winthrop</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> died an alcoholic in the arms
of his black boy friend. He had been interviewed on television by Harry
Reasoner to explain his hasty move from <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent> to <ent type='GPE'>Arkansas</ent>. <ent type='PERSON'>Winthrop</ent>
learned that his black boy friend, an <ent type='ORG'>Army</ent> sergeant who apparently taught
him the mysteries of drill,refused to live in <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent>. To celebrate this
alliance, <ent type='PERSON'>Winthrop</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> gave <ent type='PERSON'>magnificiently</ent> to <ent type='ORG'>Negro</ent>
causes,including the <ent type='ORG'>Urban League</ent> building on East 48th Street in New
York. A plaque on the second floor notes that it was his gift; it might
well have stated "From <ent type='PERSON'>Hadrian</ent> to his Antinous." </p>

<p> We do not wish to imply that the <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent>s no longer have influence,
but that the major policy dictates of the <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> Syndicate are
handed down by other caps, of whom they continue to be a visible force.
Through the person of David <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent>, the family is sometimes called
"the first family of <ent type='GPE'>the Soviet Union</ent>." Only he and Dr. <ent type='PERSON'>Armand Hammer</ent>,
the moving force behind USTEC, have permanent permission to land their
private planes at the <ent type='GPE'>Moscow</ent> Airport. Others would suffer the fate of <ent type='ORG'>KAL</ent>
007. David Rockefeller's most significant trip to <ent type='GPE'>the Soviet Union</ent> may
have been the fateful day when he landed in <ent type='GPE'>Moscow</ent>, having been told to
inform <ent type='NORP'>Khrushchev</ent> that he was "through". The <ent type='NORP'>Russians</ent> are very health
conscious, and a scientist had sent information to <ent type='NORP'>Khrushchev</ent> that the
use of chemical fertilizers in <ent type='GPE'>the Soviet Union</ent> presented a threat to the
people. <ent type='NORP'>Khrushchev</ent> then announced a major change in the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> farm
policy, centering around a reduction in the use of chemicals. This was
upsetting to the head of the world's <ent type='ORG'>Chemical Fertilizer</ent> trust, David
<ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent>, and he responded with a terse one word command, "Out". </p>

<p> Both the <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> family fortune and the considerable portion set
aside in the foundations of the <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> Syndicate are effectively
insulated against any type of government control. <ent type='ORG'>FORTUNE</ent> magazine noted
August ,1986, that <ent type='PERSON'>John</ent> D. <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent>,Jr. had created trusts in 1934
which now amounted to some $2.3 billion; another 200 million had been set
aside for the <ent type='PERSON'>Abby</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> branch. The five sons had trusts which in
1986 amounted to $2.1 billion. These trusts had originally amounted to
only $50 million each,showing the increase in their assets as well as
inflation during the ensuing half century. <ent type='ORG'>FORTUNE</ent> estimated the 1986
total <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> wealth as $3.5 billion of which $900 million was in
securities and real estate. They owned 45% of the Time Life
Building; Nelson Rockefeller's <ent type='ORG'>International Basic Economy Corporation</ent> had
been sold to a <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> company in 1980. For years, the <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> family
had deliberately kept the rents low in its major holding, <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent>
Center, a $1.6 billion investment yielding an annual return of 1% . This
was a convenient <ent type='ORG'>manuever</ent> for tax purposes, and a good one at that. </p>

<p> Much of the <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> wealth might be attributed to old <ent type='PERSON'>John</ent> D.'s
rapacity and ruthlessness; its origins are indubitably based in his
initial financing from <ent type='ORG'>the National City Bank</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>Cleveland</ent>, which was
identified in <ent type='ORG'>Congressional</ent> reports as one of the three <ent type='PERSON'>Rothschild</ent> banks
in <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States and by his later acceptance of the guidance of Jacob
<ent type='PERSON'>Schiff</ent> of <ent type='ORG'>Kuhn</ent>,Loeb Company, who had been born in the <ent type='PERSON'>Rothschild</ent> house in
<ent type='GPE'>Franfort</ent> and was now the principal <ent type='PERSON'>Rothschild</ent> representive (but unknown
as such to the public) in <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States. </p>

<p> With the seed money from <ent type='ORG'>the National City Bank</ent> in <ent type='GPE'>Cleveland</ent>, old <ent type='PERSON'>John</ent> D.
<ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> soon laid claim to the title of the "most ruthless <ent type='NORP'>American</ent>".
It is more than likely that it was this quality which persuaded the
<ent type='PERSON'>Rothschild</ent>s to back him. <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> realized early in the game that the
oil refinery business, which could offer great profits in a short time,
also was at the mercy of uncontrolled competition. His solution was a
simple one--crush all competition. The famous <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> dedication to
total monopoly was simply a business decision. <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> embarked on a
campaign of coercing all competing oil refineries out of business. He
attacked on a number of fronts, which is also a lesson to all would be
entrepreneurs. First, he would send a minion, not known to be working for
<ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent>, with an offer to buy the competing refinery for a low
price,but offering cash. If the offer was refused, the competitor would
then come under attack from a competing refinery which greatly undercut
his price. He might also suffer a sudden strike at his refinery,which
would force him to shut down. Control of labor through unions has always
been a basic <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> technique. Like <ent type='GPE'>the Soviet Union</ent>, they seldom
have labor trouble. If these techniques failed, <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> would then
be saddened by a reluctant decision to use violence; beating the rival
workers as they went to and from their jobs, or burning or blowing up the
competing refinery. </p>

<p> These techniques convinced the <ent type='PERSON'>Rothschild</ent>s that they had found their
man.They sent their personal representative,<ent type='PERSON'>Jacob Schiff</ent>, to <ent type='GPE'>Cleveland</ent> to
help <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> plan further expansion. At this time,the <ent type='PERSON'>Rothschild</ent>s
controlled 95% of all railroad mileage in <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States,through the
J.P. <ent type='ORG'>Morgan Company</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>Kuhn Loeb Company</ent>,according to official
Department of Commerce figures for the year 1895. J.P. Morgan mentions in
his "Who's Who" listing that he controlled 50000 miles of U.S.
railways. <ent type='PERSON'>Schiff</ent> worked out an elaborate rebate deal for
<ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent>,through a dummy corporation,<ent type='ORG'>South Improvement Company</ent>. These
rebates ensured that no other oil company could survive in competition
with the <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> firm. The scheme was later exposed,but by that time
<ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> had achieved a virtual monopoly of the oil business in the
U.S. The daughter of one of his victims, <ent type='PERSON'>Ida Tarbell</ent>,whose father was
ruined by Rockefeller's criminal operations, wrote the first major expose
of <ent type='ORG'>the Standard Oil Trust</ent>. She was promptly denounced as a "muckracker"
by the poseur, <ent type='PERSON'>Theodore Roosevelt</ent>, who claimed to be a "trustbuster." In
fact, he ensured the dominance of <ent type='ORG'>the Standard Oil Trust</ent> and other giant
trusts. </p>

<p> During the next half century, <ent type='PERSON'>John</ent> D. <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> was routinely
caricatured by socialist propagandists as the epitome of the ruthless
capitalist. At the same time, he was the principal financier of the
world <ent type='NORP'>Communist</ent> movement, through a firm called <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> International
Company. Despite the fact that <ent type='ORG'>the House</ent> of <ent type='PERSON'>Rothschild</ent> had already
achieved world control,the sound and the fury was directed exclusively
against its two principal representatives,<ent type='PERSON'>John</ent> D. <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> and J.P.
Morgan. One of the few revelations of the actual state of affairs
appeared in <ent type='ORG'>TRUTH</ent> magazine,Dec 161912, which pointed out that "Mr.
<ent type='PERSON'>Schiff</ent> is head of the great private banking house of <ent type='ORG'>Kuhn</ent>, Loeb Company
(I knew some of you bright readers would finally pick up that these names
are all attached to the greatest pharmaceutical firms in the world--even
into your very vitamin supplement business!), which represents the
<ent type='PERSON'>Rothschild</ent> interests on your side of the <ent type='LOC'>Atlantic</ent>. He is described as a
financial strategist and has been for years the financial minister of the
great impersonal power known as <ent type='ORG'>Standard Oil</ent>." Note that the name of
<ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> was not mentioned in the quote. </p>

<p> Because of these concealed factors,it was a relatively simple matter for
the <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> public to accept the "fact" that the <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent>s were the
preeminent power in your country. This myth was actually clothed in the
apparel of power,the <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> Oil Trust becoming the
"military-industrial complex" which assumed political control of the
nation; the <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> Medical Monopoly attained control of the health
care of the nation, and the <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> Foundation, a web of affiliated
tax emempt creations, effectively controlled the religious and
educational life of the nation. The myth succeeded in its goal of
camouflaging the hidden rulers, the <ent type='PERSON'>Rothschild</ent>s. </p>

<p> After <ent type='PERSON'>Eustis Mullins</ent> and a few others, had been exposing this charade for
some twenty-five years a new myth began to be noised about in <ent type='NORP'>American</ent>
conservative circles, effectively propagated by active double agents.
This myth found a host of eager believers,because it heralded a growing
crack in the monolithic power which had been oppressing all the peoples
of the world. This "new" revelation was that a struggle to the death for
world power had developed between the <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent>s and the <ent type='PERSON'>Rothschild</ent>s.
According to this startling development, one faction or the other,
depending on which agent you were listening to, had gained control of the
<ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> Union and would use its power as the basis for achieving the
overthrow of the other faction. The sudden death of several members of
the <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> family was cited as "proof" that such a struggle was
taking place, although no <ent type='PERSON'>Rothschild</ent> is known to have succumbed during
this "war." This ignored the general understanding that Nelson
<ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> had been "eliminated" as the result of losing deposit slips
for several billion dollars of drugs from the <ent type='GPE'>Columbian</ent> cartel, or that
the other <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> deaths showed no trace of a "<ent type='PERSON'>Rothschild</ent>
connection." </p>

<p> Having maintained extensive files on this situation for several decades,
the writer (E.M.),could not believe anyone could be so misinformed as to
think that "the <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent>s" were now trying to seize power from the
<ent type='PERSON'>Rothschild</ent>s, at a time when the influence of members of the <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent>
family was already in great decline, their family finances being handled
by <ent type='PERSON'>John</ent> J. McCloy, and other faithful retainers;none of the retainers
would have been willing to engage in a genuine power struggle, as they
were faceless managers who lived only for their weekly paycheck. They
had no ambitions of their own. Nevertheless, many hopeful <ent type='NORP'>Americans</ent>
grasped at the will-o-the-wisp notion the <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent>s were now "good
<ent type='NORP'>Americans</ent>" who were willing to risk all to overthrow the <ent type='PERSON'>Rothschild</ent>s.
Amazingly enough, this pernicious story persisted for almost a decade
before being relegated to the curiosities of history. </p>

<p> Like J.P. Morgan, who had begun his commercial career by selling the U.S.
<ent type='ORG'>Army</ent> some defective guns, the famous Hall carbine affair, <ent type='PERSON'>John</ent> D.
<ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> also was a war profiteer during <ent type='EVENT'>the Civil War</ent>;he sold
unstamped Harkness liquor to Federal troops at a high profit, gaining the
initial capital to embark on his drive for monopoly. His interest in the
oil business was a natural one; his father,<ent type='PERSON'>William</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> had been
"in oil" for years. <ent type='PERSON'>William</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> had become an oil entrepreneur
after salt wells at <ent type='ORG'>Tarentum</ent>, near <ent type='GPE'>Pittsburgh</ent>, were discovered in 1842 to
be flowing with oil. The owners of the wells,<ent type='PERSON'>Samuel</ent> L. <ent type='PERSON'>Kier</ent>, began to
bottle the oil and sell it for medicinal purposes. One of his earliest
wholesalers was <ent type='PERSON'>William</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent>. The "medicine" was originally
labelled "Kier's Magic Oil". <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> printed his own labels, using
"<ent type='ORG'>Rock Oil</ent>" or "Seneca Oil", Seneca being the name of a well known <ent type='NORP'>Indian</ent>
Tribe. <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> achieved his greatest notoriety and his greatest
profits by advertising himself as "<ent type='PERSON'>William</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent>, the Celebrated
Cancer Specialist". It is understandable that his grandsons would become
the controlling power behind the scenes of the world's most famous cancer
treatment center and would direct government funds and charitable
contributions to those areas which only benefit the Medical Monopoly.
<ent type='PERSON'>William</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> spared no claim in his flamboyant career. He
guaranteed "All Cases of Cancer Cured Unless They Are Too Far Gone". Such
were the healing powers that he attributed to his magic cancer cure that
he was able to retail it for $25 a bottle, a sum then equivalent to two
month's wages. The "cure" consisted of a few well known diuretics, which
had been diluted by water. This carnival medicine show barker could
hardly have envisioned that his descendants would control the greatest
and the most profitable Medical Monopoly in recorded history. </p>

<p> As an itinerant "carnie", a traveling carnival peddler, <ent type='PERSON'>William</ent>
<ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> had chosen a career which interfered with developing a stable
family life. His son, <ent type='PERSON'>John</ent>, rarely saw him, a circumstance which has
inspired some psychological analysts to conjecture that the absence of a
father figure or parental love may have contributed to <ent type='PERSON'>John</ent> D.
Rockefeller's subsequent development as a money mad tyrant who plotted to
maim, poison and kill millions of his fellow <ent type='NORP'>Americans</ent> during almost a
century of his monopolistic operations and whose influence, reaching up
from the grave, remains the most dire and malignant presence in <ent type='NORP'>American</ent>
life. This may have been a contributing factor--however, it is also
possible that he was totally evil. It is hardly arguable that he is
probably one of the most Satanic figures in <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> history. Evil being
defined as anything that moves the spiritual aspect of beingness away
from God as influenced through another. </p>

<p> It has long been a truism that you can find a horse thief or two in any
prominent <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> family. In the <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> family, it was more than
true in the case of <ent type='PERSON'>William</ent> who seemed to have faithfully followed the
precepts of the Will of <ent type='GPE'>Canaan</ent> throughout his career, "love robbery, love
lechery". He fled from a number of indictments for horse stealing and
you know how serious that is, finally disappearing altogether as <ent type='PERSON'>William</ent>
and <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> and magically re-emerging as a Dr. <ent type='PERSON'>William</ent> Levingston of
<ent type='GPE'>Philadelphia</ent>, a name which he retained for the rest of his life. An
investigative reporter at <ent type='PERSON'>Joseph Pulitzer</ent>'s <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent> World received a tip
that was followed up. <ent type='ORG'>The World</ent> then disclosed that <ent type='PERSON'>William</ent> Avery
<ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> had died May 11, 1906 in <ent type='GPE'>Freeport</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Illinois</ent>, where he was
interred in an unmarked grave as Dr. <ent type='PERSON'>William</ent> Levingston. </p>

<p> <ent type='PERSON'>William</ent> Rockefeller's vocation as a medicine man greatly facilitated his
preferred profession of horse thief. As one who planned to be in the
next county by morning, it was a simple matter to tie a handsome stallion
to the back of his wagon and head for the open road. It also played a
large part in his vocation as a woman-chaser; he was described as being
"woman-mad". </p>

<p> On June 281849, he was indicted for raping a hired girl in Cayuga,New
York; he later was found to be residing in <ent type='GPE'>Oswego</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent> and was
forced once again to decamp for parts unknown. He had no difficulty in
financing his woman-chasing interests from the sale of his miraculous
cancer cure and from another product, his "Wonder Working Liniment",
which he offered at only two dollars a bottle. It consisted of crude
petroleum from which the lighter oils had been boiled away, leaving a
heavy solution of paraffin,lube oil and tar, which comprised the
"liniment". <ent type='PERSON'>William</ent> Rockefeller's original miracle oil survived until
quite recently as a concoction called <ent type='ORG'>Nujol</ent>, consisting principally of
petroleum and peddled as a laxative. It was well known that <ent type='ORG'>Nujol</ent> was
merely an advertising sobriquet meaning "new oil", as opposed apparently,
to "old oil". Sold as an antidote to constipation, it robbed the body of
fat-soluble vitamins, it being a well-established medical fact that
mineral oil coated the intestine and prevented the absorption of many
needed vitamins and other nutritional needs. Its makers added carotine
as a sop to the health-conscious, but it was hardly worth the bother.
<ent type='ORG'>Nujol</ent> was manufactured by a subsidiary of <ent type='ORG'>Standard Oil</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>New Jersey</ent>,
called <ent type='PERSON'>Stanco</ent>, whose only other product, manufactured on the same
premises, was the famous insecticide, Flit. </p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>Nujol</ent> was hawked from the Senate Office Building in <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent> for years
during a more liberal interpretation of "conflict of interest". In this
case, it was hardly a conflict of interest, because the august
peddler,Senator Royal S. <ent type='PERSON'>Copeland</ent>, never had any interests other than
serving the <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent>s. He was a physician whom <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> had
appointed as head of the <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent> State Department of Health and later
financed his campaign for the Senate. Copeland's frank display of
commercialism amazed even the most blase' <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent> reporters. </p>

<p> He devoted his Senate career to a daily program advertising <ent type='ORG'>Nujol</ent>. A
microphone was set up in his Senate office each morning, the first order
of business being the <ent type='ORG'>Nujol</ent> program, for which he was paid $75000 a
year, an enormous salary in the 1930's and more than the salary of the
President of <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States. Senator Copeland's exploits earned him a
number of nicknames on Capital Hill. He was often called the Senator from
the <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> Medical Association, because of his enthusiastic backing for
any program launched by the <ent type='ORG'>AMA</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Morris Fishbein</ent>. More realistically,
he was usually referred to as "the Senator from <ent type='ORG'>Standard Oil</ent>". He could
be counted on to promote any legislation devised for the greater profit
of the <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> monopoly. During congressional debate on <ent type='ORG'>the Food and</ent>
Drug Act in 1938, he came under criticism from <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>woman Leonor
<ent type='PERSON'>Sullivan</ent>, who charged that Senator <ent type='PERSON'>Copeland</ent>, a physician who handled the
bill on the Senate floor, frankly acknowledged during the debate that
soap was exempted from the law because the soap manufacturers, who were
the nation's largest advertisers, would otherwise join with other big
industries to fight the bill. <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>woman <ent type='PERSON'>Sullivan</ent> complained that,
"Soap was officially declared in the law not to be a cosmetic. The hair
dye manufacturers were given a license to market known dangerous
products, just so long as they placed a special warning on the label -
but what woman in a beauty parlor ever sees the label on the bulk
container in which hair dye is shipped?" </p>

<p> Just as the elder <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> had spent his life in the pursuit of his
personal obsession, women, so his son <ent type='PERSON'>John</ent> was equally obsessed, being
money-mad instead of woman-mad, totally committed to the pursuit of
ever-increasing wealth and power. However, the principal accomplishments
of the <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> drive for power, the rebate scheme for monopoly, the
chartering of the foundations to gain power over <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> citizens,the
creation of the central bank, the <ent type='ORG'>Federal Reserve System</ent>, the backing of
the World <ent type='NORP'>Communist</ent> Revolution and the creation of the Medical Monoply,
all came from the <ent type='PERSON'>Rothschild</ent>s or from their European employees. </p>

<p> We cannot find in the records of <ent type='PERSON'>John</ent> D. <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> that he originated
any of these programs. The concept of the tax exempt charitable
foundation originated with the <ent type='PERSON'>Rothschild</ent> minion, <ent type='PERSON'>George Peabody</ent>, in
1865. <ent type='ORG'>The Peabody Educational</ent> Foundation later became the <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent>
Foundation and many of you should recall that item. Not that you might
have been around then but it continues to inadvertently be referred to as
such. </p>

<p> It is unlikely that even the diabolical mind of <ent type='PERSON'>John</ent> D. <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> could
have conceived of this devious twist. A social historian has described
the major development of the late nineteenth century, when charitable
foundations and world Communism became important movements, as one of the
more interesting facets of history, perhaps equivalent to the discovery
of the wheel or fire. This new discovery was the concept developed by
the rats, who after all have rather highly developed intelligences, that
they could trap people by baiting traps with little bits of cheese. The
history of mankind since then has been the rats catching humans in their
traps. Socialism -- indeed, any government program -- is simply the rat
baiting the trap with a smidgeon of cheese and catching himself a human. </p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>man <ent type='PERSON'>Wright Patman</ent>, chairman of <ent type='ORG'>the House</ent> Banking and Currency
Committee, noted from the floor of <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent> that the establishment of the
<ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> Foundation effectively insulated <ent type='ORG'>Standard Oil</ent> from
competition. The controlling stock had been removed from market
manipulation or possible buyouts by competitors. It also relieved
<ent type='ORG'>Standard Oil</ent> from most taxation, which then placed a tremendous added
burden on individual <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> taxpayers. Although a <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> relative
by marriage, Senator <ent type='PERSON'>Nelson Aldrich</ent>, <ent type='NORP'>Republican</ent> majority leader in the
Senate, had pushed <ent type='ORG'>the General</ent> Education Board charter through <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>,
the <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> Foundation charter proved to be more difficult.
Widespread criticism of Rockefeller's monopolistic practices was heard,
and his effort to insulate his profits from taxation or takeover was seen
for what it was. The charter was finally pushed through in 1913 (the
significant <ent type='NORP'>Masonic</ent> numeral 13 -- 1913 was also the year of the
progressive income tax and of the enactment of <ent type='ORG'>the Federal Reserve Act</ent>).
Senator <ent type='PERSON'>Robert</ent> F. Wagner of <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent>, another Senator from <ent type='ORG'>Standard Oil</ent>
(there were quite a few), ramrodded the <ent type='ORG'>Congressional</ent> approval of the
charter. The charter was then signed by <ent type='PERSON'>John</ent> D. <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>John</ent> D.
<ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent>, Jr., <ent type='PERSON'>Henry Pratt Judson</ent>, president of the <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent>
established University of Chicago,<ent type='PERSON'>Simon Flexner</ent>, director of the
<ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> Institute, <ent type='PERSON'>Starr Jameson</ent>, described in "Who's Who" as
"personal counsel to <ent type='PERSON'>John</ent> D. <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> in his benevolences", and
Charles W. <ent type='PERSON'>Eliot</ent>, president of <ent type='ORG'>Harvard University</ent>. </p>

<p> The <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> Oil Monopoly is now 127 years old, yet in 1911, the
<ent type='ORG'>Supreme Court</ent>, bowing to public outrage, had ruled that it had to be
broken up. The resulting companies proved to be no problem for the
<ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> interests. The family retained a two per cent holding in
each of the "new" companies, while the <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> foundations took a
three per cent holding in each company. This gave them a five per cent
stock interest in each company; a one per cent holding in a corporation
is usually sufficient to maintain working control. </p>

<p> The involvement of the <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent>s in promoting the World <ent type='NORP'>Communist</ent>
Revolution also developed from their business interests. There was never
any commitment to the <ent type='NORP'>Marxist</ent> ideology; like anything else, it was there
to be used. At the turn of the century, <ent type='ORG'>Standard Oil</ent> was competing
fiercely with <ent type='ORG'>Royal Dutch Shell</ent> for control of the lucrative European
market. <ent type='ORG'>Congressional</ent> testimony revealed that <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> had sent large
sums of money to <ent type='PERSON'>Lenin</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Trotsky</ent> to instigate the <ent type='NORP'>Communist</ent> Revolution
in 1905. His banker, <ent type='PERSON'>Jacob Schiff</ent> had previously financed the <ent type='NORP'>Japanese</ent> in
their war against <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent> and had sent a personal emissary, <ent type='PERSON'>George Kennan</ent>
to <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent> to spend some twenty years in promoting revolutionary activity
against the Czar. </p>

<p> When the 1905 revolution failed, <ent type='PERSON'>Lenin</ent> was placed "in storage" in
<ent type='GPE'>Switzerland</ent> until 1907. <ent type='PERSON'>Trotsky</ent> was brought to the U.S., where he lived
rent free on the <ent type='ORG'>Standard Oil</ent> property at <ent type='GPE'>Bayonne</ent>,<ent type='GPE'>New Jersey</ent>, its tank
field. When the Czar abdicated, <ent type='PERSON'>Trotsky</ent> was placed on a ship with three
hundred <ent type='NORP'>Communist</ent> revolutionaries from <ent type='LOC'>the Lower East Side</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent>.
<ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> obtained a special passport for <ent type='PERSON'>Trotsky</ent> from <ent type='PERSON'>Woodrow Wilson</ent>
and sent <ent type='PERSON'>Lincoln Steffens</ent> with him to make sure he was returned safely to
<ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>. For traveling expenses, <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> placed a purse containing
$10000 in Trotsky's pocket. </p>

<p> On April 131917, when the ship stopped in <ent type='GPE'>Halifax</ent>, Canadian Secret
Service officers immediately arrested <ent type='PERSON'>Trotsky</ent> and interred him in Nova
Scotia. The case became an international cause celebre, as leading
government officials from several nations frantically demanded Trotsky's
release. <ent type='ORG'>The Secret Service</ent> had been tipped off that <ent type='PERSON'>Trotsky</ent> was on his
way to take <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent> out of the war, freeing more <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> armies to attack
Canadian troups on the Western Front. </p>

<p> Prime Minister <ent type='PERSON'>Lloyd George</ent> hurriedly cabled orders from <ent type='GPE'>London</ent> to the
Canadian Secret Service to free <ent type='PERSON'>Trotsky</ent> at once - they ignored him.
<ent type='PERSON'>Trotsky</ent> was finally freed by the intervention of one of Rockefeller's
most faithful stooges, Canadian Minister <ent type='PERSON'>Mackenzie King</ent>, who had long
been a "labor specialist" for the <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent>s. King personally obtained
Trotsky's release and sent him on his way as the emissary of the
<ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent>s, commissioned to win <ent type='EVENT'>the Bolshevik Revolution</ent>. Thus, Dr.
<ent type='PERSON'>Armand Hammer</ent>, who loudly proclaimed his influence in <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent> as the
friend of <ent type='PERSON'>Lenin</ent>, has an insignificant claim compared to the role of the
<ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent>s in backing world Communism. </p>

<p> Although Communism, like other "isms", had origined with Marx's
association with <ent type='ORG'>the House</ent> of <ent type='PERSON'>Rothschild</ent>, it enlisted the reverent
support of <ent type='PERSON'>John</ent> D. <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> because he saw Communism for what it is,
the ultimate monopoly, not only controlling the government, the monetary
system and all property, but also a monopoly which, like the corporations
it emulates, is self-perpetuating and eternal. It was the logical
progression from his <ent type='ORG'>Standard Oil</ent> monopoly. </p>

<p> An important step on the road to world monopoly was the most far-reaching
corporation invented by the <ent type='PERSON'>Rothschild</ent>s. This was the international drug
and chemical cartel, I. G. <ent type='ORG'>Farben</ent>. Called "a state within a state" , it
was created in 1925 as Interessen Gemeinschaft Farbeinindustrie Aktien
Gesellschaft, usually known simply as I. G. <ent type='ORG'>Farben</ent>, which simply meant
"The <ent type='ORG'>Cartel</ent>". It had originated in 1904, when the six major chemical
companies in <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> began negotiations to form the ultimate cartel,
merging Badische Anilin,Bayer,Agfa,Hoechst,Weiler-ter-Meer, and
Greisheim-Electron. The guiding spirit,as well as the financing, came
from the <ent type='PERSON'>Rothschild</ent>s, who were represented by their <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> banker, Max
Warburg of M. M. Warburg Company, <ent type='GPE'>Hamburg</ent>. He later headed the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>
Secret Service during <ent type='EVENT'>World War</ent> I and was personal financial advisor to
the <ent type='PERSON'>Kaiser</ent>. </p>

<p> When the <ent type='PERSON'>Kaiser</ent> was overthrown, after losing the war, <ent type='PERSON'>Max Warburg</ent> was not
exiled with him to <ent type='GPE'>Holland</ent>; instead he became the financial advisor to
the new government. </p>

<p> Monarchs may come and go, but the real power remains with the bankers.
While representing <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> at <ent type='EVENT'>the Paris Peace Conference</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Max Warburg</ent>
spent pleasant hours renewing family ties with his brother, <ent type='PERSON'>Paul Warburg</ent>,
who, after drafting <ent type='ORG'>the Federal Reserve Act</ent> at <ent type='GPE'>Jekyll Island</ent>, had headed
the U.S. banking system during the war. He was in <ent type='GPE'>Paris</ent> as Woodrow
Wilson's financial advisor. </p>

<p> I. G. <ent type='ORG'>Farben</ent> soon had a net worth of six billion marks, controlling some
five hundred firms. Its first president was Professor <ent type='PERSON'>Carl Bosch</ent>. During
the period of <ent type='GPE'>the Weimar Republic</ent>, I.G. <ent type='ORG'>Farben</ent> officials,seeing the
handwriting, began a close association with one called <ent type='PERSON'>Adolf Hitler</ent>,
supplying much needed funds and political influence. </p>

<p> The success of the I.G. <ent type='ORG'>Farben</ent> cartel had aroused the interest of other
industrialists. <ent type='PERSON'>Henry Ford</ent> was favorably impressed and set up a <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>
branch of <ent type='ORG'>Ford</ent> Motor Company. Forty percent of the stock was purchased by
I.G. <ent type='ORG'>Farben</ent>. I.G. <ent type='ORG'>Farben</ent> then established an <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> subsidiary called
<ent type='NORP'>American</ent> I.G., in cooperation with <ent type='ORG'>Standard Oil</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>New Jersey</ent>. Its
directors included <ent type='PERSON'>Walter Teagle</ent>, President of <ent type='ORG'>Standard Oil</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Paul Warburg</ent>
of <ent type='ORG'>Kuhn</ent>,Loeb Company and <ent type='ORG'>Edsel</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Ford</ent>, representing the <ent type='ORG'>Ford</ent> interests.
<ent type='PERSON'>John</ent> Foster Dulles, for the law firm, <ent type='PERSON'>Sullivan</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>Cromwell</ent>, became the
attorney for I.G., frequently traveling between <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Berlin</ent> on
cartel business. His law partner, <ent type='PERSON'>Arthur Dean</ent>, is now director of the
$40 million <ent type='PERSON'>Teagle</ent> Foundation which was set up before Teagle's death.
Like other fortunes, it had become part of the network. </p>

<p> =============Continued in <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> Syndicate Part 2===================</p>

<p>--
-* <ent type='PERSON'>Don</ent> Allen *- // Only | Tavistock + Esalen = "New Age"
Internet: dona@bilver.uucp <ent type='ORG'>\X</ent>/ Amiga | <ent type='PERSON'>Rothschild</ent> + <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> = <ent type='ORG'>FED</ent>
<ent type='ORG'>UUCP</ent>: .uunet!peora!bilver!vicstoy!dona | UN + Maitreya = "Twilight Zone"
"A democracy cannot be both ignorant and free" - <ent type='PERSON'>Thomas Jefferson</ent></p>

<p> EXPOSE: <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> Syndicate - <ent type='ORG'>Secret Govt</ent> pt 1 (53K)</p>

<p>This text is being posted with the intent to EDUCATE those of you who
know not the silent and pervasive influence of your hidden masters. Some
have looked for shadows of the old illuminati; they look amiss, not seeing
that which is all around them. If you know not the "who" and the "why",
efforts will be mis-directed. This is NOT a "conspiracy"..nay, it is a
very cold and calculated NETWORK of individuals whose intent is nothing
short of implementation of a "<ent type='EVENT'>New World</ent> Order"; an oligarchic rein in which
*you* serve as little more that slaves in their "technocracy". This network
has every intention to implement a cashless society, for it is they who
control every aspect of finance and banking over the entire globe. They
have had about 100 years to perfect their plans and put them into practice.

Please understand that the <ent type='NORP'>Bilderbergers</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>the Council</ent> on Foreign Relations,
the Tri-lateral Commission,<ent type='ORG'>the Institute for Policy</ent> Studies, the <ent type='ORG'>Roundtables</ent>,
the "Club of Rome",etc are ALL bound by common denominators of long-standing
families ties, and interests and come together as a _single_ policy making
body that is known today as "<ent type='ORG'>The Committee</ent> of 300" . This has also been
known as "The <ent type='NORP'>Olympians</ent>", the "<ent type='ORG'>Policy Committee</ent>".

Don't be mis-led by labels such as "<ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent>" or "<ent type='PERSON'>Rothschild</ent>"; for these
are simply the families who have the mechanisms of control already set in
place,but of themselves are not the entire network; that being the
"Committee of 300". It is THEY who control the UN, who tell the heads of
nations "when to jump and how high", they who are behind the world's illicit
drug trade via the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> and the old <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> East India links. They who
manage the <ent type='ORG'>IMF</ent>,set policy at <ent type='ORG'>GATT</ent> conferences. It is they who ARE the
"<ent type='ORG'>Shadow Government</ent>". It is they who manage the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>,<ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent>,<ent type='ORG'>DIA</ent>..the same
group that took out <ent type='PERSON'>JFK</ent> and have MURDERED around 173 people in their efforts
to suppress the truth about all the links..they who were behind the
assassination of <ent type='PERSON'>RFK</ent>,<ent type='PERSON'>MLK</ent>..they who are behind the suppression of truth
regarding the MIA's; It is the same group behind E. Howard Hunt,
<ent type='PERSON'>John Singlaub</ent>, Ollie <ent type='PERSON'>North</ent>..the very same group who brought down Richard
Nixon in <ent type='EVENT'>Watergate</ent>..the same group behind the persecution of the <ent type='NORP'>Christic</ent>
Institute..the same people who were behind Nugan-Hand..the same group
that groomed <ent type='PERSON'>Jimmy Carter</ent> for the Presidency..the same group who ARE
the "Military-Industrial complex", the same group behind the total
militarization of <ent type='ORG'>NASA</ent>..the same group who ARE "MJ-12", were behind the
"<ent type='ORG'>Jason Group</ent>"..the same behind Project Blue Book, The Condon Committee,
the same who started up the <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent>..who are responsible for the MURDER of
<ent type='PERSON'>Danny Casalaro</ent>..the same group responsible for the world-wide DISINFO
campaign regarding the <ent type='ORG'>TRUTH</ent> of <ent type='EVENT'>UFO</ent> sightings and contacts. The very
SAME group who OWN THE ME<ent type='ORG'>DIA</ent>..ie..<ent type='ORG'>The Washington Post</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>NBC</ent> (General
Electric),<ent type='ORG'>ABC</ent>,<ent type='ORG'>CBS</ent>,<ent type='ORG'>The New York</ent> Times,etc. The same group behind the
the Warren Commission,ad nauseum..

I DO believe I could make a DIRECT connection here with just what
<ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>BASE says on <ent type='ORG'>WACKENHUT</ent> that also ties in the <ent type='ORG'>Shadow Government</ent>
with <ent type='EVENT'>UFO</ent> related installations; this is but *ONE* connection..there
are many,many more that can be and will be ferreted out for exposure.</p>

<p>===== Begin Included article =============================================</p>

<p>Message #6041 - INFO.PARANET
Date : 16-Jan-92 19:46
From : <ent type='PERSON'>Don</ent> Ecker
To : <ent type='PERSON'>John</ent> Galt
Subject : <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent>
<ent type='PERSON'>John</ent> Galt said:</p>

<p> &gt; <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> Corp., one of the nation's largest security firms, said Friday
&gt; it has bought the U.S. security operations of <ent type='ORG'>ISS International</ent> Service
&gt; System Inc. The purchase price was not disclosed. <ent type='ORG'>ISS International</ent>
&gt; has more than 700 employees in its U.S. security operations, primarily
&gt; in <ent type='GPE'>Jacksonville</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Los Angeles</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Dallas</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Atlanta</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Cleveland</ent> and
&gt; <ent type='GPE'>Chattanooga</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Tenn</ent>.</p>

<p>In several investigations that I am currently involved in for <ent type='EVENT'>UFO</ent> Magazine as
well as my radio show "<ent type='EVENT'>UFO</ent>s Tonite", I have come across the <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent>
connection. As many of you may know, <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> is responsible for outside
security around <ent type='LOC'>Area</ent> 51 and site S-4. Last year there was a helicopter crash
in <ent type='GPE'>Las Vegas</ent> that killed a number of <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> employees, plus they are
involved in the <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> scandel. At any rate much more than I can go into here.
However************</p>

<p>I checked <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>BASE and came up with the following. Incidently, all sources are
available for the following information if requested.</p>

<p>Read and contemplate.</p>

<div>*****************************************************************************</div>

<p><ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>BASE FILES
-----------------------------------------------------------------------------</p>

<p>CONFLICT, LI</p>

<p> PERU, 88-91 PRIVATE SECURITY CORPORATION FORMING IMPORTANT ROLE
IN LIC-DRUG OPERATIONS. FROM 1981-91, <ent type='ORG'>PERUVIAN SECURITY CORPORATIONS</ent>
INCREASED FROM 80 TO 350, PLUS 150 UNOFFI<ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>L ORGANIZATIONS. AMONG
THOSE IS <ent type='ORG'>WACKENHUT</ent> CORP, <ent type='ORG'>WHO</ent>SE EMPLOYEES CONSIST OF MANY EX-<ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>,
<ent type='ORG'>DEA</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>FBI</ent> MEMBERS. Z 11/90 87</p>

<p>DOMESTIC OP</p>

<p> <ent type='GPE'>CHILE</ent>, CUBA. <ent type='ORG'>WACKENHUT</ent> CORP OF CORAL <ent type='ORG'>GABLES</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>FLORIDA</ent>. PROVIDES
SECURITY SYSTEMS THRUOUT WORLD. <ent type='ORG'>INMAN</ent> WAS DIRECTOR OF CORP PLUS
OTHER INFLUENTIAL PERSONS IN 80 <ent type='ORG'>WACKENHUT</ent> WORKED CLOSELY WITH
S. CALIFORNIA'S CABAZON IN<ent type='ORG'>DIA</ent>NS AND THEIR TRIBAL ADMINISTRATOR
JOHN PHILIP NICHOLS. NICHOLS PER NEWS ARTICLE, BOASTED RE ATTEMPTED
ASSASSINATION <ent type='PERSON'>CASTRO</ent> AND SUCCESSFUL ASSASSINATION OF SALVADOR ALLENDE.
<ent type='ORG'>WACKENHUT</ent>/CABAZON CONNECTION OF PARTICULAR INTEREST TO D. CASOLARO
<ent type='ORG'>WHO</ent> DIED IN W.VIRGINIA IN 91 HE ALSO INVESTIGATING OCTOBER SURPRISE
AND INSLAW. MICHAEL <ent type='PERSON'>RICONOSCIUTO</ent> - A WEAPONS-SYSTEM DESIGNER AND
SOFTWARE SPE<ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>LIST - WAS DIR OF A RESEARCH PROJECT OF <ent type='ORG'>WACKENHUT</ent>/CABAZON
JOINT VENTURE. IN EARLY 80s <ent type='PERSON'>AFFIDAVIT</ent> SAID HE MODIFIED A STOLEN
PROMIS SOFTWARE FOR FOREIGN SALES. OTHER INFO ON <ent type='ORG'>WACKENHUT</ent>. <ent type='ORG'>ITT</ent>
9/24/81 4-5</p>

<p> FOR EIGHT YEARS INSLAW BATTLING JUSTICE DEPT FOR POSSESSION OF
PROMIS, A SOFT-WARE PROGRAM DEVELOPED BY COMPANY OWNER BILL <ent type='PERSON'>HAMILTON</ent>.
IN 91 INSLAW WENT PUBLIC AND <ent type='PERSON'>ALLEGED REAGAN</ent> JUSTICE DEPT, AFTER IT
HAD STOLEN PROMIS, TURNED IT OVER TO <ent type='PERSON'>EARL BRIAN</ent>. INSLAW ALLEGES
SOFTWARE GIVEN BRIAN AS PAYBACK FOR BRIAN'S HELP IN ARRANGING ARMS-FOR-HOSTAGE <ent type='ORG'>DEA</ent>L WITH <ent type='GPE'>IRAN</ent> IN 1980 (OCTOBER SURPRISE). PER <ent type='PERSON'>HAMILTON</ent>, BRIAN, <ent type='ORG'>WHO</ent>
RUNS UPI, <ent type='ORG'>ALLEGEDLY</ent> MARKETED PROMIS TO <ent type='ORG'>INTEL</ent> AGENCIES OF <ent type='GPE'>ISRAEL</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>JORDAN</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>IRAQ</ent>,
<ent type='GPE'>CANADA</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>SOUTH KOREA</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>LIBYA</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>ENGLAND</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>GERMANY</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>FRANCE</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>AUSTRALIA</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>THAILAND</ent>,
<ent type='GPE'>JAPAN</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>CHILE</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>GUATEMALA</ent>, AND <ent type='ORG'>BRAZIL</ent>. PER INSLAW, ONCE SOFTWARE USED BY FOREIGN
<ent type='ORG'>INTEL</ent> SERVICES, <ent type='ORG'>NATIONAL SECURITY AGENCY</ent> (<ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent>) ABLE INFILTRATE COMPUTERIZED
<ent type='ORG'>INTEL</ent> FILES THOSE COUNTRIES. MODIFICATIONS TO PROMIS <ent type='ORG'>ALLEGEDLY</ent> DONE BY
<ent type='ORG'>WACKENHUT</ent> CORP. OF CORAL <ent type='ORG'>GABLES</ent>, FL. HOUSE JUDI<ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>RY COMM<ent type='ORG'>ITT</ent>EE INVESTIGATING
SCANDAL SINCE 89. ATTORNEY GENERAL THORNBURG, UNDER SUPOENA, RELEASED
INSLAW-RELATED FILES - BUT 15 TO 20 FILES MISSING. <ent type='ORG'>ITT</ent> 9/10/91 4-5</p>

<p> STORY OF <ent type='PERSON'>DANNY CASOLARO</ent> - <ent type='ORG'>WHO</ent> HAD BEEN SORTING THRU THE S&amp;L DEBACLE,
<ent type='ORG'>BCCI</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>IRAN</ent>-CONTRA, CONTRA-CONNECTED <ent type='ORG'>WACKENHUT</ent> CORP., <ent type='ORG'>WACKENHUT</ent>-CONNECTED
INSLAW CASE AND INSLAW-CONNECTED "OCTOBER SURPRISE." <ent type='ORG'>ITT</ent> 9/10/91
4-5</p>

<p>LIAISON</p>

<p> INSLAW PRES BILL <ent type='PERSON'>HAMILTON</ent> SAYS HE HAS INFO THAT PROMIS ILLEGALLY
SOLD TO <ent type='GPE'>SOUTH KOREA</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>LIBYA</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>JORDAN</ent>, GREAT <ent type='GPE'>BRITAIN</ent> (<ent type='GPE'>ENGLAND</ent>), <ent type='GPE'>GERMANY</ent>,
<ent type='GPE'>FRANCE</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>AUSTRALIA</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>THAILAND</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>JAPAN</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>CHILE</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>GUATEMALA</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>BRAZIL</ent>, AND
<ent type='GPE'>CANADA</ent>. CANA<ent type='ORG'>DIA</ent>N COMPANY, COMMUNICATIONS <ent type='GPE'>CANADA</ent> - THE CANA<ent type='ORG'>DIA</ent>N
WORKPLACE AUTOMATION RESEARCH CENTER (CWARC) WROTE INSLAW A LETTER.
ROYAL CANA<ent type='ORG'>DIA</ent>N MOUNTED POLICE ARE OPERATING PROMIS IN 900 LOCATIONS.
MICHAEL <ent type='PERSON'>RICONOSCIUTO</ent> SWORE IN AN <ent type='PERSON'>AFFIDAVIT</ent> THAT WHEN HE DIRECTOR
OF <ent type='ORG'>WACKENHUT</ent> CORP OF CORAL <ent type='ORG'>GABLES</ent>, FL ONE OF HIS JOBS TO ADAPT
PROMIS SOFTWARE. <ent type='PERSON'>PETER VIDENIEKS</ent> AND EARL W. BRIAN WERE FREQUENT
VISITORS TO <ent type='ORG'>WACKENHUT</ent>. <ent type='PERSON'>RICONOSCIUTO</ent> SAID HE TO MODIFY PROMIS FOR
IMPLEMENTATION IN LAW ENFORCEMENT AND <ent type='ORG'>INTEL</ent> AGENCIES WORLDWIDE.
AFTER TESTIFYING BEFORE HOUSE JUDI<ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>RY COMM<ent type='ORG'>ITT</ent>EE INVESTIGATORS,
<ent type='PERSON'>RICONOSCIUTO</ent> ARRESTED AND CHARGED WITH SELLING MORE THAN 4 GRAMS
OF POTENT SPEED. <ent type='ORG'>ITT</ent> 6/11/91 11-13</p>

<p>END OF FILE ---------------------------
---------------------------------------------------</p>

<p>If you notice the name <ent type='ORG'>INMAN</ent> in the above, that is Adm. <ent type='PERSON'>Bobby Inman</ent> recently
mentioned in <ent type='PERSON'>Tim Good</ent>'s book "Alien Liason" and the subject of the January
1992 rebuttal of <ent type='PERSON'>Bob Oechsler</ent> in the M<ent type='EVENT'>UFO</ent>N Journel.</p>

<p>Best:</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Don</ent> Ecker
Director Research
<ent type='EVENT'>UFO</ent> Magazine</p>

<p>--- FD 1.99c
* Origin: ParaNet Alpha-Delta The Data Base (9:1012/3.0)</p>

<p>===End of included article=================================================</p>

<p>Also here's something from last year on the ultra secret <ent type='PERSON'>Bilderberg</ent>
meeting..what motivations and policies do you think that THEY
follow?</p>

<p>-----Begin included text---------------------------------------------------</p>

<p>From: <ent type='ORG'>campe</ent>@thor.uucp (<ent type='PERSON'>Gary Campe</ent> ext )
Newsgroups: alt.activism,talk.politics.misc,misc.headlines
Subject: BILDERBERG ANNUAL MEETING SCHEDULED
<info type="Message-ID"> 13155@fpssun</info>
Date: 22 Apr 91 17:56:38 GMT
References: The Spotlight
Sender: daemon@fpssun
Organization: FPS Computing, Beaverton, Oregon
Lines: 23</p>

<p>Ad as it appears in The Spotlight dated April 22, 1991:</p>

<p>JUNE 7-9 - <ent type='PERSON'>Bilderberg</ent> group meets secretly at Baden-Baden, <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent>.</p>

<p>Members will fly into <ent type='GPE'>Frankfurt</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> or <ent type='GPE'>Stasbourg</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>France</ent> to be taken
in government helicopters to a heavily guarded hotel near Baden-Baden, site
of secret meeting of world's elite. <ent type='ORG'>Agenda</ent> items include exploiting Middle
East oil and progress toward world government. For information, call
<ent type='PERSON'>David Rocefeller</ent> at (914) 631-1634 or his personal valet, Dr. Henry
Kissinger at (212) 759-7919.</p>

<div> ******************</div>

<p>Have any of you been invited?</p>

<p>--
RE-ELECT "Government is not reason, it is not eloquence - it
NO-ONE! is force. Like fire, it is a dangerous servant and
========== a fearful master" -- <ent type='PERSON'>George Washington</ent>.
Disclaimer: The opinions expressed are mine alone and not that of my employer.</p>

<div>------------------------------------------------------------------------------</div>

<p>From: <ent type='ORG'>campe</ent>@thor.uucp (<ent type='PERSON'>Gary Campe</ent> ext )
Newsgroups: misc.headlines,talk.politics.misc,alt.conspiracy
Subject: <ent type='PERSON'>Bilderberg</ent> Annual Meeting - What was said
<info type="Message-ID"> 14096@fpssun</info>
Date: 28 Jun 91 17:48:41 GMT
Sender: daemon@fps.com
Followup-To: misc.headlines
Distribution: usa
Organization: FPS Computing, Beaverton, Oregon
Lines: 42</p>

<p>This information was reported in the June 24, 1991 issue of "THE SPOTLIGHT".</p>

<p>This is not the entire article, only the highlights. If you would like to
read this article in its entirety please refer to the above publication.</p>

<div> ----------------------------</div>

<p>The word out of the <ent type='PERSON'>Bilderberg</ent> annual meeting is that there will be another
war within the next five years.</p>

<p>It was repeatedly stated at the <ent type='PERSON'>Bilderberg</ent> meeting that there will be
"other <ent type='PERSON'>Saddams</ent>" in the years ahead who must be dealt with swiftly and
efficiently.</p>

<p>The <ent type='PERSON'>Bilderberg</ent> group plans a global army at the disposal of <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent>
Nations. It is their hope that the U.N. will become the world government
by the year 2000.</p>

<p>"A U.N. army must be able to act immediately, anywhere in the world, without
delays involved in each country making its own decision whether to
participate, based on parochial considerations," said <ent type='PERSON'>Henry Kissinger</ent>.</p>

<p>If <ent type='NORP'>Americans</ent> can be persuaded to surrender warmaking decisions to the U.N.,
"parochial nationalism" in <ent type='GPE'>Briton</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>France</ent> and elsewhere will disappear,
<ent type='PERSON'>Bilderberg</ent> speakers said.</p>

<p>"The <ent type='LOC'>Persian Gulf</ent> venture has advanced the cause by years" one speaker said.</p>

<div> ----------------------------</div>

<p>So there you have it, the "One <ent type='PERSON'>Worlders</ent>" are still alive and well.</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Garry</ent></p>

<p>--
RE-ELECT "Government is not reason, it is not eloquence - it
NO-ONE! is force. Like fire, it is a dangerous servant and
========== a fearful master" -- <ent type='PERSON'>George Washington</ent>.
Disclaimer: The opinions expressed are mine alone and not that of my employer.</p>

<p>---End included text---------------------------------------------------------</p>

<p>The following is on the historical perspective of just the <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent>
and <ent type='PERSON'>Rothschild</ent> connections and in no way attempts to cover every
aspect, but will suffice to give you a basis on which to understand
how pervasive the Web of influence is and that it is a good deal MORE
than "merely a conspiracy". Just <ent type='ORG'>WHO</ent> makes up the ILLEGAL SHADOW
GOVERMNENT,YOUR HIDDEN MASTERS?</p>

<p>I ask no one to accept any of this at face value, and would heartily
encourage you to perform your own investigation. To that end,I've
provided an extensive list of reading materials at the end of this
text.

And lastly, I would include a very lucid assessment of our situation
by <ent type='PERSON'>John</ent> DiNardo, which in my opinion, is absolutely correct. There have
been MANY people who are posting such as <ent type='PERSON'>John</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Dave Radcliffe</ent>, Rich
Winkel and others who have been showing you just *<ent type='ORG'>WHO</ent>* the CANCER IS.</p>

<p>----------------------------------------------------------------------------
If the usurpers of our freedom, the plunderers of our life's earnings,
the despoilers of our planet <ent type='LOC'>Earth</ent>, the deluders of our TV-zombified
society, the desecrators of our Constitution can crush the <ent type='NORP'>Christic</ent>
Institute -- than what refuge is left for the few remaining
<ent type='NORP'>Christic</ent>-like organizations to shelter THEM from this Frankenstein
Monster government? What refuge is left for you and me, and for our
children who will necessarily find themselves forced to riot and
spill their blood in the streets during the twenty-first century?
It always degenerates to that, you know.</p>

<p> We <ent type='NORP'>Americans</ent> are a lazy, short-sighted bunch. We realize that if we
don't earn a living, we will be impoverished. We realize that if we
don't brush our teeth, our teeth will rot out of our mouths. We
realize that if we don't service our cars, they will fail to operate.
Yet, we don't realize -- or we're too lazy to admit -- that if we
don't supervise and participate in our system of government to ensure
that our Constitution is protected from the greedy, power-mad
neurotics whose ambitions drive them to seize the reins of power
and wealth vested in our <ent type='ORG'>Federal Government</ent>, then our libertarian
foundations will crumble beneath us, leaving us to fall into the
pit of subjugation that the corporate rulers have prepared for us.</p>

<p> As we witness our free-fall into the pit, we finally understand
that the law is slipping out of our hands; that we and our children
will have to resort to meeting in dark rooms and plotting to recover
our Constitutional freedoms which the usurpers have seized through
television, that great national <ent type='NORP'>Svengali</ent> -- that opiate of the masses
which they have so cleverly employed to sedate, delude and distract us
while quietly cuffing our ankles and wrists. How could we be so stupid
as to surrender our minds to Big Brother, never suspecting that
whenever someone offers you free entertainment, day after day and
year after year, it's got to be costing you. </p>

<p> Why shouldn't we be as vulnerable to totalitarianism as are
the peoples of most other societies around the world. More so,
considering the fact that totalitarianism originates from within the
military elite. And whose nation has the most savagely powerful
military force on the planet? What's worse is that it's not just the
military that's militating against our Constitutional freedoms.
It's the military-industrial complex. President <ent type='PERSON'>Eisenhower</ent> left office
a third of a century ago by warning us that the military-industrial
complex is the greatest threat to our freedom. That was as much of
a warning as he dared give, lest he meet the doom of his valiant
successor who tried to actually BE the President of <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States.</p>

<p> How knowledgeable was <ent type='ORG'>the General</ent> of the <ent type='ORG'>Army</ent> of the Second <ent type='EVENT'>World War</ent>,
Dwight <ent type='PERSON'>Eisenhower</ent>, in his fear of the military-industrial complex?
As knowledgeable as President <ent type='PERSON'>Kennedy</ent> is dead!</p>

<p> So you see, there really isn't much time left. If we prove to be too
lazy now to unite behind Constitutional upholders such as the
<ent type='NORP'>Christic</ent> Institute -- then our children in the twenty-first century
will NOT be too frightened to stand up against the bullets of the
<ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> Security Corporation of Coral Gables, <ent type='GPE'>Florida</ent>. Because
when the oppression becomes intolerable, you, I and anyone would
stand up to bullets, rather than go on living in unbearable agony.
Ask the <ent type='NORP'>Palestinian</ent> people who stand up to bullets every day --
or the <ent type='NORP'>Rumanian</ent> people, or the <ent type='NORP'>Guatemalan</ent> people, or the <ent type='NORP'>Filipino</ent>
people, or the <ent type='NORP'>Chinese</ent> people, or the <ent type='NORP'>Iranian</ent> people, or the
<ent type='NORP'>Tibetan</ent> people, or the <ent type='NORP'>Timorese</ent> people.</p>

<p> If we prove to be too lazy now, OUR generation may even see the day
when citizens will speak softly and listen intently for the footsteps
of the <ent type='ORG'>Gestapo</ent> who may finally come to kick down our front door and
arrest us for plotting to regain the Constitutional freedoms
that were once our heritage.</p>

<p> <ent type='PERSON'>John</ent> DiNardo</p>

<div>---------------------------------------------------------------------------</div>

<p> Excerpted from the book, "Rape of The Constitution; Death of Freedom" by
Gyeorgos C. Hatonn . </p>

<p> *** The <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> Syndicate ***</p>

<div> ========================================================================</div>

<p> Many <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> conservatives believe as a matter of faith that the
<ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent>s and <ent type='ORG'>the Council</ent> on Foreign Relations exercise absolute
control over the government and the people of the U.S. This thesis can
be accepted as a working formula if one remains conscious of the larger
issues. Two writers for whom the present writer (E.M) has great respect,
Dr. <ent type='PERSON'>Emanuel Josephson</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Morris Bealle</ent>, insisted on focusing on the
<ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent>s and excluding all other aspects of the World Order. This
severely limited the effect of their otherwise groundbreaking work on the
Medical Monopoly. This writer advanced a contrary view in "<ent type='ORG'>The World</ent>
Order," fixing upon the <ent type='PERSON'>Rothschild</ent> monetary power, which reached a point
of world control by 1885, and its <ent type='GPE'>London</ent> policy group, the Royal
Institute of International Affairs, as the policy makers for what has
essentially been, since 1900, a re-established colonial government,
functions primarily through <ent type='ORG'>the Council</ent> on Foreign Relations, but only as
the subsidiary of <ent type='ORG'>RIIA</ent> and through the <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> Foundation, which
controls government functions, the educational establishments, the media,
the religions and the state legislatures. </p>

<p> It is true that the <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> colonials have "free elections," in which
they have the absolute right to vote for one of two opposing candidates,
both of whom have been handpicked and financed by the <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent>
syndicate. This touching evidence of "democracy" serves to convince most
<ent type='NORP'>Americans</ent> that you are indeed a free people. You even have a cracked
<ent type='ORG'>Liberty Bell</ent> in <ent type='GPE'>Philadelphia</ent> to prove it. <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> youths have been free
since 1900 to be marched off to die in <ent type='NORP'>Hegelian</ent> wars in which both
combatants received their instructions from the World Order. You are free
to invest in a stock market in which the daily quantity,price and value
of the monetary unit is manipulated and controlled by a Federal Reserve
System which is answerable only to <ent type='ORG'>the Bank</ent> of England. It has maintained
its vaunted "independence" from your government control, but this is the
only independence it has ever had. </p>

<p> The realization that you do indeed live under the dictates of the
"<ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> Syndicate" can well be the starting point of the long road
back of a genuine struggle for <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> independence. In exposing "the
<ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent>s" as agents of a foreign power, which is not merely a foreign
power, but a genuine world government, you must realize that this is not
merely a group dedicated to making money, but a group which is committed
to maintaining the power of a colonial form of government over the
<ent type='NORP'>American</ent> people. Thus the ancient calumny of <ent type='PERSON'>John</ent> D. <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> as a
man obsessed by greed (a category in which he has plenty of company)
obscures the fact that from the day the <ent type='PERSON'>Rothschild</ent>s began to finance his
march towards a total oil monopoly in <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States from their
coffers at <ent type='ORG'>the National City Bank</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>Cleveland</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> was never an
independent power, nor does any department of the <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> Syndicate
operate as an independent power. You know that the <ent type='ORG'>Cosa Nostra</ent>, or
<ent type='ORG'>Mafia</ent>, with which the Syndicate is closely allied, has somewhat
autonomous power in the regions which have been assigned to that
particular "family" by the national directors, but this always implies
that that family remains under total control and answerable for
everything which occurs in its territory. </p>

<p> Similarly, the <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> Syndicate operates under clearly defined
spheres of influence. The "charitable" organizations, the business
companies and the policy groups, always meld into a working operation,
nor can any department of the Syndicate strike out on its own or
formulate an independent policy, no matter what may be its
justification. </p>

<p> The <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> Syndicate operates under the control of the world
financial structure, which means that on any given day, all of its assets
could be rendered close to worthless by adroit financial manipulation.
This is the final control, which ensures that no one can quit the
organization. Not only would he be stripped of all assets, but he would
be under contract for immediate assassination. <ent type='ORG'>The Department</ent> of Justice
is well aware that the only "terrorists" operating in <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States
are the agents of the World Order, but they prudently avoid any mention
of this fact. </p>

<p> The world financial structure, far from being an unknown or hidden
organization, is actually well known and well defined. It consists of
the major <ent type='NORP'>Swiss</ent> Banks; the survivors of the old <ent type='NORP'>Venetian</ent>-<ent type='NORP'>Genoese</ent> banking
axis; <ent type='ORG'>the Big Five</ent> of the world grain trade; the <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> combine,
centered in <ent type='ORG'>the Bank</ent> of England and its chartered merchant banks,
functioning through the <ent type='PERSON'>Rothschild</ent>s and the <ent type='ORG'>Oppenheimers</ent> and having
absolute control over their Canadian colony through <ent type='ORG'>the Royal Bank</ent> of
<ent type='GPE'>Canada</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>the Bank</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>Montreal</ent>, their Canadian lieutenants being the
Bronfmans, Belzbergs, Reichmanns and other financial operators; and the
colonial banking structure in the U.S., controlled by <ent type='ORG'>the Bank</ent> of England
through the <ent type='ORG'>Federal Reserve System</ent>; the <ent type='GPE'>Boston</ent> Brahmin families who made
their fortunes in the opium trade, including the <ent type='PERSON'>Delanos</ent> and others and
the <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> Bank, <ent type='ORG'>Chase Manhattan Bank</ent>, <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> Express, the present
form of the old <ent type='PERSON'>Rothschild</ent> representatives in the U.S., which includes
<ent type='ORG'>Kuhn</ent>,Loeb Company and <ent type='ORG'>Lehman Brothers</ent>. </p>

<p> It is notable that the <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> Syndicate is far down on the list of
the worlds financial structure. Why then is it of such importance?
Although it is not the crucial factor in financial decision in the
<ent type='LOC'>Western Hemisphere</ent>, it is the actual working control mechanism of the
<ent type='NORP'>American</ent> colony. The <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> family themselves,like the
Morgans,<ent type='PERSON'>Schiff</ent>s and <ent type='PERSON'>Warburgs</ent>, have faded into insignificance, but the
mechanism created in their name roars along at full power,still
maintaining all of the functions for which it was organized. Since he
set up the <ent type='ORG'>Trilateral Commission</ent>, David <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> has functioned as a
sort of international courier for the World Order, principally concerned
with delivering working instructions to the <ent type='NORP'>Communist</ent> bloc,either
directly, in <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent> or by traveling to the area. Laurence <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent>
is active in the operation of the Medical Monopoly, but his principal
interests are in operating various vacation spas in tropical areas. They
are the two survivors of the "Fortunate Five," the five sons of <ent type='PERSON'>John</ent> D.
<ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent>, Jr. and <ent type='PERSON'>Abby Aldrich</ent>. <ent type='PERSON'>John</ent> D. <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent>, Jr. died in an
institution in <ent type='GPE'>Tucson</ent>,<ent type='GPE'>Arizona</ent> and was hastily cremated. <ent type='PERSON'>John</ent> D.
<ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> III died in a mysterious accident on a <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent> Parkway near
his home. Nelson <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent>, named after his grandfather, died in the
arms of a TV journalist. It was later revealed that he had also been in
the arms of another TV journalist at the same time; the death was hushed
up for many hours. It was generally believed that he ran afoul of his
<ent type='GPE'>Columbian</ent> drug connection, the disagreement hardly being trivial; it
involved several billion dollars in drug profits which had not been
properly apportioned. <ent type='PERSON'>Winthrop</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> died an alcoholic in the arms
of his black boy friend. He had been interviewed on television by Harry
Reasoner to explain his hasty move from <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent> to <ent type='GPE'>Arkansas</ent>. <ent type='PERSON'>Winthrop</ent>
learned that his black boy friend, an <ent type='ORG'>Army</ent> sergeant who apparently taught
him the mysteries of drill,refused to live in <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent>. To celebrate this
alliance, <ent type='PERSON'>Winthrop</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> gave <ent type='PERSON'>magnificiently</ent> to <ent type='ORG'>Negro</ent>
causes,including the <ent type='ORG'>Urban League</ent> building on East 48th Street in New
York. A plaque on the second floor notes that it was his gift; it might
well have stated "From <ent type='PERSON'>Hadrian</ent> to his Antinous." </p>

<p> We do not wish to imply that the <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent>s no longer have influence,
but that the major policy dictates of the <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> Syndicate are
handed down by other caps, of whom they continue to be a visible force.
Through the person of David <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent>, the family is sometimes called
"the first family of <ent type='GPE'>the Soviet Union</ent>." Only he and Dr. <ent type='PERSON'>Armand Hammer</ent>,
the moving force behind USTEC, have permanent permission to land their
private planes at the <ent type='GPE'>Moscow</ent> Airport. Others would suffer the fate of <ent type='ORG'>KAL</ent>
007. David Rockefeller's most significant trip to <ent type='GPE'>the Soviet Union</ent> may
have been the fateful day when he landed in <ent type='GPE'>Moscow</ent>, having been told to
inform <ent type='NORP'>Khrushchev</ent> that he was "through". The <ent type='NORP'>Russians</ent> are very health
conscious, and a scientist had sent information to <ent type='NORP'>Khrushchev</ent> that the
use of chemical fertilizers in <ent type='GPE'>the Soviet Union</ent> presented a threat to the
people. <ent type='NORP'>Khrushchev</ent> then announced a major change in the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> farm
policy, centering around a reduction in the use of chemicals. This was
upsetting to the head of the world's <ent type='ORG'>Chemical Fertilizer</ent> trust, David
<ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent>, and he responded with a terse one word command, "Out". </p>

<p> Both the <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> family fortune and the considerable portion set
aside in the foundations of the <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> Syndicate are effectively
insulated against any type of government control. <ent type='ORG'>FORTUNE</ent> magazine noted
August ,1986, that <ent type='PERSON'>John</ent> D. <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent>,Jr. had created trusts in 1934
which now amounted to some $2.3 billion; another 200 million had been set
aside for the <ent type='PERSON'>Abby</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> branch. The five sons had trusts which in
1986 amounted to $2.1 billion. These trusts had originally amounted to
only $50 million each,showing the increase in their assets as well as
inflation during the ensuing half century. <ent type='ORG'>FORTUNE</ent> estimated the 1986
total <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> wealth as $3.5 billion of which $900 million was in
securities and real estate. They owned 45% of the Time Life
Building; Nelson Rockefeller's <ent type='ORG'>International Basic Economy Corporation</ent> had
been sold to a <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> company in 1980. For years, the <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> family
had deliberately kept the rents low in its major holding, <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent>
Center, a $1.6 billion investment yielding an annual return of 1% . This
was a convenient <ent type='ORG'>manuever</ent> for tax purposes, and a good one at that. </p>

<p> Much of the <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> wealth might be attributed to old <ent type='PERSON'>John</ent> D.'s
rapacity and ruthlessness; its origins are indubitably based in his
initial financing from <ent type='ORG'>the National City Bank</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>Cleveland</ent>, which was
identified in <ent type='ORG'>Congressional</ent> reports as one of the three <ent type='PERSON'>Rothschild</ent> banks
in <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States and by his later acceptance of the guidance of Jacob
<ent type='PERSON'>Schiff</ent> of <ent type='ORG'>Kuhn</ent>,Loeb Company, who had been born in the <ent type='PERSON'>Rothschild</ent> house in
<ent type='GPE'>Franfort</ent> and was now the principal <ent type='PERSON'>Rothschild</ent> representive (but unknown
as such to the public) in <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States. </p>

<p> With the seed money from <ent type='ORG'>the National City Bank</ent> in <ent type='GPE'>Cleveland</ent>, old <ent type='PERSON'>John</ent> D.
<ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> soon laid claim to the title of the "most ruthless <ent type='NORP'>American</ent>".
It is more than likely that it was this quality which persuaded the
<ent type='PERSON'>Rothschild</ent>s to back him. <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> realized early in the game that the
oil refinery business, which could offer great profits in a short time,
also was at the mercy of uncontrolled competition. His solution was a
simple one--crush all competition. The famous <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> dedication to
total monopoly was simply a business decision. <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> embarked on a
campaign of coercing all competing oil refineries out of business. He
attacked on a number of fronts, which is also a lesson to all would be
entrepreneurs. First, he would send a minion, not known to be working for
<ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent>, with an offer to buy the competing refinery for a low
price,but offering cash. If the offer was refused, the competitor would
then come under attack from a competing refinery which greatly undercut
his price. He might also suffer a sudden strike at his refinery,which
would force him to shut down. Control of labor through unions has always
been a basic <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> technique. Like <ent type='GPE'>the Soviet Union</ent>, they seldom
have labor trouble. If these techniques failed, <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> would then
be saddened by a reluctant decision to use violence; beating the rival
workers as they went to and from their jobs, or burning or blowing up the
competing refinery. </p>

<p> These techniques convinced the <ent type='PERSON'>Rothschild</ent>s that they had found their
man.They sent their personal representative,<ent type='PERSON'>Jacob Schiff</ent>, to <ent type='GPE'>Cleveland</ent> to
help <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> plan further expansion. At this time,the <ent type='PERSON'>Rothschild</ent>s
controlled 95% of all railroad mileage in <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States,through the
J.P. <ent type='ORG'>Morgan Company</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>Kuhn Loeb Company</ent>,according to official
Department of Commerce figures for the year 1895. J.P. Morgan mentions in
his "Who's Who" listing that he controlled 50000 miles of U.S.
railways. <ent type='PERSON'>Schiff</ent> worked out an elaborate rebate deal for
<ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent>,through a dummy corporation,<ent type='ORG'>South Improvement Company</ent>. These
rebates ensured that no other oil company could survive in competition
with the <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> firm. The scheme was later exposed,but by that time
<ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> had achieved a virtual monopoly of the oil business in the
U.S. The daughter of one of his victims, <ent type='PERSON'>Ida Tarbell</ent>,whose father was
ruined by Rockefeller's criminal operations, wrote the first major expose
of <ent type='ORG'>the Standard Oil Trust</ent>. She was promptly denounced as a "muckracker"
by the poseur, <ent type='PERSON'>Theodore Roosevelt</ent>, who claimed to be a "trustbuster." In
fact, he ensured the dominance of <ent type='ORG'>the Standard Oil Trust</ent> and other giant
trusts. </p>

<p> During the next half century, <ent type='PERSON'>John</ent> D. <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> was routinely
caricatured by socialist propagandists as the epitome of the ruthless
capitalist. At the same time, he was the principal financier of the
world <ent type='NORP'>Communist</ent> movement, through a firm called <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> International
Company. Despite the fact that <ent type='ORG'>the House</ent> of <ent type='PERSON'>Rothschild</ent> had already
achieved world control,the sound and the fury was directed exclusively
against its two principal representatives,<ent type='PERSON'>John</ent> D. <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> and J.P.
Morgan. One of the few revelations of the actual state of affairs
appeared in <ent type='ORG'>TRUTH</ent> magazine,Dec 161912, which pointed out that "Mr.
<ent type='PERSON'>Schiff</ent> is head of the great private banking house of <ent type='ORG'>Kuhn</ent>, Loeb Company
(I knew some of you bright readers would finally pick up that these names
are all attached to the greatest pharmaceutical firms in the world--even
into your very vitamin supplement business!), which represents the
<ent type='PERSON'>Rothschild</ent> interests on your side of the <ent type='LOC'>Atlantic</ent>. He is described as a
financial strategist and has been for years the financial minister of the
great impersonal power known as <ent type='ORG'>Standard Oil</ent>." Note that the name of
<ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> was not mentioned in the quote. </p>

<p> Because of these concealed factors,it was a relatively simple matter for
the <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> public to accept the "fact" that the <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent>s were the
preeminent power in your country. This myth was actually clothed in the
apparel of power,the <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> Oil Trust becoming the
"military-industrial complex" which assumed political control of the
nation; the <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> Medical Monopoly attained control of the health
care of the nation, and the <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> Foundation, a web of affiliated
tax emempt creations, effectively controlled the religious and
educational life of the nation. The myth succeeded in its goal of
camouflaging the hidden rulers, the <ent type='PERSON'>Rothschild</ent>s. </p>

<p> After <ent type='PERSON'>Eustis Mullins</ent> and a few others, had been exposing this charade for
some twenty-five years a new myth began to be noised about in <ent type='NORP'>American</ent>
conservative circles, effectively propagated by active double agents.
This myth found a host of eager believers,because it heralded a growing
crack in the monolithic power which had been oppressing all the peoples
of the world. This "new" revelation was that a struggle to the death for
world power had developed between the <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent>s and the <ent type='PERSON'>Rothschild</ent>s.
According to this startling development, one faction or the other,
depending on which agent you were listening to, had gained control of the
<ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> Union and would use its power as the basis for achieving the
overthrow of the other faction. The sudden death of several members of
the <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> family was cited as "proof" that such a struggle was
taking place, although no <ent type='PERSON'>Rothschild</ent> is known to have succumbed during
this "war." This ignored the general understanding that Nelson
<ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> had been "eliminated" as the result of losing deposit slips
for several billion dollars of drugs from the <ent type='GPE'>Columbian</ent> cartel, or that
the other <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> deaths showed no trace of a "<ent type='PERSON'>Rothschild</ent>
connection." </p>

<p> Having maintained extensive files on this situation for several decades,
the writer (E.M.),could not believe anyone could be so misinformed as to
think that "the <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent>s" were now trying to seize power from the
<ent type='PERSON'>Rothschild</ent>s, at a time when the influence of members of the <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent>
family was already in great decline, their family finances being handled
by <ent type='PERSON'>John</ent> J. McCloy, and other faithful retainers;none of the retainers
would have been willing to engage in a genuine power struggle, as they
were faceless managers who lived only for their weekly paycheck. They
had no ambitions of their own. Nevertheless, many hopeful <ent type='NORP'>Americans</ent>
grasped at the will-o-the-wisp notion the <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent>s were now "good
<ent type='NORP'>Americans</ent>" who were willing to risk all to overthrow the <ent type='PERSON'>Rothschild</ent>s.
Amazingly enough, this pernicious story persisted for almost a decade
before being relegated to the curiosities of history. </p>

<p> Like J.P. Morgan, who had begun his commercial career by selling the U.S.
<ent type='ORG'>Army</ent> some defective guns, the famous Hall carbine affair, <ent type='PERSON'>John</ent> D.
<ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> also was a war profiteer during <ent type='EVENT'>the Civil War</ent>;he sold
unstamped Harkness liquor to Federal troops at a high profit, gaining the
initial capital to embark on his drive for monopoly. His interest in the
oil business was a natural one; his father,<ent type='PERSON'>William</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> had been
"in oil" for years. <ent type='PERSON'>William</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> had become an oil entrepreneur
after salt wells at <ent type='ORG'>Tarentum</ent>, near <ent type='GPE'>Pittsburgh</ent>, were discovered in 1842 to
be flowing with oil. The owners of the wells,<ent type='PERSON'>Samuel</ent> L. <ent type='PERSON'>Kier</ent>, began to
bottle the oil and sell it for medicinal purposes. One of his earliest
wholesalers was <ent type='PERSON'>William</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent>. The "medicine" was originally
labelled "Kier's Magic Oil". <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> printed his own labels, using
"<ent type='ORG'>Rock Oil</ent>" or "Seneca Oil", Seneca being the name of a well known <ent type='NORP'>Indian</ent>
Tribe. <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> achieved his greatest notoriety and his greatest
profits by advertising himself as "<ent type='PERSON'>William</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent>, the Celebrated
Cancer Specialist". It is understandable that his grandsons would become
the controlling power behind the scenes of the world's most famous cancer
treatment center and would direct government funds and charitable
contributions to those areas which only benefit the Medical Monopoly.
<ent type='PERSON'>William</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> spared no claim in his flamboyant career. He
guaranteed "All Cases of Cancer Cured Unless They Are Too Far Gone". Such
were the healing powers that he attributed to his magic cancer cure that
he was able to retail it for $25 a bottle, a sum then equivalent to two
month's wages. The "cure" consisted of a few well known diuretics, which
had been diluted by water. This carnival medicine show barker could
hardly have envisioned that his descendants would control the greatest
and the most profitable Medical Monopoly in recorded history. </p>

<p> As an itinerant "carnie", a traveling carnival peddler, <ent type='PERSON'>William</ent>
<ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> had chosen a career which interfered with developing a stable
family life. His son, <ent type='PERSON'>John</ent>, rarely saw him, a circumstance which has
inspired some psychological analysts to conjecture that the absence of a
father figure or parental love may have contributed to <ent type='PERSON'>John</ent> D.
Rockefeller's subsequent development as a money mad tyrant who plotted to
maim, poison and kill millions of his fellow <ent type='NORP'>Americans</ent> during almost a
century of his monopolistic operations and whose influence, reaching up
from the grave, remains the most dire and malignant presence in <ent type='NORP'>American</ent>
life. This may have been a contributing factor--however, it is also
possible that he was totally evil. It is hardly arguable that he is
probably one of the most Satanic figures in <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> history. Evil being
defined as anything that moves the spiritual aspect of beingness away
from God as influenced through another. </p>

<p> It has long been a truism that you can find a horse thief or two in any
prominent <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> family. In the <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> family, it was more than
true in the case of <ent type='PERSON'>William</ent> who seemed to have faithfully followed the
precepts of the Will of <ent type='GPE'>Canaan</ent> throughout his career, "love robbery, love
lechery". He fled from a number of indictments for horse stealing and
you know how serious that is, finally disappearing altogether as <ent type='PERSON'>William</ent>
and <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> and magically re-emerging as a Dr. <ent type='PERSON'>William</ent> Levingston of
<ent type='GPE'>Philadelphia</ent>, a name which he retained for the rest of his life. An
investigative reporter at <ent type='PERSON'>Joseph Pulitzer</ent>'s <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent> World received a tip
that was followed up. <ent type='ORG'>The World</ent> then disclosed that <ent type='PERSON'>William</ent> Avery
<ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> had died May 11, 1906 in <ent type='GPE'>Freeport</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Illinois</ent>, where he was
interred in an unmarked grave as Dr. <ent type='PERSON'>William</ent> Levingston. </p>

<p> <ent type='PERSON'>William</ent> Rockefeller's vocation as a medicine man greatly facilitated his
preferred profession of horse thief. As one who planned to be in the
next county by morning, it was a simple matter to tie a handsome stallion
to the back of his wagon and head for the open road. It also played a
large part in his vocation as a woman-chaser; he was described as being
"woman-mad". </p>

<p> On June 281849, he was indicted for raping a hired girl in Cayuga,New
York; he later was found to be residing in <ent type='GPE'>Oswego</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent> and was
forced once again to decamp for parts unknown. He had no difficulty in
financing his woman-chasing interests from the sale of his miraculous
cancer cure and from another product, his "Wonder Working Liniment",
which he offered at only two dollars a bottle. It consisted of crude
petroleum from which the lighter oils had been boiled away, leaving a
heavy solution of paraffin,lube oil and tar, which comprised the
"liniment". <ent type='PERSON'>William</ent> Rockefeller's original miracle oil survived until
quite recently as a concoction called <ent type='ORG'>Nujol</ent>, consisting principally of
petroleum and peddled as a laxative. It was well known that <ent type='ORG'>Nujol</ent> was
merely an advertising sobriquet meaning "new oil", as opposed apparently,
to "old oil". Sold as an antidote to constipation, it robbed the body of
fat-soluble vitamins, it being a well-established medical fact that
mineral oil coated the intestine and prevented the absorption of many
needed vitamins and other nutritional needs. Its makers added carotine
as a sop to the health-conscious, but it was hardly worth the bother.
<ent type='ORG'>Nujol</ent> was manufactured by a subsidiary of <ent type='ORG'>Standard Oil</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>New Jersey</ent>,
called <ent type='PERSON'>Stanco</ent>, whose only other product, manufactured on the same
premises, was the famous insecticide, Flit. </p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>Nujol</ent> was hawked from the Senate Office Building in <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent> for years
during a more liberal interpretation of "conflict of interest". In this
case, it was hardly a conflict of interest, because the august
peddler,Senator Royal S. <ent type='PERSON'>Copeland</ent>, never had any interests other than
serving the <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent>s. He was a physician whom <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> had
appointed as head of the <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent> State Department of Health and later
financed his campaign for the Senate. Copeland's frank display of
commercialism amazed even the most blase' <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent> reporters. </p>

<p> He devoted his Senate career to a daily program advertising <ent type='ORG'>Nujol</ent>. A
microphone was set up in his Senate office each morning, the first order
of business being the <ent type='ORG'>Nujol</ent> program, for which he was paid $75000 a
year, an enormous salary in the 1930's and more than the salary of the
President of <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States. Senator Copeland's exploits earned him a
number of nicknames on Capital Hill. He was often called the Senator from
the <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> Medical Association, because of his enthusiastic backing for
any program launched by the <ent type='ORG'>AMA</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Morris Fishbein</ent>. More realistically,
he was usually referred to as "the Senator from <ent type='ORG'>Standard Oil</ent>". He could
be counted on to promote any legislation devised for the greater profit
of the <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> monopoly. During congressional debate on <ent type='ORG'>the Food and</ent>
Drug Act in 1938, he came under criticism from <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>woman Leonor
<ent type='PERSON'>Sullivan</ent>, who charged that Senator <ent type='PERSON'>Copeland</ent>, a physician who handled the
bill on the Senate floor, frankly acknowledged during the debate that
soap was exempted from the law because the soap manufacturers, who were
the nation's largest advertisers, would otherwise join with other big
industries to fight the bill. <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>woman <ent type='PERSON'>Sullivan</ent> complained that,
"Soap was officially declared in the law not to be a cosmetic. The hair
dye manufacturers were given a license to market known dangerous
products, just so long as they placed a special warning on the label -
but what woman in a beauty parlor ever sees the label on the bulk
container in which hair dye is shipped?" </p>

<p> Just as the elder <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> had spent his life in the pursuit of his
personal obsession, women, so his son <ent type='PERSON'>John</ent> was equally obsessed, being
money-mad instead of woman-mad, totally committed to the pursuit of
ever-increasing wealth and power. However, the principal accomplishments
of the <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> drive for power, the rebate scheme for monopoly, the
chartering of the foundations to gain power over <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> citizens,the
creation of the central bank, the <ent type='ORG'>Federal Reserve System</ent>, the backing of
the World <ent type='NORP'>Communist</ent> Revolution and the creation of the Medical Monoply,
all came from the <ent type='PERSON'>Rothschild</ent>s or from their European employees. </p>

<p> We cannot find in the records of <ent type='PERSON'>John</ent> D. <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> that he originated
any of these programs. The concept of the tax exempt charitable
foundation originated with the <ent type='PERSON'>Rothschild</ent> minion, <ent type='PERSON'>George Peabody</ent>, in
1865. <ent type='ORG'>The Peabody Educational</ent> Foundation later became the <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent>
Foundation and many of you should recall that item. Not that you might
have been around then but it continues to inadvertently be referred to as
such. </p>

<p> It is unlikely that even the diabolical mind of <ent type='PERSON'>John</ent> D. <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> could
have conceived of this devious twist. A social historian has described
the major development of the late nineteenth century, when charitable
foundations and world Communism became important movements, as one of the
more interesting facets of history, perhaps equivalent to the discovery
of the wheel or fire. This new discovery was the concept developed by
the rats, who after all have rather highly developed intelligences, that
they could trap people by baiting traps with little bits of cheese. The
history of mankind since then has been the rats catching humans in their
traps. Socialism -- indeed, any government program -- is simply the rat
baiting the trap with a smidgeon of cheese and catching himself a human. </p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>man <ent type='PERSON'>Wright Patman</ent>, chairman of <ent type='ORG'>the House</ent> Banking and Currency
Committee, noted from the floor of <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent> that the establishment of the
<ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> Foundation effectively insulated <ent type='ORG'>Standard Oil</ent> from
competition. The controlling stock had been removed from market
manipulation or possible buyouts by competitors. It also relieved
<ent type='ORG'>Standard Oil</ent> from most taxation, which then placed a tremendous added
burden on individual <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> taxpayers. Although a <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> relative
by marriage, Senator <ent type='PERSON'>Nelson Aldrich</ent>, <ent type='NORP'>Republican</ent> majority leader in the
Senate, had pushed <ent type='ORG'>the General</ent> Education Board charter through <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>,
the <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> Foundation charter proved to be more difficult.
Widespread criticism of Rockefeller's monopolistic practices was heard,
and his effort to insulate his profits from taxation or takeover was seen
for what it was. The charter was finally pushed through in 1913 (the
significant <ent type='NORP'>Masonic</ent> numeral 13 -- 1913 was also the year of the
progressive income tax and of the enactment of <ent type='ORG'>the Federal Reserve Act</ent>).
Senator <ent type='PERSON'>Robert</ent> F. Wagner of <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent>, another Senator from <ent type='ORG'>Standard Oil</ent>
(there were quite a few), ramrodded the <ent type='ORG'>Congressional</ent> approval of the
charter. The charter was then signed by <ent type='PERSON'>John</ent> D. <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>John</ent> D.
<ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent>, Jr., <ent type='PERSON'>Henry Pratt Judson</ent>, president of the <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent>
established University of Chicago,<ent type='PERSON'>Simon Flexner</ent>, director of the
<ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> Institute, <ent type='PERSON'>Starr Jameson</ent>, described in "Who's Who" as
"personal counsel to <ent type='PERSON'>John</ent> D. <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> in his benevolences", and
Charles W. <ent type='PERSON'>Eliot</ent>, president of <ent type='ORG'>Harvard University</ent>. </p>

<p> The <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> Oil Monopoly is now 127 years old, yet in 1911, the
<ent type='ORG'>Supreme Court</ent>, bowing to public outrage, had ruled that it had to be
broken up. The resulting companies proved to be no problem for the
<ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> interests. The family retained a two per cent holding in
each of the "new" companies, while the <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> foundations took a
three per cent holding in each company. This gave them a five per cent
stock interest in each company; a one per cent holding in a corporation
is usually sufficient to maintain working control. </p>

<p> The involvement of the <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent>s in promoting the World <ent type='NORP'>Communist</ent>
Revolution also developed from their business interests. There was never
any commitment to the <ent type='NORP'>Marxist</ent> ideology; like anything else, it was there
to be used. At the turn of the century, <ent type='ORG'>Standard Oil</ent> was competing
fiercely with <ent type='ORG'>Royal Dutch Shell</ent> for control of the lucrative European
market. <ent type='ORG'>Congressional</ent> testimony revealed that <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> had sent large
sums of money to <ent type='PERSON'>Lenin</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Trotsky</ent> to instigate the <ent type='NORP'>Communist</ent> Revolution
in 1905. His banker, <ent type='PERSON'>Jacob Schiff</ent> had previously financed the <ent type='NORP'>Japanese</ent> in
their war against <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent> and had sent a personal emissary, <ent type='PERSON'>George Kennan</ent>
to <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent> to spend some twenty years in promoting revolutionary activity
against the Czar. </p>

<p> When the 1905 revolution failed, <ent type='PERSON'>Lenin</ent> was placed "in storage" in
<ent type='GPE'>Switzerland</ent> until 1907. <ent type='PERSON'>Trotsky</ent> was brought to the U.S., where he lived
rent free on the <ent type='ORG'>Standard Oil</ent> property at <ent type='GPE'>Bayonne</ent>,<ent type='GPE'>New Jersey</ent>, its tank
field. When the Czar abdicated, <ent type='PERSON'>Trotsky</ent> was placed on a ship with three
hundred <ent type='NORP'>Communist</ent> revolutionaries from <ent type='LOC'>the Lower East Side</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent>.
<ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> obtained a special passport for <ent type='PERSON'>Trotsky</ent> from <ent type='PERSON'>Woodrow Wilson</ent>
and sent <ent type='PERSON'>Lincoln Steffens</ent> with him to make sure he was returned safely to
<ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>. For traveling expenses, <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> placed a purse containing
$10000 in Trotsky's pocket. </p>

<p> On April 131917, when the ship stopped in <ent type='GPE'>Halifax</ent>, Canadian Secret
Service officers immediately arrested <ent type='PERSON'>Trotsky</ent> and interred him in Nova
Scotia. The case became an international cause celebre, as leading
government officials from several nations frantically demanded Trotsky's
release. <ent type='ORG'>The Secret Service</ent> had been tipped off that <ent type='PERSON'>Trotsky</ent> was on his
way to take <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent> out of the war, freeing more <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> armies to attack
Canadian troups on the Western Front. </p>

<p> Prime Minister <ent type='PERSON'>Lloyd George</ent> hurriedly cabled orders from <ent type='GPE'>London</ent> to the
Canadian Secret Service to free <ent type='PERSON'>Trotsky</ent> at once - they ignored him.
<ent type='PERSON'>Trotsky</ent> was finally freed by the intervention of one of Rockefeller's
most faithful stooges, Canadian Minister <ent type='PERSON'>Mackenzie King</ent>, who had long
been a "labor specialist" for the <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent>s. King personally obtained
Trotsky's release and sent him on his way as the emissary of the
<ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent>s, commissioned to win <ent type='EVENT'>the Bolshevik Revolution</ent>. Thus, Dr.
<ent type='PERSON'>Armand Hammer</ent>, who loudly proclaimed his influence in <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent> as the
friend of <ent type='PERSON'>Lenin</ent>, has an insignificant claim compared to the role of the
<ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent>s in backing world Communism. </p>

<p> Although Communism, like other "isms", had origined with Marx's
association with <ent type='ORG'>the House</ent> of <ent type='PERSON'>Rothschild</ent>, it enlisted the reverent
support of <ent type='PERSON'>John</ent> D. <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> because he saw Communism for what it is,
the ultimate monopoly, not only controlling the government, the monetary
system and all property, but also a monopoly which, like the corporations
it emulates, is self-perpetuating and eternal. It was the logical
progression from his <ent type='ORG'>Standard Oil</ent> monopoly. </p>

<p> An important step on the road to world monopoly was the most far-reaching
corporation invented by the <ent type='PERSON'>Rothschild</ent>s. This was the international drug
and chemical cartel, I. G. <ent type='ORG'>Farben</ent>. Called "a state within a state" , it
was created in 1925 as Interessen Gemeinschaft Farbeinindustrie Aktien
Gesellschaft, usually known simply as I. G. <ent type='ORG'>Farben</ent>, which simply meant
"The <ent type='ORG'>Cartel</ent>". It had originated in 1904, when the six major chemical
companies in <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> began negotiations to form the ultimate cartel,
merging Badische Anilin,Bayer,Agfa,Hoechst,Weiler-ter-Meer, and
Greisheim-Electron. The guiding spirit,as well as the financing, came
from the <ent type='PERSON'>Rothschild</ent>s, who were represented by their <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> banker, Max
Warburg of M. M. Warburg Company, <ent type='GPE'>Hamburg</ent>. He later headed the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>
Secret Service during <ent type='EVENT'>World War</ent> I and was personal financial advisor to
the <ent type='PERSON'>Kaiser</ent>. </p>

<p> When the <ent type='PERSON'>Kaiser</ent> was overthrown, after losing the war, <ent type='PERSON'>Max Warburg</ent> was not
exiled with him to <ent type='GPE'>Holland</ent>; instead he became the financial advisor to
the new government. </p>

<p> Monarchs may come and go, but the real power remains with the bankers.
While representing <ent type='GPE'>Germany</ent> at <ent type='EVENT'>the Paris Peace Conference</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Max Warburg</ent>
spent pleasant hours renewing family ties with his brother, <ent type='PERSON'>Paul Warburg</ent>,
who, after drafting <ent type='ORG'>the Federal Reserve Act</ent> at <ent type='GPE'>Jekyll Island</ent>, had headed
the U.S. banking system during the war. He was in <ent type='GPE'>Paris</ent> as Woodrow
Wilson's financial advisor. </p>

<p> I. G. <ent type='ORG'>Farben</ent> soon had a net worth of six billion marks, controlling some
five hundred firms. Its first president was Professor <ent type='PERSON'>Carl Bosch</ent>. During
the period of <ent type='GPE'>the Weimar Republic</ent>, I.G. <ent type='ORG'>Farben</ent> officials,seeing the
handwriting, began a close association with one called <ent type='PERSON'>Adolf Hitler</ent>,
supplying much needed funds and political influence. </p>

<p> The success of the I.G. <ent type='ORG'>Farben</ent> cartel had aroused the interest of other
industrialists. <ent type='PERSON'>Henry Ford</ent> was favorably impressed and set up a <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>
branch of <ent type='ORG'>Ford</ent> Motor Company. Forty percent of the stock was purchased by
I.G. <ent type='ORG'>Farben</ent>. I.G. <ent type='ORG'>Farben</ent> then established an <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> subsidiary called
<ent type='NORP'>American</ent> I.G., in cooperation with <ent type='ORG'>Standard Oil</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>New Jersey</ent>. Its
directors included <ent type='PERSON'>Walter Teagle</ent>, President of <ent type='ORG'>Standard Oil</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Paul Warburg</ent>
of <ent type='ORG'>Kuhn</ent>,Loeb Company and <ent type='ORG'>Edsel</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Ford</ent>, representing the <ent type='ORG'>Ford</ent> interests.
<ent type='PERSON'>John</ent> Foster Dulles, for the law firm, <ent type='PERSON'>Sullivan</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>Cromwell</ent>, became the
attorney for I.G., frequently traveling between <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Berlin</ent> on
cartel business. His law partner, <ent type='PERSON'>Arthur Dean</ent>, is now director of the
$40 million <ent type='PERSON'>Teagle</ent> Foundation which was set up before Teagle's death.
Like other fortunes, it had become part of the network. </p>

<p> =============Continued in <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> Syndicate Part 2===================</p>

<p>--
-* <ent type='PERSON'>Don</ent> Allen *- // Only | Tavistock + Esalen = "New Age"
Internet: dona@bilver.uucp <ent type='ORG'>\X</ent>/ Amiga | <ent type='PERSON'>Rothschild</ent> + <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> = <ent type='ORG'>FED</ent>
<ent type='ORG'>UUCP</ent>: .uunet!peora!bilver!vicstoy!dona | UN + Maitreya = "Twilight Zone"
"A democracy cannot be both ignorant and free" - <ent type='PERSON'>Thomas Jefferson</ent>
</p></xml>