<xml>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Skolnick</ent> COMMENTARY #009
========================</p>

<p>[CfD Editor -- I neither necessarily believe nor disbelieve
either all or portions of the following.]</p>

<p>[The following is a transcript of a recorded phone message put
out by a group in <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> called "Citizens' Committee to Clean Up
the Courts." (312) 731-1100 and (312) 731-1505.]</p>

<p>Hi! <ent type='PERSON'>Sherman Skolnik</ent>, Citizens' Committee to Clean Up the Courts,
9800 Oglesby.</p>

<p>More about the strange death of <ent type='ORG'>White House</ent> aide, <ent type='PERSON'>Vincent Foster</ent>,
jr.:</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'><ent type='PERSON'>Hillary</ent> Rodham <ent type='PERSON'>Clinton</ent></ent> and her law partner, <ent type='PERSON'>Foster</ent>, worked on
clandestine deals for <ent type='ORG'>the Bank</ent> of Conspirators and Criminals
International [<ent type='ORG'>BCCI</ent>]. Interlocked with the <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>, the
<ent type='NORP'>French</ent> <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> and other international spy shops like Israel's
<ent type='ORG'>Mossad</ent>, the bank washed funds for dope, guns, the bribery of
public officials, and political assassinations.</p>

<p>With <ent type='PERSON'>Foster</ent> also as Hillary's lover, <ent type='PERSON'><ent type='PERSON'>Bill</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Clinton</ent></ent> was isolated
from what was going on. <ent type='PERSON'>Foster</ent> found out that an <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> murder
squad had been transferred from <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> to the Justice Department.
Specializing in domestic "wipe outs," the squad was more bloody
than those of <ent type='GPE'>Guatemala</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Brazil</ent>. Unknown to many, the U.S.
dealt with political opponents and activists just like they do in
a Banana Republic!</p>

<p>Reputed murder squad chieftain has been Colonel Wayne Adrian
Rich. His position as executive coordinator in the Justice
Department gives him more actual power than the U.S. Attorney
General.</p>

<p>(Yes, we know, it's unconstitutional to have a military officer
as the actual head of the Justice Department.)</p>

<p>Part of "the squad" reportedly included <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> <ent type='ORG'>FBI</ent> agent <ent type='PERSON'>Mike</ent>
"Chucky" <ent type='PERSON'>Peters</ent>, identified in federal court records here as
indicated in the murder of some 41 federal grand jury witnesses
in the notorious <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> affair -- covered up by former federal
district judge <ent type='PERSON'>Nicholas</ent> J. <ent type='PERSON'>Bowa</ent>(sp?) as special Justice
Department counsel. (<ent type='PERSON'>Bowa</ent> has been a defendant in an unpublicized
federal suit here on the issue.)</p>

<p>Among those bumped off by "the squad" have been journalist Danny
Casolero, working on a book on what he called "the Octopus" --
interfacing October Surprise, <ent type='GPE'>Iran</ent>-contra, <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>BCCI</ent>, Bank
Lavoro, bankruptcy court bribery, and other bloody deals.</p>

<p>Another victim was <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> bankruptcy auctioneer Wallace
Lieberman(sp?). According to accusations in the court record, he
was "rubbed out" by <ent type='ORG'>FBI</ent> agent <ent type='PERSON'>Peters</ent>.</p>

<p>"The squad" also bombed the airplane, killing <ent type='PERSON'>Gary Caradori</ent>,
private eye investigating high-level pedophile and porno rings
implicating top government officials in <ent type='GPE'>Omaha</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>, and
<ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, D.C. [see part 2 of today's "CfD"].</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>White House</ent> aide <ent type='PERSON'>Foster</ent> never lived to keep an appointment he
made with President <ent type='PERSON'>Clinton</ent> -- to warn him that <ent type='PERSON'>Clinton</ent> himself
was a possible assassination target *and* that <ent type='PERSON'>Clinton</ent> should do
something about the murder squad or eventually face impeachment.</p>

<p>Knowledgeable investigators contend that Clinton's problem is he
does not know *that he does not know* about all this.</p>

<p>"The squad" murdered <ent type='PERSON'>Foster</ent> and, on purpose, bungled up the scene
so as to try to "finger" <ent type='PERSON'>Hillary</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Bill</ent> for covering up the
murder of Hillary's lover and law partner.</p>

<p>The press fakers, assets of <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>, keep calling it "suicide." Now,
to try to incriminate the President, a major news magazine is
pressuring a <ent type='GPE'>Virginia</ent> state prosecutor to focus on <ent type='PERSON'>Bill</ent> and
<ent type='PERSON'>Hillary</ent> as accomplices to murder by covering it up. Leading the
attack has been <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> congressman <ent type='PERSON'>Henry Hyde</ent>, head of CIA's
"black budget" *and* having more actual power than the director
of <ent type='ORG'>Central Intelligence</ent>.</p>

<p>Related matters: the murders of <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> officials outside their
headquarters *and* Admiral <ent type='PERSON'>Bobby Ray Inman</ent> acting goofy, on
purpose, to withdraw his name as Secretary of Defense.</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Clinton</ent> may escape by a war scare. [CfD -- <ent type='PERSON'>Skolnik</ent> was saying
he had information suggesting an imminent war scare on a
recent broadcast of Radio Free America. The broadcast occurred
shortly before the bombing in <ent type='GPE'>Sarajevo</ent>.]</p>

<p>And so, it's an old story: an innocent husband wrecked by an
unfaithful, conniving wife. *And*, unless he goes public, it's
"bye-bye, <ent type='PERSON'>Bill</ent>." It would be also "bye-bye, <ent type='PERSON'>Hillary</ent>," huh?</p>

<p>See us on cable TV in <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>, channel 21. 9 pm [cst] Monday
evenings, February 14, 21, and 28.</p>

<p>Play it again: <ent type='ORG'>The Rotten</ent> *<ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> Tribune*, (312)731-1505. New
message Monday; we change it several times a week. Donations
appreciated. Citizens' Committee to Clean Up the Courts, 9800
South Oglesby, <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>, [<ent type='GPE'>Illinois</ent>] 60617. For the latest on
courts, banks, espionage agencies, political assassinations, and
the news media.

</p></xml>