<xml>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Skolnick</ent> COMMENTARY #005
========================</p>

<p>[CfD Editor -- I neither necessarily believe nor disbelieve
either all or portions of the following.]</p>

<p>[The following is a transcript of a recorded phone message put
out by a group in <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> called "Citizens' Committee to Clean Up
the Courts." (312) 731-1100 and (312) 731-1505.]</p>

<p>Hi! <ent type='PERSON'>Sherman Skolnik</ent>, Citizen's Committee to Clean Up the Courts,
9800 Oglesby.</p>

<p>So far, the press has stonewalled a major bribery story. This is
about <ent type='ORG'>the Bank</ent> of Criminals and Conspirators International. <ent type='ORG'>BCCI</ent>
supposedly went under in 1991. A high official of the bank turned
over to <ent type='ORG'>the Bank</ent> of England an important document showing how
<ent type='ORG'>BCCI</ent> bought its way into the U.S. government by seeking to have
the rogue bank spread out over this nation. Funny thing: the hot
paper was kept as an open record for 30 days. An international
news group retrieved it and verified that receiving bribes were
108 members of the U.S. House of Representatives and 28 U.S.
Senators. The press lords, however, killed the story. So, the
details were given to us and we pledged never to reveal the names
of the helpful journalists. Our story about it appeared
exclusively in a conservative publication. No sizeable news group
would go *near* the explosive details.</p>

<p>Six <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> commodities brokers were the vehicles of bribery.
Such as <ent type='ORG'>London Affiliates</ent>(?), reportedly including CapCom(?) and
GNP(?) Commodities. CapCom reportedly was being reviewed by top
officials of Telecommunications, Inc. [<ent type='ORG'>TCI</ent>] of <ent type='GPE'>Denver</ent> and
<ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>, the major cable monster.</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>BCCI</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>TCI</ent> also own about 16% of <ent type='ORG'>Turner Broadcasting</ent> and a
sizeable hunk of the parent of <ent type='ORG'>ABC</ent> News, and worked a corrupt
group of deals with the bigwigs at <ent type='ORG'>CBS</ent>.</p>

<p>So, the press fakers were afraid to death of the story. Also used
as money launderies to bribe both houses of <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent> were the
<ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> Board of Trade and the <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> Mercantile Exchange. At
one time, the <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> exchanges were the major givers of gifts to
<ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>. So, representatives and senators would fly into <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>
-- supposedly to give a speech -- and get their "honorarium" and,
at the same time, secret trading accounts were opened up for
them.</p>

<p>As to them [secret trading accounts(?)], the commodity records
show the loss in <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> *but* a huge profit in the name of a
strong man, or nominee, at the <ent type='GPE'>London</ent> end. The profits were
withdrawn, so the lawmakers either got the bribes or were being
blackmailed with record footprints showing they were paid off.
Either way, <ent type='ORG'>BCCI</ent> had <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent> "on the hook".</p>

<p>Early in '94, a top former <ent type='ORG'>BCCI</ent> official agreed to be extradited
to <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States to stand trial for massive fraud. So now,
the press admits he has direct knowledge of the bribery of U.S.
government officials.</p>

<p>By the way, the press are liars when they say <ent type='ORG'>BCCI</ent> is defunct.
Reportedly continuing their secret dealings is <ent type='ORG'>Chemical</ent>(?)
[Clinical(?)] Bank Group made up of shadowy types from <ent type='GPE'>Atlanta</ent>
and <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>. They have bought out known criminal money launderies
here, such as <ent type='ORG'>First National Bank</ent> of <ent type='NORP'>Cicero</ent>, originally operated
by <ent type='PERSON'>Paul Marchinkas</ent>(sp?), long-time head of the mafia/<ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>-linked
<ent type='ORG'>Vatican Bank</ent>.</p>

<p>Some contend all this diabolical data has been compiled by the
<ent type='NORP'>Dutch</ent> and the <ent type='NORP'>British</ent>, who have a long-standing scheme to
overthrow the U.S. government, explode the U.S. Constitution,
*and* exploit the U.S. workforce without [unclear], without
health benefits, and without decent wages.</p>

<p>You heard it right here: the related, exclusive details, such as
the <ent type='ORG'>Androchetti</ent>(sp?) Affair; the $50 million Resolution Trust
Corporation contingency fund which disappeared from <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> and
ended up to try to cover up Clinton's financial scandals in
<ent type='GPE'>Arkansas</ent>; <ent type='PERSON'>Bill</ent> and Hillary <ent type='PERSON'>Clinton</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>BCCI</ent>; and the <ent type='ORG'>Mena</ent>,
<ent type='GPE'>Arkansas</ent>, airport affair; dope and gun running; and...</p>

<p>In <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>, see us on cable TV, channel 21, 9 pm [CST] every
Monday evening in January [1994]. Play it again: the <ent type='PERSON'>Daley</ent> family
and crooked City Hall, (312) 731-1505. New message Thursday; we
change it several times a week. Donations appreciated. Citizens'
Committee to Clean Up the Courts, 9800 South Oglesby, <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>,
[<ent type='GPE'>Illinois</ent>] 60617. The latest on courts, banks, espionage
agencies, political assassinations, and the news media. On 24
hours a day...

</p></xml>