<xml><p>
<ent type='PERSON'>Skolnick</ent> COMMENTARY #001
========================</p>

<p>Hi. <ent type='PERSON'>Sherman Skolnik</ent>, Citizen's Committee to Clean Up the Courts,
9800 Oglesby.</p>

<p>At one time the <ent type='PERSON'>Pope</ent> owned three major banks in <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>: New
York, <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>San Francisco</ent>.</p>

<p>In <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent>, St. Peter's banker, <ent type='PERSON'>Michael Saddona</ent> (sp?) ran the
Franklin National Bank as a huge gambling device and money
laundry. Result? The bank collapsed in 1974 and was taken over by
a group of European banks with the Vatican losing *part* of their
grip.</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Saddona</ent> was sent to an <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n prison for fraudulent banking.
Later he was extradited to <ent type='GPE'>Italy</ent> on more charges. He began
talking too much. The <ent type='PERSON'>Pope</ent> silenced him in an <ent type='NORP'>Italian</ent> jail --
*murdered* with a poisoned cup of coffee. (By the way, the same
method they used to murder <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> mayor <ent type='PERSON'>Harold Washington</ent>, a
poisoned cup of coffee, and replaced him with the Vatican's man
of trust, Richie Daley.)</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Saddona</ent> and his confederate successors also ran, for the <ent type='PERSON'>Pope</ent>,
<ent type='ORG'>the Continental Bank</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>. All the <ent type='NORP'>Catholic</ent> churches of the
Western Hemisphere run their money through that bank. After all,
the archbishop of <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> is also the treasurer, for the <ent type='ORG'>Church</ent>,
for all of <ent type='PERSON'>North</ent> <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>, Central <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> and South <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>.</p>

<p>In the early 1980s, <ent type='ORG'>Continental Bank</ent>, through their holding
company owed some $20 billion to the <ent type='NORP'>Japanese</ent>, including their
mafia, the yakusa (sp?) who had put in slight capital.
<ent type='ORG'>Continental</ent> could not repay, so the <ent type='NORP'>Japanese</ent> in May, 1984,
started a run on the bank and its holding company, <ent type='ORG'>Continental</ent>
<ent type='GPE'>Illinois</ent>. Result? A consortium of banks, headed by J.P. <ent type='PERSON'>Morgan</ent>
and Company, took over -- with the <ent type='PERSON'>Pope</ent> losing *part*, but not
all, of his control.</p>

<p>The <ent type='PERSON'>Morgan</ent> banks are the front for <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> royalty and the <ent type='PERSON'>Queen</ent>,
who for over 100 years always had a director sitting to supervise
<ent type='ORG'>Continental</ent>. Through <ent type='ORG'>Continental Bank</ent>, however, the Vatican
continued to oversee Panama's General <ent type='PERSON'>Noriega</ent>, and his joint,
secret business deals with <ent type='PERSON'>George Bush</ent>. So, when the U.S. invaded
<ent type='GPE'>Panama</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Noriega</ent> naturally sought refuge in the Vatican Embassy
and branch of <ent type='ORG'>the Vatican Bank</ent>. The U.S. military used
psychological warfare, including super hard-rock music to drive
him out.</p>

<p>The Justice Department's record grabbers have descended on
<ent type='ORG'>Continental Bank</ent>, seeking to destroy incriminating records that
would put President <ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent> in the same jail cell with his <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>
business partner, General <ent type='PERSON'>Noriega</ent>. By the way, <ent type='GPE'>Panama</ent>, under
General <ent type='PERSON'>Noriega</ent> was the only country in <ent type='LOC'>the Western Hemisphere</ent>
run by a dark-skinned person. <ent type='PERSON'>Noriega</ent> was popular with the bulk
of those *in* <ent type='GPE'>Panama</ent>, who are people of color. It was only the
small, white aristocracy *there* that wanted him removed. They
used the branches of worldwide banks there to skim off loot from
dope and gun running. <ent type='PERSON'>Noriega</ent> was really just a small-time, semi-independent tyrant.</p>

<p>Helping supervise <ent type='ORG'>Continental Bank</ent> has been the Vatican's man of
trust, <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> federal appeals judge <ent type='PERSON'>Walter Cummings</ent> (sp?), for
many years also chief judge and major stockholder of the bank.
Judge <ent type='PERSON'>Cummings</ent> steers cases in his court to fellow banker/judges
-- which is most of them.</p>

<p>For many years the major owners of Bank of <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> and their
holding company were the Jesuits and the Vatican, and their long-time cronies, the <ent type='PERSON'>Rothschilds</ent> (sp?). Like <ent type='ORG'>Continental Bank</ent> up
until 1984, they owed tens of billions of dollars to the <ent type='NORP'>Japanese</ent>
and the yakusa, who own most of the other sizeable banks in
<ent type='GPE'>California</ent>. In the late 1980s, Bank of <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> was faced with a
run, so they have quietly given over most of the control to the
<ent type='NORP'>Japanese</ent>.</p>

<p>Although the <ent type='PERSON'>Pope</ent> has lost much of the control of the three banks
in <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>, the pontiff continues as the major owner in nuclear
power utility firms, including <ent type='ORG'>Commonwealth</ent> Edison and Florida
Power.</p>

<p>See us on <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> cable channel 21, 9 pm Monday evening, Aug.
23rd.</p>

<p>Play it again. Corruption in the federal prosecutors
office. (312) 731-1505</p>

<p>New message <ent type='LOC'>Sunday</ent>, we change it several times a week. Donations
appreciated.</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>Citizens Committee</ent> to Clean Up the Courts
9800 South Oglesby
<ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Illinois</ent> 60617</p>

<div>-----------------------------------------------------------------</div>

<p>The number I called was (312) 731-1100. I have an alternate
listing for them at (312) 731-1505.</p>

</xml>