<xml>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Skolnick</ent> COMMENTARY #008
========================</p>

<p>[CfD Editor -- I neither necessarily believe nor disbelieve
either all or portions of the following.]</p>

<p>[The following is a transcript of a recorded phone message put
out by a group in <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> called "Citizens' Committee to Clean Up
the Courts." (312) 731-1100 and (312) 731-1505.]</p>

<p>Hi! <ent type='PERSON'>Sherman Skolnik</ent>, Citizens' Committee to Clean Up the Courts,
9800 Oglesby.</p>

<p>A major news agency has keys to the future of the <ent type='PERSON'>Clinton</ent> White
House.</p>

<p>THE DETAILS</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Hillary</ent> Rodham <ent type='PERSON'>Clinton</ent> has been a law partner of <ent type='PERSON'>Vincent Foster</ent>,
jr., who became a <ent type='ORG'>White House</ent> aide. Earlier, <ent type='PERSON'>Foster</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Hillary</ent>,
as lawyers, arranged for <ent type='ORG'>Bank Lavoro</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Atlanta</ent>, and their twin,
Bank of Criminals and Conspirators International [<ent type='ORG'>BCCI</ent>], to get
$4 billion to <ent type='PERSON'>Saddam Hussein</ent> for weapons, including nuclear --
all disguised as U.S. agriculture loans, laundered through the
[unclear] banking group and the <ent type='PERSON'>Stevens</ent>(sp?) family, financially
interlocked with the <ent type='PERSON'>Clinton</ent>s.</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Hillary</ent>, and <ent type='PERSON'>Foster</ent>, were attorneys fronting for these Little
Rock bankers -- largest bond brokers outside of Wall Street. The
role of <ent type='PERSON'>Foster</ent> was more than just personal lawyer for <ent type='PERSON'>Bill</ent> and
his wife. <ent type='PERSON'>Foster</ent> was also Hillary's lover -- sort of balancing
off Bill's episodes with the mistress. After all, all is fair in
love and war.</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>The Resolution Trust Corporation</ent> [<ent type='ORG'>RTC</ent>] needed a new chief.
Strange, but President <ent type='PERSON'>Clinton</ent>, a purported <ent type='NORP'>Democrat</ent>, in July '93
appointed a <ent type='PERSON'>George Bush</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Republican</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Stanley Tate</ent>, to be <ent type='ORG'>RTC</ent> boss.</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Clinton</ent> was blackmailed into it.</p>

<p>Yet <ent type='PERSON'>Tate</ent> threatened a top-to-bottom corruption cleanup of this
S&amp;L salvage agency [i.e. <ent type='ORG'>RTC</ent>]. A week later, <ent type='PERSON'>Foster</ent> was murdered
by three hit men from a <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> base.</p>

<p>A <ent type='ORG'>senate</ent> committee stonewalled Tate's ratification, and he
withdrew his name late in November '93.</p>

<p>And thereafter escalated the Madison Guaranty S&amp;L mess and the
<ent type='ORG'>Whitewater Development</ent> scandal. In Foster's office were
incriminating records which were grabbed up to whitewash <ent type='PERSON'>Hillary</ent>.
It is an unanswered question whether <ent type='PERSON'>Bill</ent> himself knew how <ent type='PERSON'>Foster</ent>
and <ent type='PERSON'>Hillary</ent> siphoned off some $47 million from the S&amp;L.</p>

<p>To save <ent type='PERSON'>Hillary</ent> from possible prison, <ent type='PERSON'>Bill</ent> had key records
suppressed and announced that <ent type='PERSON'>Foster</ent> was a suicide. *Oh, yeah*?!</p>

<p>A fake, crumpled-up, so-called "suicide note" was later,
supposedly, found in Foster's suitcase.</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Bill</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Hillary</ent>, by covering up the murder, have become
accomplices to it -- a serious crime. (And some may think that
what was cruel of her was to cover up the murder of her lover
just to save herself.)</p>

<p>The major news group is deciding whether to go with these
details, all documented to their satisfaction.</p>

<p>(AND: A close relative of Vice-President <ent type='PERSON'>Albert Gore</ent> has said
that he [<ent type='PERSON'>Gore</ent>] will become President soon.)</p>

<p>But they had problems:
1) The news group's stock has already been slipping. At the same
time, release of this timely story would cause a crack in the
stock market and a fall in the news group's shares. So, they
hesitate -- at least at this time, anyway;
2) But -- if they don't go with this story [that] they already
have, they would lose credibility with other, competing news
groups [who] may run with it; and
3) The ultra-rich got what they want in pushing <ent type='PERSON'>Clinton</ent>, a
relative unknown and a perceived misfit, into high office. So why
wreck him now? Well, because it opens a window of emergency and
opportunity, and the ultra-rich can complete their rotten agenda
of repression and hardship inflicted on the ordinary people.</p>

<p>(312)731-1100 is our main message. Donations appreciated.
Citizens' Committee to Clean Up the Courts, 9800 South Oglesby,
<ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>, [<ent type='GPE'>Illinois</ent>] 60617. For the latest on courts, banks,
espionage agencies, political assassinations, and the news media.

</p></xml>