<xml>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Skolnick</ent> COMMENTARY #007
========================</p>

<p>[CfD Editor -- I neither necessarily believe nor disbelieve
either all or portions of the following.]</p>

<p>[The following is a transcript of a recorded phone message put
out by a group in <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> called "Citizens' Committee to Clean Up
the Courts." (312) 731-1100 and (312) 731-1505.]</p>

<p>Hi! <ent type='PERSON'>Sherman Skolnik</ent>, Citizen's Committee to Clean Up the Courts,
9800 Oglesby.</p>

<p>A <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> federal judge is linked to <ent type='ORG'>the White House</ent> scandals.</p>

<p>THE BACKGROUND</p>

<p>Federal district judge <ent type='PERSON'>George</ent> W. <ent type='PERSON'>Lindbergh</ent> (435-5355) has a
strange business career. He has been a top official of the
<ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>-based <ent type='ORG'>John Reed</ent> Associates (polygraph and security work).
His major clients have been <ent type='ORG'>the Central Intelligence Agency</ent> and
<ent type='ORG'>the National Security Agency</ent>. <ent type='PERSON'>Lindbergh</ent> does frequent "lie box"
work for these espionage agencies. He is an insider.</p>

<p>His firm also did work for the Paradise Island gambling cartel,
run by former top Justice Department officials in the <ent type='GPE'>Bahamas</ent>.
(They headed up, previously, the organized crime section of the
Justice Department.) According to the book *Spooks*, by Jim
Hogan, the bridge there (that is, the toll bridge) is owned by
<ent type='PERSON'>Richard Nixon</ent>.</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Clinton</ent> has used <ent type='PERSON'>Bobby Ray Inman</ent> as a sort of "kamikaze pilot" in
appointing him Secretary of <ent type='ORG'>Defense</ent>. <ent type='PERSON'>Clinton</ent> pushed the retired
admiral into a political suicide mission. Against his will, <ent type='ORG'>Inman</ent>
would've had to be ratified by a <ent type='ORG'>senate</ent> committee prepared to ask
him about a lot of things -- some relating to <ent type='PERSON'>George</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent> and
Inman's role as deputy director of the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>. <ent type='ORG'>Inman</ent> quit just after
the treasonous October Surprise deal by <ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent> and Reagan. <ent type='ORG'>Inman</ent>
was also once head of the "Puzzle Palace" (the name for the
National Security Agency).</p>

<p>The murder of journalist <ent type='PERSON'>Danny Casolero</ent> also involved the killing
of two <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent> employees aiding <ent type='PERSON'>Danny</ent> write about "The Octopus" (his
name for the giant conspiracies, which were treasonous, involving
October Surprise, Iran-Contra, and the notorious <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent> affair
(hushed up when one <ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent> employee was reportedly found murdered in
the same hotel room where they found <ent type='PERSON'>Danny</ent>)).</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>Inman</ent> withdrew his name as Secretary of <ent type='ORG'>Defense</ent> when he realized
he was pushed by <ent type='PERSON'>Clinton</ent> to blow apart <ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent> and other traitors to
their country. <ent type='ORG'>Inman</ent> had been director of <ent type='NORP'>Faranti</ent>(sp?)
<ent type='ORG'>International Signal Controls</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>Lancaster</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Pennsylvania</ent>, which
reportedly was used, by <ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent>, to supply highly-secret military
items, of an exotic nature, to <ent type='GPE'>Iraq</ent>. Used, was <ent type='ORG'>Bank Lavoro</ent>(sp?),
<ent type='GPE'>Atlanta</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>BCCI</ent>, the rogue bank. Also used were savings and
loans tied to <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>.</p>

<p>All this and *more* are involved, in one way or another, in the
<ent type='PERSON'>Andrew Cetti</ent>(sp?) [<ent type='PERSON'>Androchetti</ent>(?)] affair -- some 8 state and
federal cases.</p>

<p>FUNNY THING</p>

<p>Regardless of which judge starts out with this 10-year-old
litigation [i.e. <ent type='PERSON'>Andrew Cetti</ent> affair], the cases end up, by some
mysterious process, to be transferred to judge <ent type='PERSON'>Lindbergh</ent>! -- the
<ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>/<ent type='ORG'>NSA</ent> expert who invokes illegal proceedings to try to hush up
all the mafia/<ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> bank links (including <ent type='ORG'>Vatican Bank</ent>, run by Paul
<ent type='ORG'>Marchinkas</ent>(sp?), also the force behind <ent type='ORG'>the First National Bank</ent> of
<ent type='PERSON'>Cicero</ent>).</p>

<p>(...and that bank in <ent type='PERSON'>Cicero</ent> was taken over by the successor to
<ent type='ORG'>BCCI</ent>. *And* <ent type='ORG'>Marchinkas</ent>' nephew and that bank are among the
defendants in the <ent type='PERSON'>Andrew Cetti</ent> affair...)</p>

<p>Also a party to the cases is <ent type='ORG'>Household Bank</ent>, successor to the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>
front headquartered in <ent type='GPE'>Australia</ent>, the Nugan-Hand(sp?) Bank.</p>

<p>You can see why judge <ent type='PERSON'>Lindbergh</ent> is trying to hush all of this up.
Judge Lindbergh's specialty is to tell somebody to inform him
what is involved -- and then he calls the witness a liar even
though no one disputes the testimony! What, has he got a "lie
box" right under his bench, huh?!</p>

<p>In <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>, see us on cable TV, channel 21, 9 pm [CST] every
Monday evening in January [1994]. Play it again: <ent type='ORG'>FBI</ent>/<ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> Dirty
Business, (312) 731-1505. New message <ent type='LOC'>Sunday</ent>; we change it
several times a week. Donations appreciated. Citizens' Committee
to Clean Up the Courts, 9800 South Oglesby, <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>, [<ent type='GPE'>Illinois</ent>]
60617. The latest on courts, banks, espionage agencies, political
assassinations, and the news media. On 24 hours a day...

</p></xml>