<xml>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Skolnick</ent> COMMENTARY #002
========================</p>

<p>[The following is a transcript of a recorded phone message put
out by a group in <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> called "Citizens' Committee to Clean Up
the Courts." (312) 731-1100 and (312) 731-1505.]</p>

<p>Hi. Sherman <ent type='PERSON'>Skolnick</ent> (sp?), Citizens' Committee to Clean Up the
Courts, 9800 Oglesby (sp?).</p>

<p>Some years ago the federal government set up a special
[inaudible] group. For two-and-a-half years they met in secret at
<ent type='LOC'>Iron Mountain</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent>. Their findings were called "Report from
<ent type='LOC'>Iron Mountain</ent> on the Possibility and Desirability of <ent type='ORG'>Peace</ent>."
Their document, by some of the leading thinkers, was suppressed.
Later, it was printed in a limited edition, with the *names*
removed. Some were shocked by what they read.</p>

<p>Throughout history, permanent peace was dangerous to established
governments. <ent type='EVENT'>War</ent>, and the threat of war, are the principal
organizing force for most societies. They divert attention from
*other* economic and political problems. <ent type='EVENT'>War</ent> keeps the factories
going, wasting government manpower and material that would
otherwise be of surplus. <ent type='ORG'>Peace</ent> brings unemployment, the collapse
of prices of goods and property, and knocks down the government.
In simple terms, war prevents [economic] depression. (By the way,
sooner or later, whatever nation loses a war is overthrown. So it
has been all the centuries. The <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> ruling circles lost the
Vietnam <ent type='EVENT'>War</ent>. The aftermath is bound to scatter the rulers to the
winds.)</p>

<p>As the report says, in Europe, over the years, the typical
standing army consisted of troops unfit for employment in
commerce, industry or agriculture, led by officers unfit to
practice any legitimate profession or to conduct a business
enterprise. A large standing army is a form of social welfare
program; a form of control of the population. <ent type='EVENT'>War</ent>, and the threat
of war, keep all levels of society busy. The newspapers are kept
rich reporting it. Pundits are employed to mouth off. <ent type='EVENT'>War</ent>s speed
up so-called scientific development. <ent type='EVENT'>War</ent> goods do not have to
show a profit or be the lowest price. In permanent peace there
are vast cutbacks in research and development. And yes, wars kill
off surplus population; young men with no good job waiting for
them.</p>

<p>The [<ent type='LOC'>Iron Mountain</ent>] report points out that the war system makes
stable government of society possible. The end of war means the
end of national sovereignty.</p>

<p>Without an identified enemy, why would the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> have
a large secret budget to assassinate political leaders and
overthrow other governments <ent type='ORG'>the White House</ent> does not like?</p>

<p>To promote their secret agenda, the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> has taken over a part of
the savings and loan system to funnel men and money for "dirty
tricks" here and overseas.</p>

<p>The <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> likewise manipulates the federal bankruptcy courts to
grab up companies for use as covert action fronts. In <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>,
this is done with the help of foreign intelligence agencies, such
as <ent type='ORG'>Mossad</ent>. <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> bankruptcy trustee <ent type='PERSON'>William</ent> A. <ent type='ORG'>Brand</ent> (sp?) jr.
is a top honcho of the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> and other spy shops.</p>

<p>In the name of national security, the mass media have been
*ordered* to "soft pedal" or "stay shut" about spy agencies doing
such things. The <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> involvement in bankruptcy court should have
made headlines as the number one item on the evening TV news. Yet
not one word is said by the liars and whores of the press.</p>

<p>Play it again: <ent type='ORG'>Fermilab</ent> and weather modification. (312) 731-1505.</p>

<p>New message Monday; we change it several times a week. Donations
appreciated. Citizens' Committee to Clean Up the Courts, 9800 S.
Oglesby (sp?), <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>, 60617.</p>

<p>For the latest on courts, banks, espionage agencies, political
assassinations and the news media. On 24 hours.

</p></xml>