<xml>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Skolnick</ent> COMMENTARY #006
========================</p>

<p>[CfD Editor -- I neither necessarily believe nor disbelieve
either all or portions of the following.]</p>

<p>[The following is a transcript of a recorded phone message put
out by a group in <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> called "Citizens' Committee to Clean Up
the Courts." (312) 731-1100 and (312) 731-1505.]</p>

<p>Hi! <ent type='PERSON'>Sherman Skolnik</ent>, Citizen's Committee to Clean Up the Courts,
9800 Oglesby.</p>

<p>Cynics have their own way of explaining things. Such as? <ent type='PERSON'>Clinton</ent>
returns from Europe amid a growing scandal called "<ent type='LOC'>Whitewater</ent>."
He mutters to himself, "I have to have a distraction." A few
hours later, a devastating earthquake shakes <ent type='GPE'>California</ent>.
Conspiracy theorists shout, "Ah-HAH! I told you so! Scientists
now have a way of triggering off earthquakes!"</p>

<p>This may just be a fanciful way of expressing it. Maybe Mother
Nature just handed the President a change of subject at a
convenient time, on a national holiday, Dr. King's birthday.</p>

<p>Sooner or later, <ent type='PERSON'>Clinton</ent> may find his credibility has
disappeared. Can a lawyer-liar continue nevertheless to be the
front man, supposedly running the country, huh?! Is he going to
go along with the <ent type='LOC'>Whitewater</ent> mess because his bosses, the ultra-rich, [unclear] since he was blackmailable? Others think the
American Murder Association [A.M.A.] and the health insurance
cartel want <ent type='PERSON'>Hillary</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Bill</ent> to go.</p>

<p>Under the 25th amendment to the U.S. Constitution, <ent type='PERSON'>Gore</ent> would
become President and there is a reported deal to make Jay
<ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> Vice President -- all by appointment, without an
election.</p>

<p>Another possibility is to declare, *or create*, a national
emergency and invoke little-known provisions to suspend the
Constitution! If so, General <ent type='PERSON'>Shelley Kasivilli</ent>(sp?) would step up
to the <ent type='ORG'>White House</ent> microphone and say, "I'm in charge here." He
has been selected to be the head of <ent type='ORG'>the Joint Chiefs</ent> of Staff.
Sarcastic folks expect to see him on TV standing -- now get this
-- next to a banner of the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> era, depicting his family's pro-<ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> background.</p>

<p>A change in the <ent type='ORG'>White House</ent> most likely would cause a stock
market crash and be the basis for the so-called "national
emergency."</p>

<p>Little known is the fact key federal judges around the country
wear two hats: as judge and as selected officers for the Federal
Emergency Management Agency [<ent type='ORG'>FEMA</ent>]. As <ent type='ORG'>FEMA</ent> operatives, they
would automatically refuse *habeus corpus* and other
constitutional rights to political activists on the National
Security Index. Computer-generated arrest warrants for such
outspoken folks are already waiting. Concentration camps have
been built in remote areas, including off-shore <ent type='GPE'>Alaska</ent>.</p>

<p>The inside, sinister joke is the mass media already act as one
trumpet for the <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent>s and their ilk. The media fakers
don't need a <ent type='ORG'>FEMA</ent> directive to censor and falsify the news. Why
they do it every day right now!</p>

<p>The press whores have never allowed a candid, public discussion
of the series of Executive Orders, the blueprints for
dictatorship. In a so-called "national emergency," the so-called
"head of the country" would issue martial law decrees; taking
over the farms, the factories, communications, the courts, and
the economy of the country.</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>FEMA</ent> has computerized, crisis-action programs to control all
this. Some contend it is unconstitutional, *but* with the courts
closed... uh, after all, who would publicly proclaim the illegal
nature of these decrees?</p>

<p>In <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>, among the <ent type='ORG'>FEMA</ent> operatives are [allegedly] 7th circuit
federal appeals chief judge <ent type='PERSON'>Richard Posner</ent>(sp?). He's also a
spokesman for Rockefeller's oil-soaked University of <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>. He
is a dictator even on a quiet day!</p>

<p>Another "<ent type='ORG'>FEMA</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent>" is [allegedly] <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> federal district
judge <ent type='PERSON'>Paul</ent> E. <ent type='PERSON'>Plunkett</ent>(sp?).</p>

<p>To save the Constitution, some say, "Keep our crooked President,
right or wrong."</p>

<p>In <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>, see us on cable TV, channel 21, 9 pm every Monday
evening in January.</p>

<p>Play it again: The <ent type='ORG'>FBI</ent> and the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> Dirty Games. [312] 731-1505.
New message Monday; we change it several times a week. Donations
appreciated. Citizen's Committee to Clean Up the Courts, 9800
South Oglesby, <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>, [<ent type='GPE'>Illinois</ent>] 60617. For the latest on
courts, banks, espionage agencies, political assassinations...</p>

</xml>