<xml>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Skolnick</ent> COMMENTARY #014
========================</p>

<p>[CfD Editor -- I neither necessarily believe nor disbelieve
either all or portions of the following.]</p>

<p>[The following is a transcript of a recorded phone message put
out by a group in <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> called "Citizens' Committee to Clean Up
the Courts." (312) 731-1100 and (312) 731-1505.]</p>

<p>Hi! Sherman <ent type='PERSON'>Skolnick</ent>, Citizens' Committee to Clean Up the Courts,
9800 South Oglesby.</p>

<p>Headquartered in <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> is a law firm up to their eyeballs in
the <ent type='PERSON'>Clinton</ent> <ent type='ORG'>White House</ent> scandals: That's <ent type='PERSON'>Hopkins</ent> &amp; <ent type='PERSON'>Sutter</ent>, with
offices also in <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, D.C. and <ent type='GPE'>Dallas</ent>.</p>

<p>Their major clients have included the federal deposit insurance
and *their* stepsister, <ent type='ORG'>Resolution Trust Corp</ent>. [<ent type='ORG'>RTC</ent>]</p>

<p>The <ent type='ORG'>RTC</ent> is accused by some of being the principle whitewashing
machine for <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> and members of <ent type='ORG'>congress</ent> implicated in the S&amp;L
ripoff.</p>

<p>Strange, but <ent type='PERSON'>Hopkins</ent> &amp; <ent type='PERSON'>Sutter</ent> or <ent type='ORG'>RTC</ent> chose the faraway Rose Law
Firm in <ent type='GPE'>Little Rock</ent> to cover up a multi-million dollar mess of a
defunct S&amp;L in a west suburb of <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>. The dirty trick was done
with Rose Law Firm partners <ent type='PERSON'>Hillary</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Rodham</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Clinton</ent> and her
partner, and lover, <ent type='PERSON'>Vincent Foster</ent>, jr.</p>

<p>Details included jailbird and bond broker <ent type='PERSON'>Dan Lassiter</ent>(sp?) whose
business partner became a secretary to <ent type='ORG'>White House</ent> aide <ent type='PERSON'>Foster</ent>.
That secretary reportedly stole Foster's files after he was
murdered, and the documents are being used for blackmail in
<ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>.</p>

<p>Uh, guess who has them? Why, <ent type='PERSON'>Hopkins</ent> &amp; <ent type='PERSON'>Sutter</ent>.</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Hopkins</ent> &amp; <ent type='PERSON'>Sutter</ent> partner <ent type='PERSON'>Jay Steinberg</ent> reportedly has played a
key role in secretly transferring a $50 million <ent type='ORG'>RTC</ent> contingency
fund from <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> to <ent type='GPE'>Little Rock</ent>. Some details are in a series of
blockbuster federal cases here called "<ent type='ORG'>The Andrew Cetti Affair</ent>"
(sp?).</p>

<p>All to try to patch up the $47 million bank embezzlement crisis
pending before a federal grand jury. The accused target? Why,
<ent type='PERSON'>Hillary</ent> and "<ent type='PERSON'>Sludge Willy</ent>."</p>

<p>A close <ent type='PERSON'>Rodham</ent> family crony is <ent type='PERSON'>John Gearham</ent>(?), a lawyer in the
northwest suburb of <ent type='GPE'>Park Ridge</ent>... where <ent type='PERSON'>Hillary</ent> is from. In the
presence of a witness, <ent type='PERSON'>Gearham</ent> confessed to our [Citizen's
Committee to Clean Up the Courts] chairman that <ent type='PERSON'>Gearham</ent> fears
being *himself* framed and sent to federal prison for the $50
million secret transfer and the destruction of <ent type='ORG'>RTC</ent> records.</p>

<p>In simple terms, the murder of <ent type='PERSON'>Foster</ent> and the disappearance of
the <ent type='ORG'>RTC</ent> funds were to keep <ent type='PERSON'>Hillary</ent> from going to prison.</p>

<p>At one time, <ent type='PERSON'>Hopkins</ent> &amp; <ent type='PERSON'>Sutter</ent> were the major recipients of <ent type='ORG'>RTC</ent>
legal fees. A recent statistic shows they were cut way back.</p>

<p>Is the <ent type='ORG'>White House</ent> trying to distance themselves from <ent type='PERSON'>Hopkins</ent> &amp;
<ent type='PERSON'>Sutter</ent>?</p>

<p>Funny thing: RTC's office is actually *inside* Hopkin's &amp;
Sutter's "posh digs" in <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>!</p>

<p>Hopkin's partner, <ent type='PERSON'>Jay Steinberg</ent>, as bankruptcy trustee also
reportedly swept away what happened to about a billion dollars in
a group of companies run by a young con man, <ent type='PERSON'>William Stecker</ent>(?),
[unclear] corporation and others.</p>

<p>The [unclear] swindles and the "<ent type='PERSON'>Andrew Cetti Affair</ent>" both
implicate super <ent type='ORG'>FBI</ent> agent <ent type='PERSON'>Mike</ent> "Chucky" Peters -- according to
undisputed federal court records here, implicated in the murder
of some 41 federal grand jury witnesses.</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Hopkins</ent> &amp; <ent type='PERSON'>Sutter</ent> was hired by the federal deposit insurance to
investigate, supposedly, the offices, directors and lawyers of
<ent type='ORG'>Silverado Savings</ent> &amp; Loan of <ent type='GPE'>Denver</ent> -- a group that included
<ent type='PERSON'>George Bush</ent>'s son, <ent type='PERSON'>Neil</ent>. Hopkin's clout stems from keeping <ent type='PERSON'>Neil</ent>
Bush from going to prison and also hushing up all mention that
the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> plundered <ent type='ORG'>Silverado</ent> in the course of using that S&amp;L for
financing covert operations in <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States and overseas.</p>

<p>In <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>, see us on cable t.v. channel 21, 9 pm most Monday
evenings.</p>

<p>Play it again: The Murder of Reporters. (312) 731-1505.</p>

<p>New message Wednesday; we change it several times a week.</p>

<p>Donations appreciated. Citizen's Committee to Clean Up the
Courts, 9800 South Oglesby, <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>, [<ent type='GPE'>Illinois</ent>] 60617. For the
latest on courts, banks, espionage agencies, political
assassinations, and the news media. On 24 hours...

</p></xml>