<xml>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Skolnick</ent> COMMENTARY #015
========================</p>

<p>[CfD Editor -- I neither necessarily believe nor disbelieve
either all or portions of the following.]</p>

<p>[The following is a transcript of a recorded phone message put
out by a group in <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> called "Citizens' Committee to Clean Up
the Courts." (312) 731-1100 and (312) 731-1505.]</p>

<p>Hi! Sherman <ent type='PERSON'>Skolnick</ent>, Citizens' Committee to Clean Up the Courts
[<ent type='ORG'>CCCC</ent>], 9800 South Oglesby.</p>

<p>&gt;From the time of Clinton's election as President on -- strange
events with <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>.</p>

<p>About the time of Clinton's November '92 election a British
Intelligence operative assisting <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> was murdered, together with
all his family members, in southern <ent type='GPE'>California</ent>. That was Ian
Stewart-Sparrow(sp?) -- having inside knowledge about the
"October Surprise" treason, the <ent type='ORG'>Mena</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Arkansas</ent> airport dope and
gun smuggling implicating <ent type='PERSON'>Clinton</ent> as Governor, and much more.</p>

<p>Right after <ent type='PERSON'>Clinton</ent> was inaugurated, two <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> officials were
murdered and three seriously wounded right on the road leading
into <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> headquarters -- apparently part of a fight between <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>
faction one: <ent type='PERSON'>George Bush</ent> and his gang, and faction two: Naval
Intelligence assassins.</p>

<p>And where does <ent type='PERSON'>Clinton</ent> fit in, huh?</p>

<p>Right before the election some 15 [persons] were arrested --
charged with shipping exotic military items without export
licenses to known terrorists. Among the defendants, Diane
Lewis(sp?), a crony of first lady <ent type='PERSON'>Hillary</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>Park Ridge</ent>, a
northwest <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> suburb. The trial was right after inauguration
day. Ms. Lewis was released after her defense attorney told the
judge, in chambers, she was with <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> *and* a pal of <ent type='PERSON'>Hillary</ent>.</p>

<p>Then, the strange events in <ent type='GPE'>Waco</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Texas</ent>, right near a <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>
brainwashing facility. Some believe some of the Branch Davidian
leaders knew too much. A <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> and military "delta team" murdered
many while tanks with flame shooters burned down the compound. In
the assault on the building two federal agents, previously
Clinton's campaign bodyguards, were murdered -- now get this --
*by their fellow agents*.</p>

<p>On July 17th, '93, President <ent type='PERSON'>Clinton</ent> and/or someone in the White
House acting with them (such as <ent type='PERSON'>Vincent Foster</ent>, jr.) stopped a
genuine <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> plot to assassinate <ent type='NORP'>Iraqi</ent> strongman <ent type='PERSON'>Saddam Hussein</ent>.
Two days later, <ent type='ORG'>FBI</ent> director Sessions was "sacked," on flimsy
excuses, to block his investigation of President Clinton's
treasonous activities -- such as having military officers
assigned to <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> acting as Justice Department prosecutors pursuing
political activist civilians!</p>

<p>The next day, <ent type='ORG'>White House</ent> aide <ent type='PERSON'>Foster</ent> was found murdered in a
lower level of <ent type='ORG'>the White House</ent>. <ent type='ORG'>The Secret Service</ent> removed the
body and planted it in a national park in <ent type='GPE'>Virginia</ent>. The
circumstances, however, were designed by someone to put <ent type='PERSON'>Clinton</ent>
in a "catch-22" position. If <ent type='PERSON'>Clinton</ent> revealed the details, some
of it, somehow, might point to Foster's law partner and lover --
<ent type='PERSON'>Hillary</ent>. Did she want *him* dead to save herself from prison,
huh?</p>

<p>Some $47 million is missing from a federally insured S&amp;L in
<ent type='GPE'>Arkansas</ent>. <ent type='PERSON'>Hillary</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Foster</ent> were implicated in what seems to be
a bank embezzlement. Federal authorities are also investigating
<ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> money-laundering deals reportedly also implicating <ent type='PERSON'>Hillary</ent>
and <ent type='PERSON'>Foster</ent>.</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>The Secret Service</ent> is holding clandestine meetings across the
nation about <ent type='PERSON'>Foster</ent>, "picking the brains" of assassination
experts. <ent type='ORG'>The Secret Service</ent> contends three foreign intelligence
agents, disguised as known <ent type='ORG'>White House</ent> visitors, got into the
<ent type='ORG'>White House</ent> and "wiped out" <ent type='PERSON'>Foster</ent>. {1}. <ent type='ORG'>The Secret Service</ent> also
claims a <ent type='PERSON'>Foster</ent> "double" left <ent type='ORG'>the White House</ent> that afternoon --
all to confuse matters.</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Clinton</ent> is stonewalling release of pertinent records. Some claim
the series of mysteries somehow involve the role of <ent type='PERSON'>Bill</ent> and
<ent type='PERSON'>Hillary</ent> as <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> assets since an early age.</p>

<p>And then there's the <ent type='PERSON'>Rick Ames</ent> spy mess at <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> which <ent type='PERSON'>Clinton</ent> set
on for a year. {2}.</p>

<p>(312) 731-1100 is our main message. Donations appreciated.
Citizens' Committee to Clean Up the Courts, 9800 South Oglesby,
<ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>, [<ent type='GPE'>Illinois</ent>] 60617. The latest on courts, banks, espionage
agencies, political assassinations, and the news media. On 24
hours a day, that's <ent type='ORG'>the Citizens</ent>' Committee to Clean Up the
Courts, 9800 South Oglesby.</p>

<p>--------------------------<special> Notes </special>----------------------------
{1} According to a *<ent type='ORG'>Wall Street Journal</ent>* article dated March 10,
1994 ("Who is <ent type='PERSON'>Patsy Thomasson</ent>?"), there has been lax security at
<ent type='ORG'>the White House</ent>, apparently due to poor overall management.
{2} Again from the *<ent type='ORG'>Wall Street Journal</ent>* of March 10, 1994 ("The
<ent type='ORG'>KGB</ent> and America's War on Drugs"), regarding the <ent type='ORG'>Ames</ent> spy case,
"some key questions have gone unasked." <ent type='ORG'>Ames</ent> reportedly was
involved with the <ent type='ORG'>KGB</ent> in narco-trafficking. The amount of cash
allegedly paid to <ent type='ORG'>Ames</ent> was "far more than in most treason-for-money cases."

</p></xml>