<xml>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Skolnick</ent> COMMENTARY #011
========================</p>

<p>[CfD Editor -- I neither necessarily believe nor disbelieve
either all or portions of the following.]</p>

<p>[The following is a transcript of a recorded phone message put
out by a group in <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> called "Citizens' Committee to Clean Up
the Courts." (312) 731-1100 and (312) 731-1505.]</p>

<p>Hi! Sherman <ent type='PERSON'>Skolnick</ent>, Citizens' Committee to Clean Up the Courts,
9800 South Oglesby.</p>

<p>The signs are there, but not enough people are watching.</p>

<p>The stock market has been pumped up by a lot of people emptying
their bank accounts and other financial accounts and buying
mutual funds. The theory being: the managers of mutual funds
[pay(?)] more than others. Oh, yeah?</p>

<p>And the mutual funds, in turn, buy stocks. So a lot of
inexperienced, unsophisticated people have a lot of their life
savings into stocks. Also, the very low interest rates have
pumped up the price of bonds. On huge volume, the stock market
has been churning -- inching up, and backing down -- as the
ultra-rich use their newspapers, magazines, radio and t.v. to
lure more and more suckers into the markets.</p>

<p>Traditionally, sizeable corporate interests buy off financial
reporters to float stories heating up the know-nothings into
buying. Some such reporters, and their editors, are double-dippers: their regular salary plus "under the table" to promote
phoney stories. It's one of the great unpublicized scandals,
along with the media acting to "shake down" companies to get
advertising contracts [by] threatening to run negative items.</p>

<p>At the top of the market, the very-rich unload and it's called
"distribution." Insiders know the horrendous news is waiting to
be sprung. Such as terrible news about <ent type='ORG'>IBM</ent>, that their securities
are being racked by the ratings agencies like Standard &amp; Poors.
Or even worse, that <ent type='ORG'>IBM</ent> may be pushed into bankruptcy by panicy
banks. Items like that, if widely circulated, could be the pin to
Wall Street's balloon. With the markets so puffed up, some think
a specific "pin" is not necessary.</p>

<p>The press is avoiding discussion. We're facing a crash in bonds
or in stocks, or *both* together.</p>

<p>A few realize the great danger of overstaying a bull market.</p>

<p>Question: Is <ent type='PERSON'>Clinton</ent> up to it? Can he deal with the financial
tailspin without using emergency powers -- such as shutting down
the stock exchanges or halting the bond markets -- *huh*?!</p>

<p>Using domestic emergency powers is becoming more and more
useless. High technology makes it easy to side-step Wall Street
and trade on foreign exchanges with the blip of a computer mouse. </p>

<p>Also, so-called "derivatives" are the "tail wagging the dog" --
options and futures contracts and numbers games of every kind.</p>

<p>The ultra-rich promote paper money; they feel they can control
the [peasants(?)] that way. On the other hand: independent money
in gold, silver and platinum. When gold is able to stay over $410
an ounce, well, the paper money game will come to an end. The
<ent type='ORG'>Fed</ent>eral Reserve and other private, central banks keep trying to
keep gold under the magic number of 410. But demands for gold
will wreck The Fed's dirty trick.</p>

<p><ent type='GPE'>America</ent> and the western world are facing 3 historical cycles: the
500 year economic cycle, 1492-1992 (we're overdue on that one);
and the 60 year cycle 1933 (the date of the bank collapse) and
1993; and then there's 1943 -- the Pope made a secret 50 year
deal not to interfere with the western world and their
financials. Of course it's up in 1993.</p>

<p>Strong central governments are becoming obsolete: <ent type='GPE'>Moscow</ent>,
<ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>London</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Paris</ent> and others.</p>

<p>What can you do? Huh-huh. Call up your news-fakers and tell them
to stop *kidding* us, huh?!</p>

<p>In <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>, see us on cable TV, channel 21. 9 pm [cst] Monday
evenings, February 21, 28, and March 7.</p>

<p>Play it again: *Eliminating Presidents*, (312)731-1505. New
message Thursday; we change it several times a week. Donations
appreciated. Citizens' Committee to Clean Up the Courts, 9800
South Oglesby, <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>, [<ent type='GPE'>Illinois</ent>] 60617. For the latest on
courts, banks, espionage agencies, political assassinations, and
the news media. On 24 hours...

</p></xml>