<xml>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Skolnick</ent> COMMENTARY #017
========================</p>

<p>[CfD Editor -- I neither necessarily believe nor disbelieve
either all or portions of the following.]</p>

<p>[The following is a transcript of a recorded phone message put
out by a group in <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> called "Citizens' Committee to Clean Up
the Courts." (312) 731-1100 and (312) 731-1505.]</p>

<p>Hi! Sherman <ent type='PERSON'>Skolnick</ent>, Citizens' Committee to Clean Up the Courts
[<ent type='ORG'>CCCC</ent>], 9800 <ent type='GPE'>South Oglesby</ent>.</p>

<p>The <ent type='PERSON'>Clinton</ent> scandal: So you think the center of it is in Little
Rock, huh? *Wrong*. The center is in <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>.</p>

<p>For several years, the primary lawyers for Resolution Trust
Corporation [<ent type='ORG'>RTC</ent>] have been the <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>-based <ent type='ORG'>Hopkins</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Sutter</ent>.
In fact, the S&amp;L bailout agency's principal offices have been
*inside* <ent type='ORG'>Hopkins</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Sutter</ent>!</p>

<p>Prior efforts to show <ent type='ORG'>RTC</ent> is corrupt have been torpedoed. <ent type='ORG'>Hopkins</ent>
[and <ent type='PERSON'>Sutter</ent>] were the ones arranging on behalf of Federal Deposit
Insurance and their step-sister <ent type='ORG'>RTC</ent> for the <ent type='GPE'>Rose</ent> law firm to be
used to handle clean-up claims of defunct S&amp;Ls in the <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>
area.</p>

<p><ent type='GPE'>Rose</ent> partners <ent type='PERSON'>Vincent Foster</ent>, jr., and <ent type='PERSON'>Hillary</ent> Rodham <ent type='PERSON'>Clinton</ent>
were the "law fakers" helping friends escape paying millions.
<ent type='PERSON'>Foster</ent> was also the master "bagman" for tens of millions of
dollars of illegal speculations in <ent type='ORG'>Chicken futures</ent> and "selling
short" pharmaceutical stocks on inside information. This was done
for a circle of law-license gangsters, like <ent type='PERSON'>Hillary</ent> and her
friends, dealing with the selected, criminally-inclined types on
the <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> Mercantile Exchange and the <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> Board Options
Exchange. (By the way, Did they "rub elbows" with relatives of
state and federal judges "washing" bribe money in the same
markets!?)</p>

<p>Foster's vast dirty business in drug stocks overlapped the doings
of Al <ent type='PERSON'>Gore</ent> and his wife, <ent type='PERSON'>Tipper</ent>, and her cousin, <ent type='PERSON'>Michael</ent> R.
<ent type='PERSON'>Taylor</ent>, who went on to become a top honcho of <ent type='ORG'>the Food and</ent> Drug
Administration. <ent type='PERSON'>Gore</ent>, of course, became Vice-President.</p>

<p>Two federal agencies, the <ent type='ORG'>CFTC</ent> [<ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> Futures Trading
Commission] and the SEC [Securities Exchange Commission] are
supposed to investigate such events. *Oh, yeah?!* They and the
press fakers all look the other way so that two *known*
scoundrels could be elected to high office. The President and the
Vice-President are blackmailed by *their patrons*, the ultra-rich.</p>

<p>Some $47 million is missing resulting from the <ent type='GPE'>Arkansas</ent> S&amp;L mess
and other fakery by the <ent type='PERSON'>Clinton</ent>s. To try to patch it up, some $50
million from an <ent type='ORG'>RTC</ent> contingency fund, *in <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>*, was secretly
transferred to <ent type='GPE'>Little Rock</ent>.</p>

<p>One of the lawyers arranging this is from Park Ridge, the <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>
suburb where the <ent type='PERSON'>Rodhams</ent> are from. He is <ent type='PERSON'>John</ent> E. <ent type='PERSON'>Gearham</ent>(?), 708-xxx-xxxx. He is close to Hillary's family. In January '94,
<ent type='PERSON'>Gearham</ent>, in the presence of a former client, confessed to our
chairman [<ent type='ORG'>CCCC</ent>] that <ent type='PERSON'>Gearham</ent> was greatly concerned that his
circle was prepared to "frame" him for the clandestine money
transfer and send him to prison! The "fix" is so strong, he
confessed further, that nothing could save him!</p>

<p>The <ent type='ORG'>RTC</ent> fund is the subject of some *eight* state and federal
cases in the <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> area, known as "the <ent type='PERSON'>Joseph Androcetti</ent>(sp?)
Affair."</p>

<p>Filed in federal court (and a copy served on <ent type='PERSON'>Gearham</ent> and the
RTC's attorneys) are the particulars of Gearham's confession.
When it came up in court, they did not dispute it.</p>

<p>We remind you why <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> is the best place for the "big fix" --
like used by the <ent type='PERSON'>Clinton</ent>s. Remember: The currency and commodity
markets are here; preferred for "washing" bribery money by
government officials worldwide. The news media here are the
biggest liars in the land, with a *long* background of
criminality -- like the [<ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>] Tribune Company with their
links all the way back to Al Capone. *And* it's been documented
for more than 30 years the state and federal judges here are
moreso "for sale" than any other place in the land!</p>

<p>In <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>, see us on cable tv, channel 21, 9 pm [cst] most
Monday evenings.</p>

<p>Play it again: The Corruption of Al <ent type='PERSON'>Gore</ent>. (312) 731-1505.</p>

<p>New message Friday; we change it several times a week.</p>

<p>Donations appreciated. Citizen's Committee to Clean Up the
Courts, 9800 <ent type='GPE'>South Oglesby</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>, [<ent type='GPE'>Illinois</ent>] 60617. For the
latest on courts, banks, espionage agencies, political
assassinations, and the news media. On 24 hours a day.</p>

</xml>