<xml>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Skolnick</ent> COMMENTARY #016
========================</p>

<p>[CfD Editor -- I neither necessarily believe nor disbelieve
either all or portions of the following.]</p>

<p>[The following is a transcript of a recorded phone message put
out by a group in <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> called "Citizens' Committee to Clean Up
the Courts." (312) 731-1100 and (312) 731-1505.]</p>

<p>Hi! Sherman <ent type='PERSON'>Skolnick</ent>, Citizens' Committee to Clean Up the Courts
[<ent type='ORG'>CCCC</ent>], 9800 South Oglesby.</p>

<p>Are President <ent type='PERSON'>Clinton</ent> and Vice-President <ent type='PERSON'>Gore</ent> *both* facing
removal from office because of scandals?</p>

<p>Background
++++++++++
Prior to re-election in '72 of President <ent type='PERSON'>Nixon</ent> and Vice-President
<ent type='PERSON'>Spiro Agnew</ent>, the ultra-rich through their monopoly press played
down the <ent type='EVENT'>Watergate</ent> matter. The real rulers of <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> knew full-well they [<ent type='PERSON'>Nixon</ent>/<ent type='PERSON'>Agnew</ent>] were scoundrels and could be easily
scandalized to remove them. The secret agenda went into play in
'73; president and vice-president both to be replaced by another
team -- *all* without an election.</p>

<p>Our chairman [<ent type='ORG'>CCCC</ent>] was first in <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States to go public
with details of Agnew's bribery going back to the time when he
was Governor of <ent type='GPE'>Maryland</ent>. Since we [<ent type='ORG'>CCCC</ent>] were *ahead* of the
secret timetable, the press whores called us liars, and worse,
right up until October '73 when <ent type='PERSON'>Agnew</ent>, facing criminal
indictment, resigned.</p>

<p>Similarly, <ent type='PERSON'>Clinton</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Gore</ent> were known by the ultra-rich to be
corrupt scoundrels *before* their '92 election.</p>

<p>Involving hundreds of millions of dollars is milk bovine hormone
by <ent type='ORG'>Monsanto Chemicals</ent>. It speeds up milk production. However, it
causes the cows to be over-used and develop infections which have
to be treated with antibiotics. Pasteurization tends to conceal
all this. However milk drinkers, particularly children, are
greatly at risk.</p>

<p>The head of <ent type='ORG'>the Food and</ent> Drug Administration [<ent type='ORG'>FDA</ent>] has been David
<ent type='PERSON'>Kessler</ent>(sp?), carried over from the <ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent> administration. His
chief deputy is <ent type='PERSON'>Mike Taylor</ent>, a cousin of Al Gore's wife, <ent type='PERSON'>Tipper</ent>.
<ent type='PERSON'>Taylor</ent> was previously chief outside counsel for <ent type='ORG'>Monsanto</ent>.</p>

<p>About February '94, top <ent type='ORG'>FDA</ent> honcho <ent type='PERSON'>Taylor</ent> caused to be issued an
advisory opinion that labelling is *not* required that a product
is bovine hormone free.</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Gore</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Tipper</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Kessler</ent> and Tipper's relative, <ent type='PERSON'>Taylor</ent>, make
up what some call "<ent type='ORG'>The Gang</ent> of Four." They reportedly are
indicated in the biggest bucks corruption scandal in the history
of the nation! Millions and millions of dollars.</p>

<p>Also, <ent type='ORG'>FDA</ent> has scientific units; key personnel there have a
zillion dollar racket. Through relatives and friends they "sell
short" pharmaceutical stocks just before the <ent type='ORG'>FDA</ent> rejects putting
the o.k. on some drug with big money potential.</p>

<p>Used for this various bribery and dirty business is the highly
corrupt <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> Board Options Exchange. Two federal agencies that
supervise the markets have covered up these massive crimes
against the <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n people: That's the <ent type='ORG'>CFTC</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>SCC</ent>. [C. Futures
Trading Commission(?) and Securities C. Commission(?)]</p>

<p>Also, the <ent type='ORG'>FDA</ent> enforces an unwritten law called "Failure to
Bribe." Example: A generic drug company making low-priced items
was "plowed under" by the <ent type='ORG'>FDA</ent> -- that was <ent type='ORG'>Barr Chemical</ent>, also a
whistleblower.</p>

<p>Like in 1973, <ent type='ORG'>the New York</ent> Times and other major papers are
sitting on the Vice-President's scandal. Why? Because of a high-level secret agenda and timetable to install Jay <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> and
one other as the new <ent type='ORG'>White House</ent> team.</p>

<p>All without an election.</p>

<p>Because of his bloody family name, <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> could not be
elected on his own.</p>

<p><ent type='EVENT'>Watergate</ent> drew attention *away* from the oil fraud [a.k.a. 1973
"<ent type='ORG'>Oil Embargo</ent>"]. On the other hand, the <ent type='PERSON'>Clinton</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Gore</ent> scandals
would divert attention from the oncoming stock crash and
depression.</p>

<p>This message will run longer than usual on the air; so tell your
friends to listen also.</p>

<p>In <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>, see us on cable t.v. channel 21, 9 pm most Monday
evenings.</p>

<p>Play it again: <ent type='PERSON'>Clinton</ent> and the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> Mysteries. (312) 731-1505.</p>

<p>New message Wednesday; we change it several times a week.</p>

<p>Donations appreciated. Citizen's Committee to Clean Up the
Courts, 9800 South Oglesby, <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>, [<ent type='GPE'>Illinois</ent>] 60617. For the
latest on courts, banks, espionage agencies, political
assassinations, and the news media. On 24 hours a day.

</p></xml>