<xml>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Skolnick</ent> COMMENTARY #018
========================</p>

<p>[CfD Editor -- I neither necessarily believe nor disbelieve
either all or portions of the following.]</p>

<p>[The following is a transcript of a recorded phone message put
out by a group in <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> called "Citizens' Committee to Clean Up
the Courts." (312) 731-1100 and (312) 731-1505.]</p>

<p>Hi! Sherman <ent type='PERSON'>Skolnick</ent>, Citizens' Committee to Clean Up the Courts
[<ent type='ORG'>CCCC</ent>], 9800 South Oglesby.</p>

<p>Chicago's City Hall is an interesting study in power. It is even
considered important by those not *in* the "<ent type='GPE'>Windy City</ent>" [i.e.
<ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>].</p>

<p>Starting in 1955, the city's strong man for 21 years was <ent type='PERSON'>Richard</ent>
J. <ent type='PERSON'>Daley</ent>. He got into office because the one slated by the
<ent type='NORP'>Democrats</ent> for mayor, <ent type='PERSON'>Clarence Wagner</ent>, was assassinated.</p>

<p>You probably know there is no real G.O.P. [i.e. Republican party]
in this town. So usually, if the <ent type='NORP'>Democrats</ent> select you to run...
well, you're in.</p>

<p>In 1976, <ent type='PERSON'>Daley</ent> died -- 24 hours after he was administered an
adulterated swine flu shot. <ent type='PERSON'>Daley</ent>, and <ent type='PERSON'>Otto Kerner</ent>, jr., ran a
private "nuthouse" near <ent type='GPE'>Aurora</ent> [<ent type='GPE'>Illinois</ent>]. <ent type='PERSON'>Kerner</ent>, as local
county judge, was in charge of the "lunatic docket." Political
victims sometimes ended up getting plundered this way. <ent type='PERSON'>Kerner</ent>
went on to become <ent type='GPE'>Illinois</ent> Governor and later, federal appeals
judge. (Our work [i.e. <ent type='ORG'>CCCC</ent>], by the way, sent <ent type='PERSON'>Kerner</ent> to jail for
bribery -- highest ranking such federal judicial <ent type='PERSON'>jailbird</ent> in
history.)</p>

<p>Daley's son <ent type='PERSON'>Richie</ent> sat in the state legislature specializing,
naturally, in mental health laws -- to favor his family asylum.
<ent type='PERSON'>Richie</ent> later became <ent type='GPE'>Cook County</ent> State's Attorney. [<ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> is in
<ent type='GPE'>Cook County</ent>.] In that role, he covered up massive probate fraud.</p>

<p>Example: Former city fire commissioner Quinn was laying in the
hospital, "bombed out." [i.e. very drunk] The <ent type='PERSON'>Daley</ent>s pushed into
service a pliable nurse who helped shove a paper under Quinn's
nose. (The <ent type='PERSON'>Daley</ent>s had a supply of such medical malefactors from
their private padded-cell factory [i.e. the asylum in <ent type='GPE'>Aurora</ent>].)
Thus signed over to the <ent type='PERSON'>Daley</ent> family was some $300000, with
Richie's brother <ent type='PERSON'>Michael</ent> named as probate executor. Some cousins,
however, got gypped [i.e. they were "cheated"] and told a court
reformer all the sordid details.</p>

<p>When maverick mayor <ent type='PERSON'>Harold Washington</ent> was murdered in '87 with a
poisoned cup of coffee, uh -- who covered it up? Why, naturally,
State's Attorney <ent type='PERSON'>Richie</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Daley</ent>. Thus "snuffed out" was Chicago's
first black mayor.</p>

<p>And so, father like son, <ent type='PERSON'>Richie</ent> became mayor by murder. He
carried over police superintendent LeRoy <ent type='PERSON'>Martin</ent>. And, with <ent type='PERSON'>Martin</ent>
and <ent type='PERSON'>Daley</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> became an open city for dope. Police cars even
gave safe escort to whole truckloads of dope on the way to a
police-protected warehouse. Dope money laundries included car
washes, taverns, and certain auto repair shops.</p>

<p>About 1992, a special federal grand jury began "sniffing around."
Unable to feel safe *here*, the grand jury met in *<ent type='GPE'>Milwaukee</ent>*
instead! In on the dirty business, local federal officials
stopped the works. Why? Well, that was going too far. They were
about to indict the former police superintendent *and* his co-conspirator, <ent type='PERSON'>Richie</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Daley</ent>. Instead, the crooked federals framed
two "collectors" for City Hall: <ent type='PERSON'>Richard</ent> R. <ent type='PERSON'>Reynolds</ent>, sr., a
veteran cop, and his sidekick, <ent type='PERSON'>Leonard Kerr</ent>(?).</p>

<p><ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> federal trial judge <ent type='PERSON'>Wayne Anderson</ent> is in a position to
know the truth. That could put <ent type='PERSON'>Richie</ent> [<ent type='PERSON'>Daley</ent>] in prison. *But* --
if the judge even thinks, however, of doing the right thing...
well, this town might have another unsolved political
assassination -- like *him*!</p>

<p>Meanwhile, Richie's wife is money hungry. "Why can't you make
really *big* loot?! -- like brother <ent type='PERSON'>Bill</ent>, running the dope and
money laundering <ent type='ORG'>Amalgamated Bank</ent>, huh?" Richie's wife insists
[that] he not run for re-election in 1995.</p>

<p>So. Do you think this all is just true of <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>? Wrong. Other
big cities are about the same.</p>

<p>In <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>, see us on cable tv, channel 21, 9 pm [cst] most
Monday evenings.</p>

<p>Play it again: The Crooked Chief Federal Appeals Judge Here.
(312) 731-1505.</p>

<p>New message Friday; we change it several times a week.</p>

<p>Donations appreciated. Citizen's Committee to Clean Up the
Courts, 9800 South Oglesby, <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>, [<ent type='GPE'>Illinois</ent>] 60617. For the
latest on courts, banks, espionage agencies, political
assassinations, and the news media. On 24 hours a day.

</p></xml>