<xml>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Skolnick</ent> COMMENTARY #010
========================</p>

<p>[CfD Editor -- I neither necessarily believe nor disbelieve
either all or portions of the following.]</p>

<p>[The following is a transcript of a recorded phone message put
out by a group in <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> called "Citizens' Committee to Clean Up
the Courts." (312) 731-1100 and (312) 731-1505.]</p>

<p>Hi! Sherman <ent type='PERSON'>Skolnick</ent>, Citizens' Committee to Clean Up the Courts,
9800 Oglesby.</p>

<p>More about the <ent type='PERSON'>Clinton</ent> <ent type='ORG'>White House</ent> scandals.</p>

<p>Some contend <ent type='ORG'>White House</ent> aide <ent type='PERSON'>Vincent Foster</ent>, jr. committed
suicide *in* the <ent type='ORG'>White House</ent> and the body was removed and planted
in a park in <ent type='GPE'>Virginia</ent>. If so, whoever moved the body used the
opportunity to make it look like he was murdered. So the
President and his wife would be guilty of being accomplices to
murder by their coverup. [??] Others contend the body shows
<ent type='PERSON'>Foster</ent> was apparently murdered and the body delivered to the park
and positioned so as to cast suspicion on the <ent type='ORG'>White House</ent>.</p>

<p>Either way, <ent type='PERSON'>Clinton</ent> has stonewalled the matter and arranged to
hold back the release of the autopsy.</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Foster</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Hillary</ent> were not only lovers but also law partners,
and worked on clandestine deals for <ent type='ORG'>the Bank</ent> of Criminals and
Conspirators International [<ent type='ORG'>BCCI</ent>] -- involving money-washing for
domestic and overseas political murders, gun-running, and dope-trafficking. Military <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> officers, posing as Justice Department
officials, have twisted matters around so as to finger Bill
<ent type='PERSON'>Clinton</ent>.</p>

<p>But <ent type='PERSON'>Clinton</ent>, after all, is no angel.</p>

<p>The mass media have soft-pedalled reports that Hillary's law firm
has shredded records relating to the President and first lady's
daily financial business. Some in the press are also slanting
reports so as to blame <ent type='PERSON'>Hillary</ent> alone, as if "<ent type='PERSON'>Sludge Willy</ent>" is
himself innocent. *Oh, yeah?!*</p>

<p>Left out of the press are key details:</p>

<p>ITEM: Some $47 million is missing from the Clinton's <ent type='GPE'>Arkansas</ent>
rotten dealings -- plundering an S&amp;L, funneling money through
real estate firms, and other money [unclear].</p>

<p>ITEM: Clinton's nominee for head of the firm the S&amp;L bailout
racket called "<ent type='ORG'>Resolution Trust Corporation</ent>" [<ent type='ORG'>RTC</ent>] wanted to
clean up S&amp;L corruption. *But*, he withdrew his name. S&amp;Ls in
<ent type='GPE'>Illinois</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Texas</ent>, and <ent type='GPE'>Colorado</ent> have been plundered by <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>
operatives and left bankrupt.</p>

<p>ITEM: The <ent type='ORG'>RTC</ent> in <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> transferred some $50 million from a
little-known contingency fund here to <ent type='GPE'>Arkansas</ent>... the attempt
to cover up the <ent type='GPE'>Arkansas</ent> embezzlement done by the <ent type='PERSON'>Clinton</ent>s and
their criminal gang.</p>

<p>The fund was administered for <ent type='ORG'>RTC</ent> by <ent type='ORG'>Household Bank</ent> as part of
their merger with an S&amp;L in the <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> area. The head of the
parent firm, <ent type='ORG'>Household International</ent>, an expert on financials,
was murdered in April '93. Household is a successor to Nugan-Hand(sp?) <ent type='ORG'>Bank</ent>, the worldwide <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> front headquartered in
<ent type='GPE'>Australia</ent>.</p>

<p>ITEM: Federal judges in <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> have "stood on their head" to try
to cover up the disappearance of the <ent type='ORG'>RTC</ent> fund here and the
transfer to <ent type='GPE'>Arkansas</ent>. ([Allegedly] including <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> federal
district judge <ent type='PERSON'>George Lindbergh</ent>, who heads a "lie box" company
with major clients <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>National Security Agency</ent>, and off-shore
gambling casinos. Also, [allegedly] <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> federal bankruptcy
judge <ent type='PERSON'>John</ent> D. <ent type='ORG'>Schwartz</ent>.) It is referred to as "The Androcetti
Affair"(sp?).</p>

<p>ITEM: <ent type='PERSON'>Hillary</ent> Rodham <ent type='PERSON'>Clinton</ent> is facing indictment by a federal
grand jury in <ent type='GPE'>Little Rock</ent> for bank embezzlement and income tax
fraud.</p>

<p>ITEM: Leading the attack on the <ent type='PERSON'>Clinton</ent> <ent type='ORG'>White House</ent> is <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>
<ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>man <ent type='PERSON'>Henry Hyde</ent>, reportedly in charge of CIA's bloody
"black budget" [CfD -- This would be money budgeted for <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>
"projects" by the <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent> that for secrecy reasons does not
appear in public documents]. <ent type='PERSON'>Hyde</ent> has more actual power than the
director of <ent type='ORG'>Central Intelligence</ent> to arrange political
assassinations, to launder secret funds, and to railroad enemies
into prison. <ent type='PERSON'>Hyde</ent> has been director of a suburban S&amp;L here, now
defunct, fronting for <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>. The federal court case of <ent type='ORG'>RTC</ent> against
<ent type='PERSON'>Henry Hyde</ent> was ordered suppressed because of "national security."</p>

<p>In <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>, see us on cable TV, channel 21. 9 pm [cst] Monday
evenings, February 14, 21, and 28.</p>

<p>Play it again: <ent type='ORG'>The Rotten</ent> *<ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> Tribune*, (312)731-1505. New
message Saturday; we change it several times a week. Donations
appreciated. Citizens' Committee to Clean Up the Courts, 9800
South Oglesby, <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>, [<ent type='GPE'>Illinois</ent>] 60617. For the latest on
courts, banks, espionage agencies, political assassinations, and
the news media.

</p></xml>