<xml>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Skolnick</ent> COMMENTARY #012
========================</p>

<p>[CfD Editor -- I neither necessarily believe nor disbelieve
either all or portions of the following.]</p>

<p>[The following is a transcript of a recorded phone message put
out by a group in <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> called "Citizens' Committee to Clean Up
the Courts." (312) 731-1100 and (312) 731-1505.]</p>

<p>Hi! Sherman <ent type='PERSON'>Skolnick</ent>, Citizens' Committee to Clean Up the Courts,
9800 <ent type='LOC'>South</ent> Oglesby.</p>

<p>The very rich and powerful are not given to moist-eyed emotion.
They can hold a Christmas party, for example, for their devoted
workers and smile on them. And then, a few days later, dismiss a
bunch of them and tell their brutal security guards to throw the
workers off the premises in one hour.</p>

<p>Fearing a labor dispute, the *<ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> Tribune* put attack dogs to
terrorize the printing workers in <ent type='ORG'>the Trib</ent>'s "Freedom Center."
(With the smashing of the union, by the way, it's called "Slavery
Center.")</p>

<p>Likewise so, when the ultra-rich deal with their mannequins,
labelled "President of <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States." President <ent type='ORG'>Lincoln</ent> was
assassinated a few days after the end of <ent type='EVENT'>the Civil War</ent>. His post-war policy was to go easy on the <ent type='LOC'>South</ent>. So, agriculture would
have resumed amid plummeting prices. The very rich, including the
<ent type='PERSON'>Rothschilds</ent>, had huge commodities speculations to the contrary.
To some, bringing the <ent type='LOC'>South</ent> back [into the Union] was treason.
So, they had Lincoln's brains blown out and blamed a "lone nut."</p>

<p>The ultra-rich and their top military and <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> hawks accused
President <ent type='PERSON'>Kennedy</ent> of treason in denying U.S. air cover at the
aborted invasion of <ent type='GPE'>Cuba</ent> at <ent type='LOC'>the Bay</ent> of Pigs; also, for <ent type='PERSON'>JFK</ent>
planning detente with the <ent type='NORP'>Soviets</ent>. Yet <ent type='PERSON'>JFK</ent> was popular with the
common people. Nevertheless, his brains were blown out in an open
car with military-style triangulation firing. A "lone nut" was
blamed, and himself murdered.</p>

<p>As you can see, the very rich are not sentimental.</p>

<p>The ultra rich (and again, with their trusted <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> and military
retainers) accused President <ent type='PERSON'>Nixon</ent> of treason in his dealings
with <ent type='PERSON'>North</ent> <ent type='GPE'>Vietnam</ent>. Also, he wanted to be an imperial president,
blackmailing <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> with his knowledge of the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> murdering <ent type='PERSON'>JFK</ent>.</p>

<p>Blowing his brains out in an open car would be messy, so, ahead
of the 1972 re-election of "<ent type='PERSON'>Tricky Dick</ent>," <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> double-agents got
themselves caught at the <ent type='EVENT'>Watergate</ent> Hotel -- owned by the Pope.</p>

<p>All to finger <ent type='PERSON'>Nixon</ent>. (Some details are in the book *Silent Coup*
by <ent type='NORP'>Colodny</ent>(sp?)).</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Nixon</ent> was so popular he won re-election in 49 of the 50 states.
Yet, shortly thereafter began the <ent type='EVENT'>Watergate</ent> bombardment. The
press so ran after him he couldn't hold press conferences!</p>

<p>And, just at the height of *his* popularity, the press is
mounting *their* "Whitewater-gate" blitz, against <ent type='PERSON'>Clinton</ent>. Some
of his schemes on health care endanger large insurance companies
-- like <ent type='ORG'>Prudential</ent>, owned by the <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> royal family.</p>

<p>Funny thing: What the press trumpets of the rich are accusing
<ent type='PERSON'>Clinton</ent> are true enough.</p>

<p>Yes, he and his wife committed financial crimes in ripping off
$47 million through <ent type='GPE'>Arkansas</ent> S&amp;L and others.</p>

<p>Yes, <ent type='PERSON'>Bill</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Hillary</ent>, to try to save themselves from prison,
covered up the murder of <ent type='ORG'>White House</ent> aide <ent type='PERSON'>Vincent Foster</ent>.</p>

<p>And yes, the ultra rich contend privately that <ent type='PERSON'>Clinton</ent> committed
treason in aborting a *genuine* <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> plot to murder <ent type='NORP'>Iraqi</ent>
strongman <ent type='PERSON'>Saddam Hussein</ent>, a sworn enemy of <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States, on
July 17, 1993. And two days later, <ent type='PERSON'>Clinton</ent> chopping off the head
of <ent type='ORG'>FBI</ent> director Sessions because he was investigating Clinton's
"treason." And on July 20, <ent type='PERSON'>Foster</ent> was murdered just as he was
planning to plead with <ent type='PERSON'>Bill</ent> to leave the plot go forward for
"national security" reasons, or be impeached.</p>

<p>The ultra rich consider most <ent type='NORP'>Americans</ent> stupid and [that they]
have to be told fairy tales; to be amused with stories of an
angry wife cutting off her husbands "ding-a-ling."</p>

<p>So, will <ent type='PERSON'>Clinton</ent> be put to the wall at the height of his
popularity? Remember: The ultra rich are not sentimental.</p>

<p>(312) 731-1100 is our main message. Donations will be
appreciated...</p>

</xml>