<xml>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Skolnick</ent> COMMENTARY #019
========================</p>

<p>[CfD Editor -- I neither necessarily believe nor disbelieve
either all or portions of the following.]</p>

<p>[The following is a transcript of a recorded phone message put
out by a group in <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> called "Citizens' Committee to Clean Up
the Courts." (312) 731-1100 and (312) 731-1505.]</p>

<p>Hi! Sherman <ent type='PERSON'>Skolnick</ent>, Citizens' Committee to Clean Up the Courts
[<ent type='ORG'>CCCC</ent>], 9800 South Oglesby.</p>

<p>On the business and financial level, there really is no
difference between <ent type='NORP'>democrats</ent> and <ent type='NORP'>republicans</ent>. They all scratch
each other's back. As a center of power, <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> is a good
example.</p>

<p>Although not a city employee, <ent type='PERSON'>Jeremiah Joyce</ent> reportedly has an
unmarked office in <ent type='ORG'>City Hall</ent>. He's more powerful than <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>
mayor <ent type='PERSON'><ent type='PERSON'>Richie</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Daley</ent></ent>. <ent type='PERSON'>Joyce</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Daley</ent> reportedly own <ent type='ORG'>Glenrock</ent>
Company (<ent type='PERSON'>Northlake</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Illinois</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Brookfield</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Wisconsin</ent>, and
<ent type='NORP'>Indianapolis</ent>, <ent type='NORP'>Indiana</ent>). They distribute construction supplies of
chemicals and GE [<ent type='ORG'>General Electric</ent>] sealants.</p>

<p>Whether <ent type='NORP'>democrat</ent> or <ent type='NORP'>republican</ent>, state contractors in <ent type='GPE'>Wisconsin</ent>,
<ent type='NORP'>Indiana</ent>, and <ent type='GPE'>Illinois</ent> *know* they have to buy their supplies from
<ent type='ORG'>Glenrock</ent>, such as -- tens of millions of dollars of curing
compounds for pouring cement and wire mesh for state highways;
materials for parking lots, airport runways, bridges and
buildings; such as sealants for windows, joints, masonry and
other construction; waterproofing and weatherproofing for a long
list of construction applications.</p>

<p>Since the state contractors buy their own supplies from <ent type='ORG'>Glenrock</ent>
Company to fulfill a state contract, well, Glenrock's name does
generally not show in public records. Well of course, <ent type='PERSON'>Richie</ent>
<ent type='PERSON'>Daley</ent> and his reputed business partner, <ent type='PERSON'>Jeremiah Joyce</ent>, like this
secretive nature of doing things.</p>

<p>The popular press avoided mentioning the business interests of
Richie's father, <ent type='PERSON'>Richard</ent> J. <ent type='PERSON'>Daley</ent>, when he was mayor for 21
years. *And* they avoid saying a single word about Richie's
financial interests.</p>

<p>A natural question is, Do state highway contractors and such give
"kickbacks," huh? Well, some think so. Well why else does their
firm, <ent type='ORG'>Glenrock Company</ent>, seem to be favored by contractors? Since
they distribute items such as GE sealants, you can see why <ent type='ORG'>NBC</ent> --
owned by <ent type='ORG'>General Electric</ent> [GE] -- is silent about all this. GE
also heavily finances so-called "public t.v." such as channel 11
[<ent type='ORG'>PBS</ent>] in <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>.</p>

<p>And, some raise dark questions about where the money came from
for <ent type='PERSON'>Joyce</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Daley</ent> to be in such a tremendous business. Joyce's
son was tied to dope king <ent type='PERSON'>John Kempis</ent>(?). Two of "junior's" [i.e.
Joyce's son] friends were murdered. <ent type='PERSON'>Kempis</ent> might have escaped
prosecution -- except he put out a murder contract on Joyce's
son. Thereafter, the highly political and corrupt federal
prosecutor in <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> sprung into action, publicizing <ent type='PERSON'>Kempis</ent>'
dope trafficking and putting him in jail.</p>

<p>Knowledgeable law enforcement people contend that <ent type='PERSON'><ent type='PERSON'>Richie</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Daley</ent></ent> &amp;
Co. are the apex of the dope business, *and* are "untouchable"
because they have plugged into big business, whether <ent type='NORP'>republican</ent>
or <ent type='NORP'>democrat</ent>.</p>

<p>About March, 1992, took place a strange event. A powerful,
sophisticated bomb was discovered under the floor, of the 5th
floor, in Chicago's <ent type='ORG'>City Hall</ent>. That's where the mayor's office
is. It was described as a "triple-trigger type [bomb]," perfected
years ago by the <ent type='NORP'>Germans</ent> and hard to de-fuse. News editors here
knew about this event, but suppressed it. Risking much bloodshed,
<ent type='PERSON'>Daley</ent> did not inform his <ent type='ORG'>City Hall</ent> employees to "clear out"
[evacuate the building] during the dangerous period when the bomb
was being de-activated.</p>

<p>Now some think that all of this was a warning by some financial
group trying to "muscle in" on <ent type='PERSON'>Daley</ent> and super honcho, Jeremiah
<ent type='PERSON'>Joyce</ent>.</p>

<p>Tell the news-fakers to stop kidding us that there's a difference
between the <ent type='NORP'>democrats</ent> and the <ent type='NORP'>republicans</ent>.</p>

<p>In <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>, see us on cable tv, channel 21, 9 pm [cst] most
Monday evenings.</p>

<p>Play it again: More about the corruption of <ent type='PERSON'><ent type='PERSON'>Richie</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Daley</ent></ent> and his
family; (312) 731-1505.</p>

<p>New message Saturday; we change it several times a week.</p>

<p>Donations appreciated. Citizen's Committee to Clean Up the
Courts, 9800 South Oglesby, <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>, [<ent type='GPE'>Illinois</ent>] 60617. For the
latest on courts, banks, espionage agencies, political
assassinations, and the news media. On 24 hours a day.</p>

</xml>