<xml>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Skolnick</ent> COMMENTARY #022
========================</p>

<p>[CfD Editor -- I neither necessarily believe nor disbelieve
either all or portions of the following.]</p>

<p>[The following is a transcript of a recorded phone message put
out by a group in <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> called "Citizens' Committee to Clean Up
the Courts." (312) 731-1100 and (312) 731-1505.]</p>

<p>Hi! Sherman <ent type='PERSON'>Skolnick</ent>, Citizens' Committee to Clean Up the Courts
[<ent type='ORG'>CCCC</ent>], 9800 Oglesby.</p>

<p>All the years, the <ent type='ORG'>FBI</ent> and the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> played dirty games with each
other.</p>

<p>Example: The <ent type='ORG'>FBI</ent> had leased their cars from a west suburban auto
dealer. The two so-called "owners" are much on TV... sort of, uh,
celebrities, holding up cash. Their motto? "We always save you
more money." Funny thing: The dealership was started up,
reportedly, with funds from gangster "<ent type='ORG'>Momo</ent>" Giancana and his gang.</p>

<p>Often pursued by <ent type='ORG'>FBI</ent> agents, "<ent type='ORG'>Momo</ent>" told them to "leave him
alone"; that he "worked with <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>." Some contend "<ent type='ORG'>Momo</ent>" helped
recruit for CIA's aborted invasion of <ent type='GPE'>Cuba</ent> at <ent type='LOC'>the Bay</ent> of Pigs.
"<ent type='ORG'>Momo</ent>" was assassinated by <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> in 1975, just as he was about to
be questioned by a <ent type='NORP'>Congressional</ent> committee.</p>

<p>The auto dealer, together with their banks, reportedly acts as a
money laundry for criminal enterprises jointly with foreign and
domestic espionage units.</p>

<p>The <ent type='ORG'>FBI</ent> put together details resulting in the federal criminal
prosecution of [Frank?] <ent type='PERSON'>Carlisi</ent> and others for loan sharking and
extortion. A key federal government witness has been <ent type='PERSON'>Lenny</ent>
Patrick. <ent type='GPE'>Cuba</ent>n TV put on a documentary showing <ent type='PERSON'>Lenny</ent> and two
other <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> mobsters were implicated in the assassination of
President <ent type='PERSON'>Kennedy</ent>.</p>

<p>The <ent type='PERSON'>Carlisi</ent> trial has been by <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> federal district judge <ent type='PERSON'>Paul</ent>
E. <ent type='PERSON'>Plunkett</ent>(sp?)... implicated *himself* in covering up, in his
court, laundering of funds through the <ent type='GPE'>Illinois</ent> Judges Pension
Fund. A gift (or bribe) of $2 million was put offshore *for*
Judge <ent type='PERSON'>Plunkett</ent> when he dismissed charges against 20 name-brand
stockbrokers accused of embezzling $200 million from the Judges
Pension Fund.</p>

<p>In the <ent type='PERSON'>Carlisi</ent> case, defense attorneys have included former
<ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> federal district judge <ent type='PERSON'>George Layton</ent>(sp?). According to
documents from the <ent type='ORG'>National Archives</ent>, Layton was the secret
attorney for <ent type='PERSON'>Lee Harvey Oswald</ent>, the <ent type='GPE'>Dallas</ent> <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> "patsy."</p>

<p>Also in the <ent type='PERSON'>Carlisi</ent> case, <ent type='ORG'>FBI</ent> monitored the defendants through
the <ent type='ORG'>FBI</ent> wiretap center in Presidential Towers. The two top
honchos in that residential complex have been Congressman Dan
<ent type='PERSON'>Rostenkowski</ent> and super money wizard <ent type='PERSON'>Dan Shannon</ent>. The two operate
their dirty game through their ownership of the spy and gangster
Garfield Ridge Trust &amp; <ent type='ORG'>Savings Bank</ent>. <ent type='PERSON'>Rostenkowski</ent> also helps <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>
and foreign espionage agencies launder loot through the <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>
Board of Trade. Two of "Rosty's" daughters were supposedly
employees of <ent type='ORG'>the Board</ent> of Trade -- although apparently not
performing much work.</p>

<p>The <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> is accused of bringing into <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States 1000 kilos
of cocaine. The <ent type='ORG'>CBS</ent> TV program [CfD -- Here, I think he means *60
Minutes*], however, censored how the money flowed back *out* of
<ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States through the persons and businesses we have
outlined here.</p>

<p>Another peculiar <ent type='ORG'>FBI</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> situation involves <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> assistant
federal prosecutor <ent type='PERSON'>William</ent> R. <ent type='PERSON'>Hogan</ent>, jr. He has been accused, in
federal court, of arranging perjury in the criminal prosecutions
of the El Rukn dope gang. <ent type='ORG'>Formerly</ent> called <ent type='ORG'>Blackstone Rangers</ent>, the
El Rukns, as a terrorist group, have been financed by the Charles
Kettering Foundation and <ent type='ORG'>the Charles Merrill Trust</ent> -- *both*
money types for <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>.</p>

<p>Are the dope shipments also *arranged* through <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>? The <ent type='ORG'>FBI</ent>
started investigating <ent type='PERSON'>Hogan</ent> but were temporarily *blocked* on
"national security" grounds by <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>! Now, with the aid of <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>,
these terrorists are being put out of jails and back on the
street.</p>

<p>Call up your favorite news fakers or talk show fakers and tell
them to stop kidding us in censoring this.</p>

<p>In <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>, see us on cable tv, channel 21, 9 pm [cst] most
Monday evenings.</p>

<p>Play it again: Eliminating Presidents. (312) 731-1505.</p>

<p>New message Saturday; we change it several times a week.</p>

<p>Donations appreciated. Citizen's Committee to Clean Up the
Courts, 9800 South Oglesby, <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>, [<ent type='GPE'>Illinois</ent>] 60617. For the
latest on courts, banks, espionage agencies, political
assassinations, and the news media. On 24 hours a day.

</p></xml>