<xml>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Skolnick</ent> COMMENTARY #023
========================</p>

<p>[CfD Editor -- I neither necessarily believe nor disbelieve
either all or portions of the following.]</p>

<p>[The following is a transcript of a recorded phone message put
out by a group in <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> called "Citizens' Committee to Clean Up
the Courts." (312) 731-1100 and (312) 731-1505.]</p>

<p>Hi! Sherman <ent type='PERSON'>Skolnick</ent>, Citizens' Committee to Clean Up the Courts
[<ent type='ORG'>CCCC</ent>], 9800 <ent type='PERSON'>Oglesby</ent>.</p>

<p>A big cover-up with congressman <ent type='PERSON'>Dan Rostenkowski</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>,
arranged by the corrupt <ent type='ORG'>IRS</ent>, the Justice Department, and the
White House.</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Clinton</ent>, while Governor, supervised a <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> operation in a forest
in western <ent type='GPE'>Arkansas</ent> called the Mena airport. It was used for dope
and gun smuggling on a mass scale. Implicated also were George
Bush as vice-President and Reagan as President, and Ollie <ent type='PERSON'>North</ent>.</p>

<p>Governor <ent type='PERSON'>Clinton</ent> told the state law enforcement to "look the
other way." Used were several public and private funds, including
the <ent type='GPE'>Arkansas</ent> Development Finance Authority, <ent type='PERSON'>Jackson Stephens</ent> and
his bond brokerage and banking empire. Also reportedly used: A
company called Park-O-Meter.</p>

<p>The hundreds of millions of dollars per month from cocaine and
such was reportedly funneled through <ent type='ORG'>Garfield Ridge Trust</ent> and
<ent type='ORG'>Savings Bank</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>. The bank has been owned and operated by
congressman <ent type='PERSON'>Rostenkowski</ent> and his cronies, who have commented on
the bank's reported criminality for some 20 years now.</p>

<p>&gt;From the bank, the money was washed through the commodity,
currency, and options markets here: The <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> Board of Trade,
the <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> Mercantile Exchange, and the <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> Board Options
Exchange. (Traders on these markets have told us that they expect
a scandal. And the <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> <ent type='ORG'>IRS</ent> "torpedoed" their own
investigation of this.)</p>

<p>Over the years, "<ent type='ORG'>Rosty</ent>" (as the congressman has been called) has
received bribes of tens of thousands of dollars from these
markets. Some bribes they attempted to disguise as so-called
"lecture fees." Did "<ent type='ORG'>Rosty</ent>" ever give some of these speeches for
them, huh?</p>

<p>As head of the tax writing committee of <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>, "<ent type='ORG'>Rosty</ent>" put
through laws so quietly they were considered private laws; making
the speculators here exempt from paying taxes on little-known
market devices such as "hedges" and "straddles." And, of course,
the crooked <ent type='ORG'>IRS</ent> in <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> received part of the bribes to cover
this all up.</p>

<p>"Rosty's" two daughters reportedly worked at <ent type='ORG'>the Board</ent> of Trade
(Oh yeah?) but were seldom seen there. They reportedly
facilitated the cocaine money laundering.</p>

<p>"<ent type='ORG'>Rosty</ent>" was also one of the main culprits regarding the bribery
of <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent> by <ent type='ORG'>the Bank</ent> of Credit and Commerce International
[<ent type='ORG'>BCCI</ent>]. This criminal bank supposedly went under in 1991, *but*
it continues, however, as <ent type='ORG'>Chemical Bank Group</ent> -- successor to
<ent type='ORG'>First National Bank</ent> of <ent type='NORP'>Cicero</ent>, run by <ent type='PERSON'>Paul Marcinkas</ent>, the
gangster who headed <ent type='ORG'>the Vatican Bank</ent>.</p>

<p>Using "cook books" for <ent type='ORG'>BCCI</ent>, the commodity, currency, and options
markets here bought 25% of <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent> -- *including* congressman
<ent type='PERSON'>Rostenkowski</ent> and Company.</p>

<p>The crooked mastermind of "Rosty's" election campaign in 1994 has
been <ent type='PERSON'>Jeremiah Joyce</ent>, a little-known business partner of <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>
mayor <ent type='PERSON'>Richie Daley</ent>. <ent type='PERSON'>Joyce</ent>, and <ent type='PERSON'>Daley</ent>, are the secret owners of
<ent type='ORG'>Glenrock Company</ent>, construction supplies. By the way, if you want
to be a state highway contractor, you'd better get your cement-pouring compounds from them! And, you'd better pay "kickbacks."
<ent type='ORG'>Glenrock Company</ent> reportedly does not keep proper records for the
<ent type='ORG'>IRS</ent>!</p>

<p>"<ent type='ORG'>Rosty</ent>" is willing to "take the fall" on relatively minor charges
[in order] to continue the mass media cover-up of Mena airport,
cocaine and guns, his crooked bank, the big dealers in the
<ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> markets, and the corrupt tax collectors in the White
House and the Justice Department.</p>

<p>(By the way, if he doesn't "stay shut," I suppose they'd shoot
him.)</p>

<p>They'd need a very large jail cell for <ent type='PERSON'>Rostenkowski</ent>, and his pal
<ent type='PERSON'>Richie Daley</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Bill</ent> and Hillary <ent type='PERSON'>Clinton</ent>, the head of the <ent type='ORG'>IRS</ent> in
<ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>, the U.S. attorney general, and the pilots on the markets
here!</p>

<p>Just another story, suppressed by the liars and whores of the
press.</p>

<p>In <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>, see us on cable tv, channel 21, 9 pm [cst] most
Monday evenings; not every Monday.</p>

<p>Play it again: <ent type='PERSON'>Richie Daley</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>the Dope Business</ent> in <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>.</p>

<p>New message <ent type='LOC'>Sunday</ent>; we change it several times a week.</p>

<p>Donations appreciated. Citizen's Committee to Clean Up the
Courts, 9800 South <ent type='PERSON'>Oglesby</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>, [<ent type='GPE'>Illinois</ent>] 60617. For the
latest on courts, banks, espionage agencies, political
assassinations, and the news media. On 24 hours a day.</p>

</xml>