<xml>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Skolnick</ent> COMMENTARY #021
========================</p>

<p>[CfD Editor -- I neither necessarily believe nor disbelieve
either all or portions of the following.]</p>

<p>[The following is a transcript of a recorded phone message put
out by a group in <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> called "Citizens' Committee to Clean Up
the Courts." (312) 731-1100 and (312) 731-1505.]</p>

<p>Hi! Sherman <ent type='PERSON'>Skolnick</ent>, Citizens' Committee to Clean Up the Courts
[<ent type='ORG'>CCCC</ent>], 9800 South Oglesby.</p>

<p>Can a leopard change its spots?</p>

<p>Over the years the *<ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Tribune</ent>* has been a crooked, anti-labor, discriminatory operation. Starting in the 19th century,
they got lucrative rights to newsprint and pulp production in
<ent type='GPE'>Canada</ent> through a charter from the highly-secretive Jesuits and
<ent type='PERSON'>the King</ent> of England. To this day the *<ent type='ORG'>Tribune</ent>* is tied to the
Royal Family and says nothing about them being in worldwide
financing of dope traffic through <ent type='GPE'>Hong Kong</ent> and the <ent type='GPE'>Cayman</ent>
islands.</p>

<p>In the 1930s, the *<ent type='ORG'>Tribune</ent>* was facing a labor dispute. So, they
brought in Al Capone as a "labor consultant." He terrorized the
workers.</p>

<p>Since about 1910, the *<ent type='ORG'>Tribune</ent>* used a family of criminals
originally from <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> -- the <ent type='PERSON'>Annenbergs</ent>(?) and their
descendants -- even now, to control the circulation department.</p>

<p>In years ago when there were almost a dozen <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> papers, the
<ent type='PERSON'>Annenbergs</ent> used shoot-outs to "snuff out" competitors. The
<ent type='PERSON'>Annenbergs</ent> were major stockholders in the long-time criminal
enterprise called <ent type='ORG'>the American National Bank</ent> here. They have
other news fakers in their pocket, such as <ent type='PERSON'>Walter Jacobson</ent>.</p>

<p>The *<ent type='ORG'>Tribune</ent>* was known for running items with snide remarks --
anti-black, anti-Jew.</p>

<p>Once a private company, the *<ent type='ORG'>Tribune</ent>* company had a dispute
between the major owners like <ent type='PERSON'>the Marshall Fields</ent> and the
<ent type='PERSON'>Rockefellers</ent> *and* minority owners.</p>

<p><ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> federal district judge <ent type='PERSON'>Crowley</ent> was blackmailed into
favoring the big shots. Although one of the youngest on the
federal bench, he soon thereafter resigned.</p>

<p>The <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefellers</ent> and such wanted to be bought out so, in 1981,
the *<ent type='ORG'>Tribune</ent>* company stock went public. Some thought that they
toned down, thereafter, their highly prejudiced stories. Oh yeah?</p>

<p>To fatten their stockholders, the *<ent type='ORG'>Tribune</ent>* vowed to dump their
organized workers and smash the union. Since ensued a labor
dispute. One night the *<ent type='ORG'>Tribune</ent>* sent in their vicious guards
with attack dogs to rip the workers off the machines. To continue
production, the <ent type='ORG'>Tribune</ent> brought in "scabs" -- mostly white,
rural, southern workers (at half the wages) -- for the highly
automated new plant called "<ent type='ORG'>The Freedom Center</ent>." The *<ent type='ORG'>Tribune</ent>*
used their advance, inside information to blackmail a Chancery
Division judge to grant an injunction restricting picketing near
what savvy folks call, "<ent type='ORG'>The Slavery Center</ent>."</p>

<p>Rightfully, it can't be called the *<ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>* <ent type='ORG'>Tribune</ent> since as
little as 15% of their total circulation is inside the city
limits. With its media octopus worldwide, it should be called
"<ent type='ORG'>The Multinational Lie Machine</ent>."</p>

<p>To try to boost city circulation, the *<ent type='ORG'>Tribune</ent>* runs items
talking down their nose at blacks -- as if all blacks are dopers
engaged in drive-by shootings.</p>

<p>About 1984, joke faker <ent type='PERSON'>Mike Royko</ent> left the *<ent type='LOC'>Sun</ent> Times* and went
to the *<ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Tribune</ent>*. The *<ent type='LOC'>Sun</ent> Times* sued the *<ent type='ORG'>Tribune</ent>*,
*but* the *<ent type='ORG'>Tribune</ent>* had advance, inside data on a Chancery
Division judge taking bribes. And so, the case was steered to
him. The *<ent type='ORG'>Tribune</ent>* blackmailed the judge into ruling in favor of
"<ent type='ORG'>The Slavery Center</ent>" at the <ent type='ORG'>Tribune</ent> Tower.</p>

<p>And the *<ent type='ORG'>Tribune</ent>* company newslords have peddled false stories
that were really political assassinations. Such as of Chicago's
first black mayor, <ent type='PERSON'>Harold Washington</ent>, died of a heart attack
because he was overweight. *Oh yeah?* The story should have been
that <ent type='PERSON'>Harold Washington</ent> was murdered with a poisoned cup of
coffee. Some of the doctors told the media fakers that the mayor
was poisoned -- *but*, the press invoked "national security,"
contending it would cause riots. Well, what about the old
statement, "Let the truth be told, 'though the heavens crumble,"
huh?</p>

<p>In <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>, see us on cable tv, channel 21, 9 pm [cst] most
Monday evenings.</p>

<p>Play it again: A [unclear] discusses historical conspiracies.
(312) 731-1505.</p>

<p>New message Monday; we change it several times a week.</p>

<p>Donations appreciated. Citizen's Committee to Clean Up the
Courts, 9800 South Oglesby, <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>, [<ent type='GPE'>Illinois</ent>] 60617. For the
latest on courts, banks, espionage agencies, political
assassinations, and the news media. On 24 hours a day.

</p></xml>