<xml>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Skolnick</ent> COMMENTARY #020
========================</p>

<p>[CfD Editor -- I neither necessarily believe nor disbelieve
either all or portions of the following.]</p>

<p>[The following is a transcript of a recorded phone message put
out by a group in <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> called "Citizens' Committee to Clean Up
the Courts." (312) 731-1100 and (312) 731-1505.]</p>

<p>Hi! Sherman <ent type='PERSON'>Skolnick</ent>, Citizens' Committee to Clean Up the Courts
[<ent type='ORG'>CCCC</ent>], 9800 South Oglesby.</p>

<p>A key [unclear] in various worldwide schemes is the <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>-based
law firm, <ent type='GPE'>Hopkins</ent> &amp; <ent type='ORG'>Sutter</ent>.</p>

<p>The highly corrupt S&amp;L whitewash agency is the Resolution Trust
Corporation (<ent type='ORG'>RTC</ent>). Guess where one of their main offices is? Why,
inside the <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> offices of <ent type='GPE'>Hopkins</ent> &amp; <ent type='ORG'>Sutter</ent>.</p>

<p>A <ent type='GPE'>Hopkins</ent> [&amp; <ent type='ORG'>Sutter</ent>] partner is <ent type='PERSON'>Jay Steinberg</ent>. He was bankruptcy
trustee in the strange case of <ent type='PERSON'>William Stecker</ent>(sp?) and
Grayville(?) Corporation. *Hundreds* of millions of dollars
disappeared. <ent type='PERSON'>Steinberg</ent> doesn't seem to know *where*.</p>

<p>Also complicit with <ent type='PERSON'>Steinberg</ent> is a member of the Justice
Department's murder squad, Mike "Chucky" <ent type='PERSON'>Peters</ent>, a <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> FBI
agent with worldwide authority. In an undisputed, unpublicized
federal case, <ent type='PERSON'>Peters</ent> was accused of complicity in the murder of
some *40* federal grand jury witnesses in the notorious <ent type='ORG'>Inslaw</ent>
grand jury quiz.</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>The Federal Deposit Insurance</ent> has a evil stepsister -- namely,
<ent type='ORG'>RTC</ent>. <ent type='GPE'>Hopkins</ent> &amp; <ent type='ORG'>Sutter</ent>, *and* <ent type='ORG'>RTC</ent>, arranged to have the rotten
Rose Law Firm of <ent type='GPE'>Little Rock</ent> used to cover up massive plundering
of assets of failing or already defunct savings &amp; loans in the
<ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> area -- such as in the western suburbs here. Backed up by
a host of details, it seems <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> clandestine operatives
*plundered* these S&amp;Ls -- including Olympic S&amp;L and Clyde
Savings.</p>

<p>The Rose Law Firm partner, <ent type='PERSON'><ent type='PERSON'>Hillary</ent> Rodham <ent type='PERSON'>Clinton</ent></ent>, played a role
in *raping and plundering* one or more <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>-area S&amp;Ls!</p>

<p><ent type='GPE'>Hopkins</ent> &amp; <ent type='ORG'>Sutter</ent>, and <ent type='ORG'>RTC</ent>-<ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>, arranged in recent years to
transfer some $50 million from an <ent type='ORG'>RTC</ent> contingency fund to Little
Rock -- to help cover up the $47 million of federally insured
funds missing in <ent type='GPE'>Arkansas</ent>.</p>

<p>A federal grand jury in <ent type='GPE'>Little Rock</ent> is considering criminal
charges against the First Lady: massive bank embezzlement and
income tax fraud.</p>

<p>The [<ent type='ORG'>RTC</ent>] funds were transferred from <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> reportedly with the
help of <ent type='PERSON'>Jay Steinberg</ent> *and* with attorney <ent type='PERSON'>John Gearham</ent>(sp?), who
is of the <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> suburb of <ent type='GPE'>Park Ridge</ent> -- same place <ent type='PERSON'>Hillary</ent> is
from. <ent type='PERSON'>Gearham</ent> is "tight" with Hillary's lawyer brother.</p>

<p>With the reported connivance of <ent type='GPE'>Hopkins</ent> &amp; <ent type='ORG'>Sutter</ent>, the <ent type='ORG'>RTC</ent> records
are gone! Helping in the huge rip-off is <ent type='ORG'>Household International</ent>
and their units, <ent type='ORG'>Household Bank</ent> -- an outgrowth of CIA's Nugan-Hand Bank, once headquartered in Australia.</p>

<p>Interwoven in all this is the strange murder of <ent type='ORG'>White House</ent> aide
<ent type='PERSON'>Vincent Foster</ent>, jr. Now, one of his secretaries has been a
business partner of <ent type='PERSON'>Dan Lassater</ent> -- tied to the savings &amp; loans
through crooked bond dealings. After Foster's death, she
reportedly swiped some of his records; and they're being used by
<ent type='GPE'>Hopkins</ent> &amp; <ent type='ORG'>Sutter</ent> and other lawyers, clandestine operatives,
murder squad members, and crooked federal judges here to
blackmail the <ent type='PERSON'>Clinton</ent> <ent type='ORG'>White House</ent>.</p>

<p>To "muddy the waters," they are spreading rumors... [laughs]
possibly true [laughs]... that <ent type='PERSON'>Hillary</ent> had her former lover and
law partner, <ent type='ORG'>Foster</ent> -- now get this -- *murdered* by the Secret
Service in the <ent type='ORG'>White House</ent>! Those who removed the body, however,
planted it in a park in <ent type='GPE'>Virginia</ent> to cast suspicion on the White
House.</p>

<p>And what can you do? Well, call up your local news-fakers and
tell them to stop kidding us about what the <ent type='PERSON'>Clinton</ent> scandal is
all about, huh?</p>

<p>In <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>, see us on cable tv, channel 21, 9 pm [cst] most
Monday evenings.</p>

<p>Still playing: Mayor <ent type='PERSON'>Daley</ent> and the former police superintendant
and the dope business; (312) 731-1505.</p>

<p>New message Friday; we change it several times a week.</p>

<p>Donations appreciated. Citizen's Committee to Clean Up the
Courts, 9800 South Oglesby, <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>, [<ent type='GPE'>Illinois</ent>] 60617. For the
latest on courts, banks, espionage agencies, political
assassinations, and the news media. On 24 hours a day.</p>

</xml>