<xml><p> INTRODUCTION: URGENT!</p>

<p> On July 5, 1987 the front page of <ent type='ORG'>the Miami Herald</ent>
Newspaper carried a now famous article describing secret
<ent type='ORG'>White House</ent> plans to:</p>

<p> A.) DECLARE AN UNDEFINED "NATIONAL EMERGENCY,"</p>

<p> B.) RE-OPEN CONCENTRATION CAMPS FOR <ent type='EVENT'>PREVENTIVE</ent>
DETENTION OF LEGAL DISSIDENTS CERTAIN ETHNIC
GROUPS, AND</p>

<p> C.) <ent type='ORG'>SUSPEND</ent> OUR UNITED STATES CONSTITUTION</p>

<div> ---***---</div>

<p> Those of us viewing the <ent type='GPE'>Iran</ent>-Contragate hearings,
then being broadcast live on TV, had our curiousity peaked
when one committee member began inquiring about an article
alleging secret <ent type='ORG'>White House</ent> plans to suspend the
Constitution.</p>

<p> We were even more puzzled when committee chair
<ent type='PERSON'>Daniel Inouye</ent> interrupted him demanding all discussion on
that question take place in closed session, out of public
hearing.</p>

<p> Not content to wonder, I researched the original
article, transcribed it, and now present it to you for your
urgent consideration. You have a right to read this. In
fact, you'd better know about it because it's about secret
<ent type='ORG'>White House</ent> plans to remove your rights by <ent type='ORG'>SUSPEND</ent>ING OUR
UNITED STATES CONSTITUTION. It's about a government which
we, the people, did NOT elect but which has gained power
nonetheless.</p>

<p> What follows is not the whole story but a crucial
and overlooked part of it. Read "between the lines" and
very carefully. This is not some paranoid's nightmare or
some fanatic's fantasy. This is reality in the Reagan White
House.</p>

<div> ---***---</div>

<p> Please copy this article and circulate it among
your friends and co-workers. If <ent type='PERSON'>George Bush</ent> gets into the
<ent type='ORG'>White House</ent>, we'll have "elected," or had selected for us,
precisely the same carnivorous crew comprising The Secret
Government referred to in this article.</p>

<div> ---***---</div>

<p> First, I offer three appropriate quotes which
provide a certain perspective in which to view what follows.
Then, I present the "sidebar" articles which
summarized and accompanied the main article.
Finally, I give you the complete text of the
original article, unedited and uncensored. While local
papers ignored this historic article or presented only
extracts from it, none of them gave you this, the entire
text.</p>

<div> ---***---</div>

<p> The following did not appear with the original
article but they provide a certain appropriate perspective
on it:</p>

<p> "Perception of reality is sometimes
more important than reality itself."
-<ent type='PERSON'>Henry Kissenger</ent></p>

<p> "He who controls the past, controls the future.
He who controls the present, controls the past."
-O'<ent type='PERSON'>Brian</ent>, the dictator
in <ent type='PERSON'>George Orwell</ent>'s novel "1984"</p>

<p> "If you don't like the news,
go out and make some of your own!"
-Scoop Nisker</p>

<div> ===========================================================
* * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * *
===========================================================</div>

<p> from <ent type='GPE'>THE</ent> <ent type='GPE'>MIAMI</ent> HERALD....SUNDAY JULY 5, 1987....page one:</p>

<p> SOME SECRET ACTIVITIES</p>

<p> Sources say the parallel government behind the
Reagan administration engaged in secret actions
including:</p>

<p> A CONTINGENCY plan to suspend Constitution and impose
martial law in United States in case of nuclear
war or national rebellion.</p>

<p> 1985 VISIT to <ent type='GPE'>Libya</ent> by <ent type='PERSON'><ent type='PERSON'>William</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Wilson</ent></ent>, then U.S. ambassador
to <ent type='GPE'>Vatican</ent> and close Reagan friend, to meet with
<ent type='GPE'>Libya</ent>n leader Col. <ent type='PERSON'>Moammar Gadhafi</ent>.</p>

<p> HAVING ROUTES of sophisticated surveillance satellites
altered to follow <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> ships around world.</p>

<p> LAUNCHING of spy aircraft on secret missions over <ent type='GPE'>Cuba</ent> and
<ent type='GPE'>Nicaragua</ent>.</p>

<p> PROPOSAL in 1981 to provide covert support of anti-Sandinista groups that fled <ent type='GPE'>Nicaragua</ent> after
Sandinista revolution in 1979.</p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>DISSEMINATION</ent> of information that cast <ent type='GPE'>Nicaragua</ent> as threat
to neighbors and United States.</p>

<div> ---***---</div>

<p> Before Reagan was elected, campaign aides who
became the president's top advisers carried out
these secret activities:</p>

<p> CREATION in 1980 of October Surprise <ent type='ORG'>Group</ent> to monitor
President Carter's negotiations with <ent type='GPE'>Iran</ent> for
release of 52 <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> hostages. <ent type='ORG'>Group</ent> met with
man who claimed to represent <ent type='GPE'>Iran</ent> and who offered
to release hostages to Reagan. Offer declined,
officials say.</p>

<p> ACQUISITION of stolen confidential briefing materials from
Carter's campaign before Oct. 28, 1980, <ent type='PERSON'>Carter</ent>-Reagan debate.</p>

<div> ---***---</div>

<p> [photo captions:]</p>

<p> PRINCIPALS:</p>

<p> <ent type='PERSON'><ent type='PERSON'>William</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Clark</ent></ent>: Allowed bigger <ent type='PERSON'>North</ent> role at <ent type='ORG'>NSC</ent>.
<ent type='PERSON'>William</ent> Casey: Kept guard on President <ent type='PERSON'>Carter</ent></p>

<div> =============================================================
*************************************************************
=============================================================</div>

<p> What follows is the complete text of the original article as
printed in <ent type='ORG'>the Miami Herald</ent> for July 5, 1987:</p>

<p> <ent type='PERSON'>REAGAN</ent> AIDES AND <ent type='GPE'>THE</ent> 'SECRET' GOVERNMENT</p>

<p> by <ent type='ORG'>ALFONSO CHARDY</ent>, HERALD WASHINGTON BUREAU</p>

<p> WASHINGTON -- Some of President Reagan's top
advisers have operated a virtual parallel government outside
the traditional <ent type='ORG'>Cabinet</ent> departments and agencies almost from
the day Reagan took office, congressional investigators and
administration officials have concluded.</p>

<p> Investigators believe that the advisers'
activities extended well beyond the secret arms sales to
<ent type='GPE'>Iran</ent> and aid to the contras now under investigation.</p>

<p> Lt. Col. Oliver <ent type='PERSON'>North</ent>, for example, helped draw up
a controversial plan to suspend the Constitution in the
event of a national crisis, such as nuclear war, violent and
widespread internal dissent or national opposition to a U.S.
military invasion abroad.</p>

<p> When the attorney general at the time, <ent type='PERSON'>William</ent>
French <ent type='ORG'>Smith</ent>, learned of the proposal, he protested in
writing to North's boss, then-national security adviser
Robert McFarlane.</p>

<p> The advisers conducted their activities through
secret contacts throughout the government with persons who
acted at their direction but did not officially report to
them.</p>

<p> The activities of those contacts were coordinated
by <ent type='ORG'>the National Security Council</ent>, the officials and
investigators said.</p>

<p> There appears to have been no formal directive for
the advisers' activities, which knowledgeable sources
described as a parallel government.</p>

<p> In a secret assessment of the activities, the lead
counsel for the Senate <ent type='GPE'>Iran</ent>-contra committee called it a
"secret government-within-a-government."</p>

<p> The arrangement permitted Reagan administration
officials to claim that they were not involved in
controversial or illegal activities, the officials said.</p>

<p> "It was the ultimate plausible deniability," said
a well-briefed official who has served the Reagan
administration since 1982 and who often collaborated on
covert assistance to the <ent type='GPE'>Nicaragua</ent>n contras.</p>

<p> The roles of top-level officials and of Reagan
himself are still not clear. But that is expected to be a
primary topic when <ent type='PERSON'>North</ent> appears before the <ent type='GPE'>Iran</ent>-contra
committees beginning Tuesday. Special prosecutor Lawrence
Walsh also is believed to be trying to prove in his
investigation of the <ent type='GPE'>Iran</ent>-contra affair that government
officials engaged in a criminal conspiracy.</p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>ADVISERS FORMED SHADOW</ent> GOVERNMENT, PROBERS SAY</p>

<p> Much of the time, <ent type='ORG'>Cabinet</ent> secretaries and their
aides were unaware of the advisers' activities. When they
periodically detected operations, they complained or tried
to derail them, interviews show.</p>

<p> But no one ever questioned the activities in a
broad way, possibly out of a belief that the advisers were
operating with presidential
sanction, officials said.</p>

<p> Reagan did know of or approve at least some of the
actions of the secret group, according to previous accounts
by aides, friends and high-ranking foreign officials.</p>

<p> One such case is the 1985 visit to <ent type='GPE'>Libya</ent> by
<ent type='PERSON'><ent type='PERSON'>William</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Wilson</ent></ent>, then-U.S. ambassador to the <ent type='GPE'>Vatican</ent> and a
close Reagan friend, to meet with <ent type='GPE'>Libya</ent>n leader Col. Moammar
Gadhafi, officials said last week. Secretary of State
<ent type='PERSON'>George Shultz</ent> rebuked <ent type='PERSON'>Wilson</ent>, but the officials said Reagan
knew of the trip in advance.</p>

<p> The heart of the secret structure from 1983 to
1986 was North's office in <ent type='ORG'>the Old Executive Office</ent> Building
adjacent to the <ent type='ORG'>White House</ent>, investigators believe.</p>

<p> North's influence within the secret structure was
so great, the sources said, that he was able to have the
orbits of sophisticated surveillance satellites altered to
follow <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> ships around the world, call for the launching
of high-flying spy aircraft on secret missions over <ent type='GPE'>Cuba</ent> and
<ent type='GPE'>Nicaragua</ent> and become involved in sensitive domestic
activities.</p>

<p> Many initiatives</p>

<p> Others in the structure included some of Reagan's
closest friends and advisers, including former national
security adviser <ent type='PERSON'><ent type='PERSON'>William</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Clark</ent></ent>, the late <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> Director
<ent type='PERSON'>William</ent> Casey and Attorney General <ent type='PERSON'>Edwin Meese</ent>, officials
and investigators said.</p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>Congressional</ent> investigators said the <ent type='GPE'>Iran</ent> deal was
just one of the group's initiatives. They say exposure of
the unusual arrangement may be the legacy of their inquiry.</p>

<p> "After we establish that a policy decision was
made at the highest levels to transfer responsibility for
contra support to the <ent type='ORG'>NSC</ent>..., we favor examining how that
decision was implemented," wrote <ent type='PERSON'>Arthur Liman</ent>, chief counsel
of the Senate committee, in a secret memorandum to panel
leaders Sens. <ent type='PERSON'>Daniel Inouye</ent>, D-<ent type='GPE'>Hawaii</ent>, and <ent type='PERSON'>Warren Rudman</ent>, R-N.H., before hearings began May 5.</p>

<p> "This is the part of the story that reveals the
whole secret government-within-a-government, operated from
the [Executive Office Building] by a Lt. Col., with its own
army, air force, diplomatic agents, intelligence operatives
and appropriations capacity," <ent type='ORG'>Limon</ent> wrote in the memo, parts
of which were shared with <ent type='ORG'>The Herald</ent>.</p>

<p> A spokesman for <ent type='PERSON'>Liman</ent> declined comment but did not
dispute the memo's existence.</p>

<p> A <ent type='ORG'>White House</ent> official rejected the notion that
any of Reagan's advisers were operating secretly.</p>

<p> "The president has constantly expressed his
foreign policy positions to the public and has consulted
with the <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>," the official said.</p>

<p> <ent type='PERSON'>Began</ent> in 1980</p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>Congressional</ent> investigators and current and former
officials interviewed -- members of the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>, State
Department and <ent type='ORG'>Pentagon</ent> -- said they still do not have a
full record of the impact of the the advisers' activities.</p>

<p> But based on investigations and personal
experience, they believe the secret governing arrangement
traces its roots to the last weeks of Reagan's 1980
campaign.</p>

<p> Officials say the genesis may have been an October
1980 decision by Casey, Reagan's campaign manager and a
former officer in <ent type='EVENT'>the World War</ent> II precursor of the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>, to
create an October Surprise <ent type='ORG'>Group</ent> to monitor Jimmy Carter's
feverish negotiations with <ent type='GPE'>Iran</ent> for the release of 52
<ent type='NORP'>American</ent> hostages.</p>

<p> The group, led by campaign foreign policy adviser
<ent type='PERSON'>Richard Allen</ent>, was founded out of concern <ent type='PERSON'>Carter</ent> might pull
off an "October surprise" such as a last-minute deal for the
release of the hostages before the Nov. 4 election. One of
the group's first acts was a meeting with a man claiming to
represent <ent type='GPE'>Iran</ent> who offered to release the hostages to
Reagan.</p>

<p> <ent type='PERSON'>Allen</ent> -- Reagan's first national security adviser--
and another campaign aide, <ent type='PERSON'>Laurence Silberman</ent>, told The
<ent type='ORG'>Herald</ent> in April of the meeting. they said McFarlane, then a
Senate Armed Services Committee aide, arranged and attended
it. McFarlane later became Reagan's national security
adviser and played a key role in the <ent type='GPE'>Iran</ent>-contra affair.
<ent type='PERSON'>Allen</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Silberman</ent> said they rejected the offer to release
the hostages to Reagan.</p>

<p> Briefing book theft</p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>Congressional</ent> aides now link another well-known
campaign incident -- the theft of confidential briefing
materials from Carter's campaign before the Oct. 28, 1980,
<ent type='PERSON'>Carter</ent>-Reagan debate -- to the same group of advisers.</p>

<p> They believe that Casey obtained the briefing
materials and passed them to <ent type='PERSON'>James Baker</ent>, another top
Reagan campaign aide, who was <ent type='ORG'>White House</ent> chief of staff in
Reagan's first term.</p>

<p> Once Reagan was sworn in, the group moved quickly
to set itself up, officials said. Within months, the
advisers were clashing with officials in the traditional
agencies.</p>

<p> Six weeks after Reagan was sworn in, apparently
over State Department objections, then-<ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> director Casey
submitted a proposal to Reagan calling for covert support of
anti-Sandinista groups that had fled <ent type='GPE'>Nicaragua</ent> after the
1979 revolution.</p>

<p> [<ent type='GPE'>THE</ent> IRAN-CONTRA CONNECTION:
<ent type='ORG'>NORTH HAD BIG ROLE</ent> IN INNER CIRCLE, INVESTIGATORS SAY]</p>

<p> It is still unclear whether Casey cleared the plan
with Reagan. But In November 1981 the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> secretly flew an
<ent type='NORP'>Argentine</ent> military leader, Gen. Leopoldo Galtieri, to
<ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent> to devise a secret agreement under which
<ent type='NORP'>Argentine</ent> military officers trained <ent type='GPE'>Nicaragua</ent>n rebels,
according to an administration official familiar with the
agreement.</p>

<p> About the same time, <ent type='PERSON'>North</ent> completed his transfer
to the <ent type='ORG'>NSC</ent> from the <ent type='ORG'>Marine Corps</ent>. Those who worked with
<ent type='PERSON'>North</ent> in 1981 remember his first assignments as routine,
although not unimportant.</p>

<p> <ent type='PERSON'>North</ent>, they recalled, was briefly assigned to
carry the "football," the briefcase containing the secret
contingency plans for fighting a nuclear war, which is taken
everywhere the president goes. <ent type='PERSON'>North</ent> later widened his
assignment to cover national crisis contingency planning.
In that capacity he became involved with the controversial
national crisis plan drafted by the Federal Emergency
Management Agency.</p>

<p> NATIONAL CRISIS PLAN</p>

<p> From 1982 to 1984, <ent type='PERSON'>North</ent> assisted <ent type='ORG'>FEMA</ent>, the U.S.
government's chief national crisis-management unit, in
revising contingency plans for dealing with nuclear war,
insurrection or massive military mobilization.</p>

<p> North's involvement with <ent type='ORG'>FEMA</ent> set off the first
major clash between the official government and the advisers
and led to the formal letter of protest in 1984 from then-Attorney General <ent type='ORG'>Smith</ent>.</p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>Smith</ent> was in Europe last week and could not be
reached for comment.</p>

<p> But a government official familiar with North's
collaboration with <ent type='ORG'>FEMA</ent> said then-Director Louis O.
<ent type='ORG'>Guiffrida</ent>, a close friend of Meese's, mentioned <ent type='PERSON'>North</ent> in
meetings during that time as FEMA's <ent type='ORG'>NSC</ent> contact.</p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>Guiffrida</ent> could not be reached for comment, but
<ent type='ORG'>FEMA</ent> spokesman Bill McAda confirmed the relationship.</p>

<p> "Officials of <ent type='ORG'>FEMA</ent> met with Col. <ent type='PERSON'>North</ent> during 1982
to 1984," McAda said. "These meetings were appropriate to
Col. North's duties with <ent type='ORG'>the National Security Council</ent> and
FEMA's responsibilities in certain areas of national
security."</p>

<p> FEMA's clash with <ent type='ORG'>Smith</ent> occurred over a secret
contingency plan that called for suspension of the
Constitution, turning control of <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States over to
<ent type='ORG'>FEMA</ent>, appointment of military commanders to run state and
local governments and declaration of martial law during a
national crisis.</p>

<p> The plan did not define national crisis, but it
was understood to be nuclear war, violent and widespread
internal dissent or national opposition against a military
invasion abroad.</p>

<p> PLAN WAS PROTESTED</p>

<p> The official said the contingency plan was written
as part of an executive order or legislative package that
Reagan would sign and hold within the <ent type='ORG'>NSC</ent> until a severe
crisis arose.</p>

<p> The martial law portions of the plan were outlined
in a June 30, 1982, memo by Guiffrida's deputy for national
preparedness programs, <ent type='PERSON'>John Brinkerhoff</ent>. A copy of the memo
was obtained by <ent type='ORG'>The Herald</ent>.</p>

<p> The scenario outlined in the <ent type='ORG'>Brinkerhoff</ent> memo
resembled somewhat a paper <ent type='ORG'>Guiffrida</ent> had written in 1970 at
<ent type='ORG'>the Army War College</ent> in <ent type='GPE'>Carlisle</ent>, Pa., in which he advocated
martial law in case of a national uprising by black
militants. The paper also advocated the roundup and
transfer to "assembly centers or relocation camps" of at
least 21 million "<ent type='NORP'>American</ent> Negroes."</p>

<p> When he saw the <ent type='ORG'>FEMA</ent> plans, Attorney General <ent type='ORG'>Smith</ent>
became alarmed. He dispatched a letter to McFarlane Aug. 2,
1984 lodging his objections and urging a delay in signing
the directive.</p>

<p> "I believe that the role assigned to the Federal
Emergency Management Agency in the revised Executive Order
exceeds its proper function as a coordinating agency for
emergency preparedness," <ent type='ORG'>Smith</ent> said in the letter to
McFarlane, which <ent type='ORG'>The Herald</ent> obtained. "This department and
others have repeatedly raised serious policy and legal
objections to the creation of an 'emergency czar' role for
<ent type='ORG'>FEMA</ent>."</p>

<p> It is unclear whether the executive order was
signed or whether it contained the martial law plans.
<ent type='ORG'>Congressional</ent> sources familiar with national disaster
procedures said they believe Reagan did sign an executive
order in 1984 that revised national military mobilization
measures to deal with civilians in case of nuclear war or
other crisis.</p>

<p> ORCHESTRATED NEWS LEAKS</p>

<p> Around the time that issue was producing fireworks
with the administration, McFarlane and Casey reassigned
<ent type='PERSON'>North</ent> from national crisis planning to international covert
management of the contras. The transfer came after <ent type='PERSON'>North</ent>
took a personal interest, realizing that neither the State
Department nor any other government agency wanted to handle
the issue after it became clear early in 1984 that <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>
was moving to bar official aid to the rebels.</p>

<p> The new assignment, plus North's natural
organizational ability, creativity and the sheer energy he
dedicated to the issue, gradually led to an expansion of his
power and stature within the covert structure, officials and
investigators believe.</p>

<p> <ent type='PERSON'>Meese</ent> also was said to have played a role in the
secret government, investigators now believe, but his role
is less clear.</p>

<p> <ent type='PERSON'>Meese</ent> sometimes referred private <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> citizens
to the <ent type='ORG'>NSC</ent> so they could be screened and contacted for
soliciting support for the <ent type='GPE'>Nicaragua</ent>n contras.</p>

<p> One of those supporters, <ent type='PERSON'>Philip Mabry</ent> of Fort
Worth, told <ent type='ORG'>The Herald</ent> earlier this year that in 1983 he was
told by fellow conservatives in <ent type='GPE'>Texas</ent> to contact <ent type='PERSON'>Meese</ent>, then
<ent type='ORG'>White House</ent> counselor, if he wanted to help the contras.
After he contacted Meese's office, <ent type='ORG'>Mabry</ent> received a letter
from <ent type='PERSON'>Meese</ent> obtained by <ent type='ORG'>The Herald</ent> advising him that his name
had been given to the "appropriate people."</p>

<p> Shortly thereafter, <ent type='ORG'>Mabry</ent> said, a woman who
identified herself as Meese's secretary gave him the name
and phone number of another <ent type='ORG'>NSC</ent> secretary who, in turn, gave
him <ent type='PERSON'>North</ent> and his secretary, <ent type='PERSON'>Fawn Hall</ent>, as contacts.</p>

<p> Meese's Justice Department spokesman, Patrick
Korten, denies that <ent type='PERSON'>Meese</ent> was part of North's secret contra
supply network and notes that <ent type='PERSON'>Meese</ent> does not recall having
referred anyone to <ent type='PERSON'>North</ent> on contra-related matters.</p>

<p> In addition to North's role as contra commander
and fund-raiser, <ent type='PERSON'>North</ent> became secret overseer of the State
Department's Office of Public Diplomacy, through which the
Reagan administration disseminated information that cast
<ent type='GPE'>Nicaragua</ent> as a threat to its neighbors and <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent>
States.</p>

<p> An intelligence source familiar with North's
relationship with that office said <ent type='PERSON'>North</ent> was directly
involved in many of the best publicized news leaks,
including the Nov. 4, 1984, Election Day announcement that
<ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent>-made MiG jet fighters were on their way to <ent type='GPE'>Nicaragua</ent>.</p>

<p> McFarlane is now believed to have been the senior
administration official who told reporters that the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent>
cargo ship Bakuriani, en route to <ent type='GPE'>Nicaragua</ent> from a <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent>
<ent type='LOC'>Black Sea</ent> port, was probably carrying MiGs.</p>

<p> The intelligence official said <ent type='PERSON'>North</ent> apparently
recommended that the information be leaked to the press on
Election Day so it would reach millions of people watching
election results. <ent type='ORG'>CBS</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>NBC</ent> broadcast the report that
night.</p>

<p> <ent type='PERSON'>CLARK</ent> HAD KEY ROLE</p>

<p> The leak led to a new clash between the regular
bureaucracy and the president's advisers. The official
State Department spokesman, <ent type='PERSON'>John Hughes</ent>, tried hard to play
down the report, pointing out that it was unproven that the
Bakuriani was carrying MiGs. At the same time, employees of
<ent type='ORG'>the Office</ent> of Public Diplomacy, acting under North's
direction, insisted that the crates were inside the ship and
that MiGs were still a possibility.</p>

<p> To take a closer look, the source said, <ent type='PERSON'>North</ent>
requested a high-flying SR-71 Blackbird spy aircraft be sent
from <ent type='ORG'>Beale Air Force Base</ent> near <ent type='GPE'>Sacramento</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Calif</ent>., to fly
over the <ent type='GPE'>Nicaragua</ent>n port of <ent type='GPE'>Corinto</ent> while the Bakuriani
unloaded its cargo. The pictures showed that the Bakuriani
unloaded helicopters, not MiGs.</p>

<p> <ent type='PERSON'>North</ent> was not the only adviser who operated
outside traditional government channels, investigators have
concluded.</p>

<p> Others were known as the <ent type='ORG'>RIGLET</ent>, a semi-official
unit made up of <ent type='PERSON'>North</ent>; <ent type='PERSON'>Alan Fiers</ent>, a <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> Central <ent type='NORP'>American</ent>
affairs officer; and <ent type='PERSON'>Elliott Abrams</ent>, the current assistant
secretary of state for inter-<ent type='NORP'>American</ent> affairs, according to
<ent type='PERSON'>Abrams</ent>' subordinate <ent type='PERSON'>Richard Melton</ent>. <ent type='PERSON'>Melton</ent> revealed the
existence of the <ent type='ORG'>RIGLET</ent> in a deposition given to the <ent type='GPE'>Iran</ent>-contra committees. The name is a diminutive for <ent type='ORG'>RIG</ent>, which
stands for Restricted Interagency <ent type='ORG'>Group</ent>.</p>

<p> Among the RIGLET's actions was ordering the U.S.
ambassador to <ent type='GPE'>Costa Rica</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Lewis Tambs</ent>, to assist the contras
in setting up a front in southern <ent type='GPE'>Nicaragua</ent>. Tambs, who
resigned suddenly last year after his links to <ent type='PERSON'>North</ent> were
revealed, testified about the instructions to <ent type='GPE'>Iran</ent>-contra
investigators.</p>

<p> But perhaps the key to the parallel government was
the role played by Reagan's second national security
adviser, <ent type='PERSON'><ent type='PERSON'>William</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Clark</ent></ent>. It was during Clark's tenure that
<ent type='PERSON'>North</ent> began to gain influence in the <ent type='ORG'>NSC</ent>.</p>

<p> <ent type='PERSON'>Clark</ent> also recruited several midlevel officers
from the <ent type='ORG'>Pentagon</ent> and the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> to work on a special Central
<ent type='NORP'>American</ent> task force in 1983 to push aid for El Salvador, a
task force member said.</p>

<p> "Judge <ent type='PERSON'>Clark</ent> was the granddaddy of the system," he
said. "I was working at the <ent type='ORG'>Pentagon</ent> on another issue when
my boss said that because of special circumstances, I was to
be reassigned to the task force."</p>

<p> A former administration official familiar with
Clark's activities said <ent type='PERSON'>Clark</ent> also had approved contacts
between <ent type='GPE'>Vatican</ent> Ambassador <ent type='PERSON'>Wilson</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Libya</ent> before Wilson's
November 1985 journey, which came after McFarlane replaced
<ent type='PERSON'>Clark</ent> at the <ent type='ORG'>NSC</ent>.</p>

<p> The former official said <ent type='PERSON'>Wilson</ent> also had carried
out secret missions for the Reagan administration in a Latin
<ent type='NORP'>American</ent> country where <ent type='PERSON'>Wilson</ent> reportedly maintained contacts
with high-level officials. The source asked that the
country not be identified because the system is still in
place and had reduced tensions by circumventing the regular
bureaucracies of both countries.</p>

<p> Calls to Wilson's and Clark's offices in
<ent type='GPE'>Calif</ent>ornia were not returned.</p>

<p> -----END-----</p>

<p> *************************************************************
The above brought to you as a public service
by <ent type='ORG'>SAX</ent> ALLEN of Free <ent type='GPE'>San Francisco</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Calif</ent>ornia
*************************************************************
by <ent type='ORG'>SAX</ent> ALLEN of Free <ent type='GPE'>San Francisco</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Calif</ent>ornia
****************************************

Downloaded from Just Say Yes. 2 lines, More than 500 files online!
Full access on first call. 415-922-2008 CASFA </p>

<p>


Another file downloaded from:

!
-$- &amp; <ent type='ORG'>the Temple</ent> of the Screaming Electron
! * <ent type='GPE'>Walnut Creek</ent>, CA
+ /^
! | |//^ _^_ 2400/1200/300 baud (415) 935-5845
/^ / @ | /_-_ Jeff Hunter, Sysop
|@ _| @ @|- - -|
| | /^ | _ | - - - - - - - - - *
|___/____|_|_|_(_)_| Aaaaaeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeeee! /

Specializing in conversations, E-Mail, obscure information,
entertainment, the arts, politics, futurism, thoughtful discussion,
insane speculation, and wild rumours. An ALL-TEXT BBS.

"Raw data for raw minds."

</p></xml>