<xml><p> From <ent type='ORG'>Prevailing Winds Research</ent>, Reprint #003 :
* * * * * * * * * * * * * * * * *</p>

<p> "THE SECRET TREATY OF <ent type='GPE'>FORT</ent> HUNT"
by <ent type='PERSON'>Carl</ent> Oglesby</p>

<p>Read this article in conjunction with "How Allen Dulles and the
SS Preserved Each Other," and you'll have a pretty good idea of
how we got into the mess we're in today. This article from
"Covert Action [Information Bulletin]" tells the story of <ent type='ORG'>ODESSA</ent>
and it's relationship to <ent type='PERSON'>Reinhard Gehlen</ent>'s spy organization
which formed the basis of our modern <ent type='ORG'>Central Intelligence Agency</ent>
and <ent type='ORG'>National Security Council</ent>. "The unconditional surrender
that the <ent type='NORP'>Germans</ent> made to <ent type='ORG'>the Allied</ent> Command at the little red
schoolhouse in <ent type='GPE'>Reims</ent> was the surrender only of the German Armed
Services. It was NOT the surrender of the hard SS core of the
Nazi Party. The SS did not surrender, unconditionally or
otherwise, and thus, <ent type='NORP'>Naziism</ent> itself did not surrender. The SS
chose, rather, to seek other means of continuing the war while
the right wing of <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States Military Establishment,
through fears and secret passions and a naivet'e of its own,
chose to facilitate that choice. The history that we have lived
through since then stands witness to the consequences."
$1.30</p>

<div>- - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - - -</div>

<p>As a small non-profit group, <ent type='ORG'>Prevailing Winds Research</ent>
hopes it can serve an important social service, attempting
to preserve important and scarce information and making it
available in the form of audios, videos, books and reprints.
ASK FOR A CATALOG.</p>

<p> PREVAILING WINDS RESEARCH
P.O. Box 23511
<ent type='GPE'>Santa Barbara</ent>, CA 93121</p>

<p> Telephone: (805)566-8016 FAX (24 hours) (805) 569-2411
<ent type='ORG'>PWR Bulletin Board System</ent>: (805) 569-5005</p>

<p>----------------------------
Transcribed by John DiNardo</p>

</xml>