<xml><p>
--SOVIET <ent type='ORG'>SCALAR ELECTROMAGNETIC</ent> WEAPONS--

This briefing presents the basic concepts of <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> Scalar
electromagnetic weapons, some of the major types available, and evidence of
their widespread testing.

- <ent type='ORG'>Scalar Electromagnetics</ent> is Electrogravitation -

Scalar electromagnetics is an extension of present electromagnetics (EM)
to include gravitation. That is, a unified electrogravitation, and, what is
more important, it is a unified engineering theory. Its basis was discovered
by <ent type='ORG'>Nikola</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent>. </p>

<p> In the scalar EM extension, EM field energy can be turned into
gravitational field energy and vice versa. This exchange can be patterned and
localized, in specific areas and objects. Such a controlled change of
electromagnetics to gravitation is not possible in the normal EM or physics
presently taught in <ent type='NORP'>Western</ent> textbooks. However, the bits and pieces of the
theory have been scattered through the physics literature for some time, but
no orthodox western scientist seems to have realized that these anomalous
portions could be integrated into a startling new physics. Unorthodox
experimenters, inventors, and scientists have made discoveries in this arena
for several decades, but again have not realized the exact implications or
the precise manner in which their results could be combined with present
electrical physics.

- Fer-De-Lance -

Such sluggishness is certainly not present in the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> Union. For
over three decades, the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> Union has been developing electrogravitation
and app,ying it to develop strange new s%cret weapons of incredible power
and capability. They have sustained the largest weapons development program
ever launched by any nation, and they have kept it effectively hidden from
prying western eyes. I have called this program "Fer-De-Lance", after the
deadly <ent type='NORP'>South American</ent> pit viper of the same name. </p>

<p> The dreaded fer-de-lance is a snake of great agility and lethal effect.
It often ambushes its hapless prey, and strikes unexpectedly and without
warning. Its first sudden strike is usually lethal to its victim, which
promptly expires in writhing agony. Since the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> development of scalar EM
weapons has been designed for the same purpose, the name seems appropriate. </p>

<p> The equivalent effort of about seven <ent type='GPE'>Manhattan</ent> projects has been poured
into fer-de-lance by the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent>s, and the program has been successful almost
beyond imagination. The eerie weapons are now developed, deployed, and
tested. The ambush has been completed; Fer-de-Lance is coiled and ready to
strike.
</p>

<p>--<ent type='ORG'>ENERGETICS</ent> AND DIRECTED ENERGY WEAPONS (DEW'S)--

The ordinary <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> name for this type of weapons science is
energetics. In the west that term is believed to be associated with
conventional directed energy weapons (<ent type='ORG'>DEW</ent>s) such as particle beam weapons,
lasers, radio-frequency (RF) directed energy devices, etc. The <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent>s do not
limit the term in this way. </p>

<p> <ent type='NORP'>Western</ent> scientists are familiar only with directed energy weapons
where fragments, masses, photons, or particles travel through space and
contact the target to deliver their effects. Hence in their thinking they
limit the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> term "energetics" to the type of weapons they themselves
understand -- exotic but normal weapons using energy or mass traveling
through space to impact a target. </p>

<p> However, it is possible to focus the potential for the effects of a
weapon through spacetime itself, in a manner so that mass and energy do not
"travel through space" from the transmitter to the target at all. Instead,
ripples and patterns in the fabric of spacetime itself are manipulated to
meet and interfere in and at the local spacetime of some distant target.
There interference of these ripple patterns creates the desired energetic
effect (hence the term energetics) directly in and through the target itself,
emerging from the very spacetime (vacuum) in which the target is imbedded at
its distant location. As used by the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent>s, energetics refers to these
eerie new superweapons, as well as to the more mundane <ent type='ORG'>DEW</ent>s known to the
west. </p>

<p> As a consequence of the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> breakthrough and decades of feverish
development, monstrous strategic weapons undreamed of in the <ent type='LOC'>West</ent> are
already in <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> hands. A noose is slowly and steadily being tightened about
our throats, and it is already the 11th hour.

--THE <ent type='NORP'>SOVIETS</ent> USE A DECEPTION PLAN--

Concomitant with this <ent type='ORG'>supersecret</ent> development program, the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent>s
developed and implemented an elaborate deception plan to conceal these
startling weapons and their nature from <ent type='NORP'>Western</ent> eyes until it is too late.
<ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> deception has been so successful that even when <ent type='NORP'>Western</ent> scientists are
confronted with the actual tests of these weapons directly over their heads,
they do not recognize the weaponry nor the nature of the effects produced.

As early as January 1960, <ent type='PERSON'>Nikita Khrushchev</ent> announced the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent>
development of a new, fantastic weapon. </p>

<p> On April 10 1963 one of the first new superweapons operationally
deployed was used to destroy the U.S.S. Thresher atomic submarine
underwater, off <ent type='LOC'>the east coast</ent> of the U.S. The next day, April 11, 1963 the
same deployed superweapon was utilized in a different mode to produce a giant
underwater explosion in the ocean over the <ent type='NORP'>Puerto Rican</ent> Trench, 100 miles
north of <ent type='GPE'>Puerto Rico</ent>. </p>

<p> Over the years, various aircraft were interfered with or downed as
tests of these <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> weapons. A particular case involved the mysterious
loss of F-111s in the <ent type='GPE'>Vietnam</ent> conflict. At least one downed F-111 crew was
recovered in the subsequent prisoner of war exchange. On that aircraft all
electrical systems were in difficulty simultaneously. This was probably due
to special <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> teams converting some <ent type='PERSON'>North</ent> <ent type='GPE'>Vietnam</ent>ese SA-2 missile system
radars to the scalar EM mode, and employing "scalar beam" interference to
produce spurious EM noise throughout the electrical and electronic systems of
the aircraft. </p>

<p> In late April/early May of 1985, the entire armada of <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> strategic
scalar EM superweapons was activated as a special celebration of the 40th
anniversary of the end of W.W.II. Activation of this armada (which probably
contained over 100 giant weapons), together with 27 giant power systems and a
large number of command and control transmissions, was monitored on an
advanced, proprietary detection system by <ent type='PERSON'>Frank Golden</ent>. After the gigantic
strategic exercise, which lasted several days, most of the weapons and power
sources were once again stood down to "standby." </p>

<p> The <ent type='ORG'>NASA</ent> shuttle launches provided an convenient opportunity for <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent>
testing of these superweapons in a launch phase <ent type='ORG'>ABM</ent> mode, where a launched
missile can be detected and destroyed shortly after liftoff. At first,
electromagnetic pulse (EMP) bursts on the early shuttle trajectory were
deliberately delayed in time, to prevent actual destruction of the target and
avoid alerting the U.S. that something unusual was happening. </p>

<p> The shuttle launch of November 26, 1985 saw a particularly significant
test of this kind. In this case, a very loud "sonic boom" or explosion
occurred over the launch site 12 minutes after shuttle liftoff, when the
shuttle was already away and downrange. At least two previous shuttle
launches had also been used as pseudotargets, with delayed booms occurring
over the launch site well behind the vehicles. </p>

<p> After lack of U.S. reaction to these tests showed that the U.S. still
had no knowledge of the new technology and did not even recognize its
employment, the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent>s apparently decided to proceed with tests where the
target would actually be destroyed. </p>

<p> On December 12, 1985 the same <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> weapon tested against the <ent type='ORG'>NASA</ent>
shuttle launches deliberately interfered with the controls of an Arrow DC-8
taking off from Gander Air Force Base, <ent type='ORG'>Newfoundland</ent>. At an altitude of 100
feet, the aircraft--carrying over 250 U.S. soldiers and civilian crew
members lost power and sank into the ground tail-low, killing everyone on
board. Three Canadian witnesses to the crash were interviewed over the
Canadian Broadcast Corporation's television news on April 81986 at 10 p.m.
No flame or smoke issued from the plane before its descent and crash. However
the aircraft was seen to be mysteriously glowing with a yellow glow. That is
a signature of the use of a scalar howitzer in the "continuous EM emergence"
mode, similar to the manner in which the F-111s were downed in <ent type='GPE'>Vietnam</ent>. In
short, the DC-8s electrical systems were interfered with ny electromagnetic
noise created throughout the spacetime occupied by the aircraft. The powerful
charge created in and around the aircraft also apparently caused the loss of
two engines, one after the other. With its controls ineffective, and its
power drastically reduced, the aircraft sank to earth, still in its "tail
down" configuration from takeoff, and crashed and burned. The "yellow glow"
was a corona due to the acquisition of a high electrical charge by the skin
of the aircraft. </p>

<p> Other factors contributing to the crash may have been reduced lift due
to poor engine maintenance, increased weight of the aircraft due to icing,
and heavy loading. Still, no one has recognized the significance of the
"yellow glow" or what it implies, or the possible connection between the loss
of the aircraft and previous <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> testing of a Launch Phase <ent type='ORG'>ABM</ent> system
against U.S. shuttle launches...
</p>

<p> As of September 1987, the last two <ent type='ORG'>Air Force Titan</ent> 34-D missiles fired
from Vandenburg Air Force Base in <ent type='GPE'>California</ent> have blown up shortly after
launch. The first one blew up on Aug. 28, 1985 just after lift-off. That loss
had been attributed to failure of a high powered fuel pump, causing a massive
oxidizer leak and a smaller fuel leak. The second Titan loss occurred on
April 18, 1986 when the missile blew up 5 seconds after lift off. Its loss is
still under investigation and no determination of cause has been made.
Apparently the shuttle and the Titan presently provide the only viable launch
vehicles for launching U.S. "spy" satellites. The loss of these sensitive
satellites--if indeed they constituted the payloads--cannot help but be
damaging to our strategic capability. According to <ent type='ORG'>the Los Angeles</ent> Times
(in 1986) the single remaining KH-11 satellite was launched in December 1984
and, with an expected life of two to three years, could stop functioning
later this year. </p>

<p> Whether or not significant <ent type='ORG'>Woodpecker</ent> grid activity existed in the
vicinity of the Titan launch of August 1985 is unknown at this time. However,
significant activity in the grid definitely occurred before the April 18
Titan disaster and on the same day. </p>

<p> On Easter <ent type='LOC'>Sunday</ent>, Mar. 301986 engineer <ent type='PERSON'>Ron Cole</ent> observed significant
correlated with <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Woodpecker</ent> measurements. On April 18, T.E Bearden,
perhaps the head of SEM research today, observed traces of a cloud radial
over Huntsville, <ent type='GPE'>Alabama</ent> and took photographs of it. Preliminary reports from
Thousand Oaks Ca. indicate extensive grid activity again on April 18, the day
the second Titan exploded. </p>

<p> At least the second of these two missile destructions shortly after
launch is suspicious, since the grid positively was active during that time.
Also, a clear trail of Launch Phase <ent type='ORG'>ABM</ent> system indicators exists back to the
massive scalar exercise of April/May 1985. The first Titan explosion in Aug.
1985 thus falls within the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent>s "now lets test them against the U.S.
launch vehicles" period. The second Titan loss follows highly suspicious
losses of the Arrow DC-8 on Dec. 12, 1985 and the Challenger on Jan. 28,
1986. The same <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> weapon that destroyed those #gets may have also
destroyed one or both of the critical <ent type='NORP'>Titans</ent>. </p>

<p> The <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent>s also have been able to significantly engineer the weather
over <ent type='PERSON'>North</ent> America for more than a decade without being found out. They have
tested a fantastic range of anti-ballistic missile (<ent type='ORG'>ABM</ent>) defense weapons for
over two decades, and no one is the wiser in the <ent type='LOC'>West</ent>. </p>

<p> As previously stated, prior to the end of November, 1985, at least three
"wet-run" tests of a <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> "launch phase <ent type='ORG'>ABM</ent> system" against actual U.S.
shuttle launches were made directly over Cape Canaveral itself, and still no
one recognized what was happening or what sort of weapon was being tested. On
December 12, destruction of the Arrow DC-8 in <ent type='ORG'>Newfoundland</ent> produce no
indications that the <ent type='NORP'>Americans</ent> and Canadians knew anything about the nature
of the weapon possibly used. </p>

<p> Accordingly, after a sufficient wait to test our reactions (if any), the
<ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent>s prepared to actually destroy a shuttle after its launch... </p>

<div> </div>

<p>--DESTRUCTION OF THE CHALLENGER, JANUARY, 1986--

As the whole world knows, on January 28, 1986 the Challenger was
launched from Cape Canaveral <ent type='GPE'>Florida</ent> after exposure to undesirable weather
conditions, and disastrously exploded shortly after launch. The evidence
seems to indicate that , as the rising vehicle was stressed, one end of its
right booster broke loose, twisting away and into the main fuel tank, causing
rupture, spillage of the fuel, and catastrophic explosion. Several other
anomalies still exist however, and it is clear that a problem existed with at
least one of the booster seals. All seven astronauts aboard the flight were
killed in the fiery destruction of the vehicle. </p>

<p> Of course no one had recognized that the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent>s had already tested a
launch-phase anti-ballistic missile (LP<ent type='ORG'>ABM</ent>) system against three of our
previous shuttle launches. These "wet-runs" used a deliberate "time-offset"
to delay the explosive emergence of electromagnetic energy in a launched
shuttle's location along its trajectory. The delayed test shots resulted in
very large "booms" above the launch site after the shuttle was safely out of
the area, but did not destroy the shuttles themselves. For example, the
delayed shot-boom occurred 12 minutes after the evening launch of Nov. 26,
1985. Even a marker beacon (large light in the sky) was utilized on that
launch shortly after lift-off. The marker beacon was photographed. In
addition another photograph taken in a time sequence shows another sudden
streak of light coming down and ending in a burst of light. This was probably
a spacially-offset test of the "pulse mode" for destroying the shuttle. The
"light burst" would have been detected in the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> Union and scored against
its intended offset position. However, another mechanism was used to cause
the destruction of the shuttle itself. </p>

<p> On Jan. 1, 1986 the presence of a metal softening signal added on to the
<ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> LP<ent type='ORG'>ABM</ent> systems scalar EM transmissions was detected by a surprised
<ent type='PERSON'>Frank Golden</ent>. The metal softening ability of the detected signal was
experimentally verified by him at that time. Golden also locally nullified
the action of the scalar EM signal in a test, rather conclusively
establishing (1) that it existed and (2) what it was. The signal was
apparently being prepared for use against an upcoming U.S. shuttle launch. </p>

<p> Just prior to the launch of the shuttle in late January, 1986, the
<ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent>s accomplished significant weather engineering over the U.S. The jet
stream was severely bent southward in the middle of the U.S., bending right-ward again to move across the <ent type='GPE'>Florida</ent> panhandle. Icy cold air from <ent type='GPE'>Canada</ent> was
drawn far down, into <ent type='GPE'>Florida</ent> and onto the Challenger sitting on it launch
pad. This exposure to cold outside its tested range was probably an
additional factor contributing to the Challengers failure. Positive
signatures of the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> weather engineering and jet stream manipulation
were observed and photographed by several persons, particularly in <ent type='GPE'>Alabama</ent>
and <ent type='GPE'>California</ent>...
</p>

<p> On January 28, 1986, the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> scalar EM weapon system effects were
sharply localized in the launch zone. Localization involved higher
frequencies being present; these are quite painful to small brains--whose
hemispheres act as a scalar interferometer and detector--such as in birds.
As commented upon by national news commentators, strangely the birds were not
flying that morning. Indeed, they were staying down on the ground or avoiding
the area, since the sky over the area was painful to them. </p>

<p> As Challenger rose, the metal softening signal would have been
experienced in and around the boosters shortly after ignition, since the
booster flame acts as a special "ion-plasma" tuner/detector for the scalar
signal. The effect of such a local signal is to "charge mass in the immediate
vicinity" with the particular scalar resonance signal. </p>

<p> The ill fated Challenger was doomed. After ignition, the booster flame
acted as as a ionic plasma detector/amplifier for the metal softening signal
on the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Woodpecker</ent> grid. The metal in and around the booster flame was
slowly and steadily weakening due to a charge up with the metal softening
pattern. This contributed to booster leakage from the already cold damaged
seal. The leaking booster poured out smoke and later flame, contributing to
the impending disaster. </p>

<p> Substantial winds and air turbulence over the site increased the stress
on the Challenger as it rose through this region. This also contributed to
the disaster and may have been deliberately created there by <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> Weather
engineering. </p>

<p> As the Challenger stressed, eventually one or more weakened mounts gave
way, partially freeing the end of the right booster. Another anomalous flame
or light was observed on the vehicle, and may have represented a very small
additional "pulse mode energy form" produced from the weapon that was already
attacking the Challenger. The booster oscillated, rotating into the tank and
rupturing it. Contact of the escaping liquid fuel and the flame resulted in a
fiery explosion, destroying the vehicle and killing those on board...

By creating excess cold exposure to the shuttle, inducing metal
softening in and around the ignited booster, and possibly adding a deliberate
"intensely hot spot", THE <ent type='NORP'>SOVIETS</ent> CAUSED THE CHALLENGER TO <ent type='ORG'>WEAKEN</ent> AND DESTROY
ITSELF SHORTLY AFTER LAUNCH, IN SO SUBTLE A FASHION THAT <ent type='ORG'>NASA</ent> SCIENTISTS
WOULD NOT SUSPECT WHAT HAD ACTUALLY CAUSED THE MISHAP. THE <ent type='NORP'>SOVIETS</ent> HAD ALSO
PREVIOUSLY WITHDRAWN ALL THEIR TRAWLERS AND SHIPS WHICH NORMALLY SHADOW A
<ent type='ORG'>SHUTTLE</ent> LAUNCH, TO <ent type='EVENT'>PREVENT</ent> ANY SUGGESTION OF SOVIET PRESENCE NEAR OR
INVOLVEMENT IN THE CATASTROPHIC ACCIDENT. </p>

<p> A few days later, sporadically intense "high frequency localization
signals" were still present on the grid, at least one hinge-point at
<ent type='GPE'>Birmingham</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Alabama</ent> confirmed this. From 1-4 February 1986, many birds
inadvertently flew into the zone when an intense breakout occurred, and birds
fell dead from the sky in substantial numbers....

Next:
-Technological Surprise and a <ent type='GPE'>New Hiroshima</ent>-

(Continued)</p>

</xml>