<xml>

<p> If we interfere two transmitters in a region of great energy--such as
the molten core of the <ent type='LOC'>earth</ent> itself--and bias the transmitters negatively, we
can extract enormous energy directly from that distant source! </p>

<p> Indeed, a slight variation of this effect is precisely how the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent>
Union obtains the enormous energy with which to power its incredibly
powerful strategic "continent-buster" scalar EM weapons. <ent type='ORG'>Scalar</ent> frequency
pairs -- 12 kilohertz apart -- are transmitted into the <ent type='LOC'>earth</ent> itself on some
portion of the earth's "giant scalar resonance" frequency curve. Biasing the
two transmitters differently with respect to each other produces a high
potential difference (vo<ent type='ORG'>ltage</ent>) between them. At the same time, biasing them
both negative with respect to the earth's molten core produces a scalar
resonance current from the core to the two transmitters. In the "outer loop"
between the two scalar transmitters, there appears a gigantic v/<ent type='ORG'>ltage</ent> and
gigantic electrical current which can be captured by appropriate means. This
electrical power is tapped off and transmitted to incredibly powerful scalar
EM weapon systems. There, special accumulators ad switchers are utilized to
provide awesome amounts of power to each weapon. </p>

<p> Just before May 11985 <ent type='GPE'>the Soviet Union</ent> performed a "full-up"
operational test of their entire strategic scalar EM weap/ns complex. This
test was detected and monitored periodically by <ent type='PERSON'>Frank Golden</ent>. Some 27 of
these giant <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> "power taps" were locked into the molten core of the
<ent type='LOC'>earth</ent>, producing forced (entrained) scalar resonance of the entire planet on
54 controlled frequencies under our very feet. The remainder of the scalar
frequency spectrum was ablaze with literally hundreds of <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> scalar
transmitters: probably the entire strategic scalar command and control system
to underwater submarines, higher command centers, distant commands, etc. was
activated in the giant exercise. </p>

<p> For several days the system was exercised on a mind-boggling scale,
apparently as part of <ent type='GPE'>the Soviet Union</ent>s highly accentuated 40th anniversary
celebration of the end of <ent type='EVENT'>World War</ent> II. </p>

<p> Ironically, not a single U.S. intelligence agency, laboratory, or
scientist detected this monstrous exercise for the new <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> leader,
Gorbacev. Not one of them had a detector for scalar EM radiation, and not one
of them will --officially-- say that the exercise ever happened. </p>

<p>-- CREATING ENERGY AT A DISTANCE --
</p>
<p>
A most useful device is obtained if one uses a scalar inferometer where
the two transmitters transmit beams which intersect at a distance. </p>

<p> In the interference zone, an energy bottle is created.</p>

<p> By biasing the transmitter reference potentials well above that of the
distant energy bottle, EM energy emerges in that zone. In that case the
interferometer is operating in the Exothermic mode. </p>

<p> By biasing the transmitter reference potentials well below that of the
distant energy bottle, EM energy is extracted from the distant zone and
emerges from the transmitter. In that case the inferometer is operating in
the Endothermic mode.</p>

<p> If the transmitters transmit continuously, the effect in the distant
zone is continuous. </p>

<p> If each transmitter transmits a pulse, and the two pulses meet in the
distant intersection zone, then an explosive emergence or extraction of
energy occurs at the distant interference zone, depending on whether the
inferometer is operating in the exothermic or endothermic mode. </p>

<p>-- EXOTHERMIC MODE (SCALAR INTERFEROMETER) --
</p>
<p>
For a scalar interferometer, "<ent type='GPE'>del phi</ent>" (the gradient of the potential)
applies between the transmitter sit and the distant intersection site, not to
the intervening space in between. Thus one speaks of "energy flow" as being
between the transmitter and intersection --without-any "in between". In the
intervening space, all energy exists as locked-in artificial potential, not
EM force field energy (gradient bleed off potential). </p>

<p> In the Exothermic mode, the ground potential of the transmitter is
biased well above the ground potential of ambient vacuum. <ent type='ORG'>Energy</ent> enters the
transmitter and "disappears", to "reappear" in the distant interference zone. </p>

<p> If continuous wave transmission is used, the energy continuously
appears in the distant zone. </p>

<p> If pulse transmission is used and timed so that the two scalar pulses
meet in the distant zone, energy explosively appears there. </p>

<p> If multiple frequencies are transmitted in the manner of a Fourier
expansion of a particular geometric form, then a 3-dimensional energy form
appears at the distant intersection. In this manner a spherical or
hemispherical shell (a globe or "dome" of EM energy) can be created at a
distance. If pulse transmission is used, this will be an impulsive or
explosive emergence of that energy form. If continuous transmission is used,
this will be a continuous glowing form. </p>

<p> By feeding incredibly powerful transmitters with large amounts of
energy extracted from the earth's molten core by "energy taps," very large
spherical globes and hemispherical domes of EM energy can be created at a
distance. The energy in the interference "shell" of such a sphere or
hemisphere is sufficiently dense to lift Dirac matter from the Dirac sea of
the vacuum. Thus the shell contains a glowing plasma. </p>

<p> Many such scalar howitzer signatures have been seen over the oceans,
particularly over the north <ent type='LOC'>Pacific</ent> by jet airliners flying into and out of
<ent type='GPE'>Japan</ent>. (Remember some months ago the big story about the <ent type='ORG'>JAL</ent> flight in which
all passengers and crew saw a giant spherical "<ent type='EVENT'>UFO</ent>".) Also such globes and
domes of light have been seen deep within <ent type='GPE'>the Soviet Union</ent>, by observers in
<ent type='GPE'>Afghanistan</ent> and by pilots of aircraft landing in <ent type='GPE'>Iran</ent>. </p>

<p> In the impulsive exothermic mode, a large visible flash will occur if
EM energy in the visible spectrum is produced. "Flashes" in the infrared may
similarly occur, if the emerging energy is in that spectral band. In
September 1979 our <ent type='PERSON'>Vela</ent> satellites detected such a large "nuclear flash" over
the <ent type='LOC'>South Atlantic</ent>, off the southern coast of <ent type='LOC'>Africa</ent>. A second "nuclear
flash" detected by the <ent type='PERSON'>Vela</ent> satellites in 1980 was in the infrared only. Some
years ago, a series of anomalous "flashes" and "booms" occurred off the east
coast of <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States. The were due to the orientation and alignment --
and registration -- of one or more "scalar howitzers" -- scalar EM
interferometers in the exothermic mode. </p>

<p> Large "booms" occurred over the shuttle launch site at Cape Canaveral,
associated with three shuttle launches prior to the end of November 1985.
These were tests of such exothermic scalar EM howitzers, being tested as part
of the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> Launch Phase <ent type='ORG'>ABM</ent> system. In that mode, the scalar pulses from
the two transmitters are injected into special zero-reference scalar EM
"channels" established in the EM carriers of the <ent type='ORG'>Woodpecker</ent> over-the-horizon
radars. The scalar pulses travel through these channels, traveling in the
ordinary EM beam of the transmitter and following it in its curvature around
the <ent type='LOC'>earth</ent> in the <ent type='LOC'>earth</ent>-ionospheric waveguide. The scalar pulses are timed,
phased, and oriented so as to meet the rising shuttle. In these tests the
transmissions were offset in time so the shuttle would not actually be
destroyed, but the system could be tested against actual shuttle launches in
the U.S.

The specific uses of these various exothermic modes will be covered in
later parts of this series. </p>

<p> In the endothermic mode, the bias on the transmitters is such that
energy is extracted from the distant intersection zone, to re-emerge from the
transmitters. There the energy must be caught and disposed of if it is not to
burn out the transmitters. When very large amounts of energy are extracted
from distant points, the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent>s often use a "dump" method of temporarily
capturing, and storing in an accumulator, the heat energy emerging at the
transmitters. A second howitzer in the exothermic mode is then fed by a
"scalar energy tap" established into the accumulator. This howitzer is
focused on the distant dump site -- often <ent type='LOC'>Bennett Island</ent>, where exhausts are
continually observed by U.S. weather satellites. </p>

<p> In the impulsive endothermic mode, energy is impulsively extracted from
the distant intersection zone. In the atmosphere this results in a very sharp
cooling or "cold explosion". It also results in the type of boom and rumble
often associated with thunder after a lightning bolt. </p>

<p> On April 9, 1984 <ent type='GPE'>the Soviet Union</ent> tested such a "cold explosion" off
the coast of <ent type='GPE'>Japan</ent>, near the <ent type='LOC'>Kuril Islands</ent>. In the suddenly induced low
pressure "cold zone" above the ocean, ocean water was sharply sucked up from
the ocean, forming a dense cloud. Then air rushing into the low pressure zone
forced the cloud upward, forming a mushroom much like that of an atomic
explosion except for the absence of a flash and the absence of a shockwave
moving out and away from the center of the explosion. </p>

<p> As the cloud rises, it expands by mixing -- very similar to a giant
thunderhead buildup, except much faster. In this case the cloud rose to about
60000 feet in about 2 minutes, spreading out until it reached a diameter of
about 200 miles. The incident was seen by the pilots and crews of several
<ent type='ORG'>Boeing</ent> 747 jet airliners in the general vicinity. Sometime after that, a U.S.
weather satellite photo of the area occurred. The cloud in that photo has an
anomalous density distribution, differing from that of all other clouds in
the area...

(Continued)
</p></xml>