<xml>

<p>--TESLA'S "BIG EYE" FOR REMOTE VIEWING--
</p>
<p>
Nikola <ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent> planned a very special use for his endothermic scalar
interferometer. He planned to produce what he called his "big eye to see at a
distance." </p>

<p> The system used to accomplish this is only weakly endothermic, so that
only a small amount of energy is extracted from the distant target. Also, the
beams are "scanned" by an open receiver, timewise, from side to side and top
to bottom. By scanning yet another single beam through the intersection zone
and phasing its pulses, an even better representation can be obtained. Thus
the receiver produces a representation of the energy extracted from various
locations within the distant endothermic zone. By displaying the received
signals on an appropriately scanned screen, a representation of the distant
scene can be created. This is a special kind of "microwave interferometry,"
and -- with modern techniques -- the imagery obtained can be surprisingly
good. </p>

<p> With development, it might even become as good as the image presently
obtained by side looking acquisition radars. </p>

<p> Interestingly enough, since scalar beams will easily penetrate the <ent type='LOC'>earth</ent>
or the ocean, one can also look beneath the <ent type='LOC'>earth</ent> or ocean with this type of
scanning scalar interferometer.

The importance of this capability to strategic and tactical
reconnaissance is obvious. <ent type='ORG'>Camouflage</ent>, cover, and concealment have no effect
on such a system. One can easily look into buildings and into underground
facilities. With a small system such as this, the U.S. Marines at <ent type='PERSON'>Khe Sahn</ent>
would have had little difficulty locating the tunnels continually dug under
the perimeter by the <ent type='GPE'>Viet Cong</ent>. And targets under jungle canopies are
directly visible...

It requires little imagination to see that this system is easily
adapted for use underwater. A type of "underwater radar." With such devices,
the problem posed by the underwater nuclear submarine is solved. For example,
an entire area can be continually searched, much like acquisition radar
systems do now. A submarine can be detected and tracked, and none of its
ordinary detectors will detect anything out of the ordinary. By using a
separate pair of beams in the exothermic mode, powerful scalar pulses can be
fired at the distant sub, intersecting at the submarine in a violent EMP
throughout the sub and its armament. Thus the sub and all of its missiles
are destroyed instantly. </p>

<p> Or, continuous exothermic transmission can be used by the targeting
weapon at lesser power, gradually interfering with the sub's electrical
systems and causing it to loose control. The sub then sinks to crush depths
and implodes. </p>

<p> Precisely that scenario seems to be what happened on April 10, 1963 to
the U.S.S. Thresher nuclear submarine. It left a signature: the subs nearby
surface companion, the U.S.S. <ent type='ORG'>Skylark</ent>, was in the "splatter zone" of the
underwater scalar interference. That is, spurious EM noise was being
generated in all the Skylark's electrical systems, some of which were
actually disabled. So intense was the "electronic jamming" that it required
over an hour and a half for the <ent type='ORG'>Skylark</ent> to transmit an emergency message
back to its headquarters that the Thresher was n serious trouble and contact
with it had been lost. Some of the Skylark's communication systems actually
failed, but later resumed operation inexplicably, once the jamming was gone.
That type of "jamming" of multiple bands and multiple electronic equipment,
of course, together with the anomalous failure of electronic equipment and
its later mysterious recovery, were direct signatures of the exothermic
scalar interferometer against thee undersea target in the vicinity of the
skylark. </p>

<p> The very next day, April 111963, the same <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> scalar EM howitzer
system was tested in the "destroy submarine" pulse mode. A huge underwater EM
blast occurred off the coast of <ent type='GPE'>Puerto Rico</ent>, about 100 miles north of the
island. The underwater explosion caused a huge boiling of the surface of the
ocean, followed by the rising up of a giant mushroom of water about a third
of a mile high, the mushroom of water then fell back into the ocean,
completing the signature. </p>

<p> Fortunately the entire incident was seen by the startled crew of a
passing U.S. jetliner which was just passing its checkpoint in that area.
(See Robert J.Durant, "An underwater explosion -- or what?", Pursuit, 5(2),
April 1972, p. 30-31.) </p>

<p> These two incidents were full up operational tests of Khrushchev's
newly-deployed superweapons. He probably staged this dramatic one-two punch
in a desperate effort to recover face with <ent type='ORG'>the Communist Party</ent> after his
disastrous face down by <ent type='PERSON'>Kennedy</ent> in thee <ent type='NORP'>Cuban</ent> Missile Crisis a few short
months previously. Apparently the attempt was successful, since he remained
in power another year before being deposed. </p>

<p>--MUSHROOM CLOUD FROM SEA OFF <ent type='GPE'>JAPAN</ent> NEAR RUSSIAN TEST AREA--

The following is concerning the "cold explosion" of April 91984. The
site of the explosion was only about 200 miles from downtown <ent type='GPE'>Tokyo</ent>. It was
seen by the crews of several jet airliners, including <ent type='ORG'>Japan Air Lines</ent> Flight
36. </p>

<p> A short time before the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent>s had hastily announced missile tests
would be conducted into a zone some distance away from the ol explosion site.
This may have been a deception to cover this incident, should any nation
indicate they knew what was going on. </p>

<p> It was also a direct "stimulus" to the <ent type='NORP'>Japanese</ent> and the rest of the
world: That is stimulate the system and see if the scientists recognize what
happened. If they do, then they know about scalar EM weapons. If they don't,
then their countries know nothing of scalar EM weapons, and those countries
are defenseless against them. </p>

<p> At any rate, at about 5:14 a.m. <ent type='ORG'>Pacific Standard</ent> time on April 91984,
a giant mushroom cloud erupted above the ocean south of <ent type='LOC'>the Kuril Islands</ent>.
The mushroom rose rapidly, expanding to an altitude of 60000 feet and a
diameter of 200 miles within 2 minutes. </p>

<p> One pilot of a <ent type='ORG'>Boeing</ent> 747 who observed the cloud was a former B-52
bomber pilot. He described the cloud as being very similar to that of a
gigantic nuclear explosion, except there was no flash of visible light.
Taking evasive action, he turned off course away from the blast, and braced
for a blast shock that never came... </p>

<p>--MUSHROOM CLOUD RISING FROM THE SEA (COLD EXPLOSION)--

Indeed, this highly anomalous cloud was due to a cold explosion -- a
test of a <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> scalar EM howitzer in the pulsed endothermic mode.

Thus a beautiful "stimulus" and test was conducted: quite a few
airliners were "pinged", providing a high-level stimulus to competent
observers. The news was sure to be reported by them to several nations. The
press was sure to pick up the story. This was a high order stimulus to see
whether the U.S., <ent type='GPE'>Japan</ent>, or other potential adversaries of the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> Union
recognized the testing of a cold explosion weapon. </p>

<p> By our reaction, we assured them (with high confidence) that we still
knew nothing of scalar EM interferometry or cold explosions. </p>

<p> Five <ent type='ORG'>Boeing</ent> 747's flew through or near the cloud on their way to
<ent type='GPE'>Anchorage</ent> <ent type='GPE'>Alaska</ent>. The aircraft were checked at <ent type='GPE'>Anchorage</ent> for rad)oactive
contamination, but nothing was found. This showed that the huge explosion
had been non-nuclear. </p>

<p> The ocean in the area is also about 21000 feet deep. That is really
too deep for a submarine volcano to have erupted and caused the cloud.
(Besides, a volcano would have continued to snort at least a bit, and so that
appears to be out of the question as a cause of the incident.) </p>

<p> In short, a man made phenomenon is indicated.</p>

<p> Indeed, we know it was a cold explosion. In fact, the basic effect has
been produced over a dish of water in the laboratory, using a small scalar
interferometer in the endothermic mode. </p>

<p> Further, the story does not end there.</p>

<p> A geophysicist at <ent type='ORG'>the University</ent> of Hawaii, Dr.<ent type='PERSON'>Daniel</ent> A. <ent type='PERSON'>Walker</ent>,
together with his colleages monitor an array of Hydrophones on the ocean
bottom, recording signals such as seismic events, volcano eruptions, etc. </p>

<p> Dr.<ent type='PERSON'>Walker</ent> and his colleages performed a comprehensive analysis of the
data recorded by the hydrophones in and around the time of the incident in
question. The data shows the absence of any natural seismic or volcanic event
that could have caused the April 9th phenomenon off the coast of <ent type='GPE'>Japan</ent>.

He and his colleages concluded that it was either an as yet unknown
natural phenomenon, or a man made phenomenon. </p>

<p> Their report is published in "Science". (D.<ent type='PERSON'>Walker</ent>,"Kaitoku Seamount and
the Mystery Cloud of 9 April 1984," Science, 227(4687),Feb.81985,p.
607-611.)

(Continued)
</p></xml>