<xml><p>(From <ent type='ORG'>the Weekly World</ent> News, June 7, 1994)</p>

<p>Shocking confessions rock nation's capital!</p>

<p>12 U.S. SENATORS ARE SPACE ALIENS!</p>

<p>by <ent type='PERSON'>Nick Mann</ent> - Special report</p>

<p>WASHINGTON - A space alien who stunned the world by revealing that
five U.S. Senators were extraterrestrials in 1992 dropped another
bombshell when he met with President <ent type='PERSON'>Bill Clinton</ent> in <ent type='ORG'>the White House</ent> just
days ago -- and named seven more senators who hail from distant planets!</p>

<p>And far from denying the extraterrestrial's allegations, Senators Phil
<ent type='PERSON'>Gramm</ent>, Dennis <ent type='PERSON'>DeConcini</ent>, John D. <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> IV, <ent type='PERSON'>Bennett</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Johnston</ent>,
<ent type='PERSON'>Howell Heflin</ent>, Christopher <ent type='PERSON'>Dodd</ent>, and <ent type='PERSON'>William</ent> S. <ent type='PERSON'>Cohen</ent> conceded that
"the time is right to make our true identities known."</p>

<p>"Senators <ent type='PERSON'>John Glenn</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Orrin Hatch</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Nancy Kassebaum</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Sam Nunn</ent>, and
<ent type='PERSON'>Alan Simpson</ent> came out of the alien closet two years ago and now we find
that seven more senators are not from <ent type='LOC'>Earth</ent>," said author and <ent type='EVENT'>UFO</ent> expert
<ent type='PERSON'>Nathaniel Dean</ent>, who identified the first group of space alien senators in a
news conference that made international headlines in November 1992.</p>

<p>"The implications," he continued, "are almost beyond comprehension. For
one thing, we now know that the destiny of the most powerful nation on
<ent type='LOC'>Earth</ent> is being shaped and guided by entities who aren't even human.</p>

<p>"I'm not saying that this is bad, because it might very well be good.</p>

<p>"If the universe is inhabited by other creatures and civilizations, we need to
know about them.</p>

<p>"We also need linkage.</p>

<p>"And if nothing else, these space alien legislators can serve as our links to a
world that is even more advanced than our own."</p>

<p>Dean's report stunned political analysts and threatened to touch off a public
panic that, as one <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> source put it, "could quickly get out of control."</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>White House</ent> spokesmen declined to comment, but sources privately
confirmed that the President's meeting with the alien took place when the
Secret Service escorted the creature into <ent type='ORG'>the White House</ent> at 4:36 a.m. on
April 24.</p>

<p>They also suggested that the President will address the issue in an
upcoming news conference, although they could not provide a time or date.</p>

<p>While analysts scrambled to gauge public reaction, the senators sought
ways to minimize any negative fallout and put the right spin on the
creature's revelations.</p>

<p>Contacted at his office in <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>, Sen. <ent type='PERSON'>Gramm</ent>, R. - <ent type='GPE'>Texas</ent>, took the
high road with full and immediate disclosure, saying: "It's all true. We are
space aliens. And I'm amazed that it's taken you so long to find out.</p>

<p>"When we read that the other aliens had been exposed in 1992, we knew it
was only a matter of time before you got the rest of us."</p>

<p>Less expansive but equally honest was Sen. <ent type='PERSON'>DeConcini</ent>, D. - <ent type='GPE'>Ariz</ent>. In a
prepared statement, he said: "As chairman of the Senate Intelligence
Committee, I am quite distressed. My highly classified cover has been
blown."</p>

<p>Sen. <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent>, D. - W. Va., cleverly turned questions about the space
alien heritage into a plug for national health-care reform, saying: "I love it
here on <ent type='LOC'>Earth</ent>, but our health-care system is better at home."</p>

<p>Sen. <ent type='PERSON'>Heflin</ent>, D. - Ala., was obviously taken off-guard by reporters'
questions. He called the space alien's revelations "surprising" and went on
to say: "Yes, my parents were Heaven sent."</p>

<p>Sen. <ent type='PERSON'>Johnston</ent>, D. - La., said: "At least the cat is out of the bag, although
this isn't exactly the way I intended to tell my family and friends."</p>

<p>Sen. <ent type='PERSON'>Dodd</ent>, D. - Conn., expressed relief "that all this is public." In the most
terse response of all, Sen. <ent type='PERSON'>Cohen</ent>, R. - <ent type='GPE'>Maine</ent>, said, "I admit it."</p>

<p>Dean's sources said the space alien identified the extraterrestrial senators in
a 25-minute meeting with President <ent type='PERSON'>Clinton</ent>.</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Dean</ent> does not know what else, if anything, was discussed at the meeting.</p>

<p>"The first question that came to my mind was whether the senators are
U.S. citizens and eligible to serve in the U.S. Senate," said <ent type='PERSON'>Dean</ent>.</p>

<p>"From what I understand, they were born in the U.S. and are U.S. citizens.
It just so happens that their parents were from another world. The senators
look like ordinary humans," he continued, "but the space alien who met
with President <ent type='PERSON'>Clinton</ent> had an answer for that, too.</p>

<p>"He reportedly said the senators looked human 'because they choose to
look human. It is a simple matter for us to change our forms.' "</p>

<p>Oddly enough, the extraterrestrial alien refused to pinpoint the planet or
star system he and the alien senators came from, <ent type='PERSON'>Dean</ent> said.</p>

<p>The twelve senators identified as space aliens are:
Christopher <ent type='PERSON'>Dodd</ent>, D. - Connecticut
<ent type='PERSON'>Bennett</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Johnston</ent>, D. - <ent type='GPE'>Louisiana</ent>
<ent type='PERSON'>William</ent> S. <ent type='PERSON'>Cohen</ent>, R. - <ent type='GPE'>Maine</ent>
Dennis <ent type='PERSON'>DeConcini</ent>, D. - <ent type='GPE'>Ariz</ent>ona
<ent type='PERSON'>Orrin Hatch</ent>, R. - <ent type='GPE'>Utah</ent>
<ent type='PERSON'>Nancy Kassebaum</ent>, R. - <ent type='GPE'>Kansas</ent>
<ent type='PERSON'>Alan Simpson</ent>, R. - <ent type='GPE'>Wyoming</ent>
Phil <ent type='PERSON'>Gramm</ent>, R. - <ent type='GPE'>Texas</ent>
<ent type='PERSON'>Howell Heflin</ent>, D. - <ent type='GPE'>Alabama</ent>
John D. <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> IV, D. - <ent type='GPE'>West Virginia</ent>
<ent type='PERSON'>Sam Nunn</ent>, D. - <ent type='GPE'>Georgia</ent>
<ent type='PERSON'>John Glenn</ent>, D. - <ent type='GPE'>Ohio</ent></p>

<p>(Transcriber's Note: Christopher Dodd's father was also a senator from
Connecticut. John D. <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> IV is, as the name indicates, a member of
the <ent type='PERSON'>Rockefeller</ent> family, which has been powerful in both politics and
business for several generations. <ent type='PERSON'>John Glenn</ent> was one of the first U.S.
astronauts, and participated in Projects <ent type='ORG'>Mercury</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Gemini</ent>, and <ent type='ORG'>Apollo</ent>.)

</p></xml>