<xml><p>IN<ent type='ORG'>SID</ent>E THE SHADOW <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent></p>

<p>by</p>

<p>John Connolly</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>SPY</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Magazine</ent> - Sept 1992 - Volume 6</p>

<div>============================================================================</div>

<p>What? A big private company - one with a board of former <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>FBI</ent> and
<ent type='ORG'>Pentagon</ent> officials; one in charge of protecting Nuclear-Weapons facilities,
nuclear reactors, the <ent type='NORP'>Alaskan</ent> oil pipeline and more than a dozen <ent type='NORP'>American</ent>
embassies abroad; one with long-standing ties to a radical ring-wing
organization; one with 30000 men and women under arms - secretly helped
<ent type='GPE'>IRAQ</ent> in its effort to obtain sophisticated weapons? And fueled unrest
in <ent type='GPE'>Venezuela</ent>? This is all the plot of a new best-selling thriller,
right? Or the ravings of some overheated <ent type='PERSON'>conspiracy buff</ent>,right? Right?</p>

<p>WRONG.</p>

<div>--</div>

<p>In the WINTER OF 1990, <ent type='PERSON'>David Ramirez</ent>, a 24 year-old member of the Special
Investigations Division of the <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> Corporation, was sent by his
superiors on an unusual mission. <ent type='PERSON'>Ramirez</ent> a former <ent type='ORG'>Marine Corps</ent> sergeant
based in <ent type='GPE'>Miami</ent>, was told to fly immediately to <ent type='GPE'>San Antonio</ent> along with three
other members of <ent type='ORG'>SID</ent>-a unit, known as founder and chairman <ent type='PERSON'>George</ent>
Wackenhut's "private <ent type='ORG'>FBI</ent>," that provided executive protection and conducted
undercover investigations and sting operations. Once they arrived, they
rented two gray Ford Tauruses and drove four hours to a desolate town on the
<ent type='NORP'>Mexican</ent> border called <ent type='ORG'>Eagle Pass</ent>. There, just after dark, they met two truck
drivers who had been flown in from <ent type='GPE'>Houston</ent>. Inside a nearby warehouse was an
18 -wheel tractor-trailer, which the two truck drivers and the four
<ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> agents in their rented cars were supposed to transport to <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>.
"My instructions were very clear," <ent type='PERSON'>Ramirez</ent> recalls. "Do not look into the
trailer, secure it, and make sure it safely gets to <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>." It went
without saying that no one else was supposed to look in the trailer, either,
which is why the <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> men were armed with fully loaded <ent type='ORG'>Remington</ent> 870
pump-action shotguns.</p>

<p>The convoy drove for 30 hours straight, stopping only for gas and food. Even
then, one of the <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> agents had to stay with the truck, standing by
one of the cars, its trunk open, shotgun within easy reach. "Whenever we
stopped, I bought a shot glass with the name of the town on it," <ent type='PERSON'>Ramirez</ent>
recalls. "I have glasses from <ent type='GPE'>Oklahoma City</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Kansas City</ent>, St. Louis."</p>

<p>A little before 5:00 on the morning of the third day, they delivered the
trailer to a practically empty warehouse outside <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>. A burly man who
had been waiting for them on the loading dock told them to take off the
locks and go home, and that was that. They were on a plane back to <ent type='GPE'>Miami</ent>
that afternoon. Later Ramirez's superiors told him-as they told other <ent type='ORG'>SID</ent>
agents about similar midnight runs-that the trucks contained $40 million
worth of food stamps. After considering the secrecy, the way the team was
assembled and the orders not to stop or open the truck, <ent type='PERSON'>Ramirez</ent> decided he
didn't believe that explanation.</p>

<p>Neither do we. One reason is simple: A Department of Agriculture official
simply denies that food stamps are shipped that way. "Someone is blowing
smoke," he says. Another reason is that after a six-month investigation, in
the course of which we spoke to more than 300 people, we believe we know
what the truck did contain-equipment necessary for the manufacture of
chemical weapons-and where it was headed: to <ent type='PERSON'>Saddam Hussein</ent>'s <ent type='GPE'>Iraq</ent>. And the
<ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> Corporation-a publicly traded company with strong ties to the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>
and federal contracts worth $200 million a year-was making sure <ent type='PERSON'>Saddam</ent> would
be geting his equipment intact. The question is why. In 1954, <ent type='PERSON'>George</ent>
<ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent>, then a 34-year old former <ent type='ORG'>FBI</ent> agent, joined up with three other
former <ent type='ORG'>FBI</ent> agents to open a company in <ent type='GPE'>Miami</ent> called Special Agent
Investigators Inc. The partnership was neither successful nor
harmonious-<ent type='PERSON'>George</ent> once knocked partner Ed Dubois unconscious to end a
disagreement over the direction the company would take-and in 1958, <ent type='PERSON'>George</ent>
bought out his partners.</p>

<p>However capable Wackenhut's detectives may have been at their work, <ent type='PERSON'>George</ent>
<ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> had two personal attributes that were instrumental in the
company's growth. First, he got along exceptionally well with important
politicians. He was a close ally of <ent type='GPE'>Florida</ent> governor <ent type='PERSON'>Claude Kirk</ent>, who hired
him to combat organized crime in the state; and was also friends with
Senator <ent type='PERSON'>George</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Smathers</ent>, an intimate of John F. Kennedy's. It was <ent type='PERSON'>Smathers</ent>
who provided <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> with his big break when the senator's law firm helped
the company find a loophole in the <ent type='NORP'>Pinkerton</ent> law, the 1893 federal statute
that had made it a crime for an employee of a private detective agency to do
work for the government. Smathers's firm set up a wholly owned subsidiary of
<ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> that provided only guards, not detectives. Shortly thereafter,
<ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> received multimillion-dollar contracts from the government to
guard Cape Canaveral and the <ent type='GPE'>Nevada</ent> nuclear-bomb test site, the first of
many extremely lucrative federal contracts that have sustained the company
to this day.</p>

<p>The second thing that helped make <ent type='PERSON'>George</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> successful was that he
was, and is, a hard-line right-winger. He was able to profit from his
beliefs by building up dossiers on <ent type='NORP'>American</ent>s suspected of being <ent type='NORP'>Communists</ent>
or merely left-leaning-"subversives and sympathizers," as he put it-and
selling the information to interested parties. According to <ent type='PERSON'>Frank Donner</ent>,
the author of "Age of Surveillance", the <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> Corporation maintained
and updated its files even after the <ent type='PERSON'>McCarthyite</ent> hysteria had ebbed, adding
the names of antiwar protesters and civil-rights demonstrators to its list
of "derogatory types." By 1965, <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> was boasting to potential
investors that the company maintained files on 2.5 million suspected
dissidents-one in 46 <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> adults then living. in 1966, after acquiring
the private files of <ent type='PERSON'>Karl Barslaag</ent>; a former staff member of the House
Committee on Un-<ent type='NORP'>American</ent> Activities, <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> could confidently maintain
that with more than 4 million names, it had the largest privately held file
on suspected dissidents in <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>. In 1975, after <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent> investigated
companies that had private files, <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> gave its files to the
now-defunct anti-<ent type='ORG'><ent type='NORP'>Communist</ent> Church <ent type='ORG'>League</ent></ent> of <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>Wheaton</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Illinois</ent>.
That organization had worked closely with the red squads of big-city police
departments, particularly in <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent> and L.A., spying on suspected
sympathizers; <ent type='PERSON'>George</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> was personal friends with the League's
leaders, and was a major contributor to the group. To be sure, after giving
the <ent type='ORG'>League</ent> its files, <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> reserved the right to use them for its
clients and friends.</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> had gone public in 1965 ; <ent type='PERSON'>George</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> retained 54 percent of
the company. Between his salary and dividends, his annual compensation
approaches $2 million a year, sufficient for him to live in a $20 million
castle in <ent type='ORG'>Coral Gables</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Florida</ent>, complete with a moat and 18 full-time
servants. Today the company is the third-largest investigative security firm
in the country, with offices throughout <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States and in 39 foreign
countries.</p>

<p>It is not possible to overstate the special relationship <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> enjoys
with the federal government. It is close. When it comes to security
matters, <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> in many respects *is* the government. In 1991, a third of
the company's $600-million in revenues came from the federal government,
and another large chunk from companies that themselves work for the
government, such as <ent type='ORG'>Westinghouse</ent>.</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> is the largest single company supplying security to U.S. embassies
overseas; several of the 13 embassies it guards have been in important
hotbeds of espionage, such as <ent type='GPE'>Chile</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Greece</ent> and El Salvador. It also guards
nearly all the most strategic government facilities in the U.S., including
the <ent type='NORP'>Alaskan</ent> oil pipeline, the <ent type='GPE'>Hanford</ent> nuclear-waste facility, the Savannah
River plutonium plant and <ent type='ORG'>the Strategic Petroleum Reserve</ent>.</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> maintains an especially close relationship with the federal
government in other ways as well. While early boards of directors included
such prominent personalities of the political right as Captain Eddie
Rickenbacker; General <ent type='PERSON'>Mark Clark</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Ralph</ent> E. <ent type='PERSON'>Davis</ent>, a <ent type='ORG'>John Birch Society</ent>
leader, current and recent members of the board have included much of the
country's recent national-security directorate: former <ent type='ORG'>FBI</ent> director Clarence
<ent type='PERSON'>Kelley</ent>; former <ent type='ORG'>Defense</ent> secretary and former <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> deputy director Frank
Carlucci: former <ent type='ORG'>Defense</ent> Intelligence Agent director General <ent type='PERSON'>Joseph Carroll</ent>;
former U.S. Secret Service director <ent type='PERSON'>James</ent> J. Rowley; former <ent type='NORP'>Marine</ent>
commandant P. X. <ent type='PERSON'>Kelley</ent>; and acting chairman of President Bush's foreign-intelligence advisory board and former <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> deputy director Admiral Bobby Ray
Inman. Before his appointment as Reagan's <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> director, the late <ent type='PERSON'>William</ent>
Casey was Wackenhut's outside legal counsel. The company has 30000 armed
employees on its payroll.</p>

<p>We wanted to know more about this special relationship; but the government
was not forthcoming. Repeated requests to <ent type='ORG'>the Department</ent> of Energy for an
explanation of how one company got the security contracts for <ent type='ORG'>neariy</ent> all of
America's most strategic installations have gone unanswered.</p>

<p>Similarly, efforts to get the State Department to explain whether embassy
contracts were awarded arbitrarily or through competitive bidding were
fruitless; essentially, the State Department said, "Some of both. "
Wackenhut's competitors-who, understandably, asked not to be quoted by
name-have their own version. "All those contracts;" said one security-firm
executive, "are just another way to pay <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> for their clandestine
help. And what is the nature of that help? "It is known throughout the
industry," said retired <ent type='ORG'>FBI</ent> special agent <ent type='PERSON'>William Hinshaw</ent>, "that if you want
a dirty job done, call <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent>." We met <ent type='PERSON'>George</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> in his swanky,
muy macho offices in <ent type='ORG'>Coral Gables</ent>. The rooms are paneled in a dark, rich
rosewood, accented with gray-blue stone. The main office is dominated by
Wackenhut's 12-foot-long desk and a pair of chairs shaped like elephants-
"<ent type='NORP'>Republican</ent> chairs," he calls them-complete with real tusks, which, the old
man says with some amusement, tend to stick his visitors. The highlight of
the usual collection of pictures and awards is the <ent type='NORP'>Republican</ent> presidential
exhibit: an autographed photo of <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> shaking hands with <ent type='PERSON'>George</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent>
(whom <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent>, according to a former associate, used to call "that pinko")
as well as framed photos of Presidents Reagan, <ent type='PERSON'>Nixon</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent>, each
accompanied by a handwritten note. The chairman looks every inch the
comfortable <ent type='GPE'>Florida</ent> septuagenarian. The day we spoke, his clothing ranged
across the color spectrum from baby blue to light baby blue, and he wore a
iot of jewelry-a huge gold watch on a thick gold band, two massive goid
rings. But <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> was, at 72, quick and tough in his responses. Near the
end of our two-and-a-half hour interview, when asked if his company was an
arm of the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>, he snapped, "No!"</p>

<p>Of course, this may just be a matter of semantics. We have spoken to
numerous experts, including current and former <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> agents and analysts,
current and former agents of the Drug Enforcement Administration and current
and former <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> executives and employees, all of whom have said that in
the mid-197O's, atter the Senate Intelligence Committee's revelations of the
CIA's covert and sometimes illegal overseas operations, the agency and
<ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> grew very, very close. Those revelations had forced the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> to do
a housecleaning, and it became <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> policy that certain kinds of activities
would no longer officially be performed. But that didn't always mean that
the need or the desire to undertake such operations disappeared. And that's
where <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> came in.</p>

<p>Our sources confirm that <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> has had a long-standing relationship
with the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>, and that it has deepened over the last decade or so. Bruce
<ent type='NORP'>Berckmans</ent>, who was assigned to the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> station in <ent type='GPE'>Mexico City</ent>, left the
agency in January 1975 (putatively) to become a <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent>
international-operations vice president. <ent type='NORP'>Berckmans</ent>, who left <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> in
1981, told <ent type='ORG'>SPY</ent> that he has seen a formal proposal <ent type='PERSON'>George</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> submitted
to the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> to allow the agency to use <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> offices throughout the world
as fronts for <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> activities. Kichard Babayan, who says he was a <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>
contract employee and is currently in jail awaiting trial on fraud and
racketeering charges, has been cooperating with federal and congressional
investigators looking into illegal shipments of nuclear-and-chemical-weapons-making supplies to <ent type='GPE'>Iraq</ent>. "<ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> has been
used by the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> and other intelligence agencies for years," he told <ent type='ORG'>SPY</ent>.
"When they [the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>] need cover, <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> is there to provide it for them."
Canadian prime minister <ent type='PERSON'>Pierre Trudeau</ent> was said to have rebuffed Wackenhut's
effort in the 1980's to purchase a weapons propellant manufacturer in <ent type='GPE'>Quebec</ent>
with the remark "We just got rid of the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>-we don't want them back."
<ent type='PERSON'>Phillip Agee</ent>, the left-wing former <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> agent who wrote an expose' of the
agency in 1975, told us, "I don't have the slightest doubt that the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> and
<ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> overlap."</p>

<p>There is also testimony from people who are not convicts, renegades or
Canadians. <ent type='PERSON'><ent type='PERSON'>William</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Corbett</ent></ent>, a terrorism expert who spent 18 years as a <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>
analyst and is now an <ent type='ORG'>ABC</ent> News consultant based in Europe, confirmed the
relationship between <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> and the agency. "For years <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> has been
involved with the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> and other intelligence organizations, including the
<ent type='ORG'>DEA</ent>," he told <ent type='ORG'>SPY</ent>. "<ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> would allow the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> to occupy positions within
the company [in order to carry out] clandestine operations." He also said
that <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> would supply intelligence agencies with information, and that
it was compensated for this- "in a quid pro quo arrangement," <ent type='ORG'>Corbett</ent>
says-with government contracts worth billions of dollars over the years.</p>

<p>We have uncovered considerable evidence that <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> carried the CIA's
water in fighting <ent type='NORP'>Communist</ent> encroachment in Central <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> in the 1980s
(that is to say, during the Reagan administration when the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> director was
former <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> lawyer <ent type='PERSON'>William</ent> Casey, the late superpatriot who had a
proclivity for extralegal and illegal anti-<ent type='NORP'>Communist</ent> covert operations such
as <ent type='GPE'>Iran</ent>-contra). In 1981, <ent type='NORP'>Berckmans</ent>, the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> agent turned <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> vice
president, joined with other senior <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> executives to form the
company's Special Projects Division. It was this division that linked up
with ex-<ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> man <ent type='PERSON'>John Phillip Nichols</ent>, who had taken over the <ent type='PERSON'>Cabazon</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Indian</ent>
reservation in <ent type='GPE'>California</ent>, as we described in a previous article
["Badlands," April 1992], in pursuit of a scheme to manufacture explosives,
poison gas and biological weapons-and then, by virtue of the tribe's status
as a sovereign nation, to export the weapons to the contras. This maneuver
was designed to evade congressional prohibitions against the U.S.
government's helping the contras. Indeed, in an interview with <ent type='ORG'>SPY</ent>, Eden
Pastora, the contras' famous Commander Zero, who had been spotted at a test
of some night-vision goggles at a firing range near the <ent type='PERSON'>Cabazon</ent> reservation
in the company of <ent type='PERSON'>Nichols</ent> and a <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> executive, offhandedly identified
that executive, A. <ent type='PERSON'>Robert Frye</ent>, as "the man from the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>. " (In a subsequent
conversation he denied knowing <ent type='PERSON'>Frye</ent> at all; of course, in that same talk he
quite unbelievably denied having ever been a contra.)</p>

<p>In addition to attempted weapons supply, <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> seems to have been
involved in Central <ent type='GPE'>America</ent> in other ways. <ent type='PERSON'>Ernesto Bermudez</ent> who was
Wackenhut's director of international operations from 1987 to '89, admitted
to <ent type='ORG'>SPY</ent> that during 1985 and '86 he ran Wackenhut's operations in El
Salvador, where he was in charge of 1500 men. When asked what 1 ,500 men
were doing for <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> in El Salvador, Bermudez replied coyly, "Things."
Pressed, he elaborated: "Things you wouldn't want your mother to know about."
It's worth noting that Wackenhut's annual revenues from government
contracts--the alleged reward for cooperation in the government's
clandestine activities-increased by 150 million, a 45 percent jump, while
Ronald Reagan was in office. "You've done an awful lot of research, <ent type='PERSON'>George</ent>
<ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> said to me as I was leaving. "How would you like to run all our
<ent type='GPE'>New York</ent> operations ? "</p>

<p>If that was the extent of Wackenhut's possible involvement in a government
agency's attempt to circumvent the law, then we might dismiss it as an
interesting footnote to the overheated, cowboy anti-<ent type='NORP'>Communist</ent> 1980s.
However, the U.S. Attorney for <ent type='LOC'>the Southern District</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>Florida</ent> has been
conducting an investigation into the illegal export of dual-use
technology-that is, seemingly innocuous technology that can also be used to
make nuclear weapons to <ent type='GPE'>Iraq</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Libya</ent>. And <ent type='ORG'>SPY</ent> has learned that
Wackenhut's name has come up in the federal investigation, but not at
present as a target.</p>

<p>Between 1987 and '89, three companies in <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States received
investments from an <ent type='GPE'>Iraq</ent>i architect named <ent type='PERSON'>Ihsan Barbouti</ent>. The colorful
<ent type='LOC'>Barbouti</ent> owned an engineering company in <ent type='GPE'>Frankfort</ent> that had a $552 million
contract to build airfields in <ent type='GPE'>Iraq</ent>. He also admitted having designed
Mu'ammar Qaddafi's infamous <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>-built chemical-weapons plant in <ent type='GPE'>Rabta</ent>,
<ent type='GPE'>Libya</ent>. According to an attorney for one of the companies in which <ent type='LOC'>Barbouti</ent>
invested, the architect owned $100 million worth of real estate and
oil-drilling equipment in <ent type='GPE'>Texas</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Oklahoma</ent>. He may also be dead, there
being reports that he died of heart failure in <ent type='ORG'>Hospital</ent> in <ent type='GPE'>London</ent> on July 1,
1990, his 63rd birthday. <ent type='LOC'>Barbouti</ent>, however, had faked his death once before,
in 1969, after the Ba'ath takeover in <ent type='GPE'>Iraq</ent> which brought <ent type='PERSON'>Saddam Hussein</ent> to
power as the second-in-command. That time, <ent type='LOC'>Barbouti</ent> escaped <ent type='GPE'>Iraq</ent>;
resurfacing several years later in <ent type='GPE'>Lebanon</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Libya</ent>. There are no reports
that he is living in <ent type='GPE'>Jordan</ent> -or, according to other reports, in a <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> safe
house in <ent type='GPE'>Florida</ent>. Those reports can be considered no better than rumor; what
follows, though, is fact.</p>

<p>As reported on ABC's "Nightline" last year, the three companies in which
<ent type='LOC'>Barbouti</ent> invested were TK-7 of <ent type='GPE'>Oklahoma City</ent>, which makes a fuel additive;
<ent type='ORG'>Pipeline Recovery Systems</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>Dallas</ent>, which makes an anti-corrosive chemical
that preserves pipes; and Product Ingredient Technoiogy of <ent type='GPE'>Boca Raton</ent>, which
makes food flavorings. None of these companies was looking to do business
with <ent type='GPE'>Iraq</ent>; <ent type='LOC'>Barbouti</ent> sought them out. Why was he interested? Because TK-7 had
formulas that could extend the range of jet aircraft and liquid-fueled
missiles such as the SCUD; because Pipeline Recovery knows how to coat pipes
to make them usable in nuclear reactors and chemical-weapons plants; and
because one of the by-products in making cherry flavoring is ferric
ferrocyanide, a chemical that's used to manufacture hydrogen cyanide, which
can penetrate gas masks and protective clothing. <ent type='ORG'>Hydrogen</ent> cyanide was used
by <ent type='PERSON'>Saddam Hussein</ent> against the <ent type='NORP'>Kurds</ent> in the <ent type='GPE'>Iran</ent>-<ent type='GPE'>Iraq</ent> war.</p>

<p><ent type='LOC'>Barbouti</ent> was more than a passive investor, and soon he began pressuring the
companies to ship not only their products but also their manufacturing
technology to corporations he owned in Europe, on which, he told the
businessmen, it would be sent to <ent type='GPE'>Libya</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Iraq</ent>. In doing so, <ent type='LOC'>Barbouti</ent> was
attempting to violate the law. First, the U.S. forbade sending anything to
<ent type='GPE'>Libya</ent>, which was embargoed as a terrorist nation. Second, the U.S. specified
that material of this sort must be sent to its final destination, not to an
intermediate locale, where the U.S. would risk losing control of its
distribution. According to former <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> contract employee Richard Babayan, in
late 1989 <ent type='LOC'>Barbouti</ent> met in <ent type='GPE'>London</ent> with <ent type='PERSON'>Ibrahim Sabawai</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Saddam Hussein</ent>'s half
brother and European head of <ent type='GPE'>Iraq</ent>i intelligence, who grew excited about the
work Pipeline Recovery was doing and called for the company's technology to
be rushed to <ent type='GPE'>Iraq</ent>, so that it could be in place by early 1990. And the owner
of TK-7 swears that <ent type='LOC'>Barbouti</ent> told him he was developing an atom device for
<ent type='PERSON'>Qaddafi</ent> that would be used against the U.S. in retaliation for the 1986 U.S.
air strike against <ent type='GPE'>Libya</ent>. <ent type='ORG'>Barbouri</ent> also wanted the ferrocyanide from Product
Ingredient.</p>

<p>Assisting <ent type='LOC'>Barbouti</ent> with these investments was <ent type='GPE'>New Orleans</ent> exporter Don
Seaton, business associate of <ent type='PERSON'>Richard Secord</ent>, the right-wing U.S. Army
general turned war profiteer who was so deeply enmeshed in the <ent type='GPE'>Iran</ent>-contra
affair. It was <ent type='PERSON'>Secord</ent> who connected <ent type='LOC'>Barbouti</ent> with <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent>. <ent type='LOC'>Barbouti</ent> met
with <ent type='PERSON'>Secord</ent> in <ent type='GPE'>Florida</ent> on several occasions, and phone records show that
several calls were placed from Barbouti's office to Secord's private number
in McLean, Virginia; <ent type='PERSON'>Secord</ent> has acknowledged knowing <ent type='LOC'>Barbouti</ent>. He is
currently a partner of <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent> businessman <ent type='PERSON'>James</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Tully</ent> (who is the man
who leaked <ent type='PERSON'>Bill Clinton</ent>'s draft-dodge letter to <ent type='ORG'>ABC</ent>) and <ent type='PERSON'>Jack Brennan</ent>, a
former <ent type='ORG'>Marine Corps</ent> colonel and longtime aide to Richard <ent type='PERSON'>Nixon</ent> both in the
<ent type='ORG'>White House</ent> and in exile. <ent type='PERSON'>Brennan</ent> has gone back to <ent type='ORG'>the White House</ent>, where he
works as a director of administrative operations in President Bush's office.
He refused to return repeated calls from <ent type='ORG'>SPY</ent>. Interestingly, <ent type='PERSON'>Brennan</ent> and
<ent type='PERSON'>Tully</ent> had previously been involved in a $181 million business deal to supply
uniforms to the <ent type='GPE'>Iraq</ent>i army. Oddly, they arranged to have the uniforms
manufactured in <ent type='PERSON'>Nicolae Ceaucescu</ent>'s <ent type='GPE'>Romania</ent>. The partners in that deal were
former U.S. attorney general and <ent type='EVENT'>Watergate</ent> felon <ent type='PERSON'>John Mitchell</ent> and Sarkis
Soghanalian, a <ent type='NORP'>Turkish</ent>-born <ent type='NORP'>Lebanese</ent> citizen. Soghanalian, who has been
credited with being <ent type='PERSON'>Saddam Hussein</ent>'s leading arms procurer and with
introducing the demonic weapons inventor <ent type='PERSON'>Gerald Bull</ent> to the <ent type='GPE'>Iraq</ent>is, is
currently serving a six-year sentence in federal prison in <ent type='GPE'>Miami</ent> for the
illegal sale of 103 military helicopters to <ent type='GPE'>Iraq</ent>. According to former
<ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> agent <ent type='PERSON'>David Ramirez</ent>, the company considered Soghanalian "a very
valuable client."</p>

<p>Unfortunately for <ent type='LOC'>Barbouti</ent>, none of the companies in which he made
investments was willing to ship its products or technology to his European
divisions. That, however, doesn't necessarily mean that he didn't get some
of what he wanted. In 1990, 2000 gallons of ferrocyanide were found to be
missing from the cherry-flavor factory in <ent type='GPE'>Boca Raton</ent>. Where it went is a
mystery; <ent type='PERSON'>Peter Kawaja</ent>, who was the head of security for all of Barbouti's
U.S. investments, told <ent type='ORG'>SPY</ent>, "We were never burglarized, but that stuff didn't
walk out by itself."</p>

<p>What does all this have to do with <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent>? Lots: According to Louis
<ent type='ORG'>Champon</ent>, the owner of Product Ingredient Technology, it was <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> that
guarded his <ent type='GPE'>Boca Raton</ent> plant, a fact confirmed by <ent type='PERSON'>Murray Levine</ent>, a <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent>
vice president. <ent type='ORG'>Champon</ent> also says, and <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> also confirms, that the
security for the plant consisted of one unarmed guard. While a <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent>
spokesperson maintains that this was the only job they were doing for
<ent type='LOC'>Barbouti</ent>, he also says that they were never paid, that <ent type='LOC'>Barbouti</ent> stiffed
them.</p>

<p>This does not seem true. <ent type='ORG'>SPY</ent> has obtained four checks from <ent type='LOC'>Barbouti</ent> to
<ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent>. All were written within ten days in 1990: one on March 27 for
$168.89; one on March 28 for $24828.07; another on April 5 for $756; the
last on April 6 for $40116.25. We asked <ent type='PERSON'>Richard Kneip</ent>, Wackenhut's senior
vice president for corporate planning, to explain why a single guard was
worth $66000 a year; Kneip was at a loss to do so. He was similarly at a
loss to explain a fifth check, from another <ent type='LOC'>Barbouti</ent> company to Wackenhut's
travel-service division in 1987, almost two years before <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> has
acknowledged providing security for the <ent type='GPE'>Boca Raton</ent> plant .</p>

<p>Two former <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> operatives, separately interviewed, have the explanation.
<ent type='PERSON'>Charles Hayes</ent>, who describes himself as "a <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> asset " says <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> was
helping <ent type='LOC'>Barbouti</ent> ship chemicals to <ent type='GPE'>Iraq</ent>, "Supplying <ent type='GPE'>Iraq</ent> was originally a
good idea," he maintains, "but then it got out of hand. <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> was just
in it for the money." Richard Babayan the former <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> contract employee,
confirmed Hayes's account. He says that Wackenhut's relationship with
<ent type='LOC'>Barbouti</ent> existed before the <ent type='GPE'>Boca Raton</ent> plant opened: "<ent type='LOC'>Barbouti</ent> was placed in
the hands of <ent type='PERSON'>Secord</ent> by the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>, and <ent type='PERSON'>Secord</ent> called in <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> to handle
security and travel and protection for <ent type='LOC'>Barbouti</ent> and his export plans."
<ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent>, Babayan says was working for the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> in helping <ent type='LOC'>Barbouti</ent> ship the
chemical-and-nuclear-weapons-making equipment first to <ent type='GPE'>Texas</ent>, then to
<ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>, and then to <ent type='GPE'>Baltimore</ent> to be shipped overseas. All of which makes
the story of the midnight convoy ride of <ent type='PERSON'>David Ramirez</ent>, recounted at the
beginning of this article rather less mysterious. <ent type='ORG'>SPY</ent> has learned that this
shipment is now the subject of a joint USDA-Customs investigation.</p>

<p>When we asked <ent type='PERSON'>George</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> what was being shipped from <ent type='ORG'>Eagle Pass</ent> to
<ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>, the sharp, straightforward chairman at first claimed they were
protecting an unnamed executive. He then directed an aide to get back to me.
Two days later, <ent type='PERSON'>Richard Kneip</ent> did, repeating the tale that had been passed
on to <ent type='PERSON'>David Ramirez</ent>-that the trucks contained food stamps. We told him that
we had spoken to a Department of Agriculture official, who informed us that
food stamps are shipped from <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> to outlying areas, never the other way
around, and that food stamps, unlike money, are used once and then
destroyed. All Kneip would say then was, "We do not reveal the names of our
clients."</p>

<p>Wackenhut's connection to the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> and to other government agencies raises
several troubling questions:</p>

<p>First, is the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> using <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> to conduct operations that it has been
forbidden to undertake? Second, is <ent type='ORG'>the White House</ent> or some other party in
the executive branch working through <ent type='ORG'>Wackenhut</ent> to conduct operations that it
doesn't want <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent> to know about? Third, has Wackenhut's cozy
relationship with the government given it a feeling of security-or worse, an
outright knowledge of sensitive or embarrassing information-that allows the
company to believe that it can conduct itself as though it were above the
law? A congressional investigation into Wackenhut's activities in the
<ent type='ORG'>Alyeska</ent> affair last November began to shed some light on Wackenhut's way of
doing business; clearly it's time for <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent> to investigate just how far
Wackenhut's other tentacles extend.</p>

<p>Additional reporting by <ent type='ORG'>Erzc Reguly</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Margie Sloan</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Wendell Smith</ent></p>

<p>** End of article **
</p></xml>