<xml><p>conditions "naively in terms of 'goodness' and 'badness' is to
ignore the constituent factors...."</p>

<p> FAKE PHOTOGRAPHS</p>

<p> Not only were situations such as those at <ent type='PERSON'>Belsen</ent>
unscrupulously exploited for propaganda purposes, but this
propaganda has also made use of entirely fake atrocity
photographs and films. The extreme conditions at <ent type='PERSON'>Belsen</ent> applied
to very few camps indeed; the great majority escaped the worst
difficulties and all their inmates survived in good health. As a
result, outright forgeries were used to exaggerate conditions of
horror. A startling case of such forgery was revealed in the
<ent type='NORP'>British</ent> Catholic Herald of October 29th, 1948. It reported that
in <ent type='PERSON'>Cassel</ent>, where every adult <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> was compelled to see a film
representing the "horrors" of <ent type='GPE'>Buchenwald</ent>, a doctor from
<ent type='ORG'>Goettingen</ent> saw himself on the screen looking after the victims.
But he had never been to <ent type='GPE'>Buchenwald</ent>. After an interval of
bewilderment he realized that what he had seen was part of a
film taken after the terrible air raid on <ent type='GPE'>Dresden</ent> by the <ent type='ORG'>Allies</ent>
on 13th February, 1945 where the doctor had been working. The
film in question was shown in <ent type='PERSON'>Cassel</ent> on 19th October, 1948.
After the air raid on <ent type='GPE'>Dresden</ent>, which killed 135000 people,
mostly refugee women and children, the bodies of the victims
were piled and burned in heaps of 400 and 500 for several weeks.
These were the scenes, purporting to be from <ent type='GPE'>Buchenwald</ent>, which
the doctor had recognized.
The forgery of war-time atrocity photographs is not new. For
further information the reader is referred to <ent type='PERSON'>Arthur Ponsonby</ent>'s
book Falsehood in Wartime (London, 1928), which exposes the
faked photographs of <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> atrocities in <ent type='EVENT'>the First World War</ent>.
Ponsonby cites such fabrications as "The Corpse Factory" and
"The Belgian Baby without Hands", which are strikingly
reminiscent of the propaganda relating to <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> "atrocities".
F.J.P. <ent type='PERSON'>Veale</ent> explains in his book that the bogus "jar of human
soap" solemnly introduced by the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> prosecution at <ent type='GPE'>Nuremberg</ent>
was a deliberate jibe at the famous <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> "Corpse factory"
myth, in which the ghoulish <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>s were supposed to have
obtained various commodities from processing corpses (<ent type='PERSON'>Veale</ent>,
ibid, p. 192). This accusation was one for which the <ent type='NORP'>British</ent>
Government apologized after 1918. It received new life after
1945 in the tale of lamp shades of human skin, which was
certainly as fraudulent as the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> "human soap". In fact,
from <ent type='ORG'>Manvell</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Frankl</ent> we have the grudging admission that the
lamp shade evidence at <ent type='GPE'>Buchenwald</ent> Trial "later appeared to be
dubious" (<ent type='ORG'>The Incomparable Crime</ent>, p. 84). It was given by a
certain <ent type='PERSON'>Andreas Pfaffenberger</ent> in a "written affidavit" of the
kind discussed earlier, but in 1948 General <ent type='PERSON'>Lucius Clay</ent> admitted
that the affidavits used in the trial appeared after more
through investigation to have been mostly 'hearsay'.
An excellent work on the fake atrocity photographs pertaining
to the Myth of <ent type='EVENT'>the Six Million</ent> is Dr. <ent type='PERSON'>Udo Walendy</ent>'s Bild
'Dokumente' fur die <ent type='ORG'>Geschichtsschreibung</ent> (Vlotho/Weser, 1973),
and from the numerous examples cited we illustrate one on this
page [in the original book this information comes from]. The
origin of the first photograph is unknown, but the second is a
photomontage. Close examination reveals immediately that the
standing figures have been taken from the first photograph, and
a heap of corpses super-imposed in front of them. The fence has
been removed, and an entirely new horror "photograph" created.
This blatant forgery appears on page 341 of r. Schnabel's book
on the S.S., Macht ohne Moral: eine <ent type='ORG'>Dokumentation uber</ent> die SS
(<ent type='GPE'>Frankfurt</ent>, 1957), with the caption "<ent type='PERSON'>Mauthausen</ent>". (Walendy cites
eighteen other examples of forgery in Schnabel's book.) The same
photograph appeared in the Proceedings of the International
Military Tribunal, Vol. XXX, p. 421, likewise purporting to
illustrate <ent type='PERSON'>Mauthausen</ent> camp. It is also illustrated without a
caption in <ent type='PERSON'>Eugene Aroneanu</ent>'s <ent type='PERSON'>Konzentrationlager Documant</ent> F. 321
for <ent type='ORG'>the International Court</ent> at <ent type='GPE'>Nuremberg</ent>; <ent type='PERSON'>Heinz Kuhnrich</ent>'s Der
KZ-<ent type='GPE'>Staat</ent> (<ent type='GPE'>Berlin</ent>, 1960, p. 81); <ent type='PERSON'>Vaclav Berdych</ent>'s <ent type='PERSON'>Mauthausen</ent>
(<ent type='GPE'>Prague</ent>, 1959); and <ent type='PERSON'>Robert Neumann</ent>'s <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent>--Aufsteig and
<ent type='ORG'>Untergang des Dritten Reiches</ent> (<ent type='GPE'>Munich</ent>, 1961).</p>

<p> 9. THE JEWS AND THE CONCENTRATION CAMPS: A FACTUAL APPRAISAL BY
THE RED CROSS</p>

<p> There is one survey of the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> question in Europe during
<ent type='EVENT'>World War Two</ent> and the conditions of <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y's concentration
camps which is almost unique in its honesty and objectivity, the
three-volume Report of <ent type='ORG'>the International Committee</ent> of the Red
Cross on its Activities during <ent type='EVENT'>the Second World War</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Geneva</ent>,
1948. This comprehensive account from an entirely neutral
source incorporated and expanded the findings of two previous
works: <ent type='ORG'>Documents sur</ent> l'activite' du <ent type='ORG'>CICR</ent> en <ent type='GPE'>faveur</ent> des civils
detenus dans <ent type='ORG'>les camps</ent> de concentration en <ent type='ORG'>Allemagne</ent> 1939-1945
(<ent type='GPE'>Geneva</ent>, 1946), and <ent type='ORG'>Inter Arma Caritas</ent>: the Work of the <ent type='ORG'>ICRC</ent>
during <ent type='EVENT'>the Second World War</ent> (<ent type='GPE'>Geneva</ent>, 1947). the team of authors,
headed by <ent type='PERSON'>Frederic Siordet</ent>, explained in the opening pages of
the Report that their object, in the tradition of <ent type='ORG'>the Red Cross</ent>,
has been strict political neutrality, and herein lies its great
value.
The <ent type='ORG'>ICRC</ent> successfully applied the 1929 <ent type='GPE'>Geneva</ent> military
convention in order to gain access to civilian internees held in
<ent type='LOC'>Central and Western</ent> Europe by the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> authorities. By
contrast, the <ent type='ORG'>ICRC</ent> was unable to gain any access to the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent>
Union, which had failed to ratify the Convention. The millions
of civilian and military internees held in the <ent type='GPE'>USSR</ent>, whose
conditions were known to be by far the worst, were completely
cut off from any international contact or supervision.
<ent type='ORG'>The Red Cross Report</ent> is of value in that it first clarifies
the legitimate circumstances under which <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> were detained in
concentration camps, i.e. as enemy aliens. In describing the two
categories of civilian internees, the Report distinguishes the
second type as "<ent type='NORP'>Civilians</ent> deported on administrative grounds (in
<ent type='NORP'>German</ent>, "<ent type='PERSON'>Schutzhaftline</ent>"), who were arrested for political or
racial motives because their presence was considered a danger to
the State or the occupation forces" (Vol. III, p. 73). These
persons, it continues, "were placed on the same footing as
persons arrested or imprisoned under common law for security
reasons" (p.74).
The Report admits that the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>s were at first reluctant to
permit supervision by <ent type='ORG'>the Red Cross</ent> of people detained on
grounds relating to security, but by the latter part of 1942,
the <ent type='ORG'>ICRC</ent> obtained important concessions from <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y. They were
permitted to distribute food parcels to major concentration
camps in <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y from August 1942, and "from February 1943
onwards this concession was extended to all other camps and
prisons" (Vol. III, p. 78). The <ent type='ORG'>ICRC</ent> soon established contact
with camp commandants and launched a food relief program which
continued to function until the last months of 1945, letters of
thanks for which came pouring in form <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> internees.</p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>RED CROSS RECIPIENTS</ent> WERE JEWS</p>

<p> The Report states that "As many as 9000 parcels were packed
daily. From the autumn of 1943 until May 1945, about 1112000
parcels with a total weight of 4500 tons were sent off to the
concentration camps" (Vol III, p. 80). In addition to food,
these contained clothing and pharmaceutical supplies. "Parcels
were sent to <ent type='LOC'>Dachau</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Buchenwald</ent>, Sangerhausen, Sachsenhausen,
<ent type='GPE'>Oranienburg</ent>, Flossenburg, Landsberg-am-Lech, Floha, <ent type='GPE'>Ravensbruck</ent>,
<ent type='GPE'>Hamburg</ent>-Neuengamme, <ent type='PERSON'>Mauthausen</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Theresienstadt</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Auschwitz</ent>,
Bergen-<ent type='PERSON'>Belsen</ent>, to camps near <ent type='GPE'>Vienna</ent> and in <ent type='LOC'>Central and</ent> Southern
<ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y. The principal recipients were <ent type='NORP'>Belgians</ent>, <ent type='NORP'>Dutch</ent>, <ent type='NORP'>French</ent>,
<ent type='NORP'>Greeks</ent>, <ent type='NORP'>Italians</ent>, <ent type='NORP'>Norwegians</ent>, <ent type='NORP'>Poles</ent> and stateless <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>" (Vol.
III, p. 83). In the course of the war, "The <ent type='ORG'>Committee</ent> was in a
position to transfer and distribute in the from of relief
supplies over twenty million <ent type='NORP'>Swiss</ent> francs collected by <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent>
welfare organization throughout the world, in particular by the
<ent type='NORP'>American</ent> Joint Distribution <ent type='ORG'>Committee</ent> of New York" (Vol. I, p.
644). This latter organization was permitted by the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>
Government to maintain offices in <ent type='GPE'>Berlin</ent> until the <ent type='NORP'>American</ent>
entry into the war. The <ent type='ORG'>ICRC</ent> complained that obstruction of
their vast relief operations for <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> internees came not from
the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>s but from the tight <ent type='ORG'>Allied</ent> blockade of Europe. Most
of their purchases of relief food were made in <ent type='GPE'>Rumania</ent>, Hungary
and <ent type='GPE'>Slovakia</ent>.
The <ent type='ORG'>ICRC</ent> had special praise for the liberal conditions which
prevailed at <ent type='ORG'>Theresienstadt</ent> up to the time of their last visits
there in April 1945. This camp, "where there were about 40000
<ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> deported from various countries was a relatively privileged
ghetto" (Vol III, p. 75). According to the Report, "The
Committee's delegates were able to visit the camp at
<ent type='ORG'>Theresienstadt</ent> (Terezin) which was used exclusively for <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> and
was governed by special conditions. From information gathered
by the <ent type='ORG'>Committee</ent>, this camp had been started as an experiment by
certain leaders of the <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent> . . . These men wished to give the
<ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> the means of setting up a communal life in a town under
their own administration and possessing almost complete autonomy
. . . two delegates were able to visit the camp on April 6th,
1945. They confirmed the favorable impression gained ton the
first visit" (Vol. I, p. 642).
The <ent type='ORG'>ICRC</ent> also had praise for the regime of <ent type='PERSON'>Ion Antonescu</ent> of
<ent type='NORP'>Fascist</ent> <ent type='GPE'>Rumania</ent> where the <ent type='ORG'>Committee</ent> was able to extend special
relief to 183000 <ent type='GPE'>Rumania</ent>n <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> until time of the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent>
occupation. The aid then ceased, and the <ent type='ORG'>ICRC</ent> complained
bitterly that it never succeeded "in sending anything whatsoever
to <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>" (Vol. II, p. 62). The same situation applied to many
of the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> camps after their "liberation" by the <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>ns.
The <ent type='ORG'>ICRC</ent> received a voluminous flow of mail from <ent type='GPE'>Auschwitz</ent> until
the period of the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> occupation, when many of the internees
were evacuated westward. But the efforts of send relief to
internees remaining at <ent type='GPE'>Auschwitz</ent> under <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> control were
futile. However, food parcels continued to be sent to former
<ent type='GPE'>Auschwitz</ent> inmates transferred west to such camps as <ent type='GPE'>Buchenwald</ent>
and <ent type='GPE'>Oranienburg</ent>.</p>

<p> NO EVIDENCE OF GENOCIDE</p>

<p> One of the most important aspects of <ent type='ORG'>the Red Cross</ent> Report is
that it clarifies the true cause of those deaths that
undoubtedly occurred in the camps toward the end of the war.
Says the Report: "In the chaotic condition of <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y after the
invasion during final months of the war, the camps received no
food supplies at all and starvation claimed an increasing number
of victims. Itself alarmed by this situation, the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>
Government at last informed the <ent type='ORG'>ICRC</ent> on February 1st, 1945. . .
In March 1945, discussions between the President of the <ent type='ORG'>ICRC</ent> and
General of the S.S. Kaltenbrunner gave even more decisive
results. Relief could henceforth be distributed by the <ent type='ORG'>ICRC</ent>, and
one delegate was authorized to stay in each camp . . ." (Vol
III, p. 83). Clearly, the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> authorities were at pains to
relieve the dire situation as far as they were able. The Red
Cross are quite explicit in stating that food supplies ceased at
this time due to the <ent type='ORG'>Allied</ent> bombing of <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> transportation,
and in the interests of interned <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> they had protested on
March 15th, 1944 against "the barbarous aerial warfare of the
<ent type='ORG'>Allies</ent>" (<ent type='ORG'>Inter Arma Caritas</ent>, p. 78). By October 2nd, 1944, the
<ent type='ORG'>ICRC</ent> warned the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> Foreign Office of the impending collapse
of the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> transportation system, declaring that starvation
conditions for people throughout <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y were becoming
inevitable.
In dealing with this comprehensive, three-volume Report, it
is important to stress that the delegates of the International
Red Cross found no evidence whatever at the camps in <ent type='ORG'>Axis</ent>-occupied Europe of a deliberate policy to exterminate the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>.
In all its 1600 pages the Report does not even mention such a
thing as a gas chamber. It admits that <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, like many other
wartime nationalities, suffered rigors and privations, but its
complete silence on the subject of planned extermination is
ample refutation of <ent type='EVENT'>the Six Million</ent> legend. Like the Vatican
representatives with whom they worked, <ent type='ORG'>the Red Cross</ent> found
itself unable to indulge in the irresponsible charges of
genocide which had become the order of the day.
So far as the genuine mortality rate is concerned, the Report
points out that most of the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> doctors from the camps were
being used to combat typhus on the eastern front, so that they
were unavailable when the typhus epidemics of 1945 broke out in
the camps (Vol. I, p. 204 ff). Incidentally, it is frequently
claimed that mass executions were carried out in gas chambers
cunningly disguised as shower facilities. Again the Report makes
nonsense of this allegation. "Not only the washing places, but
installations for baths, showers and laundry were inspected by
the delegates. They had often to take action to have fixtures
made less primitive, and to get them repaired and enlarged"
(Vol. III, p. 594).</p>

<p> NOT ALL WERE INTERNED</p>

<p> Volume III of <ent type='ORG'>the Red Cross</ent> Report, Chapter 3 (I. <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent>
Civilian Population) deals with the "aid given to the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent>
section of the free population," and this chapter makes it quite
plain that by no means all of the European <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> were placed in
internment camps, but remained, subject to certain restrictions,
as part of the free civilian population. This conflicts directly
with the "thoroughness" of the supposed "extermination program",
and with the claim of the forged <ent type='ORG'>Hoess</ent> memoirs that <ent type='PERSON'>Eichmann</ent> was
obsessed with seizing "every single <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent> he could lay his hands
on." In <ent type='GPE'>Slovakia</ent>, for example, where Eichmann's assistant Dieter
<ent type='ORG'>Wisliceny</ent> was in charge, the Report states that "A large
proportion of the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> minority had permission to stay in the
country, and at certain periods <ent type='GPE'>Slovakia</ent> was looked upon as a
compassionate haven of refugee for <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, especially for those
coming from <ent type='GPE'>Poland</ent>. Those who remained in <ent type='GPE'>Slovakia</ent> seem to have
been in comparative safety until the end of August 1944, when a
rising against the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> forces took place. While it is true
the law of May 15th, 1947 had brought about the internment of
several thousand <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, these people were held in camps where
the conditions of food and lodging were tolerable, and where the
internees were allowed to do paid work on terms almost equal to
those of the free labor market" (Vol. I, p. 646).
Not only did large numbers of the three million or so
European <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> avoid internment altogether, but the emigration of
<ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> continued throughout the war, generally by way of Hungary,
<ent type='GPE'>Rumania</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Turkey</ent>. Ironically, post-war <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> emigration from
<ent type='NORP'>German</ent>-occupied territories was also facilitated by the <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent>,
as in the case of the <ent type='NORP'>Polish</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> who had escaped to <ent type='GPE'>France</ent>
before its occupation. "The <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> from <ent type='GPE'>Poland</ent> who, while in
<ent type='GPE'>France</ent>, had obtained entrance permits to <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States were
held to be <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> citizens by the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>s occupying
authorities, who further agreed to recognize the validity of
about three thousand passports issued of <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> by the consulates
of South <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> countries (Vol. I, p. 645). As further U.S.
citizens, these <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> were held at the <ent type='ORG'>Vittel</ent> camp in southern
<ent type='GPE'>France</ent> for <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> aliens.
The emigration of European <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> from Hungary in particular
proceeded during the war unhindered by the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> authorities.
"Until March 1944," says <ent type='ORG'>the Red Cross</ent> Report, "<ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> who had the
privilege of visas for <ent type='GPE'>Palestine</ent> were free to leave Hungary"
(Vol. I, p. 648). Even after the replacement of the Horthy
Government in 1944 (following its attempted armistice with the
<ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> Union) with a government more dependent on <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>
authority, the emigration of <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> continued. The <ent type='ORG'>Committee</ent>
secured the pledges of both <ent type='GPE'>Britain</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States "to
give support by every means to the emigration of <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> from
Hungary," and from the U.S. Government the <ent type='ORG'>ICRC</ent> received a
message stating that "<ent type='ORG'>The Government</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States...now
specifically repeats its assurance that arrangements will be
made by it for the care of all <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> who in the present
circumstances are allowed to leave" (Vol. I, p. 649).</p>

<p> 10. THE TRUTH AT LAST: THE WORK OF <ent type='ORG'>PAUL</ent> RASSINIER</p>

<p> Without doubt the most important contribution to a truthful
study of the extermination question has been the work of the
<ent type='NORP'>French</ent> historian, Professor <ent type='PERSON'>Paul Rassinier</ent>. The pre-eminent
value of his work lies firstly in the fact that <ent type='PERSON'>Rassinier</ent>
actually experienced life in the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> concentration camps, and
also that, as a Socialist intellectual and anti-<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>, nobody
could be less inclined to defend <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> and National Socialism.
Yet, for the sake of justice and historical truth, <ent type='PERSON'>Rassinier</ent>
spent the remainder of his post-war years until his death in
1966 pursuing research which utterly refuted the Myth of the Six
Million and the legend of <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> diabolism.
From 1933 until 1943, <ent type='PERSON'>Rassinier</ent> was a professor of history in
the College d'enseignment general at <ent type='ORG'>Belfort</ent>, Academie de
Besancon. During the war he engaged in resistance activity until
he was arrested by the <ent type='ORG'>Gestapo</ent> on October 30th, 1943, and as a
result was confined in the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> concentration camps at
<ent type='GPE'>Buchenwald</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Dora</ent> until 1945. At <ent type='GPE'>Buchenwald</ent>, towards the end
of the war, he contracted typhus, which so damaged his health
that he could not resume his teaching. After the war, <ent type='PERSON'>Rassinier</ent>
was awarded the Medaille de la Resistance and the Reconnaisance
Francaise, and was elected to the <ent type='NORP'>French</ent> Chamber of Deputies,
from which he was ousted by the <ent type='NORP'>Communists</ent> in November, 1946.
<ent type='PERSON'>Rassinier</ent> then embarked on his great work, a systematic
analysis of alleged <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> war atrocities, in particular the
supposed "extermination" of the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>. Not surprisingly, his
writings are little know; they have rarely been translated from
the <ent type='NORP'>French</ent> and none at all have appeared in English. His most
important works were: Le Mensonge d'<ent type='PERSON'>Ulysse</ent> (The Lies of
Odysseus, <ent type='GPE'>Paris</ent>, 1949), an investigation of concentration camp
conditions based on his own experiences of them; and <ent type='PERSON'>Ulysse</ent>
trahi par les <ent type='NORP'>Siens</ent> (1960), a sequel which further refuted the
impostures of propagandists concerning <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> concentration
camps. His monumental task was completed with two final volumes,
Le Veritable Proces <ent type='PERSON'>Eichmann</ent> (1962) and Le Drame des Juifs
europeen (1964), in which <ent type='PERSON'>Rassinier</ent> exposed the dishonest and
reckless distortions concerning the fate of the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> by a
careful statistical analysis. The last work also examines the
political and financial significance of the extermination legend
and its exploitation by <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent> and the <ent type='NORP'>Communist</ent> powers.
One of the many merits of Rassinier's work is exploding the
myth of unique <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> "wickedness"; and he reveals with
devastating force how historical truth has been obliterated in
an impenetrable fog of partisan propaganda. His researches
demonstrate conclusively that the fate of the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> during World
War Two, once freed from distortion and reduced to proper
proportions, loses its much vaunted "enormity" and is seen to be
only one act in a greater and much wider tragedy. In an
extensive lecture tour in West <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y in <ent type='GPE'>ghe spring</ent> of 1960,
Professor <ent type='PERSON'>Rassinier</ent> emphasised to his <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> audiences that is
was high time for a rebirth of the truth regarding the
extermination legend, and theat the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>s themselves should
begin it since the allegation remained a wholly unjustifiable
blot on <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y in the eyes of the world.</p>

<p> THE IMPOSTURE OF 'GAS CHAMBERS'</p>

<p> <ent type='PERSON'>Rassinier</ent> entitled his first book The Lies of Odysseus in
commemoration of the fact that travellers always return bearing
tall stories, and until his death he investigated all the
stories of extermination literature and attempted to trace their
authors. He made short work of the extravagant claims about gas
chambers at <ent type='GPE'>Buchenwald</ent> in <ent type='PERSON'>David Rousset</ent>'s The Other Kingdom (New
York, 1947); himself an inmate of <ent type='GPE'>Buchenwald</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Rassinier</ent> proved
that no such things ever existed there (Le Mensonge d'<ent type='PERSON'>Ulysse</ent>, p.
209 ff). <ent type='PERSON'>Rassinier</ent> also traced Abbe Jean-Paul Renard, and asked
him how he could possibly have testified in his book Chaines et
Lumieres that gas chambers were in operation at <ent type='GPE'>Buchenwald</ent>.
Renard replied that others had told him of their existence, and
hence he had been willing to pose as a witness of things that he
had never seen (ibid, p. 209 ff).
<ent type='PERSON'>Rassinier</ent> also investigated <ent type='PERSON'>Denise Dufournier</ent>'s <ent type='GPE'>Ravensbruck</ent>:
<ent type='ORG'>The Women</ent>'s Camp of Death (London, 1948) and again found that
the authoress had no other evidence for gas chambers there thatn
the vague "rumours" which <ent type='PERSON'>Charlotte Bormann</ent> stated were
deliberately spread by <ent type='NORP'>communist</ent> political prisoners. Similar
investigations were made of such books as <ent type='ORG'>Philip Friedman</ent>'s This
was <ent type='GPE'>Auschwitz</ent>: The Story of a Murder Camp (N.Y., 1946) and Eugen
Kogon's <ent type='ORG'>The Theory and Practice</ent> of Hell (N.Y., 1950), and he
found that none of these authors could produce and authentic
eye-witness of a gas chamber at <ent type='GPE'>Auschwitz</ent>, nor had they
themselves actually seen one. <ent type='PERSON'>Rassinier</ent> mentions Kogon's claim
that a deceased former inmate, <ent type='PERSON'>Janda Weiss</ent>, had said to <ent type='ORG'>Kogon</ent>
alone that she had witnessed gas chambers at <ent type='GPE'>Auschwitz</ent>, but of
couse, since this person was apparently dead, <ent type='PERSON'>Rassinier</ent> was
unable to investigate the claim. He was able to interview
Benedikt <ent type='PERSON'>Kautsky</ent>, author of <ent type='PERSON'>Teufel und Verdammte</ent> who had alleged
that millions of <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> were exterminated at <ent type='GPE'>Auschwitz</ent>. However,
<ent type='PERSON'>Kautsky</ent> only confirmed to <ent type='PERSON'>Rassinier</ent> the confession in his book,
namely that never at any time had he seen a gas chamber, and
that he based his information on what others had "told him".
The palm for extermination literature is awarded by
<ent type='PERSON'>Rassinier</ent> to <ent type='PERSON'>Miklos Nyizli</ent>'s Doctor at <ent type='GPE'>Auschwitz</ent>, in which the
falsification of facts, the evident contradictions and shameless
lies show that the author is speaking of places which it is
obvious he has never seen (Le Drame des Juifs europeen, p. 52).
According to this "doctor of <ent type='GPE'>Auschwitz</ent>", 25000 victims were
exterminated every day for four and a half years, which is a
grandiose advance on <ent type='PERSON'>Olga Lengyel</ent>'s 24000 a day for two and a
half years. It would mean a total of forty-one million victims
at <ent type='GPE'>Auschwitz</ent> by 1945, two and a half times the total pre-war
<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> population of the world. When <ent type='PERSON'>Rassinier</ent> attempted to
discover the identity of this strange "witness", he was told
that "he had died some time before the publication of the book."
<ent type='PERSON'>Rassinier</ent> is convinced that he was never anything but a mythical
figure.
Since the war, <ent type='PERSON'>Rassinier</ent> has, in fact, toured Europe in
search of somebody who was an actual eye-witness of gas chamber
exterminations in <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> concentration camps during World War
Two, but he has never found even one such person. He discovered
that not one of the authors of the many books charging that the
<ent type='NORP'>German</ent>s had exterminated millions of <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> had even seen a gas
chamber built for such purposes, much less seen one in
operation, nor could any of these authors produce a living
authentic witness who had done so. Invariably, former prisoners
such as Renard, <ent type='PERSON'>Kautsky</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>Kogon</ent> based their statements not
upon what they had actually seen, but upon what they "heard",
always from "reliable" sources, who by some chance are almost
always dead and thus not in a position to confirm or deny their
statements.
Certainly the most important fact to emerge from Rassinier's
studies, and of which there is now no doubt at all, is the utter
imposture of "gas chamber". Serious investigations carried out
in the sites themselves have revealed with irrefutable proof
that, contrary to the declarations of the surviving "witnesses"
examined above, no gas chambers whatever existed in the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>
camps at <ent type='GPE'>Buchenwald</ent>, Bergen-<ent type='PERSON'>Belsen</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Ravensbruck</ent>, <ent type='LOC'>Dachau</ent> and
<ent type='PERSON'>Dora</ent>, or <ent type='PERSON'>Mauthausen</ent> in <ent type='GPE'>Austria</ent>. This fact, which wer noted
earlier was attested to by <ent type='PERSON'>Stephen Pinter</ent> of the U.S. War
Office, has now been recognised and admitted officially by the
Institute of Contemporary History at <ent type='GPE'>Munich</ent>. However, <ent type='PERSON'>Rassinier</ent>
points out that in spite of this, "witnesses" again declared at
the <ent type='PERSON'>Eichmann</ent> trail that they had seen prisoners at Bergen-<ent type='PERSON'>Belsen</ent>
setting out for the gas chambers. So far as the eastern camps of
<ent type='GPE'>Poland</ent> are concerned. <ent type='PERSON'>Rassinier</ent> shows that the sole evidence
attesting to the existence of gas chambers at Treblinka,
<ent type='GPE'>Chelmno</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Belze</ent>c, <ent type='ORG'>Maidanek</ent> and Sobibor are the discredited
memoranda of <ent type='PERSON'>Kurt Gerstein</ent> referred to above. His original
claim, it will be recalled was that an absurd 40 million people
had been exterminated during the war, while in his first signed
memorandum he reduced the number to 25 million. Further
reductions were made in his second memorandum. These documents
were considered of such dubious authenticity that they were not
even admitted by the <ent type='GPE'>Nuremberg</ent> Court, though they continue to
circulate in three different versions, one in <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>
(distributed in schools) and two in <ent type='ORG'>Frenc</ent>, none of which agee
with each other. The <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> version featured as "evidence" at
the <ent type='PERSON'>Eichmann</ent> Trial in 196l.
Finally, Professor <ent type='PERSON'>Rassinier</ent> draws attention to an important
admission by Dr. <ent type='PERSON'>Kubovy</ent>, director of <ent type='ORG'>the World Centre</ent> of
Contemporary <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> Documentation at Tel-Aviv, made in La Terre
Retrouvee, December 15th, 1960. Dr. <ent type='PERSON'>Kubovy</ent> recognised that not a
single order for extermination exists from <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Himmler</ent>,
<ent type='PERSON'>Heydrich</ent> or <ent type='PERSON'>Goering</ent> (Le Drame des Juifs europeen, p. 31, 39).</p>

<p> 'SIX MILLION' FALSEHOOD REJECTED</p>

<p> As for the fearful propaganda figure of <ent type='EVENT'>the Six Million</ent>,
Professor <ent type='PERSON'>Rassinier</ent> rejects it on the basis of an extremely
detailed statistical analysis. He shows that the number has been
falsely established, on the one had through inflation of the
pre-war <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> population by ignoring all emigration and
evacuation, and on the other by a corresponding deflation of the
number of survivors after 1945. This was the method used by the
World <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> Congress. <ent type='PERSON'>Rassinier</ent> also rejects any written or
oral testimony to <ent type='EVENT'>the Six Million</ent> given by the kind of
"witnesses" cited above, since they are full of contradictions,
exaggerations and falsehoods. He gives the example of <ent type='LOC'>Dachau</ent>
casualties, noting that in 1946, <ent type='PERSON'>Pastor Niemoller</ent> reiterated
Auerbach's Fraudulent "238000" deaths there, while in 1962
Bishop <ent type='PERSON'>Neuhausseler</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>Munich</ent> stated in a speech at <ent type='LOC'>Dachau</ent> that
only 30000 people died "of the 200000 perons from thirty-eight
nations who were interned there" (Le Drame des Juifs europeen,
p. 12). Today, the estimate has been reduced by several more
thousands, and so it goes on. <ent type='PERSON'>Rassinier</ent> concludes, too, that
testimony in support of <ent type='EVENT'>the Six Million</ent> given by accused men
such as <ent type='ORG'>Hoess</ent>, Hoettl, <ent type='ORG'>Wisliceny</ent> and <ent type='NORP'>Hoellriegel</ent>, who were faced
with the prospect of being condemned to death or with the hope
of obtaining a reprieve, and who were frequently tortured during
their detention, is completely untrustworthy.
<ent type='PERSON'>Rassinier</ent> finds it very significant that the figure of Six
Million was not mentioned in court during the <ent type='PERSON'>Eichmann</ent> trial.
"The prosecution at the <ent type='GPE'>Jerusalem</ent> trail was considerably
weakened by its central motif, the six million European <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>
alleged to have been exterminated in gas chambers. It was an
argument that easily won conviction the day after the war ended,
amidst the general state of spiritual and material chaos. Today,
may documents have been published which were not available at
the time of the <ent type='GPE'>Nuremberg</ent> trials, and which tend to prove that
if the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> nationals were wronged and persecuted by the
<ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> regime, there could not possibly have been six million
victims" (ibid, p. 125).
With the help of one hundred pages of cross-checked
statistics, Professor <ent type='PERSON'>Rassinier</ent> concludes in Le Drame des Juifs
europeen that the number of <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> casualties during the Second
World War could not have exceeded 1200000, and he notes that
this has finally been accepted as valid by <ent type='ORG'>the World Centre</ent> of
Contemporary <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> Documentation at <ent type='GPE'>Paris</ent>. However, he regards
such a figure as a maximum limit, and refers to the lower
estimate of 896892 casualties in a study of the same problem by
the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> statisticial <ent type='PERSON'>Raul Hilberg</ent>. <ent type='PERSON'>Rassinier</ent> points out that
the State of <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent> nevertheless continues to claim compensation
for six million dead, each one representing an indemnity of
5000 marks.</p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>EMIGRATION</ent>: THE FINAL SOLUTION</p>

<p> Prof. <ent type='PERSON'>Rassinier</ent> is emphatic in stating that the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>
Government never had any plicy other thatn the emigration of
<ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> overseas. He shows that after the promulgation of the
<ent type='GPE'>Nuremberg</ent> Race Laws in September 1935, the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>s negotiated
with the <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> for the transfer of <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> to <ent type='GPE'>Palestine</ent> on
the basis of the Balfour Declaration. When this failed, they
asked other countries to take charge of them, but these refused
(ibid, p. 20). The <ent type='GPE'>Palestine</ent> project was revived in 1938, but
broke down because <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y could not negotiate their departure
on the basis of 3000000 marks, as demanded by <ent type='GPE'>Britain</ent>, without
some agreement for compensation. Despite these difficulties,
<ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y did manage to secure the emigration of the majority of
their <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, mostly to <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States. <ent type='PERSON'>Rassinier</ent> also refers
to the <ent type='NORP'>French</ent> refusal of <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y's <ent type='GPE'>Madagascar</ent> plan at the end of
1940. "In a report of the 21st August, 1942, the Secretary of
State for <ent type='ORG'>the Ministry</ent> of Foreign Affairs of the Third <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent>,
Luther, decided that it would be possible to negotiate with
<ent type='GPE'>France</ent> in this direction and described conversations which has
taken place between July and December 1940, and which were
brought to a halt following the interview with <ent type='PERSON'>Montoire</ent> on 13th
December 1940 by Pierre-Etienne Flandin, Laval's successor.
During the whole of 1941 the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>s hoped that they would be
able to re-open these negotiations and bring them to a happy
conclustion" (ibid, p. 108).
After the outbreak of war, the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, who, as <ent type='PERSON'>Rassinier</ent>
reminds us, had declared economic and financial was on <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y
as early as 1933, were interned in concentration camps, "which
is the way countries all over the world treat enemy aliens in
time of war . . . It was decided to regroup them and put them to
work in one immense ghetto which, after the successful invasion
of <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>, was situated toward the end of 194l in the so-called
<ent type='NORP'>Eastern</ent> territories near the former frontier between <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent> and
<ent type='GPE'>Poland</ent>: at <ent type='GPE'>Auschwitz</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Chelmno</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Belze</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Maidanek</ent>, Treblinka etc...
There they were to wait until end of the war for the reopening
of international discussions which would decide their future"
(Le Veritable Proces <ent type='PERSON'>Eichmann</ent>, p. 20). The order for this
concentration in the eastern ghetto was given by <ent type='PERSON'>Goering</ent> to
<ent type='PERSON'>Heydrich</ent>, as noted earlier, and it was regarded as a prelude to
"the desired final solution," their emigration overseas after
the war had ended.</p>

<p> ENORMOUS FRAUD</p>

<p> Of great concern to Professor <ent type='PERSON'>Rassinier</ent> is the way in which
the extermination legend is deliberately exploited for political
and financial advantage, and in this he finds <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent> and the
<ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> Union to be in concert. He notes how, after 1950, an
avalanche of fabricated extermination literature appeared under
the stamp of two organisations, so remarkably synchronised in
their activities that one might well believe them to have been
contrived in partnership. One was the "<ent type='ORG'>Committee</ent> for the
Investigation of War Crimes and Criminals" established under
<ent type='NORP'>Communist</ent> auspices at <ent type='GPE'>Warsaw</ent>, and the other, the "<ent type='ORG'>World Centre</ent>
of Contemporary <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> Documentation" at <ent type='GPE'>Paris</ent> and Tel-Aviv.
Their publications seem to appear at favourable moments in the
political climate, and for the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> Union their purpose is
simply to maintain the threat of <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>sm as a manoeuvre to divert
attention from their own activities.
As for <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Rassinier</ent> sees the myth of <ent type='EVENT'>the Six Million</ent> as
inspired by a purely material problem. In Le Drame des Juifs
europeen (P. 31, 39). he writes:
"... It is simply a question of justifying by a
proportionate number of corpses the enormous subsidies which
<ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y has been paying annually since the end of the war to the
State of <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent> by way of reparation for injuries which moreover
she cannot be held to have caused her either morally or legally,
since there was no State of <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent> at the time the alleged deeds
took place; thus it is a purely and contemptibly material
problem.
"Perhaps I may be allowed to recall here that the State of
<ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent> was only founded in May 1948 and that the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> were
nationals of all states with the exception of <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent>, in order
to underline the dimenstions of a fraud which defies description
in any language; on the one hand <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y pays to <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent> sums
which are calculated on six million dead, and on the other,
since at least four-fifths of these six million were decidedly
alive at the end of the war, she is paying substantial sums by
way of reparation to the victims of Hitler's <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y to those
who are still alive in countries all over the world other than
<ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent> and to the rightful claimants of those who have since
deceased, which means that for the former (i.e. the six
million), or in other words, for the vast majority, she is
paying twice."</p>

<p> CONCLUSION</p>

<p> Here we may briefly summarise the data on <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> wartime
casualties.
<ent type='ORG'>Contrary</ent> to the figure of over 9 million <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> in <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>-occupied territory put forward at the <ent type='GPE'>Nuremberg</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Eichmann</ent>
trials, it has already been established that after extensive
emigration, approximately 3 million were living in Europe,
excluding the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> Union. Even when the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> of <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>-occupied <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent> are included (the majority of <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>n <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> were
evacuated beyond <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> control), the overall number probably
does not exceed four million. Himmler's statistician, Dr.
<ent type='PERSON'>Richard Korherr</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>the World Centre</ent> of Contemporary <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent>
Documentation put the number respectively at 5550000 and
5294000 when <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>-occupied territory was at its widest, but
both these figures include the two million <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> of the <ent type='LOC'>Baltic</ent>
and western <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent> without paying any attention to the large
number of these who were evacuated. However, it is at least an
admission from the latter organisation that there were not even
six million <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> in Europe and western <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent> combined.
Nothing better illustrates the declining plausibility of
<ent type='EVENT'>the Six Million</ent> legend than the fact that the prosecution at the
<ent type='PERSON'>Eichmann</ent> trial deliberately avoided mentioning the figure.
Moreover, official <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> estimates of the casualties are being
quietly revised downwards. Our analysis of the population and
emigration statistics, as well as the studies by the <ent type='NORP'>Swiss</ent>
Baseler Nachrichten and Professor <ent type='PERSON'>Rassinier</ent>, demonstrate that it
would have been simply impossible for the number of <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent>
casualties to have exceeded a limit of one and a half million.
It is very significant, therefore, that <ent type='ORG'>the World Centre</ent> of
Contemporary <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> Documentation in <ent type='GPE'>Paris</ent> now states that only
1485292 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> died from all causes during <ent type='EVENT'>the Second World War</ent>,
and although this figure is certainly too high, at least it
bears no resemblance at all to the legendary Six Million. As has
been noted earlier, the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> statistician <ent type='PERSON'>Raul Hilberg</ent>
estimates an even lower figure of 896892. <ent type='ORG'>Thuis</ent> is beginning to
approach a realistic figure, and the process of revision is
certain to continue.
Doubtless, several thousand <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> persons did die in the
course of <ent type='EVENT'>the Second World War</ent>, but this must be seen in the
context of a war that cost many millions of innocent victims on
all sides. To put the matter in perspective, for example, we may
point out that 700000 <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>n civilians died during the siege
of <ent type='GPE'>Leningrad</ent>, and a total of 2050000 <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> civilian were
killed in <ent type='ORG'>Allied</ent> air raids and forced repatriation after the
war. In 1955, another neutral <ent type='NORP'>Swiss</ent> source, <ent type='ORG'>Die Tat</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>Zurich</ent>
(January 19th, 1955), in a survey of all <ent type='EVENT'>Second World War</ent>
casualties based on figures of <ent type='ORG'>the INternational Red Cross</ent>, put
the "Loss of victims of persecution because of politics, race or
religion who died in prisons and concentration camps between
1939 and 1945" at 300000, not all of whom were <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, and this
figure seems the most accurate assessment.</p>

<p> IMAGINARY SLAUGHTER</p>

<p> The question most pertinent to the extermination legend is,
of course: how many of the 3 million European <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> under <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>
control survived after 1945? The <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> Joint Distribution
<ent type='ORG'>Committee</ent> estimated the number of survivors in Europe to be only
one and a half million, but such a figure is not totally
unacceptable. This is proved by the growing number of <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>
claiming compensation from the WEst <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> Government for having
allegedly suffered between 1939 and 1945. By 1965, the number of
these claimants registered with the West <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> Government had
tripled in ten years and reached 3375000 (<ent type='PERSON'>Aufbau</ent>, June 30th,
1965). Nothing could be a more devastating proof of the brazen
fantasy of <ent type='EVENT'>the Six Million</ent>. Most of these claimants are <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, so
there can be no doubt that the majority of the 3 million <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>
who experienced the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> occupation of Europe are, in fact, very
much alive. It is a resounding confirmation of the fact that
<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> casualties during <ent type='EVENT'>the Second World War</ent> can only be
estimated at a figure in thousands. Surely this is enough grief
for the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> people? Who has the right to compound it with
vast imaginary slaughter, marking with eternal shame a great
European nation, as well as wringing faudulent monetary
compensation from them?
----------------------------------------------------------------
<ent type='PERSON'>RICHARD</ent> HARWOOD is a writer and specialist in political and
diplomatic aspects of <ent type='EVENT'>the Second World War</ent>. At present he is
with <ent type='ORG'>the University</ent> of London. Mr. <ent type='PERSON'>Harwood</ent> turned to the vexed
subject of war crimes under the influence of Professor Paul
<ent type='PERSON'>Rassinier</ent>, to whose monumental work this little volume is
greatly indebted. The author is now working on a sequel in this
series on the Main <ent type='GPE'>Nuremberg</ent> Trial, 1945-1946. </p></xml>