<xml><p> THE TRUE HISTORY OF THE HOLOCAUST</p>

<p> BY RICHARD HARWOOD</p>

<p> Introduction</p>

<p> In the following chapters the author has, he believes,
brought together irrefutable evidence that the allegation that 6
million <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> died during <ent type='EVENT'>the Second World War</ent>, as a direct
result of official <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> policy of extermination, is utterly
unfounded. This conclusion, admittedly an unpopular one,
resulted from an inquiry which was begun with no pre-conceived
opinions, beyond a general notion that the statistical
possibility of such huge casualties was perhaps open to doubt,
as well as an awareness that political capital was being made
from the implications of this alleged atrocity. A great deal of
careful research into this question, however, has now convinced
me beyond any doubt that the allegation is not merely an
exaggeration but an invention of post-war propaganda.
Of course, atrocity propaganda is nothing new. It has
accompanied every conflict of the 20th century and doubtless
will continue to do so. During the first <ent type='EVENT'>World War</ent>, the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>s
were actually accused of eating <ent type='NORP'>Belgian</ent> babies, as well as
delighting to throw them into the air and transfix them on
bayonets. The <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> also alleged that the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> forces were
operating a "<ent type='ORG'>Corpse Factory</ent>", in which they boiled down the
bodies of their own dead in order to obtain glycerine and other
commodities, a calculated insult to the honor of an <ent type='ORG'>Imperial</ent>
army. After the war, however, came the retractions; indeed, a
public statement was made by the Foreign Secretary in <ent type='ORG'>the House</ent>
of Commons apologizing for the insults to <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> honor, which
were admitted to be war-time propaganda.
No such statements have been made after <ent type='EVENT'>the Second World War</ent>.
In fact, rather than diminish with the passage of years, the
atrocity propaganda concerning the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> occupation, and in
particular their treatment of the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, has done nothing but
increase its virulence and elaborate its catalog of horrors.
<ent type='GPE'>Gruesome</ent> paperback books with lurid covers continue to roll from
the presses, adding continuously to a growing mythology of the
concentration camps and especially to the story that no less
than Six Million <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> were exterminated in them. The ensuing
pages will reveal this claim to be the most colossal piece of
fiction and the most successful of deceptions; but here an
attempt may be made to answer an important question: What has
rendered the atrocities stories of <ent type='EVENT'>the Second World War</ent> so
uniquely different from those of the First? Why were the latter
retracted while the former are reiterated louder than ever? Is
it possible that the story of <ent type='EVENT'>the Six Million</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> is serving a
political purpose, even that it is a form of political
blackmail?
So far as the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> people themselves are concerned, the
deception has been an incalculable benefit. Every conceivable
race and nationality had its share of suffering in the Second
<ent type='EVENT'>World War</ent>, but none has so successfully elaborated it and turned
it to such great advantage. The alleged extent of their
persecution quickly aroused sympathy for the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> homeland
they had sought for so long; after the War the <ent type='NORP'>British</ent>
Government did little to prevent <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> emigration to <ent type='GPE'>Palestine</ent>
which they had declared illegal, and it was not long afterwards
that the <ent type='NORP'>Zionists</ent> wrested from the Government the land of
<ent type='GPE'>Palestine</ent> and created their haven from persecution, the State of
<ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent>. Indeed, it is a remarkable fact that the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> people
emerged from <ent type='EVENT'>the Second World War</ent> as nothing less than a
triumphant minority. Dr. <ent type='PERSON'>Max Nussbaum</ent>, the former chief rabbi of
the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> community in <ent type='GPE'>Berlin</ent>, stated on April 11, 1953: "The
position the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> people occupy today in the world -- despite
the enormous losses -- is ten times stronger than what it was
twenty years ago." It should be added, if one is to be honest,
that this strength has been much consolidated financially by the
supposed massacre of <ent type='EVENT'>the Six Million</ent>, undoubtedly the most
profitable atrocity allegation of all time. To date, the
staggering figure of six thousand million pounds has been paid
out in compensation by <ent type='ORG'>the Federal Government</ent> of West <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y,
mostly to the State of <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent> (which did not even exist during
<ent type='EVENT'>the Second World War</ent>), as well as to individual <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent>
claimants.</p>

<p> DISCOURAGEMENT OF NATIONALISM</p>

<p> In terms of political blackmail, however, the allegation that
Six Million <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> died during <ent type='EVENT'>the Second World War</ent> has much more
far-reaching implications for the people of <ent type='GPE'>Britain</ent> and Europe
than simply the advantages it has gained for the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> nation.
And here one comes to the crux of the question: Why the Big Lie?
What is its purpose? In the first place, it has been used quite
unscrupulously to discourage any form of nationalism. Should the
people of <ent type='GPE'>Britain</ent> or any other European country attempt to
assert their patriotism and preserve their national integrity in
an age when the very existence of nation-states is threatened,
they are immediately branded as "neo-<ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent>". Because, of course,
<ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent>m was nationalism, and we know what happened then -- Six
Million <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> were exterminated! So long as the myth is
perpetuated, peoples everywhere will remain in bondage to it;
the need for international tolerance and understanding will be
hammered home by <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> Nations until nationhood itself; the
very guarantee of freedom, is abolished.
A classic example of the use of the 'Six Million' as an anti-national weapon appears in <ent type='ORG'>Manvell</ent> and Frankl's book, The
Incomparable Crime (<ent type='GPE'>London</ent>, 1967), which deals with 'Genocide in
the Twentieth Century'. Anyone with a pride in being <ent type='NORP'>British</ent>
will be somewhat supersede by the vicious attack made on the
<ent type='NORP'>British</ent> Empire in this book. The authors quote Pandit <ent type='PERSON'>Nehru</ent>, who
wrote the following while in a <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> prison in India: "Since
<ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> emerged from obscurity and became the <ent type='PERSON'>Fuhrer</ent> of <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y,
we have heard a great deal about racialism and the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> theory
of the "<ent type='ORG'>Herrenvolk</ent>"...But we in India have known racialism in
all its forms ever since the commitment of <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> rule. The
whole idealogy of this rule was that of the "<ent type='ORG'>Herrenvolk</ent>" and the
master race...India as a nation and <ent type='NORP'>Indians</ent> as individuals were
subjected to insult, humiliation and contemptuous treatment.
The English were an imperial race, we were told, with the God-given right to govern us and keep us in subjection; if we
protested we were reminded of the 'tiger qualities of an
imperial race'." The authors <ent type='ORG'>Manvell</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Frankl</ent> then go on to
make the point perfectly clear to us: "The white races of Europe
and <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>." they write, "have become used during the centuries
to regarding themselves as a "<ent type='ORG'>Herrenvolk</ent>". The twentieth
century, the century of Auschwitz, has also achieved the first
stage in the recognition of multi-racial partnership" (ibid, p.
14).</p>

<p> THE RACE PROBLEM SUPPRESSED</p>

<p> One could scarcely miss the object of this diatribe, with its
insidious hint about "multi-racial partnership". Thus the
accusation of <ent type='EVENT'>the Six Million</ent> is not only used to undermine the
principle of nationhood and national pride, but it threatens the
survival of the Race itself. It is wielded over the heads of the
populace, rather as the threat of hellfire and damnation was in
the Middle Ages. Many countries of the <ent type='NORP'>Anglo</ent>-Saxon world,
notably <ent type='GPE'>Britain</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>, are today facing the gravest danger
in their history, the danger posed by the alien races in their
midst. Unless something is done in <ent type='GPE'>Britain</ent> to halt the
immigration and assimilation of <ent type='NORP'>Africans</ent> and <ent type='NORP'>Asians</ent> into our
country, we are faced in the near future, quite apart from the
bloodshed of racial conflict, with the biological alteration and
destruction of the <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> people as they have existed since the
coming of the <ent type='NORP'>Saxons</ent>. In short, we are threatened with the
irrecoverable loss of our European culture and racial heritage.
But what happens if a man dares to speak of the race problem, of
its biological and political implications? He is branded as that
most heinous of creatures, a "racialist". And what is racialism.
of course, but the very hallmark of a <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>! They so everyone is
told, anyway) murdered Six Million <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> because of racialism, so
it must be a very evil thing indeed. When <ent type='PERSON'>Enoch Powell</ent> drew
attention to the dangers posed by coloring immigration into
<ent type='GPE'>Britain</ent> in one of his early speeches, a certain prominent
Socialist raised the specter of <ent type='LOC'>Dachau</ent> and Auschwitz to silence
his presumption.
Thus any rational discussion of the problems of Race and the
effort to preserve racial integrity is effectively discouraged.
No one could have sought to preserve their race through so many
centuries, and continue to do so today. In this effort they have
frankly been assisted by the story of <ent type='EVENT'>the Six Million</ent>, which,
almost like a religious myth, and stressed the need for greater
<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> racial <ent type='ORG'>solidarity</ent>. Unfortunately, it has worked in quite
the opposite way for all other peoples, rendering them impotent
in the struggle for self-preservation.
The aim in the following is quite simply to tell the <ent type='ORG'>Truth</ent>.
The distinguished <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n historian <ent type='PERSON'>Harry Elmer Barnes</ent> once
wrote that "An attempt to make a competent, objective and
truthful investigation of the extermination question...is surely
the most precarious venture that an historian or demographer
could undertake today." In attempting this precarious task, it
is hoped to make some contribution, not only to historical
truth, but towards lifting the burden of a Lie from our own
shoulders, so that we may freely confront the dangers that
threaten us all.
<ent type='PERSON'>Richard</ent> E. Harwood</p>

<p> 1) GERMAN POLICY TOWARDS THE <ent type='NORP'>JEWS</ent> PRIOR TO THE WAR</p>

<p> Rightly or wrongly, the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y of Adolf <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> considered
the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> to be a disloyal and avaricious element within the
national community, as well as a force of decadence in <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y's
cultural life. This was held to be particularly unhealthy since,
during the <ent type='NORP'>Weimar</ent> period, the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> had risen to a position of
remarkable strength and influence in the nation, particularly in
law, finance and the mass media, even though they constituted
only 5 per cent of the population. The fact that <ent type='PERSON'>Karl Marx</ent> was a
<ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent> and that <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> such as <ent type='PERSON'>Rosa Luxembourg</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Karl Liebknecht</ent>
were disproportionately prominent in the leadership of
revolutionary movements in <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y, also tended to convince the
<ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent> of the powerful internationalist and <ent type='NORP'>Communist</ent> tendencies
of the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> people themselves.
It is no part of the discussion here to argue whether the
<ent type='NORP'>German</ent> attitude to the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> was right or not, or to judge
whether its legislative measures against them were just or
unjust. Our concern is simply the fact that, believing of the
<ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> as the did, the <ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent>' solution to the problem was to
deprive them of their influence within the nation by various
legislative acts, and most important of all, to encourage their
emigration from the country altogether. By 1939, the great
majority of <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> had emigrated, all of them with a
sizable proportion of their assets. Never at any time had the
<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> leadership even contemplated a policy of genocide towards
them.</p>

<p> <ent type='NORP'>JEWS</ent> CALLED <ent type='ORG'>EMIGRATION</ent> '<ent type='GPE'>EXTERMINATION</ent>'</p>

<p> It is very significant, however, that certain <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> were quick
to interpret these policies of internal discrimination as
equivalent to extermination itself. A 1936 anti-<ent type='NORP'>German</ent>
propaganda book by <ent type='PERSON'>Leon Feuchtwanger</ent> and others entitles Der
Gelbe Fleck: Die Ausrotung von 500000 <ent type='PERSON'>duetschen Juden</ent> (The
Yellow Spot: The Extermination of 500000 <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Paris</ent>,
1936), presents a typical example. Despite its baselessness in
fact, the annihilation of the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> is discussed from the first
pages -- straightforward emigration being regarded as physical
"extermination" of <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ry. The <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> concentration camps
for political prisoners are also seen as potential instruments
of genocide, and special reference is made to the 100 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> still
detained in <ent type='LOC'>Dachau</ent> in 1936, of whom 60 had been there since
1933. A further example was the sensational book by the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>-<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Communist</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Hans Beimler</ent>, called Four Weeks in the Hands
of Hitler's Hell-Hounds: The <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> Murder Camp at <ent type='LOC'>Dachau</ent>, which
was published in <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent> as early as 1933. Detained for his
<ent type='NORP'>Marxist</ent> affiliations, he claimed that <ent type='LOC'>Dachau</ent> was a death camp,
though by his own admission he was released after only a month
there. The present regime in <ent type='LOC'>East</ent> <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y now issues a Hans
Beimler Award for services to Communism.
The fact that anti-<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> genocide propaganda was being
disseminated as this early date, therefore, by people biased on
racial or political grounds, should suggest extreme caution to
the independent-minded observer when approaching similar stories
of the war period.
The encouragement of <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> emigration should not be confused
with the purpose of concentration camps in pre-war <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y.
These were used for the detention of political opponents and
subversives -- principally liberals, Social <ent type='NORP'>Democrats</ent> and
<ent type='NORP'>Communist</ent>s of all kinds, of whom a proportion were <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> such as
<ent type='PERSON'>Hans Beimler</ent>. Unlike the millions enslaved in <ent type='GPE'>the Soviet Union</ent>,
the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> concentration camp population was always small;
Reitlinger admits that between 1934 and 1938 it seldom exceeded
20000 throughout the whole of <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y, and the number of <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>
was never more than 3000. (The S.S.: <ent type='ORG'>Alibi</ent> of a Nation, <ent type='GPE'>London</ent>,
1956, p. 253)</p>

<p> ZIONIST POLICY STUDIED</p>

<p> The <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> view of <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> emigration was not limited to a
negative policy of simple expulsion, but was founded along the
lines of modern <ent type='NORP'>Zionism</ent>. <ent type='PERSON'>Theodore Herzl</ent>, in his work The <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent>
State had originally conceived of <ent type='GPE'>Madagascar</ent> as a national
homeland for the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, and this possibility was seriously
studied by the party in pamphlet form. This stated that the
revival of <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent> as a <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> state was much less acceptable
since it would result in perpetual war and disruption in the
<ent type='NORP'>Arab</ent> world, which has indeed been the case. The <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>s were not
original in proposing <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> emigration to <ent type='GPE'>Madagascar</ent>; the
<ent type='NORP'>Polish</ent> Government had already considered the scheme in respect
of their own <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> population, and in 1937 they sent the
<ent type='PERSON'>Michael Lepecki</ent> expedition to <ent type='GPE'>Madagascar</ent>, accompanied by <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent>
representatives to investigate the problems involved.
The first <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> proposals for a <ent type='GPE'>Madagascar</ent> solution were made
in association with <ent type='ORG'>the Schacht Plan</ent> of 1938. On the advice of
<ent type='PERSON'>Goering</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> agreed to send the President of the <ent type='ORG'>Reichbank</ent>,
Dr. <ent type='PERSON'>Hjalmar Schacht</ent>, to <ent type='GPE'>London</ent> for discussions with <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent>
representatives <ent type='PERSON'>Lord Bearsted</ent> and Mr. <ent type='PERSON'>Rublee</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent> (cf.
Reitlinger, The <ent type='ORG'>Final Solution</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>London</ent>, 1953, p. 20). The plan
was that <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> assets would be frozen as security for an
international loan to finance <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> emigration to <ent type='GPE'>Palestine</ent>,
and <ent type='ORG'>Schacht</ent> reported on these negotiations to <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> at
<ent type='GPE'>Berchtesgaden</ent> on January 2, 1939. The plan,. which failed due to
<ent type='NORP'>British</ent> refusal to accept the financial terms, was first put
forward on November 12, 1938 at a conference convened by
<ent type='PERSON'>Goering</ent>, who revealed that <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> was already considering the
emigration of <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> to a settlement in <ent type='GPE'>Madagascar</ent> (ibid., p. 21).
Later, in December, <ent type='ORG'>Ribbentrop</ent> was told by M. <ent type='PERSON'>George Bonnet</ent>, the
<ent type='NORP'>French</ent> Foreign Secretary, that the <ent type='NORP'>French</ent> Government itself was
planning the evacuation of 10000 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> to <ent type='GPE'>Madagascar</ent>.
Prior to the <ent type='ORG'>Schacht</ent> <ent type='GPE'>Palestine</ent> proposals of 1938, which were
essentially a protraction of discussions that had begun as early
as 1935, numerous attempts had been made to secure <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent>
emigration in <ent type='EVENT'>the Evian Conference</ent> of July, 1938. However, by
1939 the scheme of <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> emigration to <ent type='GPE'>Madagascar</ent> had gained
the most favor in <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> circles. It is true that in <ent type='GPE'>London</ent>
Helmuth Wohltat of the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> Foreign Office discussed limited
<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> emigration to <ent type='GPE'>Rhodesia</ent> and <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> Guiana as late as
April 1939; but by January 24th, when <ent type='PERSON'>Goering</ent> wrote to <ent type='ORG'>Interior</ent>
Minister <ent type='PERSON'>Frick</ent> ordering the creation of a Central Emigration
Office for <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, and commissioned <ent type='PERSON'>Heydrich</ent> of the <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent> Security
Head Office to solve the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> problem "by means of emigration
and evacuation", the <ent type='GPE'>Madagascar</ent> Plan was being studied in
earnest.
By 1939, the consistent efforts of the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> Government to
secure the departure of <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> from the <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent> had resulted in the
emigration of 400000 <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> from a total population of
about 600000, and an additional 480000 emigrants from <ent type='GPE'>Austria</ent>
and <ent type='GPE'>Czechoslovakia</ent>, which constituted almost their entire <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent>
populations. This was accomplished through <ent type='ORG'>the Offices</ent> of <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent>
Emigration in <ent type='GPE'>Berlin</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Vienna</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Prague</ent> established by Adolf
<ent type='PERSON'>Eichmann</ent>, the head of the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> Investigative Office of the
<ent type='ORG'>Gestapo</ent>. So eager were the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>s to secure this emigration
that <ent type='PERSON'>Eichmann</ent> even established a training center in <ent type='GPE'>Austria</ent>,
where young <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> could learn farming in anticipation of being
smuggled illegally into <ent type='GPE'>Palestine</ent> (<ent type='ORG'>Manvell</ent> &amp; <ent type='PERSON'>Frankl</ent>, S.S. and
<ent type='ORG'>Gestapo</ent>, p. 60). Had <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> cherished any intention of
exterminating the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, it in inconceivable that he would have
allowed more than 800000 to leave <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent> territory with the bulk
of their wealth, much less considered plans for mass emigration
to <ent type='GPE'>Palestine</ent> or <ent type='GPE'>Madagascar</ent>. What is more, we shall see that the
policy of emigration from Europe was still under consideration
well into the war period, notably the <ent type='GPE'>Madagascar</ent> Plan, which
<ent type='PERSON'>Eichmann</ent> discussed in 1940 with <ent type='NORP'>French</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Colonial Office</ent> experts
after the defeat of <ent type='GPE'>France</ent> had made the surrender of the colony
a practical proposition.</p>

<p> 2) GERMAN POLICY TOWARDS THE <ent type='NORP'>JEWS</ent> AFTER THE OUTBREAK OF WAR</p>

<p> With the coming of the war, the situation regarding the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>
altered drastically. It is not widely known that world <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent>ry
declared itself to be a belligerent party in the Second World
War, and therefore there was ample basis under international law
for the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>s to intern the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> population as a hostile
force. On September 5, 1939 <ent type='PERSON'>Chaim Weizmann</ent>, the principle
<ent type='NORP'>Zionist</ent> leader, had declared war against <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y on behalf of
the world's <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, stating that "<ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> stand by Great <ent type='GPE'>Britain</ent> and
will fight on the side of the democracies...The <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> Agency is
ready to enter into immediate arrangements for utilizing <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent>
manpower, technical ability, resources ect..." (<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> Chronicle
September 8, 1939)</p>

<p> DETENTION OF ENEMY ALIENS</p>

<p> All <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> had thus been declared agents willing to prosecute a
war against the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent>, and as a consequence, <ent type='ORG'>Himmler</ent> and
<ent type='PERSON'>Heydrich</ent> were eventually to begin the policy of internment. It
is worth noting that <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> states and <ent type='GPE'>Britain</ent> had already
interned all <ent type='NORP'>Japanese</ent> aliens and citizens of <ent type='NORP'>Japanese</ent> descent in
detention camps before the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>s applied the same security
measures against the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> of Europe. Moreover, there had been no
such evidence or declaration of disloyalty by these <ent type='NORP'>Japanese</ent>
<ent type='GPE'>America</ent>ns as had been given by <ent type='PERSON'>Weizmann</ent>. The <ent type='NORP'>British</ent>, too,
during <ent type='EVENT'>the Boer War</ent>, interned all the women and children of the
population and thousands died as a result, yet in no sense could
the <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> be charged with wanting to exterminate the <ent type='NORP'>Boers</ent>.
The detention of the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> in the occupied territories of
Europe served two essential purposes from the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> viewpoint.
The first was to prevent unrest and subversion; <ent type='ORG'>Himmler</ent> had
informed <ent type='PERSON'>Mussolini</ent> on October 11th, 1042, that <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> policy
towards the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> had altered during wartime entirely for reasons
of military security. He complained that thousands of <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> in
the occupied regions were conducting partisan warfare, sabotage
and espionage, a view confirmed by official <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> information
given to <ent type='PERSON'>Raymond Arthur Davis</ent> that no less than 35000 European
<ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> were waging partisan war under <ent type='PERSON'>Tito</ent> in <ent type='GPE'>Yugoslavia</ent>. As a
result, <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> were to be transported to restricted areas and
detention camps, both in <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y, and especially after March
1942, in the Government-General of <ent type='GPE'>Poland</ent>.
As the war proceeded, the policy developed of using <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent>
detainees for labor in the war-effort. The question of labor is
fundamental when considering the alleged plan of genocide
against the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, for on the grounds of logic alone the latter
would entail the most senseless waste of manpower, time and
energy while prosecuting a war for survival on two fronts.
Certainly after the attack on <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>, the idea of compulsory
labor had taken precedence over <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> plans for <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent>
emigration. The protocol of a conversation between <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> and
the Hungarian regent <ent type='PERSON'>Horthy</ent> on April 17th, 1943, reveals that
the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> leader personally requested <ent type='PERSON'>Horthy</ent> to release 100000
Hungarian <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> for work in the "pursuit-plane program" of the
<ent type='ORG'>Luftwaffe</ent> at a time when the aerial bombardment of <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y
was increasing (Reitlinger, Die <ent type='ORG'>Endlosung</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Berlin</ent>, 1956, p.
478). This took place at a time when, supposedly, the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>s
were already seeking to exterminate the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, but Hitler's
request clearly demonstrates the priority aim of expanding his
labor force.
In harmony with this program, concentration camps became, in
fact, industrial complexes. At every camp where <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> and other
nationalities were detained, there were large industrial plants
and factories supplying material for the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> war-effort --
the <ent type='PERSON'>Buna</ent> rubber factory at Bergen-Belsen, for example, <ent type='PERSON'>Buna</ent> and
I. G. Farben Industry at Auschwitz, and the electrical firm of
<ent type='ORG'>Siemens</ent> at <ent type='GPE'>Ravensbruck</ent>. In many cases, special concentration
camp money notes were issued as payment for labor, enabling
prisoners to buy extra rations from camp shops. The <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>s were
determined to obtain the maximum economic return from the
concentration camp system, an object wholly at variance with any
plan to exterminate millions of people in them. It was the
function of the S.S. Economy and Administration Office, headed
by <ent type='PERSON'>Oswald Pohl</ent>, to see that the concentration camps became major
industrial producers.</p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>EMIGRATION</ent> STILL FAVORED</p>

<p> It is a remarkable fact, however, that well into the war
period, the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>s continued to implement the policy of <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent>
emigration. The fall of <ent type='GPE'>France</ent> in 1940 enabled the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>
Government to open serious negotiations with the <ent type='NORP'>French</ent> for the
transfer of European <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> to <ent type='GPE'>Madagascar</ent>. A memorandum of August,
1942 from <ent type='PERSON'>Luther</ent>, Secretary-of-State in the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> Foreign
Office, reveals that he had conducted these negotiations between
July and December 1940, when they were terminated by the <ent type='NORP'>French</ent>.
A circular from Luther's department dated August 15th, 1940
shows that the details of the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> play had been worked out by
<ent type='PERSON'>Eichmann</ent>, for it is signed by his assistant, <ent type='PERSON'>Dannecker</ent>. <ent type='PERSON'>Eichmann</ent>
had in fact been commissioned in August to draw up a detailed
<ent type='GPE'>Madagascar</ent> Plan, and <ent type='PERSON'>Dannecker</ent> was employed in research on
<ent type='GPE'>Madagascar</ent> at the <ent type='NORP'>French</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Colonial Office</ent> (Reitlinger, The Final
Solution, p. 77). The proposals of August 15th were that an
inter-European bank was to finance the emigration of four
million <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> throughout a phased program. Luther's 1942
memorandum shows that <ent type='PERSON'>Heydrich</ent> had obtained Himmler's approval
of this plan before the end of August and has also submitted it
to <ent type='PERSON'>Goering</ent>. It certainly met with Hitler's approval, for as
early as June 17th his interpreter, <ent type='PERSON'>Schmidt</ent>, recalls <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent>
observing to <ent type='PERSON'>Mussolini</ent> that "One could found a State of <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent>
in <ent type='GPE'>Madagascar</ent>" (<ent type='PERSON'>Schmidt</ent>, Hitler's Interpreter, <ent type='GPE'>London</ent>, 1951, p.
178).
Although the <ent type='NORP'>French</ent> terminated the <ent type='GPE'>Madagascar</ent> negotiations
in December, 1940, <ent type='PERSON'>Poliakov</ent>, the director of <ent type='ORG'>the Centre</ent> of
<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> Documentation in <ent type='GPE'>Paris</ent>, admits that the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>s
nevertheless pursued the scheme, and the <ent type='PERSON'>Eichmann</ent> was still busy
with it throughout 1941. Eventually, however, it was rendered
impractical by the progress of the war, in particular by the
situation after the invasion of <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>, and on February 10th,
1942, <ent type='ORG'>the Foreign Office</ent> was informed that the plan had been
temporarily shelved. This ruling, sent to <ent type='ORG'>the Foreign Office</ent> by
Luther's assistant, Rademacher, is of great importance, because
it demonstrates conclusively that the term "<ent type='ORG'>Final Solution</ent>"
meant only the emigration of <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, and also that transportation
to the eastern ghettos and concentration camps such as Auschwitz
constituted nothing but an alternative plan of evacuation. The
directive reads: "The was with <ent type='GPE'>the Soviet Union</ent> has in the
meantime created the possibility of disposing of other
territories for the <ent type='ORG'>Final Solution</ent>. In consequence the <ent type='PERSON'>Fuhrer</ent>
has decided that the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> should be evacuated not to <ent type='GPE'>Madagascar</ent>
but to the <ent type='LOC'>East</ent>. <ent type='GPE'>Madagascar</ent> need no longer therefore be
considered in connection with the <ent type='ORG'>Final Solution</ent>" (Reitlinger,
ibid. p. 79). The details of this evacuation has been discussed
a month earlier at the Wannsee Conference in <ent type='GPE'>Berlin</ent>, which we
shall examine below.
Reitlinger and <ent type='PERSON'>Poliakov</ent> both make the entirely unfounded
supposition that because the <ent type='GPE'>Madagascar</ent> Plan had been shelved,
the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>s must necessarily have been thinking of
"extermination". Only a month later, however, on March 7th,
1942, <ent type='PERSON'>Goebbels</ent> wrote a memorandum in favor of the <ent type='GPE'>Madagascar</ent>
Plan as a "final solution" of the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> question (<ent type='ORG'>Manvell</ent> &amp;
<ent type='PERSON'>Frankl</ent>, Dr. <ent type='PERSON'>Goebbels</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>London</ent>, 1960, p. 165). In the meantime he
approved of the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> being "concentrated in the <ent type='LOC'>East</ent>". Later
<ent type='PERSON'>Goebbels</ent> memoranda also stress deportation to the <ent type='LOC'>East</ent> (i.e. the
Government-General of <ent type='GPE'>Poland</ent>) and lay emphasis on the need for
compulsory labour there; once the policy of evacuation to the
<ent type='LOC'>East</ent> had been inaugurated, the us of <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> labour became a
fundamental part of the operations. It is perfectly clear from
the foregoing that the term "<ent type='ORG'>Final Solution</ent>" was applied both
to <ent type='GPE'>Madagascar</ent> and to the <ent type='LOC'>East</ent>ern territories, and that therefore
it meant only the deportation of the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>.
Even as late as may 1944, the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>s were prepared to allow
the emigration of one million European <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> from Europe. An
account of this proposal is given by <ent type='PERSON'>Alexander Weissberg</ent>, a
purges, in his book <ent type='PERSON'>Die Geschichte von Joel Brand</ent> (<ent type='GPE'>Cologne</ent>,
1956). <ent type='PERSON'>Weissberg</ent>, who spent the war in <ent type='GPE'>Cracow</ent> though he expected
the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>s to intern him in a concentration camp, explains that
on the personal authorization of <ent type='ORG'>Himmler</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Eichmann</ent> had sent the
<ent type='GPE'>Budapest</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> leader <ent type='PERSON'>Joel Brand</ent> to <ent type='GPE'>Istanbul</ent> with an offer to
the <ent type='ORG'>Allies</ent> to permit the transfer of one million European <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>
in the midst of the war. (If the 'extermination' writers are to
be believed, there were scarcely one million <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> left by May,
1944). The <ent type='ORG'>Gestapo</ent> admitted that the transportation involved
would greatly inconvenience the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> war-effort, but were
prepared to allow it in exchange for 10000 trucks to be used
exclusively on the <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>n front. Unfortunately, the plan came
to nothing; the <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> concluded that <ent type='ORG'>Brand</ent> must be a dangerous
<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> agent and immediately imprisoned him in <ent type='GPE'>Cairo</ent>, while the
<ent type='ORG'>Press</ent> denounced the offer as a <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> trick. <ent type='PERSON'>Winston Churchill</ent>,
though orating to the effect that the treatment of the Hungarian
<ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> was probably "the biggest and most horrible crime ever
committed in the whole history of the world", nevertheless told
<ent type='PERSON'>Chaim Weizmann</ent> that acceptance of the <ent type='ORG'>Brand</ent> offer was
impossible, since it would be a betrayal of this <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>n <ent type='ORG'>Allies</ent>.
Although the plan was fruitless, it well illustrates that no one
allegedly carrying out "thorough" extermination would permit the
emigration of a million <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, and it demonstrates, too, the
prime importance placed by the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>s on the war-effort.</p>

<p> 3) POPULATION AND <ent type='ORG'>EMIGRATION</ent></p>

<p> Statistics relating to <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> populations are not everywhere
known in precise detail, approximation for various countries
differing widely, and it is also unknown exactly how many <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>
were deported and interned at any one time between the years
1939-1945. In general, however, what reliable statistics there
are, especially those relating to emigration, are sufficient to
show that not a fraction of six million <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> could have been
exterminated.
In the first place, this claim cannot remotely be upheld on
examination of the European <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> population figures. According
to <ent type='ORG'>Chambers</ent> Encyclopedia the total number of <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> living in pre-war Europe was 6500000. Quite clearly, this would mean that
almost the entire number was exterminated. But the Baseler
Nachrichten, a neutral <ent type='NORP'>Swiss</ent> publication employing available
<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> statistical data, establishes that between 1933 and 1945,
1500000 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> emigrated to <ent type='GPE'>Britain</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Sweden</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Spain</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Portugal</ent>,
<ent type='GPE'>Australia</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>China</ent>, India, <ent type='GPE'>Palestine</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States. This
is confirmed by the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> journalist <ent type='PERSON'>Bruno Blau</ent>, who cites the
same figure in the <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> paper <ent type='PERSON'>Aufbau</ent>, August 13th,
1948. Of these emigrants, approximately 400000 came from
<ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y before September 1939. This is acknowledged by the World
<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> Congress in its publication <ent type='ORG'>Unity</ent> in Dispersion (P. 3778)
which states that: "The majority of the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> succeeded in
leaving <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y before the war broke out." In addition to the
<ent type='NORP'>German</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, 220000 of the total 280000 <ent type='GPE'>Austria</ent>n <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> had
emigrated by September, 1939, while from March 1939 onwards the
Institute for <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> Emigration in <ent type='GPE'>Prague</ent> had secured the
emigration of 260000 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> from former <ent type='GPE'>Czechoslovakia</ent>. In all,
only 360000 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> remained in <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y, <ent type='GPE'>Austria</ent>, and
<ent type='GPE'>Czechoslovakia</ent> after September 1939. From <ent type='GPE'>Poland</ent>, an estimated
500000 had emigrated prior to the outbreak of war. These
figures mean that the number of <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> emigrants from other
European countries (<ent type='GPE'>France</ent>, the <ent type='GPE'>Netherlands</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Italy</ent>, the
countries of <ent type='LOC'>East</ent>ern Europe etc.) was approximately 120000.
This exodus of <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> before and during hostilities, therefore,
reduces the number of <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> in Europe to approximately 5000000.
In addition to these emigrants, we must include the number of
<ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> who fled to <ent type='GPE'>the Soviet Union</ent> after 1939, and who were later
evacuated beyond reach of the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> invaders. It will be shown
below that the majority of these, about 1250000, were migrants
from <ent type='GPE'>Poland</ent>. But apart from <ent type='GPE'>Poland</ent>, Reitlinger admits that
300000 other European <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> slipped into <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> territory
between 1939 and 1941. This brings the total of <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> emigrants
to <ent type='GPE'>the Soviet Union</ent> to about 1500000. In <ent type='ORG'>Colliers</ent> magazine,
June 9th, 1945, <ent type='PERSON'>Freiling Foster</ent>, writing of the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> in <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>,
explained that "22222000 have migrated to <ent type='GPE'>the Soviet Union</ent>
since 1939 to escape the <ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent>," but our lower estimate is
probably more accurate.
<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> migration to <ent type='GPE'>the Soviet Union</ent>, therefore, reduces the
number of <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> within the sphere of <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> occupation to around
31/2 million, approximately 3450000. From these should be
deducted those <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> living in neutral European countries who
escaped the consequences of the war. According to the 1942 World
Almanac (p. 594) the number of <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> living in <ent type='GPE'>Gibraltar</ent>,
<ent type='GPE'>Britain</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Portugal</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Spain</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Sweden</ent>. <ent type='GPE'>Switzerland</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Ireland</ent> and
<ent type='GPE'>Turkey</ent> was 413128.</p>

<p> 3 MILLION <ent type='NORP'>JEWS</ent> IN EUROPE</p>

<p> A figure consequently, of around 3 million <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> in <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>-occupied Europe is as accurate as the available emigration
statistics will allow. Approximately the same number, however,
can be deduced in another way if we examine statistics for the
<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> populations remaining in countries occupied by the <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent>.
More than half of those <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> who migrated to <ent type='GPE'>the Soviet Union</ent>
after 1939 came from <ent type='GPE'>Poland</ent>. It is frequently claimed that the
war with <ent type='GPE'>Poland</ent> added some 3 million <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> to the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> sphere
of influence and that almost the whole of this <ent type='NORP'>Polish</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent>
population was "exterminated." This is a major factual error.
The 1931 <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> population census for <ent type='GPE'>Poland</ent> put the number of
<ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> at 2732600 (Reitlinger, Die <ent type='ORG'>Endlosung</ent>, p. 36). Reitlinger
states that at least 1170000 of these were in the <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>n zone
occupied in the autumn of 1939, about a million of whom were
evacuated to the <ent type='LOC'>Urals</ent> and south <ent type='LOC'>Siberia</ent> after the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>
invasion of June 1941 (ibid, p. 50). As described above, an
estimated 500000 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> had emigrated from <ent type='GPE'>Poland</ent> prior to the
war. Moreover, the journalist <ent type='PERSON'>Raymond Arthur Davis</ent>, who spent
the war in <ent type='GPE'>the Soviet Union</ent>, observed that approximately 250000
had already fled from <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>-occupied <ent type='GPE'>Poland</ent> to <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent> between
1939 and 1941 and were to be encountered in every <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent>
province (<ent type='GPE'>Odyssey</ent> through Hell, N.Y., 1946). Subtracting these
figures from the population of 2732600, therefore, and
allowing for the normal population increase, no more than
1100000 <ent type='NORP'>Polish</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> could have been under <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> rule at the
end of 1939. (Gutachen des Instituts fur <ent type='GPE'>Zeitgeschichte</ent>, Munich,
1956, p. 80)
To this number we may add the 360000 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> remaining in
<ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y, <ent type='GPE'>Austria</ent> and former <ent type='GPE'>Czechoslovakia</ent> (<ent type='GPE'>Bohemia</ent>-<ent type='GPE'>Moravia</ent> and
<ent type='PERSON'>Slavakia</ent>) after the extensive emigration from those countries
prior to the war described above. Of the 320000 <ent type='NORP'>French</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>,
the Public Prosecutor representing that part of the indictment
relating to <ent type='GPE'>France</ent> at <ent type='EVENT'>the Nuremberg Trials</ent>, stated that 120000
<ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> were deported, though Reitlinger estimates only about
50000. Thus the total number of <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> under <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> rule remains
below two million. Deportations from the Scandinavian countries
were few, and from <ent type='GPE'>Bulgaria</ent>, none at all. When the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent>
populations of <ent type='GPE'>Holland</ent> (140000), <ent type='GPE'>Belgium</ent> (40000), <ent type='GPE'>Italy</ent>
(50000), <ent type='GPE'>Yugoslavia</ent> (55000), Hungary (380000) and <ent type='GPE'>Romania</ent>
(725000) are included, the figure does not much exceed 3
million. This excess is due to the fact that the latter figures
are pre-war estimates unaffected by emigration, which from these
countries accounted for about 120000 (see above). This cross-checking, therefore, confirms the estimate of approximately 3
million <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> under <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> occupation.</p>

<p> RUSSIAN <ent type='NORP'>JEWS</ent> EVACUATED</p>

<p> The precise figures concerning <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>n <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> are unknown, and
have therefore been the subject of extreme exaggeration. The
<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> statistician <ent type='PERSON'>Jacob Leszczynski</ent> states that in 1939 there
were 2100000 <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> living in future <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>-occupied <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>,
i.e. western <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>. In addition, some 260000 lived in the
<ent type='NORP'>Baltic</ent> states of <ent type='GPE'>Estonia</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Latvia</ent> and Luthuania. According to
<ent type='PERSON'>Louis Levine</ent>, President of the <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> Council for
<ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>n relief, who made a post-war tour of <ent type='GPE'>the Soviet Union</ent> and
submitted a report on the status of <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> there, the majority
of these numbers were evacuated east after the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> armies
launched their invasion. In <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>, on October 30th, 1946, he
declared that: "At the onset of the war, <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> were amongst the
first evacuated from the western regions threatened by the
<ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent>ite invaders, and shipped to safety east of the <ent type='LOC'>Urals</ent>.
Two million <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> were thus saved." This high number is confirmed
by the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> journalist <ent type='PERSON'>David Bergelson</ent>, who wrote in the
<ent type='GPE'>Moscow</ent> Yiddish paper <ent type='ORG'>Ainikeit</ent>, December 5th, 1942, that "Thanks
to the evacuation, the majority (80%) of the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> in the
<ent type='GPE'>Ukraine</ent>, White <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Lithuania</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Latvia</ent> before the arrival
of the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>s were rescued." Reitlinger agrees with the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent>
authority <ent type='PERSON'>Joseph Schechtmann</ent>, who admits that huge numbers were
evacuated, though he estimates a slightly higher number of
<ent type='NORP'>Baltic</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>n <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> remaining in <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> territory, it will
be proved later that in the war in <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent> no more than one
hundred thousand persons were killed by the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> Action Groups
as partisans and <ent type='NORP'>Bolshevik</ent> commissars, not all of whom were
<ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>. By contrast, the partisans themselves claimed to have
murdered five times that number of <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> troops.</p>

<p> "SIX MILLION" UNTRUE ACCORDING TO NEUTRAL SWISS</p>

<p> It is clear, therefore, that the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>s could not have
possibly have gained control over or exterminated anything like
six million <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>. Excluding <ent type='GPE'>the Soviet Union</ent>, the number of <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>
in <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent>-occupied Europe after emigration was scarcely more than
3 million, by no means all of whom were interned. To approach
the extermination of even half of six million would have meant
the liquidation of every <ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent> living in Europe. And yet it is
known that large numbers of <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> were alive in Europe after
1945. <ent type='PERSON'>Philip Freidmann</ent> in Their Brother's Keepers (N.Y., 1957,
p. 13), states that "at least a million <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> survived in the
very crucible of the <ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> hell," while the official figure of
the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> Joint Distribution Committee is 1559600. Thus, even
if one accepts the latter estimate, the number of possible
wartime <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> deaths could not have exceeded a limit of one and
a half million. Precisely this conclusion was reached by the
reputable journal <ent type='ORG'>Baseler Nachrichten</ent> of neutral <ent type='GPE'>Switzerland</ent>. In
an article entitled "<ent type='PERSON'>Wie hoch</ent> ist die <ent type='ORG'>Zahl der</ent> judischen Opfer?"
("How high is the number of <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> victims?", June 13th, 1946),
it explained that purely on the basis of the population and
emigration figures described above, a maximum of only one and a
half million <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> could have been numbered as casualties. Later
on, however, it will be demonstrated conclusively that the
number was actually far less, for the <ent type='ORG'>Baseler Nachrichten</ent>
accepted <ent type='ORG'>the Joint Distribution Committee</ent>'s figure of 1559600
survivors after the war, but we shall show that the numbers of
claims for compensation by <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> survivors is more than
double that figure. This information was not available to the
<ent type='NORP'>Swiss</ent> in 1946.</p>

<p> IMPOSSIBLE BIRTH RATE</p>

<p> Indisputable evidence is also provided by the post-war world
<ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> population statistics. The <ent type='EVENT'>World Almanac</ent> of 1938 gives
the number of <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> in the world as 16588259. But after the
war, the <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent> Times, February 22nd, 1948 placed the number
of <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> in the world at a minimum of 15600000 and a maximum of
18700000. Quite obviously, these figures make it impossible
for the number of <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> war-time casualties to be measured in
anything but thousands. 15 1/2 million in 1939 minus the alleged
six million leaves nine million; the <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent> Times figures
would mean, therefore, that the world's <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> produced seven
million births, almost doubling their numbers, in the space of
ten years. This is patently ridiculous!
It would appear, therefore, that the great majority of the
missing "Six million" were in fact emigrants -- emigrants to
European countries, to <ent type='GPE'>the Soviet Union</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States
before, during and after the war. And emigrants also, in vast
numbers to <ent type='GPE'>Palestine</ent> during and especially at the end of the
war. After 1945, boat-loads of these <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> survivors entered
<ent type='GPE'>Palestine</ent> illegally from Europe, causing considerable
embarrassment to the <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> Government at the time; indeed, so
great were the numbers that the H.M. Stationary Office
publication No. 190 (November 5th, 1946) described them as
"almost amounting to a second Exodus." It was these emigrants to
all parts of the world who had swollen the world <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent>
population to between 15 and 18 millions by 1948, and probably
the greatest part of them were emigrants to <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States
who entered in violation of the quota laws.
On August 16th, 1963 <ent type='PERSON'>David Ben Gurion</ent>, President of <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent>,
stated that although the official <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> population of <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>
was said to be 5600000, "the total number would not be
estimated too high at 9000000" (Dueutsche Wochenzeitung
November 23rd, 1963). The reason for his high figure is
underlined by <ent type='PERSON'>Albert Maisal</ent> in his article "Our Newest
<ent type='GPE'>America</ent>ns" (Reader's Digest, January 1957), for he reveals that
"Soon after <ent type='EVENT'>World War</ent> II, by Presidential decree, 90% of all
quota visas for central and eastern Europe were issued to the
uprooted."
Reprinted on this page [in the booklet] is just one extract
from hundreds that regularly appear in the obituary columns of
<ent type='PERSON'>Aufbau</ent>, the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n weekly published in <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent> (June
16th, 1972). It shows how <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> emigrants to <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States
subsequently changer their names: their former names when in
Europe appear in bracket. For example, as below, <ent type='PERSON'>Arthur Kingsley</ent>
(formerly Dr. Konigsberger of <ent type='GPE'>Frankfort</ent>). Could it be that some
or all of these people whose names are "deceased" were included
in the missing six million of Europe?
-----------------------
Am 30 Janur 1972 verschied <ent type='PERSON'>mein herzensguter Mann</ent>, unser
<ent type='PERSON'>geliebter Vater und</ent> Grossvater</p>

<p> ARTHUR KINGSLEY
(Fruher Dr. Konigsberger. <ent type='GPE'>Frankfort</ent>/Main)
drei <ent type='ORG'>Woohen vor seinem</ent> 90. Geburtstag.
In tiefer <ent type='PERSON'>Trauer</ent>:
<ent type='PERSON'>Alice Kingsley</ent>
700 <ent type='GPE'>Fort</ent> Washington Ave.
<ent type='GPE'>New York</ent>, N.Y.
<ent type='PERSON'>Leo</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Eve Lenin</ent>
geb. Kingsley
Apt 1110 South,
4800 <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Beach</ent> Drive,
<ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>, Ill 60615
<ent type='PERSON'>Anne</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Martin Kingsley</ent>
232 <ent type='LOC'>Sunset</ent> Drive
Wilmette Ill. 60691
Nina and Ronnie</p>

<p> [ad as it is reproduced in the article]
4) THE SIX MILLION: DOCUMENTARY EVIDENCE</p>

<p> From the foregoing it would seem certain that the figure of
six million murdered <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> amounts to nothing more than a vague
compromise between several quite baseless estimates; there is
not a shred of documentary evidence for it that is trustworthy.
Occasionally, writers narrow it down to give a disarming
appearance of authenticity. Lord <ent type='PERSON'>Russell</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>Liverpool</ent>, for
example, in his The Scourge of the Swastika (<ent type='GPE'>London</ent>, 1964)
claimed that "not less than five million" <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> died in <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>
concentration camps, having satisfied himself that he was
somewhere between those who estimated 6 million and those who
preferred 4 million. But, he admitted, "the real number will
never be known." If so, it is difficult to know how he could
have asserted "not less than 5 million." The Joint Distribution
Committee favors 5012000, but the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> "expert" Reitlinger
suggests a novel figure of 4192000 "missing <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>" of whom an
estimated one third died of natural causes. This would reduce
the number deliberately "exterminated" to 2796000. However,
Dr. M. Perlzweig, the <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent> delegate to a World <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> press
conference held at <ent type='GPE'>Geneva</ent> in 1948 stated: "The price of the
downfall of National Socialism and Fascism is the fact that seven
million <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> lost their lives thanks to cruel Anti-Semitism." In
the <ent type='ORG'>Press</ent> and elsewhere, the figure is often casually lifted to
eight million or sometimes even nine million. As we have proved
in the previous chapter, none of these figures are in the
remotest degree plausible, indeed, they are ridiculous.</p>

<p> FANTASTIC EXAGGERATIONS</p>

<p> So far as is known, the first accusation against the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>s
of mass murder of <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> in war-time Europe was made by the <ent type='NORP'>Polish</ent>
<ent type='NORP'>Jew</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Rafael Lemkin</ent> in his book Axis Rule in Occupied Europe,
published in <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent> in 1943. Somewhat coincidentally, <ent type='PERSON'>Lemkin</ent>
was later to draw up the U.N. Genocide Convention, which seeks
to outlaw "racialism". His book claimed that the <ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent> had
destroyed millions of <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, perhaps as many as six millions.
This, by 1943, would have been remarkable indeed, since the
action was allegedly started only in the summer of 1942. At such
a rate, the entire world <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> population would have been
exterminated by 1945.
After the war, propaganda estimates spiraled to heights even
more fantastic. <ent type='PERSON'>Kurt Gerstein</ent>, an anti-<ent type='NORP'>Nazi</ent> who claimed to have
infiltrated the S.S., told the <ent type='NORP'>French</ent> interrogator Raymond
Cartier that he knew that no less than forty million
concentration camp internes had been gassed. In his first
signed memorandum of April 26th, 1945, he reduced the figure to
25 million, but even this was too bizarre for <ent type='NORP'>French</ent>
Intelligence and in his second memorandum, signed at <ent type='ORG'>Rottweil</ent> on
May 4th, 1945, he brought the figure closer to the six million
preferred at <ent type='EVENT'>the Nuremberg Trials</ent>. Gerstein's sister was
congenitally insane and died by euthanasia, which may well
suggest a streak of mental instability in <ent type='PERSON'>Gerstein</ent> himself. He
had, in fact, been convicted in 1936 of sending eccentric mail
through the post. After his two "confessions" he hanged himself
at <ent type='LOC'>Cherche</ent> Midi prison in <ent type='GPE'>Paris</ent>.
<ent type='PERSON'>Gerstein</ent> alleged that during the war he passed on information
concerning the murder of <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> to the Swedish Government through
a <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> baron, but for some inexplicable reason his report was
"filed away and forgotten". He also claimed that in August 1942
he informed the Papal nuncio in <ent type='GPE'>Berlin</ent> about the whole
"extermination program", but the reverend person merely told him
to "Get out." The <ent type='PERSON'>Gerstein</ent> statements abound with claims to have
witnessed the most gigantic mass executions (twelve thousand in
a single day at Belzec), while the second memorandum describes a
visit by <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> to a concentration camp in <ent type='GPE'>Poland</ent> on June 6th,
1942 which is known never to have taken place.
Gerstein's fantastic exaggerations have done little but
discredit the whole notion of mass extermination. Indeed,
<ent type='NORP'>Evangelical</ent> Bishop <ent type='PERSON'>Wilhelm Dibelius</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>Berlin</ent> denounced his
memoranda as "Untrustworthy" (H. Rothfels, "Augenzeugenbricht zu
den <ent type='ORG'>Massenvergasungen</ent>" in <ent type='GPE'>Viertelijahtshefte</ent> fur <ent type='GPE'>Zeitgeschichte</ent>,
April 1953). It is an incredible fact, however, that in spite of
this denunciation, the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> Government in 1955 issued an
edition of the second <ent type='PERSON'>Gerstein</ent> memorandum for distribution in
<ent type='NORP'>German</ent> schools (<ent type='ORG'>Dokumentation zur Massenvergasung</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Bonn</ent>, 1955).
In it they stated that <ent type='PERSON'>Dibelius</ent> placed his special confidence in
<ent type='PERSON'>Gerstein</ent> and that the memoranda were "valid beyond any doubt."
This is a striking example of the way in which the baseless
charge of genocide by the <ent type='NORP'>Nazis</ent> is perpetuated in <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y, and
directed especially to the youth.
The story of the six million <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> exterminated during the war
was given final authority at <ent type='EVENT'>the Nuremberg Trials</ent> by the
statement of Dr. <ent type='PERSON'>Wilhelm Hoettl</ent>. He had been an assistant of
Eichmann's but was in fact a rather strange person in the
service of <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n Intelligence who had written several books
under the pseudonym of <ent type='PERSON'>Walter Hagen</ent>. <ent type='PERSON'>Hoettl</ent> also worked for
<ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> espionage, collaborating with two <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> emigrants from
<ent type='GPE'>Vienna</ent>, Perger and <ent type='PERSON'>Verber</ent>, who acted as U.S. officers during the
preliminary inquiries of <ent type='EVENT'>the Nuremberg Trials</ent>. It is remarkable
that the testimony of this highly dubious person <ent type='PERSON'>Hoettl</ent> is said
to constitute the only "Proof" regarding the murder of six
million <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>. In his affidavit of November 26th, 1945 he states,
not that he knew but that <ent type='PERSON'>Eichmann</ent> had "told him" in August 1944
in <ent type='GPE'>Budapest</ent> that a total of 6 million <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> had been
exterminated. Needless to say, <ent type='PERSON'>Eichmann</ent> never corroborated this
claim at his trial. <ent type='PERSON'>Hoettl</ent> was working as an <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n spy during
the whole of the latter period of the war, and it is therefore
very odd indeed that he never gave the slightest hint to the
<ent type='GPE'>America</ent>ns of a policy to murder <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, even though he worked
directly under <ent type='PERSON'>Heydrich</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Eichmann</ent>.</p>

<p> ABSENCE OF EVIDENCE</p>

<p> It should be emphasized straight away that there is not a
single document in existence which proves that the <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>s
intended to, or carried out, the deliberate murder of <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>. In
<ent type='PERSON'>Poliakov</ent> and Wulf's Das Dritte <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent> und die Juden: Dokumente
und Aufsatze (<ent type='GPE'>Berlin</ent> 1955), the most that they can assemble are
statements extracted after the war from people like <ent type='PERSON'>Hoettl</ent>,
Ohlendorf and <ent type='ORG'>Wisliceny</ent>, the latter under torture in a <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent>
prison. In the absence of any evidence, therefore, <ent type='PERSON'>Poliakov</ent> is
forced to write: "The three or four people chiefly involved in
drawing up the plan for total extermination are dead, and no
documents survive." This seems very convenient. Quite obviously,
both the plan and the "three or four" people are nothing but
nebulous assumptions on the part of the writer, and are
entirely unprovable.
The documents which do survive, of course, make no mention at
all of extermination, so that writers like <ent type='PERSON'>Poliakov</ent> and
Reitlinger again make the convenient assumption that such orders
were generally "verbal". Though lacking any documentary proof,
they assume that a plan to murder <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> must have originated in
1941. coinciding with the attack on <ent type='GPE'>Russia</ent>. Phase one of the
plan is alleged to have involved the massacre of <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, a
claim we shall disprove later. The rest of the program is
supposed to have begun in March 1942, with the deportation and
concentration of European <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> in the eastern camps of the
<ent type='NORP'>Polish</ent> Government-General, such as the giant industrial complex
at Auschwitz near <ent type='GPE'>Cracow</ent>. The fantastic and quite groundless
assumption throughout is that transportation to the <ent type='LOC'>East</ent>,
supervised by Eichmann's department, actually meant immediate
extermination in ovens upon arrival.
According to <ent type='ORG'>Manvell</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Frankl</ent> (Heinrich <ent type='ORG'>Himmler</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>London</ent>,
1965), the policy of genocide "seems to have been arrived at"
after "secret discussions" between <ent type='PERSON'>Hitler</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>Himmler</ent> (p. 118),
though they fail to prove it. Reitlinger and <ent type='PERSON'>Poliakov</ent> guess
along similar "verbal" lines, adding that no one else was
allowed to be present at these discussions, and no records were
ever kept of them. This is the purest invention, for there is
not a shred of evidence that even suggests such outlandish
meetings took place. <ent type='PERSON'>William Shirer</ent>, in his generally wild and
irresponsible book The Rise and Fall of the Third <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent>, is
similarly muted on the subject of documentary proof. He states
weakly that Hitler's supposed order for the murder of <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>
"apparently was never committed to paper - at least no copy of
it has ever been unearthed. It was probably given verbally to
<ent type='PERSON'>Goering</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Himmler</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Heydrich</ent>, who passed it down..." (p. 1148).
A typical example of the kind of "proof" quoted in support
of the extermination legend is given by <ent type='ORG'>Manvell</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Frankl</ent>. They
cite a memorandum of 31st July, 1941, sent by <ent type='PERSON'>Goering</ent> to
<ent type='PERSON'>Heydrich</ent>, who headed the <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent> Security Head Office and was
Himmler's deputy. Significantly, the memorandum begins:
"Supplementing the task that was assigned to you on 24th January
1939, to solve the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> problem by means of emigration and
evacuation in the best possible way according to present
conditions..." The supplementary task assigned in the memorandum
is a "total solution (Gesamtlosung) of the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> question
within the area of <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> influence in Europe," which authors
admit means concentration in the <ent type='LOC'>East</ent>, and it requests
preparations for the "organizational, financial and material
matters" involved. The memorandum then requests a future plan
for the "desired final solution (<ent type='ORG'>Endlosung</ent>), which clearly
refers to the ideal and ultimate scheme of emigration mentioned
at the beginning of the directive. No mention whatever is made
of murdering people, but <ent type='ORG'>Manvell</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Frankl</ent> assure us that this
is what the memorandum is really about. Again, of course, the
"true nature" of the final as distinct from the total solution
"was made known to <ent type='PERSON'>Heydrich</ent> by <ent type='PERSON'>Goering</ent> verbally" (ibid p. 118).
The convenience of these "verbal" directives issuing back and
forth is obvious.</p>

<p> THE WANNSEE CONFERENCE</p>

<p> The final details of the plan to exterminate <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> were
supposedly to have been made at a conference at <ent type='PERSON'>Gross Wannsee</ent> in
<ent type='GPE'>Berlin</ent> on 20th January 1942, presided over by <ent type='PERSON'>Heydrich</ent>
(<ent type='PERSON'>Poliakov</ent>, Das Dritte <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent> und die Juden, p. 1220 ff.
Reitlinger, The <ent type='ORG'>Final Solution</ent>, p. 95 ff). Officials of all
<ent type='NORP'>German</ent> Ministries were present, and <ent type='PERSON'>Muller</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Eichmann</ent>
represented <ent type='ORG'>Gestapo</ent> Head Office. Reitlinger and <ent type='ORG'>Manvell</ent> and
<ent type='PERSON'>Frankl</ent> consider the minutes of this conference to be their trump
card in proving the existence of a genocide plan, but the truth
is no such plan was even mentioned, and what is more, they
freely admit this. <ent type='ORG'>Manvell</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Frankl</ent> explain it away rather
lamely by saying that "The minutes are shrouded in the form of
officialdom that cloaks the real significance of the words and
terminology used" (The Incomparable Crime, <ent type='GPE'>London</ent>, 1967, p. 46),
which really means that they intend to interpret them in their
own way. What <ent type='PERSON'>Heydrich</ent> actually said was that, as in the
memorandum quoted above, he had been commissioned by <ent type='PERSON'>Goering</ent> to
arrange a solution to the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> problem. He reviewed the
history of <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> emigration, stated that the war had rendered
the <ent type='GPE'>Madagascar</ent> project impractical, and continued: "The
emigration program has been replaced now by the evacuation of
<ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> to the east as a further solution in accordance with the
previous authorization of the <ent type='PERSON'>Fuhrer</ent>." Here, he explained, their
labor was to be utilized. All this is supposed to be deeply
sinister, and pregnant with the hidden meaning that the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>
were to be exterminated, though Prof. <ent type='PERSON'>Paul Rassinier</ent>, a
<ent type='NORP'>French</ent>man interned at <ent type='PERSON'>Buchenwald</ent> who has done sterling work in
refuting the myth of <ent type='EVENT'>the Six Million</ent>, explains that it means
precisely what it says, i.e. the concentration of the <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> for
labor in the immense eastern ghetto of <ent type='ORG'>the Polish Government</ent>-General. "There they were to wait until the end of the war, for
the re-opening of internal discussions which would decide their
future. This decision was finally reached at the inter
ministerial <ent type='GPE'>Berlin</ent>-Wannsee conference...." (Rassinier, Le
Vertitable Proces <ent type='PERSON'>Eichmann</ent>, p. 20). <ent type='ORG'>Manvell</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Frankl</ent>, however,
remain undaunted by the complete lack of reference to
extermination. At the Wannsee conference, they write, "Direct
references to killing were avoided, <ent type='PERSON'>Heydrich</ent> favoring the term
"<ent type='ORG'>Arbeitseinsatz</ent> in <ent type='GPE'>Osten</ent>" (labor assignment in the <ent type='LOC'>East</ent>)"
(Heinrich <ent type='ORG'>Himmler</ent>, p. 209). Why we should not accept labor
assignment in the <ent type='LOC'>East</ent> to mean labor assignment in the <ent type='LOC'>East</ent> is
not explained.
According to Reitlinger, and others, innumerable directives
actually specifying extermination then passed between <ent type='ORG'>Himmler</ent>,
<ent type='PERSON'>Heydrich</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Eichmann</ent> and Commandant Hoess in the subsequent months
of 1942, but of course, "none have survived".</p>

<p> TWISTED WORDS AND <ent type='ORG'>GROUNDLESS</ent> ASSUMPTIONS</p>

<p> The complete lack of documentary evidence to support the
existence of an extermination plan has led to the habit of re-interpreting the documents that do survive. For example, it is
held that a document concerning deportation is not about
deportation at all, but a cunning way of talking about
extermination. <ent type='ORG'>Manvell</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Frankl</ent> state that "various terms were
used to camouflage genocide. These included "<ent type='ORG'>Aussiedlung</ent>"
(desettlement) and "Abbeforderung" (removal)" (ibid, p. 265).
Thus, as we have seen already, words are no longer assumed to
mean what they say if they prove too inconvenient. This kind
of thing is taken to the most incredible extremes, such as their
interpretation of Heydrich's directive for labor assignment in
the east. Another example is a reference to Himmler's order for
sending deportees to the <ent type='LOC'>East</ent>, "that is, having them killed"
(ibid, p. 251). Reitlinger, equally at a loss for evidence, does
exactly the same, declaring that from the "circumlocutionary"
words of the Wannsee conference it is obvious that "the slow
murder of an entire race was intended" (ibid, p. 98).
A review of the documentary situation is important, because
it reveals the edifice of guesswork and baseless assumptions
upon which the extermination legend is built. The <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>s had an
extraordinary propensity for recording everything on paper in
the most careful detail, yet among the thousands of captured
documents of the S.D. and <ent type='ORG'>Gestapo</ent>, the records of the <ent type='PERSON'>Reich</ent>
Security Head Office, the files of Himmler's headquarters and
Hitler's own war directives there is not a single order for the
extermination of <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> or anyone else. It will be seen later that
this has, in fact, been admitted by <ent type='ORG'>the World Center</ent> of
Contemporary <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> Documentation at Tel-Aviv. Attempts to find
"veiled allusions" to genocide in speeches like that of
Himmler's to his S.S. Obergruppenfuhrers at Posen in 1943 are
likewise hopeless. <ent type='GPE'>Nuremberg</ent> statements extracted after the war,
invariably under duress, are examined in the following chapter. </p></xml>