<xml><p>From COVERT ACTION INFORMATION BULLETIN Number 33
</p>
<p>
Bush's <ent type='ORG'>Boys Club</ent>: <ent type='ORG'>Skull</ent> and Bones
</p>
<p>
To be a member of the ruling elite, <ent type='PERSON'>George Bush</ent> must meet
certain criteria. He must be white, he must be male, and he must
be rich. He must also belong to certain elite clubs and
institutions which help to distinguish him from those he is
called upon to rule.
<ent type='PERSON'>George Bush</ent> is a member of <ent type='ORG'>Skull</ent> and Bones, an elite
secret society open only to a select 15 males in their senior
year at <ent type='ORG'>Yale University</ent>. If this club appears somewhat
exclusionary, don't worry; they have made great strides in the
past few years. Recent Bones inductees include a few blacks,
gays, and even some foreign students. However, it has been said
that if women were ever allowed into the secret "tomb" (meeting
place) of <ent type='ORG'>Skull</ent> and Bones, the tomb would "have to be
bulldozed."
The importance of <ent type='ORG'>Skull</ent> and Bones is not that it provides
good gossip about young males doing strange things in tombs, but
that it provides a certain bond between members which they carry
for life. Membership to <ent type='ORG'>Skull</ent> and Bones is the first initiation
into the world of power politics and capitalism. It is somewhat
akin to a "junior" old boys' network.
One of the interesting aspects of this secret society is
the number of Bones members who, after graduation, move on to do
intelligence work. There has even been informed speculation that
there is a "Bones cell" in the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>.
Whether there is a Bones cell or not in the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> is open to
interesting debate. We can, however, examine the histories of
several <ent type='PERSON'>Bonesmen</ent> who have gone on to illustrious careers in
intelligence work.
One of the most unusual <ent type='PERSON'>Bonesmen</ent> is the Reverend <ent type='PERSON'>William</ent>
Sloane Coffin, Jr. Known best for his anti-<ent type='GPE'>Vietnam</ent> war activities
and his political activism at <ent type='ORG'>Riverside Church</ent> in <ent type='GPE'>New York City</ent>,
Sloane Coffin was recruited by the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> shortly after he graduated
from <ent type='ORG'>Yale</ent> in 1949. Although his tenure at the <ent type='ORG'>Agency</ent> was short,
he is one example of the CIA's use of the secret society to fill
their ranks.
Another illustrious <ent type='ORG'>Skull</ent> and Bones member with close ties
to the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> is arch-conservative and reknowned propagandist
<ent type='PERSON'>William</ent> F. <ent type='ORG'>Buckley</ent>. According to several experts on the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>,
<ent type='ORG'>Buckley</ent> began his cooperation with the <ent type='ORG'>Agency</ent> while he was in
<ent type='GPE'>Mexico City</ent> in 1952, where his good friend, E. Howard Hunt, was
<ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> station chief at the time.
As an interesting aside, <ent type='ORG'>Buckley</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent> (as well as many
other <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent> and business elites) are members of the
"prestigious" older-boys <ent type='GPE'>California</ent> getaway, "The Bohemian
Club."
It is not surprising, given the <ent type='ORG'>Buckley</ent> family's wealth and
status, that Bill's older brother, James <ent type='ORG'>Buckley</ent>, is also a
member of <ent type='ORG'>Skull</ent> and Bones. From 1981-82 <ent type='ORG'>Buckley</ent> was Under
Secretary of State for Security Assistance, Science, and
Technology where it was his job to see the U.S. military aid went
to support the right regimes.
He once stated that <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> covert activities in <ent type='GPE'>Chile</ent>, which
led to the overthrow of democratically-elected <ent type='PERSON'>Salvador Allende</ent>,
were necessary because, "It was only by virtue of covert help by
<ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States that these free institutions were able to
survive in the face of increasingly repressive measures by the
<ent type='PERSON'>Allende</ent> regime."
<ent type='ORG'>Buckley</ent> was also directly connected to the work of the
<ent type='GPE'>Chile</ent>an secret police, <ent type='ORG'>DINA</ent>. In September 1976, <ent type='ORG'>DINA</ent> agents
assassinated former <ent type='GPE'>Chile</ent>an diplomat <ent type='PERSON'>Orlando Letelier</ent> and his
colleague, <ent type='PERSON'>Ronni Moffitt</ent>, in <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent> DC. "Independent
researchers verified through the <ent type='ORG'>FBI</ent> and Department of Justice --
that on September 14, 1976, one week before the <ent type='PERSON'>Letelier</ent>
assassination, <ent type='PERSON'>Michael Townley</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Guillermo Novo</ent> [two <ent type='ORG'>DINA</ent>
agents involved in the assassination] drove to the office of
Senator James <ent type='ORG'>Buckley</ent> in <ent type='GPE'>New York City</ent> for a meeting. <ent type='ORG'>Buckley</ent> had
helped finance trips to <ent type='GPE'>Chile</ent> for <ent type='ORG'>Novo</ent> and others close to the
killing."
When <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> agent <ent type='PERSON'>David Atlee Phillips</ent> was accused of being
involved in the assassination he started an organization
entitled "<ent type='ORG'>Challenge</ent>: An Intelligence Officers' Legal Action
Fund." The board of "<ent type='ORG'>Challenge</ent>" included former <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> director
<ent type='PERSON'>William</ent> Colby, former <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> Inspector General <ent type='PERSON'>Lyman Kirkpatrick</ent>,
former intelligence officer General <ent type='PERSON'>Richard Stillwell</ent>, and
interestingly, James <ent type='ORG'>Buckley</ent>.
<ent type='PERSON'>Hugh Cunningham</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Bonesman</ent> from the class of 1934, is a
Rhodes Scholar with a lengthy career in the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>. He was in the
<ent type='ORG'>Agency</ent> from 1947 to 1973 during which time he served in top
positions with the Clandestine Services, <ent type='ORG'>the Board</ent> of National
Estimates, and was the Director of Training from 1969-73. He also
served with the CIA's precursor, <ent type='ORG'>the Central Intelligence Group</ent>,
from 1945-47.
<ent type='PERSON'>William</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Bundy</ent> is a <ent type='PERSON'>Bonesman</ent> from the class of 1939. <ent type='PERSON'>Bundy</ent>
began his intelligence career in the <ent type='ORG'>OSS</ent> during <ent type='EVENT'>World War</ent> II.
From 1951-61 he worked at the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>, including at its Office of
National Estimates. During the <ent type='GPE'>Vietnam</ent> War, he was the Assistant
Secretary of State for Asian Affairs and a vocal advocate for
escalating the war.
A true <ent type='EVENT'>Cold War</ent> liberal, <ent type='PERSON'>Bundy</ent> expressed his belief in the
necessity of <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> covert actions in his foreword to the book "The
Counter-Insurgency Era": "The preservation of liberal values, for
<ent type='GPE'>America</ent> and other nations, required the use of the full range of
U.S. power, including, if necessary, its more shady
applications." "<ent type='ORG'>Shady</ent> applications" is a veiled euphemism for
covert activities which support dictators, overthrow legitimate
governments, and contribute to the destabilization of world
order.
From the class of 1950 comes <ent type='PERSON'>Bonesman</ent> Dino <ent type='PERSON'>Pionzio</ent>. His
claim to fame was the time he spent as <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> deputy chief of
station in <ent type='GPE'>Santiago</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Chile</ent>, in 1970, during the massive <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>
destabilization of the <ent type='PERSON'>Allende</ent> government. He is also a member of
the Association of Former Intelligence Officers. The <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> proved
not to be lucrative enough for <ent type='PERSON'>Pionzio</ent> so he left his
intelligence career behind and became an investment banker. As of
1983, he was a vice president at the investment firm <ent type='ORG'>Dillon</ent>,
Read. (Just to illustrate how small these circles really are --
<ent type='PERSON'>Nicholas Brady</ent>, the current Secretary of the <ent type='ORG'>Treasury</ent>, was the
co-chair of <ent type='ORG'>Dillon</ent>, Read, and a graduate of <ent type='ORG'>Yale University</ent>.
Brady, however, was not a <ent type='PERSON'>Bonesman</ent>. He belonged to another <ent type='ORG'>Yale</ent>
secret society called "Book and Snake.")
From the days of <ent type='PERSON'>George Bush</ent>'s father, Prescott <ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent>, comes
former spook F. <ent type='PERSON'>Trubee Davidson</ent>. <ent type='PERSON'>Davidson</ent>, a <ent type='PERSON'>Bonesman</ent> from the
class of 1918, was the Director of Personnel at the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> in 1951.
<ent type='PERSON'>Davidson</ent> then begot little <ent type='PERSON'>Bonesmen</ent>, Endicott Peabody <ent type='PERSON'>Davidson</ent>
and Daniel Pomeroy <ent type='PERSON'>Davidson</ent>. Endicott <ent type='PERSON'>Davidson</ent> went to work at
the law firm of <ent type='ORG'>Winthrop</ent>, Stimson, Putnam, and <ent type='PERSON'>Roberts</ent> (Henry
Stimson was the Secretary of War during <ent type='EVENT'>World War</ent> II and also a
<ent type='PERSON'>Bonesman</ent>.)
Another interesting <ent type='PERSON'>Bonesman</ent> is <ent type='PERSON'>David Lyle Boren</ent>, the
Senate <ent type='NORP'>Democrat</ent> from <ent type='GPE'>Oklahoma</ent>. While he is not an employee of the
<ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> (some say this is open to question), <ent type='PERSON'>Boren</ent> nevertheless is
part of the intelligence community because he is the chair of the
Select Committee on Intelligence.
Finally, but certainly not the end of the list, comes
<ent type='PERSON'>Richard</ent> A. <ent type='PERSON'>Moore</ent>. <ent type='PERSON'>Moore</ent> began his intelligence career in World
War II where he served as a special assistant to the chief of
military intelligence. He was rewarded for this service with the
Legion of Merit for Intelligence Work.
In the 1970s, <ent type='PERSON'>Moore</ent> was special assistant to President
<ent type='PERSON'>Nixon</ent> and in the thick of things during the <ent type='EVENT'>Watergate</ent> scandal. At
his recent congressional confirmation hearing for the post of
Ambassador to <ent type='GPE'>Ireland</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Moore</ent> was asked by one of the committee
members if he was one of 14 unnamed and unindicted
co-conspirators of the <ent type='EVENT'>Watergate</ent> scandal. <ent type='PERSON'>Moore</ent>, however,
emphatically denied the accusation. It is interesting to note
that <ent type='PERSON'>Moore</ent>, a <ent type='PERSON'>Bonesman</ent> from 1936, was recently appointed to a
high-level State Department post by <ent type='PERSON'>George Bush</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Bonesman</ent>, 1948.
The list of <ent type='PERSON'>Bonesmen</ent>-made-good goes on and on and includes
McGeorge <ent type='PERSON'>Bundy</ent> (<ent type='ORG'>National Security Advisor</ent> to <ent type='PERSON'>Kennedy</ent> and
<ent type='PERSON'>Johnson</ent>), <ent type='PERSON'>William</ent> Draper (<ent type='ORG'>Defense Department Import</ent>-Export Bank,
etc.), <ent type='ORG'>Dean Witter</ent>, Jr. (investment banker), <ent type='ORG'>Potter Stewart</ent>
(<ent type='ORG'>Supreme Court</ent> Justice who swore in <ent type='PERSON'>George Bush</ent> as Vice
President in 1981), <ent type='PERSON'>John Forbes Kerry</ent> (Senator from
<ent type='GPE'>Massachusetts</ent>), <ent type='PERSON'>Winston Lord</ent> (<ent type='PERSON'>Kissinger</ent> protege and former
Ambassador to <ent type='GPE'>China</ent>), Robert H. Gow (president of <ent type='PERSON'>Zapata Oil</ent>,
once owned by <ent type='PERSON'>Bush</ent> and which had possible links to the <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent>), and
<ent type='PERSON'>Henry Luce</ent> of Time-Life fame.
This old (and new) boys network helps to illustrate the old
adage "it's not what you know, it's who you know." Given the
extent of Bones members in intelligence, it is also "how you come
to know it." </p></xml>