<xml><p>
--SOVIET <ent type='ORG'>SCALAR ELECTROMAGNETIC</ent> WEAPONS--
</p>
<p>
This briefing presents the basic concepts of <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Scalar</ent>
electromagnetic weapons, some of the major types available, and evidence of
their widespread testing.
</p>
<p>
- <ent type='ORG'>Scalar Electromagnetics</ent> is Electrogravitation -
</p>
<p>
<ent type='ORG'>Scalar</ent> electromagnetics is an extension of present electromagnetics (EM)
to include gravitation. That is, a unified electrogravitation, and, what is
more important, it is a unified engineering theory. Its basis was discovered
by <ent type='ORG'>Nikola</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent>. </p>

<p> In the scalar EM extension, EM field energy can be turned into
gravitational field energy and vice versa. This exchange can be patterned and
localized, in specific areas and objects. Such a controlled change of
electromagnetics to gravitation is not possible in the normal EM or physics
presently taught in <ent type='NORP'>Western</ent> textbooks. However, the bits and pieces of the
theory have been scattered through the physics literature for some time, but
no orthodox western scientist seems to have realized that these anomalous
portions could be integrated into a startling new physics. Unorthodox
experimenters, inventors, and scientists have made discoveries in this arena
for several decades, but again have not realized the exact implications or
the precise manner in which their results could be combined with present
electrical physics.
</p>
<p>
- Fer-De-Lance -
</p>
<p>
Such sluggishness is certainly not present in the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> Union. For
over three decades, the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> Union has been developing electrogravitation
and app,ying it to develop strange new s%cret weapons of incredible power
and capability. They have sustained the largest weapons development program
ever launched by any nation, and they have kept it effectively hidden from
prying western eyes. I have called this program "Fer-De-Lance", after the
deadly <ent type='NORP'>South American</ent> pit viper of the same name. </p>

<p> The dreaded fer-de-lance is a snake of great agility and lethal effect.
It often ambushes its hapless prey, and strikes unexpectedly and without
warning. Its first sudden strike is usually lethal to its victim, which
promptly expires in writhing agony. Since the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> development of scalar EM
weapons has been designed for the same purpose, the name seems appropriate. </p>

<p> The equivalent effort of about seven <ent type='GPE'>Manhattan</ent> projects has been poured
into fer-de-lance by the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent>s, and the program has been successful almost
beyond imagination. The eerie weapons are now developed, deployed, and
tested. The ambush has been completed; Fer-de-Lance is coiled and ready to
strike.
</p>

<p>--<ent type='ORG'>ENERGETICS</ent> AND DIRECTED ENERGY WEAPONS (DEW'S)--
</p>
<p>
The ordinary <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> name for this type of weapons science is
energetics. In the west that term is believed to be associated with
conventional directed energy weapons (<ent type='ORG'>DEW</ent>s) such as particle beam weapons,
lasers, radio-frequency (RF) directed energy devices, etc. The <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent>s do not
limit the term in this way. </p>

<p> <ent type='NORP'>Western</ent> scientists are familiar only with directed energy weapons
where fragments, masses, photons, or particles travel through space and
contact the target to deliver their effects. Hence in their thinking they
limit the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> term "energetics" to the type of weapons they themselves
understand -- exotic but normal weapons using energy or mass traveling
through space to impact a target. </p>

<p> However, it is possible to focus the potential for the effects of a
weapon through spacetime itself, in a manner so that mass and energy do not
"travel through space" from the transmitter to the target at all. Instead,
ripples and patterns in the fabric of spacetime itself are manipulated to
meet and interfere in and at the local spacetime of some distant target.
There interference of these ripple patterns creates the desired energetic
effect (hence the term energetics) directly in and through the target itself,
emerging from the very spacetime (vacuum) in which the target is imbedded at
its distant location. As used by the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent>s, energetics refers to these
eerie new superweapons, as well as to the more mundane <ent type='ORG'>DEW</ent>s known to the
west. </p>

<p> As a consequence of the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> breakthrough and decades of feverish
development, monstrous strategic weapons undreamed of in the <ent type='LOC'>West</ent> are
already in <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> hands. A noose is slowly and steadily being tightened about
our throats, and it is already the 11th hour.
</p>
<p>
--THE <ent type='NORP'>SOVIETS</ent> USE A DECEPTION PLAN--
</p>
<p>
Concomitant with this <ent type='ORG'>supersecret</ent> development program, the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent>s
developed and implemented an elaborate deception plan to conceal these
startling weapons and their nature from <ent type='NORP'>Western</ent> eyes until it is too late.
<ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> deception has been so successful that even when <ent type='NORP'>Western</ent> scientists are
confronted with the actual tests of these weapons directly over their heads,
they do not recognize the weaponry nor the nature of the effects produced.
</p>
<p>
As early as January 1960, <ent type='PERSON'>Nikita Khrushchev</ent> announced the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent>
development of a new, fantastic weapon. </p>

<p> On April 10 1963 one of the first new superweapons operationally
deployed was used to destroy the U.S.S. Thresher atomic submarine
underwater, off <ent type='LOC'>the east coast</ent> of the U.S. The next day, April 11, 1963 the
same deployed superweapon was utilized in a different mode to produce a giant
underwater explosion in the ocean over the <ent type='NORP'>Puerto Rican</ent> Trench, 100 miles
north of <ent type='GPE'>Puerto Rico</ent>. </p>

<p> Over the years, various aircraft were interfered with or downed as
tests of these <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> weapons. A particular case involved the mysterious
loss of F-111s in the <ent type='GPE'>Vietnam</ent> conflict. At least one downed F-111 crew was
recovered in the subsequent prisoner of war exchange. On that aircraft all
electrical systems were in difficulty simultaneously. This was probably due
to special <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> teams converting some <ent type='PERSON'>North</ent> <ent type='GPE'>Vietnam</ent>ese SA-2 missile system
radars to the scalar EM mode, and employing "scalar beam" interference to
produce spurious EM noise throughout the electrical and electronic systems of
the aircraft. </p>

<p> In late April/early May of 1985, the entire armada of <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> strategic
scalar EM superweapons was activated as a special celebration of the 40th
anniversary of the end of W.W.II. Activation of this armada (which probably
contained over 100 giant weapons), together with 27 giant power systems and a
large number of command and control transmissions, was monitored on an
advanced, proprietary detection system by <ent type='PERSON'>Frank Golden</ent>. After the gigantic
strategic exercise, which lasted several days, most of the weapons and power
sources were once again stood down to "standby." </p>

<p> The <ent type='ORG'>NASA</ent> shuttle launches provided an convenient opportunity for <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent>
testing of these superweapons in a launch phase ABM mode, where a launched
missile can be detected and destroyed shortly after liftoff. At first,
electromagnetic pulse (EMP) bursts on the early shuttle trajectory were
deliberately delayed in time, to prevent actual destruction of the target and
avoid alerting the U.S. that something unusual was happening. </p>

<p> The shuttle launch of November 26, 1985 saw a particularly significant
test of this kind. In this case, a very loud "sonic boom" or explosion
occurred over the launch site 12 minutes after shuttle liftoff, when the
shuttle was already away and downrange. At least two previous shuttle
launches had also been used as pseudotargets, with delayed booms occurring
over the launch site well behind the vehicles. </p>

<p> After lack of U.S. reaction to these tests showed that the U.S. still
had no knowledge of the new technology and did not even recognize its
employment, the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent>s apparently decided to proceed with tests where the
target would actually be destroyed. </p>

<p> On December 12, 1985 the same <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> weapon tested against the <ent type='ORG'>NASA</ent>
shuttle launches deliberately interfered with the controls of an Arrow DC-8
taking off from Gander Air Force Base, <ent type='ORG'>Newfoundland</ent>. At an altitude of 100
feet, the aircraft--carrying over 250 U.S. soldiers and civilian crew
members lost power and sank into the ground tail-low, killing everyone on
board. Three Canadian witnesses to the crash were interviewed over the
Canadian Broadcast Corporation's television news on April 81986 at 10 p.m.
No flame or smoke issued from the plane before its descent and crash. However
the aircraft was seen to be mysteriously glowing with a yellow glow. That is
a signature of the use of a scalar howitzer in the "continuous EM emergence"
mode, similar to the manner in which the F-111s were downed in <ent type='GPE'>Vietnam</ent>. In
short, the DC-8s electrical systems were interfered with ny electromagnetic
noise created throughout the spacetime occupied by the aircraft. The powerful
charge created in and around the aircraft also apparently caused the loss of
two engines, one after the other. With its controls ineffective, and its
power drastically reduced, the aircraft sank to <ent type='LOC'>earth</ent>, still in its "tail
down" configuration from takeoff, and crashed and burned. The "yellow glow"
was a corona due to the acquisition of a high electrical charge by the skin
of the aircraft. </p>

<p> Other factors contributing to the crash may have been reduced lift due
to poor engine maintenance, increased weight of the aircraft due to icing,
and heavy loading. Still, no one has recognized the significance of the
"yellow glow" or what it implies, or the possible connection between the loss
of the aircraft and previous <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> testing of a Launch Phase ABM system
against U.S. shuttle launches...
</p>

<p> As of September 1987, the last two <ent type='ORG'>Air Force Titan</ent> 34-D missiles fired
from Vandenburg Air Force Base in <ent type='GPE'>California</ent> have blown up shortly after
launch. The first one blew up on Aug. 28, 1985 just after lift-off. That loss
had been attributed to failure of a high powered fuel pump, causing a massive
oxidizer leak and a smaller fuel leak. The second Titan loss occurred on
April 18, 1986 when the missile blew up 5 seconds after lift off. Its loss is
still under investigation and no determination of cause has been made.
Apparently the shuttle and the Titan presently provide the only viable launch
vehicles for launching U.S. "spy" satellites. The loss of these sensitive
satellites--if indeed they constituted the payloads--cannot help but be
damaging to our strategic capability. According to <ent type='ORG'>the Los Angeles</ent> Times
(in 1986) the single remaining KH-11 satellite was launched in December 1984
and, with an expected life of two to three years, could stop functioning
later this year. </p>

<p> Whether or not significant <ent type='ORG'>Woodpecker</ent> grid activity existed in the
vicinity of the Titan launch of August 1985 is unknown at this time. However,
significant activity in the grid definitely occurred before the April 18
Titan disaster and on the same day. </p>

<p> On Easter <ent type='LOC'>Sunday</ent>, Mar. 301986 engineer <ent type='PERSON'>Ron Cole</ent> observed significant
correlated with <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Woodpecker</ent> measurements. On April 18, T.E Bearden,
perhaps the head of SEM research today, observed traces of a cloud radial
over Huntsville, <ent type='GPE'>Alabama</ent> and took photographs of it. Preliminary reports from
Thousand Oaks Ca. indicate extensive grid activity again on April 18, the day
the second Titan exploded. </p>

<p> At least the second of these two missile destructions shortly after
launch is suspicious, since the grid positively was active during that time.
Also, a clear trail of Launch Phase ABM system indicators exists back to the
massive scalar exercise of April/May 1985. The first Titan explosion in Aug.
1985 thus falls within the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent>s "now lets test them against the U.S.
launch vehicles" period. The second Titan loss follows highly suspicious
losses of the Arrow DC-8 on Dec. 12, 1985 and the Challenger on Jan. 28,
1986. The same <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> weapon that destroyed those #gets may have also
destroyed one or both of the critical <ent type='NORP'>Titans</ent>. </p>

<p> The <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent>s also have been able to significantly engineer the weather
over <ent type='PERSON'>North</ent> America for more than a decade without being found out. They have
tested a fantastic range of anti-ballistic missile (ABM) defense weapons for
over two decades, and no one is the wiser in the <ent type='LOC'>West</ent>. </p>

<p> As previously stated, prior to the end of November, 1985, at least three
"wet-run" tests of a <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> "launch phase ABM system" against actual U.S.
shuttle launches were made directly over Cape Canaveral itself, and still no
one recognized what was happening or what sort of weapon was being tested. On
December 12, destruction of the Arrow DC-8 in <ent type='ORG'>Newfoundland</ent> produce no
indications that the <ent type='NORP'>Americans</ent> and Canadians knew anything about the nature
of the weapon possibly used. </p>

<p> Accordingly, after a sufficient wait to test our reactions (if any), the
<ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent>s prepared to actually destroy a shuttle after its launch... </p>

<p>--DESTRUCTION OF THE CHALLENGER, JANUARY, 1986--
</p>
<p>
As the whole world knows, on January 28, 1986 the Challenger was
launched from Cape Canaveral <ent type='GPE'>Florida</ent> after exposure to undesirable weather
conditions, and disastrously exploded shortly after launch. The evidence
seems to indicate that , as the rising vehicle was stressed, one end of its
right booster broke loose, twisting away and into the main fuel tank, causing
rupture, spillage of the fuel, and catastrophic explosion. Several other
anomalies still exist however, and it is clear that a problem existed with at
least one of the booster seals. All seven astronauts aboard the flight were
killed in the fiery destruction of the vehicle. </p>

<p> Of course no one had recognized that the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent>s had already tested a
launch-phase anti-ballistic missile (<ent type='ORG'>LPABM</ent>) system against three of our
previous shuttle launches. These "wet-runs" used a deliberate "time-offset"
to delay the explosive emergence of electromagnetic energy in a launched
shuttle's location along its trajectory. The delayed test shots resulted in
very large "booms" above the launch site after the shuttle was safely out of
the area, but did not destroy the shuttles themselves. For example, the
delayed shot-boom occurred 12 minutes after the evening launch of Nov. 26,
1985. Even a marker beacon (large light in the sky) was utilized on that
launch shortly after lift-off. The marker beacon was photographed. In
addition another photograph taken in a time sequence shows another sudden
streak of light coming down and ending in a burst of light. This was probably
a spacially-offset test of the "pulse mode" for destroying the shuttle. The
"light burst" would have been detected in the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> Union and scored against
its intended offset position. However, another mechanism was used to cause
the destruction of the shuttle itself. </p>

<p> On Jan. 1, 1986 the presence of a metal softening signal added on to the
<ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> <ent type='ORG'>LPABM</ent> systems scalar EM transmissions was detected by a surprised
<ent type='PERSON'>Frank Golden</ent>. The metal softening ability of the detected signal was
experimentally verified by him at that time. Golden also locally nullified
the action of the scalar EM signal in a test, rather conclusively
establishing (1) that it existed and (2) what it was. The signal was
apparently being prepared for use against an upcoming U.S. shuttle launch. </p>

<p> Just prior to the launch of the shuttle in late January, 1986, the
<ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent>s accomplished significant weather engineering over the U.S. The jet
stream was severely bent southward in the middle of the U.S., bending right-ward again to move across the <ent type='GPE'>Florida</ent> panhandle. Icy cold air from <ent type='GPE'>Canada</ent> was
drawn far down, into <ent type='GPE'>Florida</ent> and onto the Challenger sitting on it launch
pad. This exposure to cold outside its tested range was probably an
additional factor contributing to the Challengers failure. Positive
signatures of the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> weather engineering and jet stream manipulation
were observed and photographed by several persons, particularly in <ent type='GPE'>Alabama</ent>
and <ent type='GPE'>California</ent>...
</p>

<p> On January 28, 1986, the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> scalar EM weapon system effects were
sharply localized in the launch zone. Localization involved higher
frequencies being present; these are quite painful to small brains--whose
hemispheres act as a scalar interferometer and detector--such as in birds.
As commented upon by national news commentators, strangely the birds were not
flying that morning. Indeed, they were staying down on the ground or avoiding
the area, since the sky over the area was painful to them. </p>

<p> As Challenger rose, the metal softening signal would have been
experienced in and around the boosters shortly after ignition, since the
booster flame acts as a special "ion-plasma" tuner/detector for the scalar
signal. The effect of such a local signal is to "charge mass in the immediate
vicinity" with the particular scalar resonance signal. </p>

<p> The ill fated Challenger was doomed. After ignition, the booster flame
acted as as a ionic plasma detector/amplifier for the metal softening signal
on the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Woodpecker</ent> grid. The metal in and around the booster flame was
slowly and steadily weakening due to a charge up with the metal softening
pattern. This contributed to booster leakage from the already cold damaged
seal. The leaking booster poured out smoke and later flame, contributing to
the impending disaster. </p>

<p> Substantial winds and air turbulence over the site increased the stress
on the Challenger as it rose through this region. This also contributed to
the disaster and may have been deliberately created there by <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> Weather
engineering. </p>

<p> As the Challenger stressed, eventually one or more weakened mounts gave
way, partially freeing the end of the right booster. Another anomalous flame
or light was observed on the vehicle, and may have represented a very small
additional "pulse mode energy form" produced from the weapon that was already
attacking the Challenger. The booster oscillated, rotating into the tank and
rupturing it. Contact of the escaping liquid fuel and the flame resulted in a
fiery explosion, destroying the vehicle and killing those on board...

By creating excess cold exposure to the shuttle, inducing metal
softening in and around the ignited booster, and possibly adding a deliberate
"intensely hot spot", THE <ent type='NORP'>SOVIETS</ent> CAUSED THE CHALLENGER TO <ent type='ORG'>WEAKEN</ent> AND DESTROY
ITSELF SHORTLY AFTER LAUNCH, IN SO SUBTLE A FASHION THAT <ent type='ORG'>NASA</ent> SCIE<ent type='ORG'>NTIS</ent>TS
WOULD NOT SUSPECT WHAT HAD ACTUALLY CAUSED THE MISHAP. THE <ent type='NORP'>SOVIETS</ent> HAD ALSO
PREVIOUSLY WITHDRAWN ALL THEIR TRAWLERS AND SHIPS WHICH NORMALLY SHADOW A
<ent type='ORG'>SHUTTLE</ent> LAUNCH, TO <ent type='EVENT'>PREVENT</ent> ANY SUGGESTION OF SOVIET PRESENCE NEAR OR
INVOLVEMENT IN THE CATASTROPHIC ACCIDENT. </p>

<p> A few days later, sporadically intense "high frequency localization
signals" were still present on the grid, at least one hinge-point at
<ent type='GPE'>Birmingham</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Alabama</ent> confirmed this. From 1-4 February 1986, many birds
inadvertently flew into the zone when an intense breakout occurred, and birds
fell dead from the sky in substantial numbers....

Next:
-Technological Surprise and a <ent type='GPE'>New Hiroshima</ent>-

(Continued)</p>

<p> Sadly, the bureaucratic smugness of orthodox <ent type='NORP'>Western</ent> scientists has
materially assisted the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> deception process. Most <ent type='NORP'>Western</ent> managerial
scientists -particularly in weapons development activities - have continued
to view the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent>s as ignorant peasants, still trying to clean the mud off
their boots. This view is of course, Totally untrue and unwarranted. </p>

<p> It takes only a few examples to refute this attitude. In nonlinear
mathematics, engineering and science, the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent>s have led their <ent type='NORP'>Western</ent>
counterparts since the beginning. The electromagnetic pulse (EMP) effect of a
nuclear explosion appeared in the ordinary <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> scientific literature
before <ent type='NORP'>Western</ent> scientists were even aware that te effect existed. The <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent>s
continue to lead the world in explosive welding, titanium welding and
forming, etc. While the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> scientists exhibit little inclination to build
good washing machines, they certainly do produce state of the art
technology-- and beyond-- in any area in which they focus their main efforts.
(We do lead the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent>s in some areas such as computers hardware, computer
software, miniaturization, etc.)</p>

<p> Once before, a modern nation, <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States, developed a mighty
weapon in secrecy and used it to force a powerful foe, <ent type='GPE'>Japan</ent>, to its knees...
The mindbending atomic blows to <ent type='GPE'>Hiroshima</ent>, and <ent type='GPE'>Nagasaki</ent>, showed once and for
all that in the modern age technological surprise can prove instantly
disastrous. Yet in our scientific arrogance, we have assumed that it could
never happen to us, and that the "secret weapon" scenario will never be
repeated. On the contrary, it HAS happened again, someone else has done it,
and it has happened to us. </p>

<p> It has also become fashionable in the <ent type='LOC'>West</ent> to believe that all the
laws of physics are already discovered. We assume we know all of them. While
we have been pridefully crowing this tune, the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent>s have been steadily new
laws in secret, as well as new ways to circumvent the old laws.
Our defense is strategic, we rely on our offense. Our huge nuclear arsenal..
If this offense were nullified or destroyed by <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> secret weapons, we
would be powerless to prevent our own destruction and <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> domination of
our world.</p>

<p> We have been viewing ourselves as indestructible, confident in the
strength of our defense. Yet literally our defense has been stripped from us.
Indeed <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> energetics weapons are now capable of destroying our defense,
our homeland, our armed forces in the field, and our population, quickly and
efficiently. We have a new gap of monumental proportions: not a missile gap,
not a submarine or bomber gap, and not even a particle beam or laser gap.
We have a "<ent type='ORG'>Scalar Electromagnetics</ent> or Electrogravitation" gap.....


He that has ears, let him hear.</p>

<p> Here is the secret of antigravity.</p>

<p> The "electrical charge" of a charged particle-- such as one of the
charged particles of an atom or one of the protons of its nucleus--
represents a difference in flux intensity (potential) between the local
particle and its ambient vacuum. Its the continual bleed-off of
gravitational charge as electrical charge. If that bleed off is reversed or
stopped, a drastic effect on the gravitational charge ensues. The 5-potential
and the 5-charge have become 4-G-potential and 4-d-charge respectively. Thus
"charging" an object with its scalar EM pattern charges it gravitationally.
Now the only "bleed off channel" is through the 4-G force field. Further,
in a nucleus the nucleons continually back and forth between proton and
neutron, so the electrical charge is "spread" throughout the nucleus and
shared by all the nucleons. </p>

<p> Further, each element (actually each isotope) has its own unique
"ensemble pattern" of Fourier expansion scalar frequencies, amplitudes, ect.
This pattern can, of course, be reproduced artificially and transmitted by
modified EM transmitters). There is, however, a sort of "master key" scalar
EM (EG) pattern for nucleons (protons and neutrons which are changing back
and forth into each other by exchange of virtual charge currents). </p>

<p> If one reverses the charge by inverting this pattern, and then
"charges up a mass with the inverted charge," to the external observer the
charging mass just gets lighter and lighter, and its inertia gets less and
less. Eventually it seems (to him) to acquire negative mass and negative
inertia, and just accelerate away from the <ent type='LOC'>earth</ent>. the object falls upward
instead of falling downwards.</p>

<p> There are also some weird time effects; that object can be moving
slower through time than the laboratory observer, or even be moving backwards
through time in respect to the laboratory observer. (Don't believe everything
they taught you in relativity; none of those guys ever had engineered a
single general relativistic situation. &amp;othing they teach in GR is based on
direct experiment. Most of what they teach has already experimentally proven
to be in error. </p>

<p> This is the concept for a scalar EG detector for a scalar EG waves.
This is the Bendini scalar wave detector, adapted from an original concept by
<ent type='PERSON'>Dea</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Faretto</ent>. </p>

<p> The idea is quite simple: install a very powerful bar magnet inside a
grounded <ent type='PERSON'>Faraday</ent> cage. Then install an open-ended coil longitudally above the
magnet so that a line through the longitudal axis of the magnet passes
through the longitudal axis of the coil above it. The open end of the coil
does not touch the magnet. </p>

<p> Connect the other end of the coil to a variable tuning capacitor, so
that the coil and the capacitor form a tunable, series-L-C-oscillatory
circuit. The output of the capacitor is connected to a transistorized
preamplifier inside the cage. A tuning shaft for the capacitor is very
carefully placed through a small hole in the shield to allow tuning from
outside. </p>

<p> The output of the preamp passes through a small hole in the shield,
through a shielded cable, to an adjacent oscilloscope. The cable shield is
also grounded t a reference ground potential.

The theory is as follows: Suppose a normal EM wave appears inside
the cage, above the magnet or closely adjacent thereto. In that case a
coupled oscillation appears in the field of the magnet, and this oscillation
is coupled to the coil immediately above it. If the oscillation is within the
bandwidth of the tuned series LC circuit, detection occurs. This is amplified
by the preamp and passed to the oscilloscope, where it is displayed on the
scope. </p>

<p> Note that the detector detects normal EM wave. Now our problem is:
How do we get an EG wave to be detected? And how do we assure that we do not
detect ordinary EM waves from the outside? Actually this is simple. Ordinary
waves (except for quite low frequency) will be grounded out by the <ent type='PERSON'>Faraday</ent>
shield, and will not penetrate the cage. Thus these normal EM waves cannot
enter the cage and appear above the magnet. They will not be detected. <ent type='ORG'>Scalar</ent>
EG waves, on the other hand, will enter the cage since they do not couple to
conduction electrons in the metal of the cage. Above the pole of the magnet,
spacetime is locally bent. After all, a pole is a magnetostatic scalar
potential, which is a part of the conglomerate called "G-potential." The pole
represents an increase (or decrease, depending on whether it is a north or a
south pole) in the magnetostatic component of the local G-potential. This is a
curvature of spacetime. An EG wave entering this region adds a varying
component component of magnetostatic G-potential, which bleeds off in the coil
as an ordinary EM wave.

Another way to view the detector is to model the EG wave as a
longitudal wave, and an ordinary EM wave as a transverse wave. When the EG
wave enters the curved spacetime region above the magnet, to the coil (the
"observer" in this case!) the longitudal aspect of the EG wave appears to be
rotating back and forth, so that an oscillating transverse component is
present. This transverse component appears to the coil as an ordinary EM
field, and so the LC circuit detects it if it is in the proper frequency
band. </p>

<p> Yet another way to view the situation is to realize that an EG wave
entering the magnet results in an oscillating component added to the
magnetostatic scalar potential (pole strength) of t8e magnet. Accordingly,
the magnet is a receiver for scalar waves, which are detected to "bleed-off"
as an oscillation of the magnetic field strength of the magnet. <ent type='ORG'>Coupling</ent> of
this oscillating magnetic field to the coil creates an oscillating current
flow into the capacitor. This oscillates the vo<ent type='ORG'>ltage</ent> input to the preamp,
which amplifies and feeds the signal to the oscilloscope for display.


It is important to remember that a magnetostatic potential and an
electrostatic potential can be oscillated by a scalar EG wave. By placing a
magnetic material inside a <ent type='PERSON'>Faraday</ent> cage, the oscillation of the magnetostatic
scalar potential (pole strength of the magnet) can be used as the EG
detecting mechanism. By placing a chargeable material inside a <ent type='PERSON'>Faraday</ent> cage,
the oscillation of the electrostatic scalar potential can be detected.
(Possible examples of the latter type detectors are given by <ent type='ORG'>Hodowanec</ent>,"Radio
Electronics," April 1986.) </p>

<p> Note also that one may detect waves at one reference level and not
at another. Changing the bias on the zero-reference ground of the Bendini
detector affects the detection. To look inside a normal EM carrier (such as
the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Woodpecker</ent> carrier) and see what scalar signals are riding upon
it, the carrier may be used to bias the reference ground of the Bendini
detector. To produce a spectrum analyzer, simply use additional series
resonant LC tuning circuits in parallel (put multiple taps on the coil, and
wire each tap to a separate tuning capacitor of different capacitance).
Again, varying the zero reference level is important, as is varying the
strength of the magnet. <ent type='PERSON'>Frank Golden</ent> has also invented an excellent series of
scalar wave detectors based on quite different proprietary principles.</p>

<p> The bottom line is: we can indeed rigorously detect and measure
scalar EG waves. When one considers the large sums of money presently being
spent to bury large aluminum cylinders etc. in an attempt to detect
gravitational waves, one wonders why some funds could not be released to a
few unorthodox researchers by <ent type='ORG'>the National Academy</ent> of Sciences to fund the
proven creation and detection of electrogravitational waves... </p>

<p>(Continued)</p>

<p> Here is explained a new kind of resonance: scalar EM resonance, or
electrogravitational resonance. </p>

<p> First, imagine we have a standard resonant cavity. In this cavity we
have a resonant EM wave moving back and forth. In accordance with convention,
the E-field vector and the B-field vector are at right angles in this moving
wave front. As the wave moves back and forth, the vectors vary back and
forth; however, at any one point between the walls, the two vectors always
have the same value. Thus our resonant EM wave forms a standing wave in the
cavity. </p>

<p> Now imagine that a second wave front, precisely like the first and of
the same frequency, is superposed over the first one and travels with it.
This second wave -- the "antiwave" -- has its force vectors 180 degrees out
of phase with the force vectors of the reference wave. Hence the E-fields
and B-fields of the two superposed waves always sum to vector zeros, anywhere
in the cavity. To an external observer, the cavity contains no ordinary
electromagnetic force fields, hence no ordinary EM energy. </p>

<p> However the energy density of a single EM sine wave in vacuum is given
by:</p>

<p> density 2
[ E + B ]/8pi

This energy density is always positive. Hence the energy density of the
two waves at any point X between the walls is equal to: </p>

<p>
2 2
[ E + B ]/4pi

where

E=E(x) ; B=B(x)

Thus the energy density of vacuum varies with X. But, rigorously, since
the resultant E and B fields are zero, this describes a standing
gravitational wave. Hence we have a standing EG wave existing in the cavity.
This is an example of scalar resonance. Rigorously the cavity has mass and
inertia, to an outside observer, as a result of the two warps in spacetime it
contains. </p>

<p> Note that in one half cycle the energy density of vacuum is greater
than ambient, and in the other half cycle it is less. In the region of one
half cycle, time flows at a faster rate than to the ambient observer, and in
the other half cycle time flows at a slower rate than to the ambient
observer. One half cycle appears to contain negative electrical charge, and
the other appears to contain positive charge. </p>

<p> One half cycle appears to contain a north pole (positive magnetostatic
scalar potential), and the other half cycle appears to contain a south pole
(negative magnetostatic scalar potential). </p>

<p> Perhaps n/w one can begin to understand why a continuously accelerated
orbital electron in the atom does not radiate EM energy, completely in
violation of Maxwell's equations. The electron is naught but a complex aspect </p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>Scalar</ent> resonance is not in the conventional textbook.</p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>Scalar</ent> resonance is a particular zero summed multi-resonance,
electromagnetically, so that it does not act in an electromagnetic manner. </p>

<p> A scalar resonance is a standing electromagnetic wave. It can be made
electrically, but is not electrical in behavior.</p>

<p> In any scalar resonance, spacetime is curved, and it is the magnitude
(and direction) of this spacetime curvature that is oscillating in "standing
wave" fashion. </p>

<p> In respect to stress of the vacuum medium, one half of a standing sine
wave of scalar resonance is tensile; the other half is compressive. However,
this is with respect to the local ambient stress of the vacuum. </p>

<p> "Mass" of a particle is just a characteristic exhibited by a trapped
scalar resonance. Usually this trapping is done by the "spin" of the
individual particle. </p>

<p> The concept of "mass" may be compared with the concept of
"capacitance." That is, a mass is an accumulator for scalar waves; that is,
for scalar resonances. It is continually being "charged" and "discharged"
by absorption and emission of scalar waves from and to the ambient vacuum
scalar wave flux. </p>

<p> Indeed the magnitude of a mass may be defined in terms of the absolute
value of this "switching" (absorption = switch in; emission = switch out)
rate. For details on this see (Bearden, T.E. "Quinton/Perception Physics: A
Theory of Existence, Perception, and <ent type='ORG'>Physical Phenomena</ent>," March, 1973, AD
763210, available through <ent type='ORG'>NTIS</ent>.) </p>

<p> In the normal linear spacetime, the "charging" and "discharging" are
equal in all directions; so the mass exhibited in any direction is the same. </p>

<p> With respect to an "external observer's" equilibrium flux, a moving
object encounters an increased amount of flux rate along its line of motion,
just as a moving object in a rainstorm encounters more raindrops per second
in the direction of its path, than does a stationary object. Encountering
increased scalar wave flux (with respect to the external observer) forces the
moving object to absorb and emit scalar waves at a higher rate along its
direction of motion than when its not moving. Thus to the external observer,
the mass of the object has increased, insofar as any disturbing force along
its line of motion is concerned. </p>

<p> At right angles to its line of motion however, the flux rate is
precisely the same as when the object is at rest. Therefore the "mass" of the
moving object with respect to any disturbing force at right angles to its
line of motion has not changed, as seen by the external observer. </p>

<p> Thus is explained both parts of one of the all time great mysteries of
special relativity: (1) how the mass of an object increases with respect to
its motion, and (2) why the mass only increases with respect to its line of
motion, and not at any right angles to it. </p>

<p> The inertia of a particle is due to its mass, i.e., to the total
magnitude of its trapped scalar resonance. </p>

<p> The gravitational attraction between two masses is due to their
spacetime curvature. Further, mass is like a capacitance. It can trap
additional scalar waves as trapped resonance; hence increase its magnitude or
"inertial charge". Or, it can discharge more scalar waves than it absorbs;
hence decrease its magnitude or "internal charge"... </p>

<p> Those scalar waves emitted from resonance are emitted as a pattern
ensemble of the resonance. Hence they may be regarded as constituting a
current of scalar resonance leaving the mass accumulator object. <ent type='ORG'>Scalar</ent> waves
absorbed into trapped resonance may be regarded as constituting a current of
scalar resonance into the mass accumulator object. Thus it is proper to speak
of scalar resonance as being able to "flow". </p>

<p> Further, it is possible to increase the mass of an object directly, by
transmitting scalar EM waves to it so that it absorbs them. (By absorbing
scalar waves one means that more enter the object than leave it, so that the
object acts as an internal accumulator charging up with internal charge. This
is done by insuring the reference potential of the scalar wave transmitter is
higher than the reference potential of the irradiated object.) </p>

<p> It is also possible to decrease the mass of an object directly, by
transmitting scalar EM waves to it so that it emits more than it absorbs. (By
emitting scalar waves one means that more leave the object than enter it, so
the object acts as if it were an internal accumulator that is discharging its
internal charge. this is done by insuring that the reference potential of the
scalar transmitter is lower than the reference potential of the irradiated
object.) </p>

<p> As can be seen, the scalar wave "transmitter" is actually somewhat
comparable to a heat pump; it can either act as an "energy transmitter" or as
an "energy extractor", depending on the difference in potential between
"transmitter" and "receiver." </p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>Scalar</ent> resonance can have a specific pattern: both in frequency and in
spatial curvature aspects, as well as "rate of flow of time" aspects. Indeed,
scalar-wise every object has its individual "scalar pattern" which is a
unique fingerprint. Since that print is spatiotemporal, it is a product of
that objects entire past history. Thus --scalar wise-- no two objects are
identical. </p>

<p> This brings up another rather amazing potential: If a reasonably
precise scalar pattern of an object can be "irradiated" and resonated with
scalar waves, energy may be created in or extracted from the distant object,
just as stimulating one tuning fork can excite another at a distance by
sympathetic resonance. I leave it to you to ascertain the relavence of this
statement to clairvoyance, radionics, remote viewing, etc.</p>

<p> For the skeptic, however, we must point out that --rigorously--quantum
mechanics requires that, continually, in any localized region of spacetime,
the "pattern" of any object in the universe appears momentarily in the
virtual state, purely from statistical considerations alone. So long as the
situation remains statistical, any place in the universe can continue to have
the "ghosts" of everything present there, in an ethereally thin pattern, and
the observable world will not be affected by it. However if one can
discriminate and scalarly "charge" or "discharge" individual patterns in this
"ghost-realm", action at a distance is directly possible, as is
materialization and dematerialization. If one accepts that even thought
itself produces such virtual "ghost-patterns" in the virtual particle flux of
vacuum, then it is at least theoretically possible to materialize thoughts
and thought images.
</p>

<p> We have entered a new kind of reality where the old rules and the old
limitations do not necessarily apply. </p>

<p> As pointed out, we can greatly simplify matters by considering
'currents of scalar resonance'. These currents flow from higher potential to
lower potential, regardless of whether we are considering "transmission" or
"reception". </p>

<p> Indeed, to transmit at lower potential is to receive, and to receive
at higher potential is to transmit. Thus the "transmitter-receiver" is a
special system where simply biasing two nodes differently determines which
way the scalar resonance will flow. We may increase or decrease an object's
inertia and mass, simply by properly biasing the transmitter-receiver's two
nodes.</p>

<p> In one accidental experiment of some hours duration, Golden charged
up an area so that, locally, all clocks became erratic. This included
electrical clocks, battery driven watches, wind up kitchen clocks, and a
pendulum operated grandfather clock. The rate of flow of time itself was
apparently altered in the local area by the accumulated charge, which took
four days to drain off and discharge. At the end of four days of discharge,
all clocks and watches returned to normal.</p>

<p>(Continued)</p>

<p> If we interfere two transmitters in a region of great energy--such as
the molten core of the <ent type='LOC'>earth</ent> itself--and bias the transmitters negatively, we
can extract enormous energy directly from that distant source! </p>

<p> Indeed, a slight variation of this effect is precisely how the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent>
Union obtains the enormous energy with which to power its incredibly
powerful strategic "continent-buster" scalar EM weapons. <ent type='ORG'>Scalar</ent> frequency
pairs -- 12 kilohertz apart -- are transmitted into the <ent type='LOC'>earth</ent> itself on some
portion of the earth's "giant scalar resonance" frequency curve. Biasing the
two transmitters differently with respect to each other produces a high
potential difference (vo<ent type='ORG'>ltage</ent>) between them. At the same time, biasing them
both negative with respect to the earth's molten core produces a scalar
resonance current from the core to the two transmitters. In the "outer loop"
between the two scalar transmitters, there appears a gigantic v/<ent type='ORG'>ltage</ent> and
gigantic electrical current which can be captured by appropriate means. This
electrical power is tapped off and transmitted to incredibly powerful scalar
EM weapon systems. There, special accumulators ad switchers are utilized to
provide awesome amounts of power to each weapon. </p>

<p> Just before May 11985 the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> Union performed a "full-up"
operational test of their entire strategic scalar EM weap/ns complex. This
test was detected and monitored periodically by <ent type='PERSON'>Frank Golden</ent>. Some 27 of
these giant <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> "power taps" were locked into the molten core of the
<ent type='LOC'>earth</ent>, producing forced (entrained) scalar resonance of the entire planet on
54 controlled frequencies under our very feet. The remainder of the scalar
frequency spectrum was ablaze with literally hundreds of <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> scalar
transmitters: probably the entire strategic scalar command and control system
to underwater submarines, higher command centers, distant commands, etc. was
activated in the giant exercise. </p>

<p> For several days the system was exercised on a mind-boggling scale,
apparently as part of the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> Unions highly accentuated 40th anniversary
celebration of the end of <ent type='EVENT'>World War</ent> II. </p>

<p> Ironically, not a single U.S. intelligence agency, laboratory, or
scientist detected this monstrous exercise for the new <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> leader,
Gorbacev. Not one of them had a detector for scalar EM radiation, and not one
of them will --officially-- say that the exercise ever happened. </p>

<p>-- CREATING ENERGY AT A DISTANCE --

A most useful device is obtained if one uses a scalar inferometer where
the two transmitters transmit beams which intersect at a distance. </p>

<p> In the interference zone, an energy bottle is created.</p>

<p> By biasing the transmitter reference potentials well above that of the
distant energy bottle, EM energy emerges in that zone. In that case the
interferometer is operating in the Exothermic mode. </p>

<p> By biasing the transmitter reference potentials well below that of the
distant energy bottle, EM energy is extracted from the distant zone and
emerges from the transmitter. In that case the inferometer is operating in
the Endothermic mode.</p>

<p> If the transmitters transmit continuously, the effect in the distant
zone is continuous. </p>

<p> If each transmitter transmits a pulse, and the two pulses meet in the
distant intersection zone, then an explosive emergence or extraction of
energy occurs at the distant interference zone, depending on whether the
inferometer is operating in the exothermic or endothermic mode. </p>

<p>-- EX<ent type='ORG'>OTH</ent>ERMIC MODE (SCALAR INTERFEROMETER) --

For a scalar interferometer, "<ent type='GPE'>del phi</ent>" (the gradient of the potential)
applies between the transmitter sit and the distant intersection site, not to
the intervening space in between. Thus one speaks of "energy flow" as being
between the transmitter and intersection --without-any "in between". In the
intervening space, all energy exists as locked-in artificial potential, not
EM force field energy (gradient bleed off potential). </p>

<p> In the Exothermic mode, the ground potential of the transmitter is
biased well above the ground potential of ambient vacuum. <ent type='ORG'>Energy</ent> enters the
transmitter and "disappears", to "reappear" in the distant interference zone. </p>

<p> If continuous wave transmission is used, the energy continuously
appears in the distant zone. </p>

<p> If pulse transmission is used and timed so that the two scalar pulses
meet in the distant zone, energy explosively appears there. </p>

<p> If multiple frequencies are transmitted in the manner of a Fourier
expansion of a particular geometric form, then a 3-dimensional energy form
appears at the distant intersection. In this manner a spherical or
hemispherical shell (a globe or "dome" of EM energy) can be created at a
distance. If pulse transmission is used, this will be an impulsive or
explosive emergence of that energy form. If continuous transmission is used,
this will be a continuous glowing form. </p>

<p> By feeding incredibly powerful transmitters with large amounts of
energy extracted from the earth's molten core by "energy taps," very large
spherical globes and hemispherical domes of EM energy can be created at a
distance. The energy in the interference "shell" of such a sphere or
hemisphere is sufficiently dense to lift Dirac matter from the Dirac sea of
the vacuum. Thus the shell contains a glowing plasma. </p>

<p> Many such scalar howitzer signatures have been seen over the oceans,
particularly over the north <ent type='LOC'>Pacific</ent> by jet airliners flying into and out of
<ent type='GPE'>Japan</ent>. (Remember some months ago the big story about the <ent type='ORG'>JAL</ent> flight in which
all passengers and crew saw a giant spherical "<ent type='EVENT'>UFO</ent>".) Also such globes and
domes of light have been seen deep within the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> Union, by observers in
<ent type='GPE'>Afghanistan</ent> and by pilots of aircraft landing in <ent type='GPE'>Iran</ent>. </p>

<p> In the impulsive exothermic mode, a large visible flash will occur if
EM energy in the visible spectrum is produced. "Flashes" in the infrared may
similarly occur, if the emerging energy is in that spectral band. In
September 1979 our <ent type='PERSON'>Vela</ent> satellites detected such a large "nuclear flash" over
the <ent type='LOC'>South Atlantic</ent>, off the southern coast of <ent type='LOC'>Africa</ent>. A second "nuclear
flash" detected by the <ent type='PERSON'>Vela</ent> satellites in 1980 was in the infrared only. Some
years ago, a series of anomalous "flashes" and "booms" occurred off the east
coast of <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States. The were due to the orientation and alignment --
and registration -- of one or more "scalar howitzers" -- scalar EM
interferometers in the exothermic mode. </p>

<p> Large "booms" occurred over the shuttle launch site at Cape Canaveral,
associated with three shuttle launches prior to the end of November 1985.
These were tests of such exothermic scalar EM howitzers, being tested as part
of the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> Launch Phase ABM system. In that mode, the scalar pulses from
the two transmitters are injected into special zero-reference scalar EM
"channels" established in the EM carriers of the <ent type='ORG'>Woodpecker</ent> over-the-horizon
radars. The scalar pulses travel through these channels, traveling in the
ordinary EM beam of the transmitter and following it in its curvature around
the <ent type='LOC'>earth</ent> in the <ent type='LOC'>earth</ent>-ionospheric waveguide. The scalar pulses are timed,
phased, and oriented so as to meet the rising shuttle. In these tests the
transmissions were offset in time so the shuttle would not actually be
destroyed, but the system could be tested against actual shuttle launches in
the U.S.

The specific uses of these various exothermic modes will be covered in
later parts of this series. </p>

<p> In the endothermic mode, the bias on the transmitters is such that
energy is extracted from the distant intersection zone, to re-emerge from the
transmitters. There the energy must be caught and disposed of if it is not to
burn out the transmitters. When very large amounts of energy are extracted
from distant points, the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent>s often use a "dump" method of temporarily
capturing, and storing in an accumulator, the heat energy emerging at the
transmitters. A second howitzer in the exothermic mode is then fed by a
"scalar energy tap" established into the accumulator. This howitzer is
focused on the distant dump site -- often <ent type='LOC'>Bennett Island</ent>, where exhausts are
continually observed by U.S. weather satellites. </p>

<p> In the impulsive endothermic mode, energy is impulsively extracted from
the distant intersection zone. In the atmosphere this results in a very sharp
cooling or "cold explosion". It also results in the type of boom and rumble
often associated with thunder after a lightning bolt. </p>

<p> On April 9, 1984 the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> Union tested such a "cold explosion" off
the coast of <ent type='GPE'>Japan</ent>, near the <ent type='LOC'>Kuril Islands</ent>. In the suddenly induced low
pressure "cold zone" above the ocean, ocean water was sharply sucked up from
the ocean, forming a dense cloud. Then air rushing into the low pressure zone
forced the cloud upward, forming a mushroom much like that of an atomic
explosion except for the absence of a flash and the absence of a shockwave
moving out and away from the center of the explosion. </p>

<p> As the cloud rises, it expands by mixing -- very similar to a giant
thunderhead buildup, except much faster. In this case the cloud rose to about
60000 feet in about 2 minutes, spreading out until it reached a diameter of
about 200 miles. The incident was seen by the pilots and crews of several
<ent type='ORG'>Boeing</ent> 747 jet airliners in the general vicinity. Sometime after that, a U.S.
weather satellite photo of the area occurred. The cloud in that photo has an
anomalous density distribution, differing from that of all other clouds in
the area... </p>

<p>(Continued)</p>

<p>--TESLA'S "BIG EYE" FOR REMOTE VIEWING--

<ent type='ORG'>Nikola</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent> planned a very special use for his endothermic scalar
interferometer. He planned to produce what he called his "big eye to see at a
distance." </p>

<p> The system used to accomplish this is only weakly endothermic, so that
only a small amount of energy is extracted from the distant target. Also, the
beams are "scanned" by an open receiver, timewise, from side to side and top
to bottom. By scanning yet another single beam through the intersection zone
and phasing its pulses, an even better representation can be obtained. Thus
the receiver produces a representation of the energy extracted from various
locations within the distant endothermic zone. By displaying the received
signals on an appropriately scanned screen, a representation of the distant
scene can be created. This is a special kind of "microwave interferometry,"
and -- with modern techniques -- the imagery obtained can be surprisingly
good. </p>

<p> With development, it might even become as good as the image presently
obtained by side looking acquisition radars. </p>

<p> Interestingly enough, since scalar beams will easily penetrate the <ent type='LOC'>earth</ent>
or the ocean, one can also look beneath the <ent type='LOC'>earth</ent> or ocean with this type of
scanning scalar interferometer.

The importance of this capability to strategic and tactical
reconnaissance is obvious. <ent type='ORG'>Camouflage</ent>, cover, and concealment have no effect
on such a system. One can easily look into buildings and into underground
facilities. With a small system such as this, the U.S. Marines at <ent type='PERSON'>Khe Sahn</ent>
would have had little difficulty locating the tunnels continually dug under
the perimeter by the <ent type='GPE'>Viet Cong</ent>. And targets under jungle canopies are
directly visible...

It requires little imagination to see that this system is easily
adapted for use underwater. A type of "underwater radar." With such devices,
the problem posed by the underwater nuclear submarine is solved. For example,
an entire area can be continually searched, much like acquisition radar
systems do now. A submarine can be detected and tracked, and none of its
ordinary detectors will detect anything out of the ordinary. By using a
separate pair of beams in the exothermic mode, powerful scalar pulses can be
fired at the distant sub, intersecting at the submarine in a violent EMP
throughout the sub and its armament. Thus the sub and all of its missiles
are destroyed instantly. </p>

<p> Or, continuous exothermic transmission can be used by the targeting
weapon at lesser power, gradually interfering with the sub's electrical
systems and causing it to loose control. The sub then sinks to crush depths
and implodes. </p>

<p> Precisely that scenario seems to be what happened on April 10, 1963 to
the U.S.S. Thresher nuclear submarine. It left a signature: the subs nearby
surface companion, the U.S.S. <ent type='ORG'>Skylark</ent>, was in the "splatter zone" of the
underwater scalar interference. That is, spurious EM noise was being
generated in all the Skylark's electrical systems, some of which were
actually disabled. So intense was the "electronic jamming" that it required
over an hour and a half for the <ent type='ORG'>Skylark</ent> to transmit an emergency message
back to its headquarters that the Thresher was n serious trouble and contact
with it had been lost. Some of the Skylark's communication systems actually
failed, but later resumed operation inexplicably, once the jamming was gone.
That type of "jamming" of multiple bands and multiple electronic equipment,
of course, together with the anomalous failure of electronic equipment and
its later mysterious recovery, were direct signatures of the exothermic
scalar interferometer against thee undersea target in the vicinity of the
skylark. </p>

<p> The very next day, April 111963, the same <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> scalar EM howitzer
system was tested in the "destroy submarine" pulse mode. A huge underwater EM
blast occurred off the coast of <ent type='GPE'>Puerto Rico</ent>, about 100 miles north of the
island. The underwater explosion caused a huge boiling of the surface of the
ocean, followed by the rising up of a giant mushroom of water about a third
of a mile high, the mushroom of water then fell back into the ocean,
completing the signature. </p>

<p> Fortunately the entire incident was seen by the startled crew of a
passing U.S. jetliner which was just passing its checkpoint in that area.
(See Robert J.Durant, "An underwater explosion -- or what?", Pursuit, 5(2),
April 1972, p. 30-31.) </p>

<p> These two incidents were full up operational tests of Khrushchev's
newly-deployed superweapons. He probably staged this dramatic one-two punch
in a desperate effort to recover face with <ent type='ORG'>the Communist Party</ent> after his
disastrous face down by <ent type='PERSON'>Kennedy</ent> in thee <ent type='NORP'>Cuban</ent> Missile Crisis a few short
months previously. Apparently the attempt was successful, since he remained
in power another year before being deposed. </p>

<p>--MUSHROOM CLOUD FROM SEA OFF <ent type='GPE'>JAPAN</ent> NEAR RUSSIAN TEST AREA--

The following is concerning the "cold explosion" of April 91984. The
site of the explosion was only about 200 miles from downtown <ent type='GPE'>Tokyo</ent>. It was
seen by the crews of several jet airliners, including <ent type='GPE'>Japan</ent> Air Lines Flight
36. </p>

<p> A short time before the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent>s had hastily announced missile tests
would be conducted into a zone some distance away from the ol explosion site.
This may have been a deception to cover this incident, should any nation
indicate they knew what was going on. </p>

<p> It was also a direct "stimulus" to the <ent type='GPE'>Japan</ent>ese and the rest of the
world: That is stimulate the system and see if the scientists recognize what
happened. If they do, then they know about scalar EM weapons. If they don't,
then their countries know nothing of scalar EM weapons, and those countries
are defenseless against them. </p>

<p> At any rate, at about 5:14 a.m. <ent type='LOC'>Pacific</ent> Standard time on April 91984,
a giant mushroom cloud erupted above the ocean south of the <ent type='LOC'>Kuril Islands</ent>.
The mushroom rose rapidly, expanding to an altitude of 60000 feet and a
diameter of 200 miles within 2 minutes. </p>

<p> One pilot of a <ent type='ORG'>Boeing</ent> 747 who observed the cloud was a former B-52
bomber pilot. He described the cloud as being very similar to that of a
gigantic nuclear explosion, except there was no flash of visible light.
Taking evasive action, he turned off course away from the blast, and braced
for a blast shock that never came... </p>

<p>--MUSHROOM CLOUD RISING FROM THE SEA (COLD EXPLOSION)--

Indeed, this highly anomalous cloud was due to a cold explosion -- a
test of a <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> scalar EM howitzer in the pulsed endothermic mode.

Thus a beautiful "stimulus" and test was conducted: quite a few
airliners were "pinged", providing a high-level stimulus to competent
observers. The news was sure to be reported by them to several nations. The
press was sure to pick up the story. This was a high order stimulus to see
whether the U.S., <ent type='GPE'>Japan</ent>, or other potential adversaries of the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> Union
recognized the testing of a cold explosion weapon. </p>

<p> By our reaction, we assured them (with high confidence) that we still
knew nothing of scalar EM interferometry or cold explosions. </p>

<p> Five <ent type='ORG'>Boeing</ent> 747's flew through or near the cloud on their way to
<ent type='GPE'>Anchorage</ent> <ent type='GPE'>Alaska</ent>. The aircraft were checked at <ent type='GPE'>Anchorage</ent> for rad)oactive
contamination, but nothing was found. This showed that the huge explosion
had been non-nuclear. </p>

<p> The ocean in the area is also about 21000 feet deep. That is really
too deep for a submarine volcano to have erupted and caused the cloud.
(Besides, a volcano would have continued to snort at least a bit, and so that
appears to be out of the question as a cause of the incident.) </p>

<p> In short, a man made phenomenon is indicated.</p>

<p> Indeed, we know it was a cold explosion. In fact, the basic effect has
been produced over a dish of water in the laboratory, using a small scalar
interferometer in the endothermic mode. </p>

<p> Further, the story does not end there.</p>

<p> A geophysicist at <ent type='ORG'>the University</ent> of Hawaii, Dr.<ent type='PERSON'>Daniel</ent> A. <ent type='PERSON'>Walker</ent>,
together with his colleages monitor an array of Hydrophones on the ocean
bottom, recording signals such as seismic events, volcano eruptions, etc. </p>

<p> Dr.<ent type='PERSON'>Walker</ent> and his colleages performed a comprehensive analysis of the
data recorded by the hydrophones in and around the time of the incident in
question. The data shows the absence of any natural seismic or volcanic event
that could have caused the April 9th phenomenon off the coast of <ent type='GPE'>Japan</ent>.

He and his colleages concluded that it was either an as yet unknown
natural phenomenon, or a man made phenomenon. </p>

<p> Their report is published in "Science". (D.<ent type='PERSON'>Walker</ent>,"Kaitoku Seamount and
the Mystery Cloud of 9 April 1984," Science, 227(4687),Feb.81985,p.
607-611.) </p>

<p>(Continued)</p>

<p>--THE TESLA SHIELD--

Of particular interest is the hemispherical shell of energy which years
ago was dubbed the "<ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent> Shield." </p>

<p> Two scalar hemispherical surfaces are created, using multiple frequency
transmitters and truncated Fourier series expansions. Interference of the two
scalar hemispheres creates a great, glowing hemispherical shell of ordinary
electromagnetic energy. In the shell, the energy density is sufficient to
lift Dirac matter from the Dirac sea of vacuum. The shell is thus filled with
a glowing plasma. </p>

<p> Such a shell may be several hundreds of miles in diameter at the base.
The enormous energy required to form such a defense shell is obtained by a
"scalar power tap" into the molten core of the <ent type='LOC'>earth</ent> itself as previously
explained. In late April/early May of 1985, 27 such "power taps" were placed
in the <ent type='LOC'>earth</ent> by the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent>s. If each tap is capable of powering 4 to 6 large
scalar EM weapons, then the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> strategic scalar EM arsenal contains over
100 monstrous superweapons capable of generating exothermic explosions,
endothermic explosions, engineering the weather, locating and destroying
underwater submarines, detecting and destroying ballistic missiles shortly
after launch, detecting and destroying long range strategic bombers as soon
as they are airborne, etc. </p>

<p> At any rate, the giant <ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent> shield is useful against any penetrating
vehicle. If the shell is not so large, its energy density may be very high.
In that case, the intense plasma heating will fuse and even vaporize metallic
bodies. In addition, any vehicle encountering the shell is subjected to an
extremely intense EMP arising everywhere inside its circuitry. EMP shielding
is of no use against the creation of energy throughout the spacetime of the
circuits; such shielding only helps against energy flow through space in the
conventional sense. </p>

<p> Thus the electronics of any vehicle encountering the shield are
instantly dudded, whether or not they are shielded against ordinary
electromagnetic interference (<ent type='ORG'>EMI</ent>). This includes the electronics operating a
nuclear warhead, carried by a re-entry vehicle. Electrically everything
penetrating the shell is totally dudded. Further, explosive materials are
exploded when such an EMP is encountered, and combustible materials are
fiercely consumed or set afire. Ablative shielding suffers an interesting
catastrophe: since energy does not try to "flow into" the shielding but
"arises" everywhere in it simultaneously, "ablation" occurs everywhere
throughout the ablative material, simply exploding it instantly. In addition,
for smaller <ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent> shells (say of 50 miles in diameter) the energy density is
sufficient to melt or vaporize metals such as missile structures. </p>

<p> With such a <ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent> shield, there is no need to discriminate true
warhead bearing re-entry vehicles from decoys, chaff, etc. The whole "mess"
entering the shield is simply "cleaned up" and "sterilized" or destroyed. The
shield can take care of ICBMs/IRBMs and their nuclear warheads, strategic
bombers and their nuclear bombs, cruise missiles and their nuclear warheads,
re-entry vehicles and their warheads, decoys, chaff, etc.</p>

<p>--<ent type='ORG'>SARYSHAGAN</ent> DIRECTION-SEPTEMBER 1979--

<ent type='ORG'>The London</ent> <ent type='LOC'>Sunday</ent> Times of 17 August 1980 contained information and a
photo-sketch of incidents fo sighting of the testing of very large <ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent>
globes deep within the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> Union. The sightings were made in <ent type='GPE'>Afghanistan</ent>
by <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> war cameraman <ent type='PERSON'>Nick Downie</ent>. The phenomena seen were in the
direction of the <ent type='GPE'>Saryshagan</ent> Missile Test Range, which -- according to the
U.S. Defense Departments "<ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Military Power</ent>," 1986 -- contains one or
more large directed energy weapons (DEW's).

Even though <ent type='ORG'>Downie</ent> was seeing the globe of light from a great
distance, it flared silently over the <ent type='NORP'>Hindu</ent> Kush and expanded to subtend an
arc of about 20 degrees, dimming as it expanded. (An arc of 20 degrees
subtended by an object many hundreds of miles distant indicates an object of
well over a hundred miles in diameter. This gives some idea of the enormous
energy being controlled and manipulated by these <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> weapons.) </p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>Downie</ent> saw the sight on more than one occasion in September 1979.</p>

<p> In the same month --December 1979-- a stationary luminous globe
containing a vertical stripe of black in the center was seen in the sky off
the coast of St.<ent type='GPE'>Petersburg</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Florida</ent>. This particular type of sighting in that
area has been previously correlated with times of known activity at
<ent type='GPE'>Saryshagan</ent>. </p>

<p> Further, in the same month, U.S. nuclear warning <ent type='PERSON'>Vela</ent> satellites
detected a "nuclear flash" over the <ent type='LOC'>South Atlantic</ent>, off the coast of <ent type='LOC'>Africa</ent>.
Controversy has raged in U.S. Intelligence and scientific circles to this day
as to whether a nuclear explosion or some other kind of mechanism produced
the flash. </p>

<p> Indeed, the flash may have been produced by a scalar EM howitzer from
<ent type='GPE'>Saryshagan</ent> as one more "ping" of the U.S. Intelligence system, to ascertain
whether or not it knew anything about scalar EM howitzers. Again the negative
response told them with high confidence that (1) We still didn't know about
scalar EM stuff, and (2) We were still totally defenseless against the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent>
scalar EM weaponry. </p>

<p> At any rate, from Downie's sightings, it is highly probable that the
<ent type='ORG'>DEW</ent> weaponry at <ent type='GPE'>Saryshagan</ent> Missile Test Range was active in September 1979,
and was producing large <ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent> globes. If the <ent type='ORG'>DEW</ent>s at <ent type='GPE'>Saryshagan</ent> can produce
the giant luminous <ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent> globe, they are almost certainly scalar EM
interferometers and can produce the giant <ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent> shields as well. <ent type='ORG'>Downie</ent>
reported other earlier sightings of similar phenomena seen by <ent type='NORP'>Afghans</ent> deep
within the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> Union in the same direction toward <ent type='GPE'>Saryshagan</ent>... </p>

<p> Briefly, let us cover the uses of such a giant globe or spherical
shell of glowing EM energy and plasma. </p>

<p> By placing such a giant globe hundreds of miles out away from the
defended heartland, an entire arc of the sky can be defended against long
range ballistic missile attack in midcourse. During their midcourse
trajectory, the attacking missiles would have to penetrate the globular shell
twice, exposing them to giant internal EMPs twice. A very high probability
thus exists that all missiles entering the space occupied by the globe are
dudded upon entry and/or exit. This includes the electronics inside the
nuclear warheads themselves. Also this is particularly effective against <ent type='PERSON'>MIRV</ent>
and MARV missile carriers since the multiple re-entry vehicles are normally
still on the main vehicle during most of midcourse. The use of this midcourse
ABM globe defense greatly reduces the number of vehicles arriving at the
latter part of midcourse and the terminal phase of their trajectory. </p>

<p> By using a smaller, more intense globe, and placing it on incoming
clusters of objects or single objects, both EMP and local heating are used
against the objects. This is suitable in the latter part of midcourse and in
the terminal phase of ICBMs, IRBMs, SLBMs, and cruise missiles. It is also
useful against incoming strategic bombers and their air to surface missiles
both ballistic and cruise. </p>

<p> Two modes of the globes -- especially the small ones -- can be used.
First the continuous mode can be used to "fry" or vaporize incoming objects
in a relatively small volume (say ten to fifteen miles in diameter). Second,
the "pulse" mode can be used to "service" all incoming objects, whether or
not they have passed through the "large globe" midcourse defense. This
provides an additional guarantee of killing the objects; discrimination is
not require, just get all of them. The exposure of all incoming objects to
multiple attacks raises the probability of kill to essentially 100%, or as
close to that as one wishes. Of course the incoming vehicle may still
encounter a terminal defense consisting of the <ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent> shield and associated
roving "<ent type='ORG'>quickshot</ent>" small intense globes. </p>

<p> In short, with these systems an essentially 100% ABM and anti bomber
defense is possible. Further, the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent>s have possessed such an effective
defense for two decades, JUST AS THEY HAVE OPENLY STATED SINCE 1960 WHEN
KHRUSHCHEV ANNOUNCED HIS "SUPERWEAPONS"!!

</p>

<p>--CONTINUOUS TESLA EMP GLOBE--

Here is another verified incident of a gigantic test of a <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent>
scalar EM howitzer deep within the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> Union. </p>

<p> This is a C.I.A. report, released under the Freedom of Information
Act. One can be quite sure that the incident occurred as stated. </p>

<p> The phenomenon was seen from two aircraft approaching Mehrabad Airport
in <ent type='GPE'>Teheran</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Iran</ent> on June 17, 1966 and reported by their pilots. </p>

<p> On the far horizon deep within the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> Union, an intense spherical
ball of light appeared, "sitting on the horizon" so to speak. The globe of
light increased to enormous size, dimming as it did so, literally filling an
arc of the distant sky as it expanded. The sighting was shielded from most
ground observers view at the airport itself due to an intervening mountain
range which masked most of the phenomena from the ground. </p>

<p> The silent, expanding globe was observed for four or five minutes
before it faded away. </p>

<p> Again this is positive evidence of the testing of a giant scalar
interferometer, in the "midcourse ABM globe" type of action.</p>

<p> However, note the date -- mid 1966! The <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent>s have therefore been
testing such scalar weapons of enormous size and power for at least two
decades. This implies that development must have started at least a decade
earlier, or in the mid '50s. </p>

<p> Still earlier, in January 1960 <ent type='PERSON'>Nikita Khrushchev</ent> had announced the
development of a "fantastic" <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> weapon, one which could even destroy all
life on <ent type='LOC'>earth</ent> if unrestrainedly used. In 1962 the ebullient <ent type='NORP'>Khrushchev</ent> was
forced to back down and lose face before John <ent type='PERSON'>Kennedy</ent>, in the <ent type='NORP'>Cuban</ent> Missile
Crisis. Khrushchev's missiles and bombers were in woeful shape, as <ent type='PERSON'>Kennedy</ent>
well knew (by courtesy of the <ent type='NORP'>Russian</ent> spy, Colonel <ent type='PERSON'>Oleg Penkovsky</ent>). <ent type='PERSON'>Kennedy</ent>
did not know that Khrushchev's new superweapons were nearing deployment, but
were not quite ready yet. </p>

<p> To save face and prevent his immediate ouster, <ent type='NORP'>Khrushchev</ent> apparently
conducted a startling two-strike demonstration of his new weapons as soon as
they became operationally ready. On April 10, 1963 he detected and destroyed
the U.S.S. Thresher nuclear submarine, using a scalar EM howitzer in the
underwater "continuous" mode. The next day he demonstrated the "pulsed"
underwater destruction mode for underwater subs by producing a giant
underwater
explosion underneath the water 100 miles north of <ent type='GPE'>Puerto Rico</ent>. Ironically,
just as the <ent type='LOC'>Atlantic</ent> was coming alive with U.S. naval vessels searching for
the lost Thresher, a second test of the weapons that had finished off the sub
occurred to the south of them, unnoticed and disregarded, even though seen
and reported to he F.B.I. and the U.S. Coast Guard by a passing U.S.
jetliner's pilot and crew, who observed the underwater explosion. </p>

<p> We thus can peg the development of these weapons by the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent>s as
starting well before 1960. The first operational deployment of the gigantic
strategic weaponry occurred in early 1963.

Note that the 1966 testing observed here is completely consistent
with this estimated development schedule. </p>

<p> Thus large <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> strategic scalar EM weapons have been operational
on site for 24 YEARS !!! This implies that at least three additional
generations of the scalar EM weapons have been developed and deployed by
now...
</p>

<p>--MYSTERIOUS LIGHTS OVER NORTH PACIFIC--

Incidents of <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> testing of the <ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent> shield and the <ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent> globe
weapons are routinely observed by airline pilots flying over the <ent type='PERSON'>North</ent>
<ent type='LOC'>Pacific</ent> into and out of <ent type='GPE'>Japan</ent>. </p>

<p> This is one typical example. Two jetliners, <ent type='GPE'>Japan</ent> Air Lines flights
403 and 421, sighted and reported a large glowing globe of light sitting just
beyond the horizon and extending well above it. The aircraft were in the
vicinity of 42 degrees N latitude and 153 degrees longitude at the time. The
sighting was thus about 700 miles east of <ent type='GPE'>Kushiro</ent>. </p>

<p> The diameter of the ball was estimated as at least 18-27 kilometers
by the pilots. Depending upon the actual distance to the sphere it may have
been of much larger size. </p>

<p> This incident is reported in <ent type='ORG'>the Asahi Evening</ent> News, <ent type='GPE'>Tokyo</ent>, June 22,
1982.

Many similar sightings have been reported by jet airliner pilots
flying over these waters.

--WHITE SPHERE SEEN IN <ent type='GPE'>NORTH ATLANTIC</ent> 1976--

Here is another sighting closer to home. </p>

<p> This incident was observed from a passing ship on June 221976 in the
<ent type='PERSON'>North</ent> <ent type='LOC'>Atlantic</ent>, at about 2113-2140 hours. It is reported in the Marine
Observer, Vol.471977, p.66. </p>

<p> First an orange glow was sighted behind some distant clouds. A couple
of minutes later, a glowing white sphere of light was observed to the left of
the orange glow, just above the clouds. The white sphere then slowly expanded
to a much larger sphere, dimming as it expanded. At its maximum size, the top
of the white sphere reached about 24 degrees 30 minutes elevation angle to
<ent type='ORG'>the observer</ent>. Development to maximum size required about 10 minutes. </p>

<p> By 2140 hours the sphere had faded and disappeared. The sphere was
sufficiently thin that the stars could be seen through it at all times. </p>

<p> Again, this incident strong&lt;y fits the large <ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent> globe mode of a
<ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> scalar EM interferometer.</p>

<p> The significance and role of the orange glow are not known at this
time.
</p>

<p>--CONTINUOUS TESLA FIREBALL--

Here is another incident that represents a stimulus to the <ent type='NORP'>British</ent>
government, to see if the <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> are aware of scalar electromagnetics.</p>

<p> Again this is a <ent type='ORG'>CIA</ent> report released under the Freedom of Information
Act, so the details are reliable.</p>

<p> On Sep. 10, 1976 <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> European Airways flight 831, flying between
<ent type='GPE'>Moscow</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>London</ent> and over <ent type='GPE'>Lithuania</ent> at the time, observed an intense ball
of light above the clouds below the aircraft. The light was so intense it
lit up the sky in the entire vicinity.</p>

<p> The concerned pilot reported the glowing object to <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> ground
authorities with whom he was in contact. He received harsh instructions to
ignore the light, and essentially to continue on his way out of there.</p>

<p> Here we see an incident involving a small, intense <ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent> globe, of the
kind with which the defense could "service" objects that had already
penetrated a large midcourse globe, or aircraft approaching the defended
area.</p>

<p> Obviously the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> authorities were tracking the aircraft, and knew
it was in the vicinity. It seems logical, then, that they deliberately
placed the brightly glowing ball beneath the aircraft so that the pilot and
crew could not fail to observe it.</p>

<p> The strange message to the pilot was simply designed to increase the
intensity of the stimulus. The stimulus was to be something like, "The
<ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent>s are doing something in research and development that allows them to
create intense balls of glowing light at a distance, and place these objects
in and around the air in and around aircraft, possibly to intercept them."
The purpose, of course, was to observe the <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> governments reaction
after the incident was reported by the pilot upon his arrival in <ent type='GPE'>London</ent>.</p>

<p> Again the reaction of the <ent type='NORP'>British</ent> -- and the U.S. as well -- was as
predicted. Again we showed that we knew nothing of scalar electromagnetic
weapons, and did not recognize one when we encountered its effects.</p>

<p>(Continued)</p>

<p>--TERMINAL ABM SYSTEM--

Very neat things can be done if one "nests" several <ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent> shields --
say three or four -- concentrically, one inside the other. In that case even
the nuclear radiation (such as gamma rays) from a defense-suppressive high
altitude nuclear burst can be handled.

For example, suppose three such concentric shields are placed over a
large vital area. Further, suppose a high altitude nuclear burst is placed
above the outer shield. Gamma radiation almost instantly strikes the plasma
in the outer shell, where it is absorbed, scattered, and re-radiated at a
lower temperature. (That after all is what plasmas do.) Inside the first
shell, the scattered radiation is now in the x-ray and ultra violet region.
Let us track the most lethal component, the x-rays. </p>

<p> The scattered x-rays then strike the second plasma shell, and are
absorbed scattered and re-radiated at a lower temperature. Inside the second
shell the scattered radiation is now in the visible and infrared region, with
a little ultraviolet.

This optical radiation in turn strikes the third plasma shell, and is
absorbed scattered and re-radiated at still lower temperature. Inside the
third shell, most of the energy is now in the form of radio frequency (RF)
energy, with a little IR and visible band spectral energy content.

At this point, ordinary electromagnetic interference (<ent type='ORG'>EMI</ent>) shielding of
electronic equipment on the ground inside the third shield can take care of
any RF interference resulting from the emergent RF noise. </p>

<p> As can be seen, three shells are sufficient to convert the gamma and
x-ray radiation (and ultraviolet and infrared) mostly to harmless RF energy
before all three shells are penetrated. Thus the tactic of deliberate defense
suppression by a preliminary high altitude nuclear burst can be countered by
multiple <ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent> shields. </p>

<p> In addition, of course, any ordinary vehicles penetrating all three
shields are exposed to successive violent EMP's and are almost certainly
electrically dudded. The vehicles are also subjected to multiple periods of
intense heating, so combustibles, fuels, explosives, and ablatives are
destroyed. In addition, metal structures may be melted or vaporized. </p>

<p> Think of it this way: anything which hits one of these <ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent> shields
goes phhht! Just like a bug hitting an electrified bugkiller screen. </p>

<p> For years passing ships have observed and reported such multiple-shield
"light phenomena" over remote regions of the ocean. U.S. intelligence has
routinely not paid any heed to "lights at night" over remote ocean areas, and
so <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> tests in this manner have remained relatively unnoticed by
officialdom... </p>

<p>--<ent type='ORG'>WOODPECKER</ent> BEAMS INTERSECT OVER <ent type='ORG'>NORTH AMERICA</ent>--

In July 1976 the U.S. received very special <ent type='GPE'>Bicentennial</ent> greetings from
the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> Union. </p>

<p> At that time, communications systems of the world in the 3-30 megaHertz
band suddenly met substantial interference from extremely powerful, chirped
<ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> transmitters which were suddenly activated. These transmitters
continue their transmission to this day. </p>

<p> Estimates of the power of these transmitters vary, but figures range as
high as several hundred megawatts, with a nominal figure being 100 megawatts. </p>

<p> These powerful transmitters were properly nicknamed "<ent type='ORG'>Woodpecker</ent>s"
because of the characteristic sound of the chirped signal when received. That
is, the received signal makes a "pecking" sound much like a woodpecker's beak
hitting a block of wood. </p>

<p> Several nations protested, but the powerful signals have continued,
right down to this day. The only <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> response was to add a "spread
spectrum" capability, so that the transmitter would not dwell too long on one
specific frequency, but shifted periodically to other frequencies. </p>

<p> These transmitters have apparently never been precisely located by U.S.
intelligence, but their beams carry much of the characteristics of an over-the-horizon (<ent type='ORG'>OTH</ent>) radar. They have been dubbed <ent type='ORG'>OTH</ent> radars by U.S.
intelligence, and can without question perform that mission, in addition to
some very interesting missions that U.S. intelligence does not assess. </p>

<p> "<ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Military Power</ent>", Department of Defense, 1985, p.45 shows the
direct intersection over <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States of the <ent type='ORG'>Woodpecker</ent> radar beams used
in an <ent type='ORG'>OTH</ent> role. In addition, shown is an additional "scanner" beam which can
be scanned across the intersection "grid" over the U.S., formed by waveform
interference of two main <ent type='ORG'>Woodpecker</ent> beams. </p>

<p> First, they can be used in a conventional <ent type='ORG'>OTH</ent> radar mode, since their
beams follow the <ent type='LOC'>earth</ent>-ionosphere waveguide and curve around the <ent type='LOC'>earth</ent>. In
this mode they can detect missiles at launch and thereafter, and strategic
bombers at launch and thereafter. </p>

<p> These scalar interference grid weapons can be used to biologically
attack entire populations in a targeted area. This aspect is not covered in
this briefing. Suffice it to say that phase locked ELF modulation signals of
10 Hz and less are often detected on multiple woodpecker frequencies
simultaneously. In a target area, this modulation -- is sufficiently stronger
than the <ent type='PERSON'>Schumann</ent> resonance of the earth's magnetic field -- will entrain a
percentage of the brains into "forced entrainment". In that case, these human
brains are "synchronized" to the <ent type='ORG'>Woodpecker</ent> signals so that multiple coherent
frequencies are phase-locked into them. That is, multiple coherent EM
channels directly into these entrained brains now exist. At that point,
Fourier expansions may now be used to attack specific portions of the brain
geometrically. </p>

<p> In addition, scalar EM disease patterns can be modulated upon the
carriers, again with fourier expansions. Specific biological effects can be
induced in the entrained populations at will, limited only by the state of
the art of the <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> technology used to attack them. Possible effects
include instantaneous death, heart seizure, severe emotional disruption, loss
of control of internal functions, diseases, disabling of the immune system,
and even implantation of thoughts, emotions, and ideas which are interpreted
by the subjects as their own. </p>

<p> While further discussion of this area is beyond the scope of my
knowledge, the biological aspects of the <ent type='ORG'>Woodpecker</ent> transmitters are
horrible. It suffices to say that, in thousands of experiments, <ent type='PERSON'>Kaznacheyev</ent>
demonstrated that almost any kind of cellular death and disease pattern
could be electromagnetically transmitted. <ent type='PERSON'>Kaznacheyev</ent> reported the effect in
te near ultraviolet. Experimenters at <ent type='ORG'>the University</ent> of Marburg in <ent type='LOC'>West</ent>
Germany duplicated the experiments in the infrared.</p>

<p> The bottom line is that photons themselves can carry death and disease
patterns between cells. <ent type='ORG'>Scalar</ent> EM technology allows synthesis of the actual
potential pattern (which after all represents total control of charge and
charge distribution, hence biochemistry in the cell) of a particular
disease or death mechanism. Symptoms (and cellular death from them!) of
nuclear radiation, chemical poisoning, bacterial infection, and other
mechanisms were induced by the <ent type='PERSON'>Kaznacheyev</ent> experiments.</p>

<p> Dr. <ent type='PERSON'>Popp</ent> of <ent type='LOC'>West</ent> Germany has published an analysis of the virtual
photon master control system of the cells. Since scalar EM represents the
deliberate ordering of virtual particle flux into deterministic patterns,
the master control system can readily be entered with scalar techniques to
induce disease and disorder at will...

</p></xml>