<xml><p><ent type='ORG'>The World</ent> of Surveillance</p>

<p>COPYRIGHT (C) 1991 BY FULL DISCLOSURE. ALL RIGHTS RESERVED.</p>

<p>Surveillance (7906 Hope Valley Ct, <ent type='GPE'>Adamstown</ent>, MD 20710, $35/yr) reports on
phone taps via teleconferencing. This simple technique involves the
"tappers'' conference calling two parties he wishes to spy on. He then
listens and records the ensuring conversation. It is pointed out that this
technique is not universally applicable, but is limited to situations where
both parties normally answer the phone on the first ring. (And don't realize
that neither one called the other).</p>

<p>2600 (Box 752, <ent type='GPE'>Middle Island</ent>, NY 11953, $18/yr) reports that some cordless
phones, including <ent type='ORG'>the General Electric System</ent> 10, model 2-9675, transmits
phone conversation made through a standard phone when the unit is hooked up.
Most people would assume that when they didn't use the cordless handset,
their calls wouldn't be broadcast for any nosey neighbors or others to
monitor.</p>

<p>CAR CADDY</p>

<p>The Concealment or Car Caddy is a device to covertly record the conversations
of passengers in an automobile. It looks just like a litterbasket / snack
tray.</p>

<p>However, hidden inside is a tape recorder. It can either have one microphone
powered by a hearing aid battery or two powered by the tape recorder.</p>

<p>The <ent type='ORG'>SME</ent>-700 unit (stereo unit, with two microphones) sale is restricted only
to federal and state law enforcement agencies. However, the <ent type='ORG'>SME</ent>-RN36 unit is
available to anyone wishing to pay $385 for it. The <ent type='ORG'>SME</ent>-RN36 is configured
with a 2 hour recorder.</p>

<p>When asked what the reason for the restriction on the <ent type='ORG'>SME</ent>-700 was, Saul
Mineroff stated that "it has certain features designed with federal agencies
and that was the agreement.''</p>

<p>The snack tray is slid back to activate the recorder and forward to turn it
off. </p>

<p>This unit is produced by <ent type='PERSON'>Saul Mineroff</ent> Electronics, Inc., 574 Meacham Av,
Elmont, New York 11003, Phone: (516) 775 1370, Fax: (516) 775-1371.</p>

<p>When <ent type='PERSON'>Saul Mineroff</ent> refused to openly provide information on the features of
the <ent type='ORG'>SME</ent>-700 recorder, Full Disclosure was able to obtain "Confidential
Information on <ent type='ORG'>SME</ent> 700 Surveillance System.'' The <ent type='ORG'>SME</ent> 700 is actually, just
the recorder, which can go in the car caddy, be worn on the body or used in
another applicable situation. Following are excerpts from the document:</p>

<p>"<ent type='PERSON'>Saul Mineroff</ent>, of <ent type='ORG'>Mineroff Electronics</ent> has worked for over a decade in
cooperation with the Drug Enforcement Administration and F.B.I. personnel
(along with various U.S. Governmental agencies) to develop a highly
sophisticated foolproof body surveillance recorder with simple operating
functions.</p>

<p>"The <ent type='ORG'>SME</ent> 700 Recorder is designed strictly for law enforcement agencies. The
sale of this unit will only be distributed to law enforcement personnel. Its
primary use and design is for the agent in the field.</p>

<p>"The <ent type='ORG'>SME</ent> 700 makes recordings in stereo. Because stereo utilizes two
channels, it is easier for the human ear to identify certain sounds in the
recordings (e.g. if multiple voices were recorded, it is easier to depict
each individual voice when recorded in stereo). After recordings are made on
the <ent type='ORG'>SME</ent> 700 Recorder they are played back on the <ent type='ORG'>SME</ent> 701 playback unit.</p>

<p>"There are many features fabricated into the <ent type='ORG'>SME</ent> 700 Recorder. The first
feature is the ability to record multiple voices and attenuate background
noise levels drastically. By using fast acting A.L.C., special filtering, and
compressing circuits, along with <ent type='ORG'>DNR</ent> (Dynamic Noise Reduction) in playback
unit, background noises are suppressed allowing the primary voices to be
recorded and played back.</p>

<p>"The <ent type='ORG'>SME</ent> 700 Recorder is non-detectable (via tape recorder detectors). The
circuit employs low frequency A-C bias, is completely shielded, and doesn't
generate radiation. Radiation is what tape recorder detectors detect.</p>

<p>The other features are mechanical in nature to prevent accidental operation.</p>

<p>MINIATURE BUG</p>

<p>This subminiature bug, is available in a VHF and UHF version. The 900mhz
version is pictured here (actual size). The manufacturer, ATET, Via G. da
Verrazzano, 42, 10129 Torino, <ent type='GPE'>Italy</ent>, Phone: 011/ 59-04 93, Telex: 213273,
TOATET I, claims that the unit is the smallest crystal controlled units being
manufactured in the world today.</p>

<p>Both units work over a input voltage range of 3 to 12 volts providing maximum
flexibility in power sources. The power output ranges from
.7mw to 135mw on the VHF unit and 3mw to 20mw on the UHF depending
on input voltage.</p>

<p>Several adapters are available for the units: 1) Telephone adapter, converts
the module into a series telephone transmitter which obtains power from the
phone line, 2) External microphone adapter, converts the module into a
body-worn transmitter with the capability of total concealment, and 3)
Vehicle adapter, connects to the internal supply circuitry of a motor vehicle
and produces continuous transmission.</p>

<p>The VHF unit has a frequency range of 135 - 175 mhz FM. The UHF frequency
range is 700 - 1100mhz FM. The dimensions of both are 9 x 21 x 22 mm.</p>

<p>The most significant problem with these units is a frequency shift over time.
As you can see from the photograph, the unit was originally manufactured for
900.270mhz and shifted to 900.265mhz and 900.260mhz.</p>

<p>This particular unit was tested by the Drug Enforcement Administration. </p>

<p>The U.S. Distributor for these bugs is: <ent type='ORG'>Knox Security</ent>, 335 Greenwich Rd,
Greenwich, CT 06830, Phone: (203) 622-7300.</p>

<p>CIGARETTE LIGHTER</p>

<p>Pictured on page 9 with complete specifications below is a VHF
microtransmitter disguised in a non-functional cigarette lighter.</p>

<p>WHAT DO YOU WANT?</p>

<p>Please let us know what types of surveillance devices and information you'd
like to see here</p>

<p>The above is reprinted from Full Disclosure Newspaper. Subscribe today and
get interesting articles like the above, plus more... pictures, graphics,
advertisement, and more articles. Full Disclosure is your source for
information on the leading edge of surveillance technology. Print the
following form, or supply the information on a plain piece of paper:</p>

<div>----</div>

<p>Please start my subscription to Full Disclosure for:</p>

<p>[ ] Sample issue, $2.00</p>

<p>[ ] 12 issue subscription, $18.00</p>

<p>[ ] 24 issue subscription, $29.95
With 24 issue susbcription include free one of the following:
[ ] Directory of Electronic Surveillance Equipment Suppliers
[ ] Citizen's Guide on How to Use the Freedom of Info/Privacy Acts
[ ] Maximizing PC Performance</p>

<p>Also available separately:</p>

<p>[ ] Directory of Electronic Surveillance Equipment Suppliers, $6.00</p>

<p>[ ] Citizen's Guide on How to Use the Freedom of Info/Privacy Acts, $5.00</p>

<p>[ ] Maximizing PC Performance, $6.00</p>

<p> <ent type='GPE'>Illinois</ent> residences, add 6.5% sales tax on above 3 items.</p>

<p>Enclosed is payment in the form of:</p>

<p>[ ] Check/Money order, [ ] Visa, [ ] Mastercard</p>

<p>Card no:___________________________________ Exp date:_______</p>

<p>Signature:__________________________________________________</p>

<p>Phone:______________________________________________________
(required for credit card orders)</p>

<p>My name/address:</p>

<p>Name:_______________________________________________________</p>

<p>Street:_____________________________________________________</p>

<p>City/State/Zip:_____________________________________________</p>

<p>Return to: Full Disclosure, Box 903, <ent type='GPE'>Libertyville</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Illinois</ent> 60048

</p></xml>