<xml>

<p>3.RM 7.50"
THEORETICAL ELECTROMAGNETIC STUDIES AND LEARNING ASSOCIATION, INC.
522 WEST THIRD STREET
LEADVILLE, COLORADO 80461
(719) 486-0133</p>

<p>THE INFLUENCE OF <ent type='ORG'>VEDIC</ent> PHILOSOPHY ON NIKOLA TESLA'S UNSTANDIING FREE ENERGY</p>

<p> "The first thing to realize about the ether is its absolute
continuity. A deep sea fish has probably no means of
apprehending the existence of water; it is too uniformly
immersed in it: and that is our condition in regard to the
ether."
Sir <ent type='PERSON'>Oliver Lodge</ent>, Ether and Reality.</p>

<p> ABSTRACT</p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>Nikola</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent> used ancient Sanskrit terminology in his descriptions of
natural phenomena. As early as 1891 <ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent> described the universe as a
kinetic system filled with energy which could be harnessed at any
location. His concepts during the following years were greatly
influenced by the teachings of <ent type='PERSON'><ent type='PERSON'>Swami</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Vivekananda</ent></ent>. <ent type='PERSON'><ent type='PERSON'>Swami</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Vivekananda</ent></ent>
was the first of a succession of eastern yogi's who brought Vedic
philosophy and religion to the west. After meeting the <ent type='PERSON'>Swami</ent> and after
continued study of the <ent type='ORG'>Eastern</ent> view of the mechanisms driving the
material world, <ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent> began using the Sanskrit words <ent type='PERSON'>Akasha</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Prana</ent>, and
the concept of a luminiferous ether to describe the source, existence
and construction of matter. This paper will trace the development of
Tesla's understanding of Vedic Science, his correspondence with Lord
<ent type='PERSON'>Kelvin</ent> concerning these matters, and the relation between <ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent> and
<ent type='PERSON'>Walter Russell</ent> and other turn of the century scientists concerning
advanced understanding of physics. Finally, after being obscured for
many years, the author will give a description of what he believes is
the the pre-requisite for the free energy systems envisioned by <ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent> .</p>

<p> TESLA'S EARLIER DESCRIPTION OF THE PHYSICAL UNIVERSE</p>

<p> By the year 1891, <ent type='ORG'>Nikola</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent> had invented many useful devices.
These included a system of arc lighting (1886), the alternating current
motor, power generation and transmission systems (1888), systems of
electrical conversion and distribution by oscillatory discharges
(1889), and a generator of high frequency currents (1890), to name a
few. The most well known patent centers around an inspiration that
occurred while walking with a friend in a park in <ent type='GPE'>Budapest</ent>, Hungry. It
was while observing the sunset that <ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent> had a vision of how rotating
electromagnetic fields could be used in a new form of electric motor.
This led to the well known system of alternating current power
distribution. In 1891 however, <ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent> patented what one day may become
his most famous invention. It is the basis for the wireless
transmission of electrical power and is know as the <ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent> Coil
Transformer. It was during this year that <ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent> made the following
comments during a speech before <ent type='ORG'>the American Institute</ent> of Electrical</p>

<p> Engineers;</p>

<p> "Ere many generations pass, our machinery will be driven by
a power obtainable at any point in the universe. This idea
is not novel... We find it in the delightful myth of
<ent type='PERSON'>Antheus</ent>, who derives power from the earth; we find it among
the subtle speculations of one of your splendid
mathematicians... Throughout space there is energy. Is
this energy static or kinetic.? If static our hopes are in
vain; if kinetic - and this we know it is, for certain -
then it is a mere question of time when men will succeed
in attaching their machinery to the very wheelwork of
nature." 1</p>

<p> This description of the physical mechanisms of the universe was given
before <ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent> became familiar with the Vedic science of <ent type='ORG'>the eastern</ent>
Nations of India, <ent type='GPE'>Tibet</ent>, and <ent type='GPE'>Nepal</ent>. This science was first popualized
in <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States and the west during the three year visit of <ent type='PERSON'>Swami</ent>
<ent type='PERSON'>Vivekananda</ent>.</p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>VEDIC</ent> SCIENCE AND <ent type='ORG'>SWAMI</ent> VIVEKANANDA</p>

<p> The Vedas are a collection of writings consisting of hymns, prayers,
myths, historical accounting, dissertations on science, and the nature
of reality, which date back at least 5000 years. The nature of
matter, antimatter, and the make up of atomic structure are described
in the Vedas. The language of the Vedas is known as Sanskrit. The
origin of Sanskrit is not fully understood. Western scholars suggest
that it was brought into the <ent type='LOC'>Himalayas</ent> and thence south into India by
the southward migrations of the <ent type='NORP'>Aryan</ent> culture. <ent type='ORG'>Paramahansa Yogananda</ent>
and other historians however do not subscribe to that theory, pointing
out that there is no evidence within India to substantiate such
claims. 2</p>

<p> There are words in Sanskrit that describe concepts totally foreign to
the western mind. Single words may require a full paragraph for
translation into english. Having studied Sanskrit for a brief period
during the late 70's, it finally occurred to this writer that Tesla's
use of Vedic terminology could provide a key to understanding his view
of electromagnetism and the nature of the universe. But where did
<ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent> learn Vedic concepts and Sanskrit terminology? A review of the
well known biographies by <ent type='PERSON'>Cheney</ent>, Hunt and Draper, and O'<ent type='PERSON'>Neil</ent> 345,
reveal no mention of Tesla's knowledge of Sanskrit. O'<ent type='PERSON'>Neal</ent> however
includes the following excerpt from an unpublished article called Man's
Greatest Achievement;</p>

<p> "There manifests itself in the fully developed being , Man,
a desire mysterious, inscrutable and irresistible: to
imitate nature, to create, to work himself the wonders he
perceives.... Long ago he recognized that all
perceptible matter comes from a primary substance, or
tenuity beyond conception, filling all space, the <ent type='PERSON'>Akasha</ent> or
luminiferous ether, which is acted upon by the life giving</p>

<p> <ent type='PERSON'>Prana</ent> or creative force, calling into existence, in never
ending cycles all things and phenomena. The primary
substance, thrown into infinitesimal whirls of
prodigious velocity, becomes gross matter; the force
subsiding, the motion ceases and matter disappears,
reverting to the primary substance."
According to <ent type='PERSON'>Leland Anderson</ent> the article was written May 13th,
1907. <ent type='PERSON'>Anderson</ent> also suggested that it was through association with
<ent type='PERSON'><ent type='PERSON'>Swami</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Vivekananda</ent></ent> that <ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent> may have come into contact with Sanskrit
terminology and that <ent type='PERSON'><ent type='PERSON'>John</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Dobson</ent></ent> of the San Francisco Sidewalk
Astronomers Association had researched that association. 6</p>

<p> <ent type='PERSON'><ent type='PERSON'>Swami</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Vivekananda</ent></ent> was born in <ent type='GPE'>Calcutta</ent>, India in 1863. He was
inspired by his teacher, <ent type='PERSON'>Ramakrishna</ent> to serve men as visible
manifestations of God. In 1893 <ent type='PERSON'><ent type='PERSON'>Swami</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Vivekananda</ent></ent> began a tour of the
west by attending <ent type='ORG'>the Parliament</ent> of Religions held in <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>. During
the three years that he toured <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States and Europe,
<ent type='PERSON'>Vivekananda</ent> met with many of the well known scientists of the time
including Lord <ent type='PERSON'>Kelvin</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>Nikola</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent>. 7 According to <ent type='PERSON'>Swami</ent>
<ent type='ORG'>Nikhilananda</ent>;</p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>Nikola</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent>, the great scientist who specialized in the
field of electricity, was much impressed to hear from the
<ent type='PERSON'>Swami</ent> his explanation of the <ent type='PERSON'>Samkhya</ent> cosmogony and the theory
of cycles given by the <ent type='NORP'>Hindus</ent>. He was particularly struck by
the resemblance between the <ent type='PERSON'>Samkhya</ent> theory of matter and
energy and that of modern physics. The <ent type='PERSON'>Swami</ent> also met in New
York Sir <ent type='PERSON'>William Thompson</ent>, afterwards Lord <ent type='PERSON'>Kelvin</ent>, and
Professor Helmholtz, two leading representatives of western
science. <ent type='PERSON'>Sarah Bernhardt</ent>, the famous <ent type='NORP'>French</ent> actress had an
interview with the <ent type='PERSON'>Swami</ent> and greatly admired his teachings. 8</p>

<p> It was at a party given by <ent type='PERSON'>Sarah Bernhardt</ent> that <ent type='ORG'>Nikola</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent> probably
first met <ent type='PERSON'><ent type='PERSON'>Swami</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Vivekananda</ent></ent>. 9 <ent type='PERSON'>Sarah Bernhardt</ent> was playing the part of
'<ent type='ORG'>Iziel</ent>' in a play of the same name. It was a <ent type='NORP'>French</ent> version about the
life of <ent type='PERSON'>Bhudda</ent>. The actress upon seeing <ent type='PERSON'><ent type='PERSON'>Swami</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Vivekananda</ent></ent> in the
audience, arranged a meeting which was also attended by <ent type='ORG'>Nikola</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent>.
In a letter to a friend, dated February 13th, 1896, <ent type='PERSON'><ent type='PERSON'>Swami</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Vivekananda</ent></ent>
noted the following;</p>

<p> ...Mr. <ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent> was charmed to hear about the Vedantic <ent type='PERSON'>Prana</ent>
and <ent type='PERSON'>Akasha</ent> and the <ent type='PERSON'>Kalpas</ent>, which according to him are the
only theories modern science can entertain.....Mr <ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent>
thinks he can demonstrate that mathematically that force and
matter are reducible to potential energy. I am to go see him
next week to get this mathematical demonstration. 10</p>

<p> <ent type='PERSON'><ent type='PERSON'>Swami</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Vivekananda</ent></ent> was hopeful that <ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent> would be able to show that
what we call matter is simply potential energy because that would
reconcile the teachings of the Vedas with modern science. The <ent type='PERSON'>Swami</ent>
realized that "In that case, the Vedantic cosmology [would] be placed
on the surest of foundations". The harmony between Vedantic theories
and and western science was explained by the following diagram;</p>

<p> BRAHMAN = THE ABSOLUTE
|
MAHAT OR <ent type='NORP'>ISHVARA</ent> = PRIMAL CREATIVE ENERGY
+---------+ +---------+
PRANA and AKASHA = ENERGY and MATTER</p>

<p> <ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent> understood the Sanskrit terminology and philosophy and found
that it was a good means to describe the physical mechanisms of the
universe as seen through his eyes. It would behoove those who would
attempt to understand the science behind the inventions of <ent type='ORG'>Nikola</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent>
to study Sanskrit and Vedic philosophy.</p>

<p> <ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent> apparently failed to show the identity of energy and matter.
If he had, certainly <ent type='PERSON'><ent type='PERSON'>Swami</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Vivekananda</ent></ent> would have recorded that
occasion. The mathematical proof of the principle did come until
about ten years later when <ent type='PERSON'>Albert Einstein</ent> published his paper on
relativity. What had been known in the <ent type='LOC'>East</ent> for the last 5000 years
was then known to the West.</p>

<p> Brahman is defined as the one self existent impersonal spirit; the
Divine Essence, from which all things emanate, by which they are
sustained, and to which they return. Notice that this is very similar
to the concept of the Great Spirit as understood by <ent type='NORP'>Native American</ent>
cultures. <ent type='PERSON'>Ishvara</ent> is the Supreme Ruler; the highest possible
conception of the <ent type='ORG'>Absolute</ent>, which is beyond all thought. Mahat means
literally the Great One, and is also interpreted as meaning universal
mind or cosmic intelligence. <ent type='PERSON'>Prana</ent> means energy (usually translated as
life force) and <ent type='PERSON'>Akasha</ent> means matter (usually translated as ether).
<ent type='PERSON'>Dobson</ent> points out that the more common translations for <ent type='PERSON'>Akasha</ent> and
<ent type='PERSON'>Prana</ent> are not quite correct, but that <ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent> did understand their true
meanings.</p>

<p> The meeting with <ent type='PERSON'><ent type='PERSON'>Swami</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Vivekananda</ent></ent> greatly stimulated <ent type='ORG'>Nikola</ent> Tesla's
interest in <ent type='ORG'>Eastern</ent> Science. The <ent type='PERSON'>Swami</ent> later remarked during a lecture
in India, "I myself have been told by some of the best scientific minds
of the day, how wonderfully rational the conclusions of the <ent type='ORG'>Vedanta</ent>
are. I know of one of them personally, who scarcely has time to eat
his meal, or go out of his laboratory, but who would stand by the hour
to attend my lectures on the <ent type='ORG'>Vedanta</ent>; for, as he expresses it, they are
so scientific, they so exactly harmonize with the aspirations of the
age and with the conclusions to which modern science is coming at the
present time". 11</p>

<p> TESLA AND LORD KELVIN</p>

<p> William S. <ent type='ORG'>Thompson</ent> was one of the prominent scientists and engineers
of the 1800s. He developed analogies between heat and electricity and
his work influenced the theories developed by <ent type='PERSON'>James Clerk</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Maxwell</ent>, one
of the founders of electromagnetic theory. <ent type='ORG'>Thompson</ent> supervised the
successful laying of <ent type='ORG'>the Trans Atlantic Cable</ent> and for that work was
knighted Lord <ent type='PERSON'>Kelvin</ent>. <ent type='PERSON'>Kelvin</ent> had endorsed Tesla's theories and proposed
system for the wireless transmission of electrical power. 12 FootNOTE-<ent type='ORG'>Grotz</ent> PACE</p>

<p> <ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent> continued to study <ent type='NORP'>Hindu</ent> and Vedic philosophy for a number of
years as indicated by the following letter written to him by Lord
<ent type='PERSON'>Kelvin</ent>.</p>

<p> 15, Eaton Place
<ent type='GPE'>London</ent>, S.W.
May 20, 1902</p>

<p> Dear Mr. <ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent>,</p>

<p> I do not know how I can ever thank you enough for the
most kind letter of May, 10, which I found in my cabin in the
<ent type='GPE'>Lucania</ent>, with the beautiful books which you most kindly sent
me along with it: -"The Buried Temple", "The Gospel of
<ent type='PERSON'>Bhudda</ent>", Les Grands Inities", the exquisite edition of
Rossetti's "House of Life", and last but not least the
Century Magazine for June, 1900 with the splendid and
marvelous photographs on pp. 176, 187, 190, 191, 192, full of
electrical lessons.</p>

<p> We had a most beautiful passage across the <ent type='LOC'>Atlantic</ent>, much
the finest I have ever had. I was trying hard nearly all the
way, but quite unsuccessfully, to find something definite as
to the functions of ether in respect to plain, old fashioned
magnetism. A propos of this, I have instructed the
publishers, Messrs. <ent type='ORG'>Macmillan</ent>, to send you at the <ent type='PERSON'>Waldorf</ent> a
copy of my book (Collection of Separate Papers) on
<ent type='ORG'>Electrostatics</ent> and Magnetism. I shall be glad if you will
accept it from me as a very small mark of my gratitude to you
for your kindness. You may possibly find something
interesting in the articles on <ent type='ORG'>Atmospheric Electricity</ent> which
it contains.</p>

<p> Lady <ent type='PERSON'>Kelvin</ent> joins me in kind regards, and I remain,</p>

<p> Yours always truly,</p>

<p> <ent type='PERSON'>Kelvin</ent></p>

<p> Thank you also warmly for the beautiful flowers 13</p>

<p> TESLA AND RUSSELL</p>

<p> <ent type='PERSON'>Walter Russell</ent> was one of the most accomplished artists, sculptors,
writers and scientists of this century. His periodic chart of the
elements accurately predicted the location and characteristics of four
elements years before they were discovered in laboratories. These are
now known as Deuterium, Tritium, Neptunium, and Plutonium. <ent type='PERSON'>Russell</ent></p>

<p> apparently entered into a heightened state of awareness after being
struck by lightning. He began several weeks of drawing and writing
about the basic nature and make up of the physical universe. <ent type='ORG'>Russells</ent>'
family finally called the family doctor to determine if <ent type='PERSON'>Russell</ent> should
be committed to an mental institution. The doctor, upon seeing the
results of <ent type='ORG'>Russells</ent> weeks of work, said that he did not know what
<ent type='PERSON'>Russell</ent> was doing, but that he definitely was not mad.</p>

<p> Although the exact time and occasion of their meeting has not yet
been determined, <ent type='ORG'>Nikola</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent> and <ent type='PERSON'>Walter Russell</ent> did meet and discuss
their respective cosmologies. 14 <ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent> recognized the wisdom and power
of <ent type='ORG'>Russells</ent>' teaching and urged <ent type='PERSON'>Russell</ent> to lock up his knowledge in a
safe for 1000 years until man was ready for it. 15</p>

<p> WHY FREE ENERGY HASN'T HAPPENED YET</p>

<p> COMMENTS, POSSIBILITIES AND <ent type='ORG'>SOCIO ECONOMIC</ent> IMPLICATIONS</p>

<p> Although <ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent> did not accept many of the tenants of relativity and
quantum theory and never made the connection between matter and
energy, he did recognize the possibility of free and unlimited energy
as demonstrated by the following statement.</p>

<p> Can Man control [the ] grandest, most awe inspiring of all processes
in nature?...If he could do this, he would have powers almost unlimited
and supernatural... He could cause planes to collide and produce his
suns and stars, his heat and light. He could originate and develop
life in all its infinite forms....[Such powers] would place him beside
his creator, make him fulfill his ultimate destiny. 16</p>

<p> We see that <ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent> is asking a question, speculating, searching for an
answer. If <ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent> had developed free energy sources or learned how to
manipulate space time and gravity, during the time of his most public
and productive years, (up until about 1920), he would have had answers
to those questions.</p>

<p> Tesla's most misunderstood invention is popularly known as the "Death
Ray". It was simply a particle beam weapon which he proposed in 1937
and was fabricated under contracts with <ent type='ORG'>Alcoa Aluminum</ent> and the English
and <ent type='NORP'>Italian</ent> governments. 17 It used electrostatic propulsion
techniques and similar devices are being developed today by the
Strategic Defense Initiative Organization (SDIO) and the US Army
Strategic Defense Command. 18</p>

<p> So we see that mankind has not yet harnessed the infinite power of
the universe as envisioned by <ent type='ORG'>Nikola</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent>. The question remains, why
not?</p>

<p> Free energy devices, if they are feasible, are not about smaller
faster microcircuits or a bigger better mouse traps. This is a
technology which may revolutionize the socio-economic status quo on
planet <ent type='LOC'>Earth</ent>. At this moment the big pie is unevenly divided. One
quarter of the population on this rock, the third stone from the sun,
consumes three quarters of the yearly resource output. As one can
easily deduce, from a brief study of world affairs, there are about</p>

<p> three billion people who have just about had it with this scenario.
There are wars starvation and strife in every nook and cranny of the
planet. So what do we do about it?</p>

<p> Spaceship <ent type='LOC'>Earth</ent> Needs A Flight Plan</p>

<p> Either we divide the pie more evenly or we make the pie larger. The
first option requires that our standard of living must fall so that the
standard of living in the third world may rise. The second option
allows us to maintain our standard of living while we help raise the
standard of living of under privileged nations. This we must do. It
is our destiny. It is our responsibility. It is our final test.</p>

<p> Thirty thousand people starve to death every day on this planet, most
of them are children. Nations fight nations, war is part of our lives.
What drives our economy in the western world, allows us to enjoy a high
standard of living, a life of leisure compared to our neighbors south
of the imaginary line called a border? Many answers both economic,
social, political, and spiritual can be given. We do know that the
standard of living that a nation enjoys is directly related energy
consumption.</p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>Energy</ent> drives the economies of nations and Tesla's life long goal was
to make electric power equally available to all people any where on
this planet. He continued to promote his plan for the wireless
transmission of power in the yearly interviews he gave on his birthday
as late as 1940. 19 Electrical power allows on site processing of raw
materials. Electrical power can run pumps from water wells in areas
affected by drought. Electrical power delivered to the poverty
stricken areas of the world can make the pie larger, can help bring
about the needed economic equality which is our birth right.</p>

<p> Why hasn't power been made equally available to all people and
nations? Why haven't the much touted free energy devices described by
<ent type='PERSON'>Tom Bearden</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>John</ent> Bedini, Bruce DePalma, and others ever materialized?
Perhaps because "easy things are seldom done for the same reason that
impossible things are rarely done: no one will pay for anything
believed to be easy or impossible". 20 Perhaps because when we talk
about power there is more there than one would initially visualize.
What we are talking about is personal power, national power, planetary
power, karmic power and the power of love.</p>

<p> The sages tell us that in order to enjoy power we have to let go of
power, to overcome ourselves. As an example this author can describe
one of his recent experiences. After a very successful symposium
celebrating the 100th year after <ent type='ORG'>Nikola</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent> arrived in <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent>
States 21, a non profit corporation, 501(c)(3), was formed specifically
to encourage and pursue research into the inventions and discoveries of
<ent type='ORG'>Nikola</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent>. Two years later, after a second symposium, several of
the founding members approached the board of directors with a proposal
to validate Tesla's claim that wireless transmission of power was
possible. <ent type='ORG'>Board</ent> members suggested that permission be obtained from the
<ent type='ORG'>FCC</ent>, an environmental impact statement be filed with the <ent type='ORG'>EPA</ent>, and we
should go form "our own non profit corporation". 22 It was also
decided that since there was no procedure to cover research, the</p>

<p> organization could not be involved.</p>

<p> Another goal of the organization had been to establish a museum to be
named the <ent type='ORG'>Nikola</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent> Museum of Science and Technology. We proposed
that since 60 -70 billion dollars are given away to non profit
organizations annually, we had as good a chance as any other
organization for obtaining funding, for a museum or research. We
reasoned that:</p>

<p> "Since only 16% of the museums in this country are science
museums, this museum in honor of <ent type='ORG'>Nikola</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent> will help educate the
public in technological areas. With the need for economic
revitalization of industry in <ent type='GPE'>Colorado</ent>, 1986is the time to begin
supporting the scientific education of our region. With the current
statistics showing that <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States is falling behind the world
technologically, the effort to educate the public is becoming more
important, and the surge of public awareness of <ent type='ORG'>Nikola</ent> Tesla's
inventions makes him an appropriate namesake for a science and
technology museum." 23</p>

<p> The board moved to table our proposal indefinitely.</p>

<p> What had happened? Of the 15 - 20 people that had started the
organization only four remained as part of the governing body. Three
of those members were opposed to research. The collective mind of the
board of directors had become the antithesis of the momentum <ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent> had
gained in his lifetime. Unlike the independent inventor and
businessman, the board was now composed of members who were bureaucrats
and paper pushers for Fortune 500 companies. <ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent> was a vegetarian,
the board members all ate meat. <ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent> did not ask for permission to be
inventive and strike out on bold new adventures, the board needed
approval from higher sources. The dichotomies were endless.</p>

<p> Tesla's visions have been delayed for 89 years. The squabbling
started with Thomas Edison, J.P. Morgan and <ent type='ORG'>Nikola</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent> himself. 24 It
continues to this day. Perhaps the reason for the delay of wireless
power transmission or free energy devices lies even deeper within the
human psyche. Is it possible that we could compare the <ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent> story to
a biblical story? <ent type='PERSON'>Bruce Gordan</ent> thinks so. In Gordan's analysis
Tesla's attempt at building a prototype magnifying transmitter
parallels <ent type='ORG'>Genesis</ent> 11:1-9. 25</p>

<p> "The message; human curiosity and technological derring-do makes God
nervous; God demolishes project, confounds language". <ent type='PERSON'>Gordan</ent> further
outlines the the scenario as follows:</p>

<p> "ISOMORPHISM"</p>

<p> BIBLE STORY TESLA TALE</p>

<p> Human Efforts <ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent> Projects
Tower of Babel Wardenclyffe Tower
God Money (J.P. Morgan)</p>

<p> Demolition and Confounding to maintain Withdrawal of Morgan's
Status Quo of God drunk on power above, Financial Support and</p>

<p> humanity groveling in ignorance below. subsequent suppression of
Tesla's work in orthodox
science &amp; engineering circles
Perpetuation of mediocre
technology for energy
generation, storage,distribu-tion, to maintain favorable
cash flow for existing system
for energy management by
forcing continued combustion
of scarce fuels, keep
consumers, paying, paying,
paying......</p>

<p> "When everything is perfect, the right time shows up." 26 This is
equivalent to saying, "<ent type='ORG'>Absolute</ent> knowledge in the hands of one whose
heart is not yet tender, would be a terrible weapon. 27 We might postulate that technological developments do not occur until
the planet is ready. The recent examination of the theory of Gaia
credits the <ent type='LOC'>Earth</ent> with an intelligence. "Thousands of years ago, by
means of seeing, sorcerers became aware that the <ent type='LOC'>Earth</ent> was sentinent
and that its awareness could affect the awareness of humans." 28 By
implication of reciprocity the reverse could be true. The group or
collective unconscious is still struggling with the result of quantum
and relativity theory. We as a race were ready for nuclear power,
every thing was perfect and the right time showed up. Soon we will
have put the technology to good use or abandon it to insure our
survival as a species.</p>

<p> SO WHAT DO YOU DO ABOUT IT</p>

<p> FREE ENERGY: CREATING AN IDEA WHOSE <ent type='ORG'>TIME</ent> HAS COME</p>

<p> Wireless transmission of power and free energy have not happened yet,
perhaps we aren't ready, perhaps the <ent type='LOC'>Earth</ent> isn't ready. <ent type='ORG'>Pogo</ent> said it
best, " we have met the enemy and it is us." In the <ent type='NORP'>Jungian</ent> view of
collective unconscious, things happen when the time is right, we get
what we agree to. We need a flight plan. And that plan must realize
that,</p>

<p> WHEN THE POWER OF LOVE</p>

<p> OVERCOMES</p>

<p> THE LOVE OF POWER</p>

<p> THERE WILL BE</p>

<p> PEACE</p>

<p> [Source; <ent type='ORG'>Girls Lavatory</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Boulder High School</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Boulder</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Colorado</ent>]
Described as "<ent type='ORG'>Post Industrial</ent>, neo-technical, teen-age graffiti."</p>

<p> "So astounding are the facts in this connection, that it
would seem as though the Creator, himself had electrically
designed this planet...."</p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>Nikola</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent> describing what is now known as Schumann
Resonance (7.8 Hz) in "<ent type='ORG'>The Transmission</ent> of Electrical <ent type='ORG'>Energy</ent>
Without Wires As A Means Of Furthering World Peace",
Electrical World And Engineer, January 7, 1905, PP 21-24.</p>

<p> FOOTNOTES</p>

<p> 1. <ent type='PERSON'>Ratzlaff</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>John</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent> Said, <ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Book Company</ent>, PO Box
1649, <ent type='GPE'>Greenville</ent>, TX 75401, 1984.</p>

<p> 2. <ent type='ORG'>Yogananda</ent>, Paramahansa, Autobiography of a Yogi, Self
Realization Fellowship,, 3880 San Rafael Ave., <ent type='GPE'>Los Angeles</ent>,
CA 90065, 1985.</p>

<p> 3. <ent type='PERSON'>Cheney</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Margaret</ent>, Man Out of Time, Prentice Hall, 1981.</p>

<p> 4. Hunt, Inez and Draper. Wanetta, W., Lightning In His
Hand, The Life Story Of <ent type='ORG'>Nikola</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Omni Publications</ent>,
<ent type='GPE'>Hawthorne</ent>, CA, 1981.</p>

<p> 5. O'<ent type='PERSON'>Neal</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>John</ent>, J., Prodigal Genius, The Life Of <ent type='ORG'>Nikola</ent>
<ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Ives Washington</ent>, Inc., 1944.</p>

<p> 6. <ent type='PERSON'>Anderson</ent>, Leland, personal communication. See also
<ent type='PERSON'>Anderson</ent>, L.I., and <ent type='PERSON'>Ratzlaff</ent>, J.T., Dr. <ent type='ORG'>Nikola</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent>
Bibliography, Ragusan Press, 936 Industrial Avenue, Palo
Alto, CA 94303, 1979.</p>

<p> 7. <ent type='ORG'>Nikhilananda</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Swami</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Vivekananda</ent>, The Yogas and Other
Works, <ent type='PERSON'>Ramakrishna</ent>-<ent type='PERSON'>Vivekananda</ent> Center, <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent>, 1973.</p>

<p> 8. <ent type='ORG'>Nikhilananda</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Swami</ent>.</p>

<p> 9. <ent type='PERSON'>Dobson</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>John</ent>, personal communication.</p>

<p> 7. <ent type='PERSON'>Dobson</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>John</ent>, Advaita <ent type='ORG'>Vedanta</ent> and <ent type='ORG'>Modern Science</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Vedanta</ent>
Book Center, 5423 S. Hyde Park, <ent type='GPE'>Chicago</ent>, IL 60615, 1979.</p>

<p> 10. <ent type='ORG'>Nikhilananda</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Swami</ent>.</p>

<p> 11. Burke, <ent type='PERSON'>Marie Louise</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'><ent type='PERSON'>Swami</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Vivekananda</ent></ent> in the West, New
Discoveries, The World Teacher, <ent type='PERSON'>Advaita Ashrama</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Mayavati</ent>,
India, 1985, p. 500</p>

<p> 12. <ent type='ORG'>Grotz</ent>, T., "Artificially Stimulated Resonance of the
Earth's Schumann Cavity Waveguide", Proceedings of the Third
International New <ent type='ORG'>Energy</ent> Technology Symposium/Exhibition,
June 25th-28th, 1988, Hull, Quebec, Planetary Association for
Clean <ent type='ORG'>Energy</ent>, 191 Promenade du Portage/600, Hull, Quebec J8X
2K6 <ent type='GPE'>Canada</ent></p>

<p> 13. From the personal collection of L. <ent type='PERSON'>Anderson</ent>.</p>

<p> 14. <ent type='PERSON'>Russell</ent>, <ent type='NORP'>Lao</ent>. personal communication.</p>

<p> 15. <ent type='ORG'>The University</ent> of Science and Philosophy, Swannanoa,
<ent type='GPE'>Waynesboro</ent>, VA 22980, (703) 942-5161.</p>

<p> 16. First written by <ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent> on May 13, 1907, for the "Actors
Fair Fund", text transcribed from an A.L.S. in the
collections of <ent type='ORG'>the Bakken Library</ent> of Electricity in Life.
The article later appeared in the "<ent type='GPE'>New York</ent> American", July
6, 1930, pg. 10.</p>

<p> 17. <ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Nikola</ent>, <ent type='EVENT'>The New Art</ent> of Projecting Concentrated
Non-Dispersive <ent type='ORG'>Energy</ent> Through Natural Media, Proceedings of
the <ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent> <ent type='EVENT'>Centennial Symposium</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Grotz</ent>, T. &amp; <ent type='PERSON'>Rauscher</ent>, E.,
Editors, 1984.</p>

<p> 18. Turchi, P.J.,Conte, D.,Seiler, S., Electrostatic
Acceleration of Microprojectiles to Ultrahypervelocities,
"Proceedings of <ent type='ORG'>the Seventh Pulsed Power Conference</ent>", June
12th-14th, <ent type='GPE'>Monterey</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>California</ent>, Jointly Sponsored by the
<ent type='ORG'>DOD</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>DOE</ent>, and <ent type='ORG'>the IEEE Electron Devices Society</ent>.</p>

<p> 19. "<ent type='PERSON'>Death Ray</ent> for Planes", <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent> Times, September 20,
1940.</p>

<p> 20. Pawlicki, T.B., Exploring Hyperspace, 848 Fort Street,
Victoria, B.C., <ent type='GPE'>Canada</ent>, electronic book on floppy disk, 1988,
(Log onto the TESLA BBS at (719) 486-2775 for copy of ASCII
text files)</p>

<p> 21. Broad, William J., "<ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent> a Bizarre Genius, Regains Aura
of Greatness", <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent> Times, Aug. 28th, 1984</p>

<p> 22. El-Kareh, E., Elswick, S., memo, 1987.</p>

<p> 23. <ent type='ORG'>Grotz</ent>, T., &amp; Sheppard, J., The <ent type='ORG'>Nikola</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent> Museum of
Science and Technology submitted to the <ent type='ORG'>Board</ent> of Directors of
<ent type='ORG'>the International</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent> Society, December 12th, 1986.
[Available as an ASCII text file on the TESLA BBS (719) 486-2775]</p>

<p> 24. <ent type='PERSON'>Cheney</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Margaret</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent>, Man Out of Time, Prentice Hall
Inc, <ent type='GPE'>Englewood Cliffs</ent>, NJ, 1981.</p>

<p> 25. <ent type='PERSON'>Gordan</ent>, Bruce, private communication, 1988.</p>

<p> 26. Arguelles, Jose &amp; Lloydine, personal communication.</p>

<p> 27. <ent type='ORG'>Hercules</ent>, Michael, The Circle of Love, published by the
author.</p>

<p> 28. <ent type='PERSON'>Castenada</ent>, Carlos, The Power of Silence, Further Lessons
of <ent type='PERSON'>don Jaun</ent>, <ent type='PERSON'>Simon</ent> and Schuster, <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent>, 1987, Pg. 120.</p>

<p> FURTHER INFORMATION ABOUT TESLA</p>

<p> TESLA BBS: This is a full featured computer Bulletin <ent type='ORG'>Board</ent> Service for
access to information about current research and the life and times of
<ent type='ORG'>Nikola</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent>. A subsection of the <ent type='GPE'>Colorado</ent> Mountain College BBS, it
may be contacted using a computer and 300/1200/2400 baud modems at
(719) 486-2775.</p>

<p> The <ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent> Memorial Society The <ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent> Coil Builders Association
% <ent type='PERSON'>Nicholas Kosanovich</ent> % <ent type='PERSON'>Harry Goldman</ent>
453 Martin Road RD #6 Box 181
<ent type='GPE'>Lackawanna</ent>, NY 14218 Glenns Falls, NY 12801
(716) 822-0281 (518) 792-1003</p>

<p> The <ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Book Company</ent> High Voltage Press
PO Box 1649 PO Box 532
<ent type='GPE'>Greenville</ent>, TX 75401 <ent type='GPE'>Claremont</ent>, CA 91711
(214) 454-6819</p>

<p> Mr. Toby <ent type='ORG'>Grotz</ent>, President, <ent type='ORG'>Wireless Engineering</ent>, is an electrical
engineer and has 16 years experience in the field of geophysics,
aerospace and industrial research and design. While working for the
Geophysical Services Division of Texas Instruments and at the
University of Texas at <ent type='GPE'>Dallas</ent>, Mr. <ent type='ORG'>Grotz</ent> was introduced to and worked
with the geophysical concepts which are of importance to the wireless
transmission of power. As a Senior Engineer at <ent type='ORG'>Martin Marietta</ent>, Mr.
<ent type='ORG'>Grotz</ent> designed and supervised the construction of industrial process
control systems and designed and built devices and equipment for use in
research and development and for testing space flight hardware. Mr.
<ent type='ORG'>Grotz</ent> also worked for the public utility industry installing mini
computer based pollutant measuring data acquisition systems in fossil
fuel power plants and as a results engineer in a nuclear power plant.
Mr. <ent type='ORG'>Grotz</ent> organized and chaired the 1984 <ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent> <ent type='EVENT'>Centennial Symposium</ent> and
the 1986 International <ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent> Symposium and was president of the
International <ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent> Society, a not for profit corporation formed as a
result the first symposium. As Project Manager for Project <ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent>, Mr.
<ent type='ORG'>Grotz</ent> aided in the design and construction of a recreation of the
equipment <ent type='ORG'>Nikola</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Tesla</ent> used for wireless transmission of power
experiments in 1899 in <ent type='GPE'>Colorado</ent> Springs. Mr. <ent type='ORG'>Grotz</ent> received his
B.S.E.E. from <ent type='ORG'>the University</ent> of Connecticut in 1973.
</p></xml>