<xml><p>
A LIE THAT IS KILLING US</p>

<p> Animal experimentation, also known as vivisection, is directly
responsible for the rampant growth of cancer, heart disease, diabetes,
birth defects, arthritis, muscular dystrophy, leukemia, all kinds of mental
diseases, and an endless list of many other old afflictions as well as
scores of new ones, such as Alzheimer's disease and AIDS. These diseases
are causing the most massive, systematic, and widespread destruction of
human health ever known. The reason is fundamental: Today's research Is
based almost entirely on animal experimentation, which Is a medical and
scientific fraud. It is impossible to recreate a naturally occurring
disease In a healthy animal simply because once it is "retreated," it is
no longer the original, natural disease. The
predictable result of looking at artificially diseased animals is that the data
obtained is not applicable to man and thus is tragically misleading. This
is the reason why no disease has been cured in the 20th century except for
the control of infectious diseases, which was accomplished thanks to
nutrition, hygiene, and public sanitation. Consequently, all the old
diseases along with the new ones are killing and damaging more and more
people every day, including you and your family and friends.</p>

<p> A LIE THAT IS COSTING US TRILLIONS
OF DOLILARS (YES, TRILLIONS!)</p>

<p> There is no money to be made from healthy people. This is why
the medical and research establishments are not in the least interested in
prevention (practically all diseases are preventable). The criminal
refusal to remove the known causes of so many human ailments guarantees a situation where practically everyone is sick or will eventually get sick
(the flat refusal to educate people about the vital need to adopt a
vegetarian diet is a prime example). Once millions upon millions of
people are sick and dying and pronounced "in need" of drugs, tests,
radiation, surgeries, transplants, and all kinds of medical attention and
intervention, the expenditures connected with "health care" skyrocket
accordingly. In 1991 alone, <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States spent 750 billion dollars on
what should more appropriately be called "sickness care." It is
conservatively estimated that by the year 2000, annual "health care" costs
in <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States will have increased to at least 1.5 trillion dollars
($1500000000000) (1) Needless to say, such astronomical expenditures
(which have made countless doctors, surgeons, pharmaceutical companies,
and all kinds of institutions rich) have already broken the financial back
of the country. It is clear that prevention, and not "health care reform,"
is the real cure.</p>

<p> A LIE THAT TORTURES BILLIONS OF ANIMALS</p>

<p> It is estimated that, just in <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States, 100 million
animals of all kinds are tortured to death every year by vivisectionist
mills, which operate hidden from public view in colleges and universities,
hospitals, chemical and pharmaceutical companies, cosmetic and tobacco
companies, countless other corporations such as General Motors (in
car crash experiments), and by <ent type='ORG'>NASA</ent> and the military. The number of animals
used by the military is unknown and thus is not included in the 100
million figure. In addition, millions of animals are consumed by the
vivisectionist machinery in other countries all over the world (countries
that follow the "scientific standard" set by <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States). The 1991
budget of <ent type='ORG'>the National Institutes</ent> of Health (<ent type='ORG'>NIH</ent>) in <ent type='GPE'>Washington</ent>,D.C., the
largest source of funding for <ent type='PERSON'>vivisectors</ent>, was 8.6 billion tax dollars
($8600000000).(2) Because of AIDS (the new gold mine for the biomedical
establishment), we are now pouring more billions into the pockets of the
very "researchers" and "scientists" who never cured cancer, heart disease,
diabetes, or anything else despite having consumed hundreds of billions of
our tax dollars and billions of animals just in the last few decades.</p>

<p> A LIE THAT IS DESTROYING THE PLANET</p>

<p> Not only are our health and economy being systematically destroyed
by the vivisectionist mind-set, but so is our environment. The massive
production and widespread use of pesticides and countless other chemicals
found "safe" based on animal tests are responsible for the relentless and
massive pollution of our land, rivers, and oceans, the consequent
poisoning of our food and water supplies, the destruction of the earth's
protective ozone layer,and many other threats that are jeopardizing the
very survival of life on the planet.</p>

<p> A LIE THAT IS RESPONSIBLE FOR THE
BIRTH AND GROWTH OF NUCLEAR ARMS</p>

<p> Horrifying chemical, biological, and nuclear weapons, possessed by an
ever-increasing number of countries, were developed by <ent type='PERSON'>vivisectors</ent> and
"tested" on animals the same way a drug, detergent, or toothpaste is
"tested" on animals. Conventional weapons of all sorts were also created
in vivisectionist laboratories, where animals are routinely used as
surrogates for man in warlike situations.</p>

<p> A LIE THAT SABOTAGES REAL SOLUTIONS TO DRUG
ADDICTION AND MENTAL DISEASE</p>

<p> There is plenty of tax money to fund endless numbers of grotesque
and useless "experiments"where perfectly healthy animals are turned
into drug addicts and alcoholics. No money is available, however, to help
the millions of human beings who are being destroyed not only by the drugs
and alcohol they are addicted to, but also by the utter hopelessness they
feel when life-saving treatment is denied them because of this criminal
waste of precious resources. The same applies to the increasing numbers of
mentally ill people who are often totally ignored, while incredibly huge
amounts of money are poured by <ent type='ORG'>the National Institutes</ent> of Mental Health
and other sources into psychological and other "experiments" where animals
are driven insane. It is important to remember that the overwhelming
majority of homeless people are drug addicts, alcoholics, and/or mentally
ill individuals.</p>

<p> WHY ANIMAL <ent type='ORG'>EXPERIMENTATION</ent> IS A
MEDICAL AND SCIENTIFIC FRAUD</p>

<p> The medical and scientific fraud of vivisection is based on the following
lies that the
biomedical empire relentlessly spoon-feeds the public in countries all over the
world with the
help of the beholden media:</p>

<p> LIE #1 : It is possible to recreate a naturally occurring human
disease in a healthy animal (what researchers call "an animal model of a
human disease"). SCIENTIFIC FACT #1: h is by definition impossible. Trying
to re-create spontaneous human diseases (naturally occurring diseases that
arise from within) in a healthy being constitutes "experimental research." It is impossible to re-create a naturally occurring human disease
in a healthy animal (or in a healthy human being for that matter) simply
because once it Is "recreated,"It is artificial and is no longer the
original, natural disease. Clearly,"re-creation" and "spontaneous" are
contradictory terms. It then follows that experimental research cannot
find cures for any diseases no matter how many millions of animal or human
experiments are performed (human experiments are also common place). It is
sometimes possible to re-create some of the symptoms of a disease but
never the disease itself. The exception to this fact is the case of
infectious diseases. However, animals do not get human infectious diseases
and we do not get theirs. This Is why <ent type='PERSON'>vivisectors</ent> cannot infect a single
animal with human AIDS despite massive efforts aimed at creating "an
animal model of human AIDS." (Besides, a nonhuman animal cannot have a
human disease because each species of animal is a different biomechanical
entity.)</p>

<p> Obviously, prevention is the ideal situation. Once disease has
occurred, however, the only hope for a successful treatment and possible
cure is clinical research, or the observation of human beings who have
naturally occurring diseases. Clinical research is the only way to get
valid answers. Tragically, we keep financing experimental research to the
almost total exclusion of prevention and clinical research.</p>

<p> LIE #2: It is possible to learn human anatomy and physiology by
studying four legged animals (quadrupeds), fish, and/or birds.
5ClENTIFICFACT#2: Animals are totally different from man and from each
other genetically, histologically, anatomically, physiologically,
immunologically, emotionally, psychologically, sexually, and socially. It
Is clear that human medical cannot be based on veterinary medicine.</p>

<p> LIE #3: It is possible to predict human reactions to drugs, vaccines,
and other chemicals by testing them in animals. SCIENTIFIC FACT#3: Animals
react differently to drugs, vaccines, and other chemicals not only from
man but also from each other. Hence the incalculable damage to human
health caused by pharmaceutical drugs and vaccines.</p>

<p> LIE #4: Animal experimentation is useful in order to learn about
animal diseases in veterinary schools. SCIENTIFIC FACT #4: No knowledge
about animal diseases can be obtained by looking at artificially diseased
animals (experimental research). Same reasons as in Scientific Fact #1 .</p>

<p> THE NEW ANTIVIVISECTIONIST MOVEMENI</p>

<p> The new antivivisectionist movement represented by <ent type='ORG'>SUPRESS</ent> is seeking
the total abolition of animal experimentation and testing on medical and
scientific ground:. For the first time ever, the public is being informed
about one of the most suppressed issues of the last 100 years: the
connection between animal experimentation and the systematic devastation
to our health, environment, and economy.</p>

<p> BEWARE OF <ent type='ORG'>IHE</ent> "ANIMAL RIGHTS" TRAP</p>

<p> The biomedical empire has a vested interest in promoting the slogan
"animal rights" because making vivisection a moral, ethical,
philosophical, and/or religious issue Is the most effective way to shift
the public's attention away from its medical and scientific fraudulence.
For decades the <ent type='PERSON'>vivisectors</ent> have been able to disarm the opposition by
using the tired line: What will it be, your dog or your baby? (which
implies that anyone opposed to animal experimentation is <ent type='ORG'>antihuman</ent>). We
are now painfully aware of the fact that this emotional question tries to
hide an indisputable fact: <ent type='ORG'>Vivisectors</ent> routinely take the lives of both
the dog and the baby. Vivisection as it is presented to the public is not
a moral issue. It is a medical and scientific issue, a human health issue.</p>

<div>-----------------------------------------------------------------------------</div>

<p> Please do not remove this advertisement!</p>

<p> Call The Cell - Would like more information on animal rights?

(817) 589-0283

Directly working from <ent type='ORG'>IDA</ent>, SURPESS, PETA Literature</p>

<p> Article above from Suppress - Call 1-800-KILL-VIV</p>

<p>X-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-X
Another file downloaded from: The NIRVANAnet(tm) Seven</p>

<p> &amp; <ent type='ORG'>the Temple</ent> of the Screaming Electron Taipan Enigma 510/935-5845
Burn This Flag Zardoz 408/363-9766
reality check <ent type='PERSON'>Poindexter Fortran</ent> 510/527-1662
Lies Unlimited <ent type='PERSON'>Mick Freen</ent> 801/278-2699
The New Dork Sublime Biffnix 415/864-DORK
The Shrine Rif Raf 206/794-6674
Planet Mirth Simon Jester 510/786-6560

"Raw Data for Raw Nerves"
X-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-=-X
</p></xml>