<xml>

<p> The Strange Case of Maj. Gen. <ent type='PERSON'>Edwin</ent> A. <ent type='PERSON'>Walker</ent></p>

<p>General <ent type='PERSON'>Edwin</ent> A. <ent type='PERSON'>Walker</ent> is known to most <ent type='PERSON'>JFK</ent> assassination buffs as
the man whom <ent type='PERSON'>Oswald</ent> allegedly shot at in April 1963. The general's
right-wing connections are often noted, as is the fact that he was
forced out of his command by the <ent type='PERSON'>Kennedy</ent> administration for his
political indoctrination of his troops. His activities during the
race riots in <ent type='GPE'>Oxford</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Mississippi</ent> in 1962 are also often mentioned,
when he was arrested on four federal charges including insurrection.</p>

<p>His public statement at <ent type='GPE'>Oxford</ent> was as follows:</p>

<p> This is <ent type='PERSON'>Edwin</ent> A. <ent type='PERSON'>Walker</ent>. I am in <ent type='GPE'>Mississippi</ent> beside Gov. Ross
Barnett. I call for a national protest against the conspiracy
from within.</p>

<p> Rally to the cause of freedom in righteous indignation, violent
vocal protest and bitter silence under the flag of <ent type='GPE'>Mississippi</ent>
at the use of Federal troops.</p>

<p> This today is a disgrace to the nation in 'dire peril,' a
disgrace beyond the capacity of anyone except its enemies.
This is the conspiracy of the crucifixion by anti-Christ
conspirators of <ent type='ORG'>the Supreme Court</ent> in their denial of prayer
and their betrayal of a nation.</p>

<p> [source <ent type='ORG'>NYT</ent>, 9/30/62]</p>

<p>The <ent type='ORG'>Army</ent> ordered General <ent type='PERSON'>Walker</ent> to undergo psychiatric testing.</p>

<p>The general's case is strange indeed. But another fact, not often mentioned,
makes his activities in 1961-3 even stranger. Going back to 1957, we find
him in charge of *enforcing* the desegregation order in <ent type='LOC'>Little Rock</ent>,
<ent type='GPE'>Arkansas</ent>. His public statements on the matter were limited to exhorting
the public to uphold the will of the courts and desegregate peacefully.
The following article details his biography up to that time.</p>

<p>============================================================================
<ent type='ORG'>New York</ent> Times, September 25, 1957, page 18</p>

<p> HE GUARDS THE PEACE
<ent type='PERSON'>Edwin</ent> Anderson <ent type='PERSON'>Walker</ent></p>

<p>LITTLE ROCK, Sept. 24 -- Maj. Gen. <ent type='PERSON'>Edwin</ent> Anderson <ent type='PERSON'>Walker</ent>, who will be
responsible for maintaining peace in <ent type='LOC'>Little Rock</ent>, was described by staff
officers today as "tough, but fair." A tall, lean-visaged <ent type='NORP'>Texan</ent>,
General <ent type='PERSON'>Walker</ent> came to <ent type='LOC'>Little Rock</ent> only seven weeks ago as commander of
the <ent type='GPE'>Arkansas</ent> Military District. He is still a stranger to the city.
Today, General <ent type='PERSON'>Walker</ent> was at his desk in a downtown office building at
7 A.M. He had not yet received formal orders to take over the <ent type='GPE'>Arkansas</ent>
<ent type='ORG'>National Guard</ent>, but he knew what was coming. Already orders carrying
his signature were being processed for the deployment of <ent type='ORG'>National Guard</ent>
units. He will command a combined force of regulars and Federalized
Guardsmen.</p>

<p>He stands 6 feet 3 inches in height. He is a bachelor and has been
considered a prize for hostesses wherever he has been stationed.
He was born in Center Point, <ent type='GPE'>Texas</ent>, on Nov. 10, 1909.</p>

<p>General Walker's favorite expression is "check," a word he snaps to
indicate a mission has been accomplished or that he understands his
orders.</p>

<p>As a member of the Special Services group, he was required to be a
paratrooper. At his test, he approached a subordinate and asked:</p>

<p>"How do you put this thing on?"</p>

<p>He received a fast five-minute briefing and climbed into an airplane.
He jumped, landed safe and snapped to the test officer: "Check."</p>

<p>General <ent type='PERSON'>Walker</ent> is a combat officer. He has seen action in <ent type='EVENT'>World War</ent> II
and in <ent type='GPE'>Korea</ent>. He has carried out a number of unusual and hazardous
assignments, particularly during <ent type='EVENT'>World War</ent> II.</p>

<p>He started his military career as an artillery officer after he
graduated from <ent type='LOC'>West Point</ent> in 1931. But he switched to commando
operations during the war and led a special force of Canadians and
<ent type='NORP'>Americans</ent>, in <ent type='GPE'>Italy</ent> and in <ent type='GPE'>France</ent>.</p>

<p>This outfit, trained for airborne, amphibious, mountain and ski
operations, was called the Special Services Force.</p>

<p>General <ent type='PERSON'>Walker</ent> led the Third Regiment, First Special Service Force,
in its initial operation at <ent type='ORG'>Kiska</ent> during the <ent type='NORP'>Aleutians</ent> campaign. When
the commandos were transferred to the <ent type='NORP'>Italian</ent> campaign, General <ent type='PERSON'>Walker</ent>
led the first Special Service Force in tough mountain fighting up the
<ent type='NORP'>Italian</ent> peninsula and at Anzio beachhead.</p>

<p> A Surprise Landing</p>

<p>In August, 1944, his men made a surprise landing on the <ent type='ORG'>Hyeres</ent> Islands
off the <ent type='NORP'>French</ent> <ent type='ORG'>Riviera</ent> and killed or captured a strong <ent type='NORP'>German</ent> garrison
that could have jeopardized the Seventh <ent type='ORG'>Army</ent> landings on the mainland
near by.</p>

<p>With the <ent type='ORG'>Hyeres</ent> occupied, his troops rejoined the main invasion force
and moved up the <ent type='LOC'>Rhone Valley</ent>. Toward the end of the war he was detached
from the commandos and placed in command of the 417 <ent type='ORG'>Infantry Regiment</ent>,
a separate force attached to the Third <ent type='ORG'>Army</ent>. At V-E Day he was commanding
a special task unit in <ent type='GPE'>Oslo</ent>.</p>

<p>Returning to <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States in January, 1946, General <ent type='PERSON'>Walker</ent> served as
assistant director of the combined arms department, Field Artillery
School, Fort Sill, Okla. He was in charge of the <ent type='NORP'>Greek</ent> desk at the
<ent type='ORG'>Pentagon</ent> during the <ent type='NORP'>Greek</ent> civil war and made an official visit to <ent type='GPE'>Greece</ent>
and <ent type='GPE'>Turkey</ent>.</p>

<p>During the <ent type='GPE'>Korea</ent>n War, General <ent type='PERSON'>Walker</ent> commanded <ent type='ORG'>the Seventh Regiment</ent>
of <ent type='ORG'>the Third Infantry Division</ent> and later was senior adviser to
Generalissimo Chiang Kai-shek. His last assignment before coming to
<ent type='LOC'>Little Rock</ent> was as commanding general at the Twenty-fifth Artillery
Division in <ent type='GPE'>Hawaii</ent>.</p>

<p>He holds the Silver Star and the Bronze Star with oak leaf cluster.
============================================================================</p>

<p>This is the man arrested on four federal charges in <ent type='GPE'>Mississippi</ent> in 1962?</p>

<p>Those charges were:</p>

<p> Section 111-- For assault and resisting or other opposing Federal
officers, including marshals, in the performance of their duty.</p>

<p> Section 372-- For conspiracy to prevent a Federal officer from
discharging his duties.</p>

<p> Section 2383-- For inciting or engaging in an insurrection
against <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States.</p>

<p> Section 2384-- For conspiracy to overthrow or oppose by force
the execution of the laws of <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States.</p>

<p>A conspiracy is defined legally as including two or more persons.</p>

<p>On October 7, 1962, <ent type='PERSON'>Walker</ent> posted $50000 bond and returned home to
<ent type='GPE'>Dallas</ent> amid 200 cheering supporters carrying signs like "Welcome
Home, General <ent type='PERSON'>Walker</ent>," "Win With General <ent type='PERSON'>Walker</ent>," and "President '64." </p>

<p>On January 21, 1963, a federal grand jury in <ent type='GPE'>Oxford</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Mississippi</ent> adjourned
without indicting <ent type='PERSON'>Walker</ent> on any of the four counts against him.</p>

<p>The Justice Department dismissed the charges "without prejudice" after
the grand jury failed to indict. The dismissal "without prejudice"
meant that the charges could be reinstated before the five year statute
of limitations expired.</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Walker</ent> and his supporters then went on the offensive. On April 2, 1963,
a group called <ent type='ORG'>the Citizens Congressional Committee</ent> filed a petition
with the Senate Judiciary Committee requesting an investigation of the
treatment of "America's fearless patriot on the occasion of his
incarceration at the instigation of <ent type='ORG'>the Department</ent> of Justice."</p>

<p>Nine days later, on April 9, <ent type='PERSON'>Walker</ent> was sitting at his desk at home when
the famous shooting incident occurred.</p>

<p>Meanwhile, the <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n Medical Association was receiving "a volume of
letters from individual physicians" charging Dr. Charles E. <ent type='ORG'>Smith</ent>, the
<ent type='ORG'>Army</ent> psychiatrist -- who commented on Walker's mental state at the time
of the <ent type='GPE'>Oxford</ent> violence -- with unethical conduct: that he made an improper
diagnosis without a personal examination. Dr. <ent type='ORG'>Smith</ent> was cleared by the
<ent type='ORG'>AMA</ent> on July 4, 1963. He said that news stories of Walker's "reported
behavior reflects sensitivity and essentially unpredictable and seemingly
bizarre outbursts of the type often observed in individuals suffering
with paranoid mental disorder." The society had received 2500 letters
from physicians alleging unethical conduct by Dr. <ent type='ORG'>Smith</ent>. Nevertheless,
the board unanimously ruled in Smith's favor.</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Walker</ent> then took his case to court, filing a total of $23 million dollars
in libel damages against numerous media outlets alleging that they had
made "false statements" and that their "suppression of truth was motivated
by malice and a desire to hurt and harm him in his good reputation and
blacken his good name." The statements in question were that he "led a
charge of students against Federal marshals on the Ole Miss campus"
and various other statements attributing to him a very active role in leading
the insurrection such as "<ent type='PERSON'>Walker</ent> assumed command of the crowd." A jury
in <ent type='GPE'>Fort Worth</ent> awarded an $800000 judgment against the Associated Press,
ruling that malice was intended.</p>

<p>The offensive was also being taken up by <ent type='NORP'>Republicans</ent> in <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent> in an
alliance with <ent type='NORP'>Southern Democrats</ent>, who wanted to embarrass Attorney
General <ent type='PERSON'>Robert</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Kennedy</ent> because of his civils rights activities. <ent type='ORG'>The House</ent>
Judiciary Committee voted on September 1, 1964 by a margin of 18 to 14 to
open an investigation of the Justice Department's handling of cases
including, but not limited to, those of <ent type='PERSON'>Jimmy Hoffa</ent>, Roy M. Cohn, and
former Maj. Gen. <ent type='PERSON'>Edwin</ent> A. <ent type='PERSON'>Walker</ent>. The vote among <ent type='NORP'>Republican</ent> and Southern
<ent type='NORP'>Democrat</ent>ic committee members was 16-2; that of non-<ent type='NORP'>Southern Democrats</ent>
was 2-12. </p>

<p>Meanwhile, a <ent type='GPE'>Louisiana</ent> jury awarded <ent type='PERSON'>Walker</ent> $3 million in damages in another
one of his libel suits.</p>

<p>His luck started to turn sour however, and finally on June 12, 1967, the
Supreme Court ruled 9-0 extending the constitutional protection of
freedom of the press to libelous falsehoods about private individuals
who willingly take part in public affairs. Such protections were already in
place concerning libel against political officials, but this was a landmark
case extending the applicability to private individuals who willingly
venture into the public arena. Walker's awards were overturned.</p>

<p>Chief Justice <ent type='PERSON'>Warren</ent> explained, "Our citizenry has a legitimate and
substantial interest in the conduct of such persons... Freedom of the
press to engage in uninhibited debate about their involvement in public
issues should be subject to derogatory criticism, even when based on
false statements."</p>

<p>Walker's name occasionally surfaced in the press after this, usually
in connection with anti-UN activities or in connection with the
presidential campaign of <ent type='PERSON'>George Wallace</ent>.</p>

<div>-----------------------------------------------------------------------------</div>

<p>APPENDIX</p>

<p>These articles concern the controversy about right-wing extremism in the
military in the early Sixties, specifically related to General <ent type='PERSON'>Walker</ent> and
the <ent type='PERSON'>Kennedy</ent> administration.</p>

<p>=============================================================================
<ent type='ORG'>New York</ent> Times, June 18, 1961, page 1</p>

<p> Right-Wing Officers Worrying <ent type='ORG'>Pentagon</ent></p>

<p> by Cabell Philips</p>

<p>WASHINGTON, June 17 -- The <ent type='ORG'>Pentagon</ent> is having its troubles with
right-wingers in uniform.</p>

<p>A number of officers of high and middle rank are indoctrinating their
commands and the civilian population near their bases with political
theories resembling those of <ent type='ORG'>the John Birch Society</ent>. They are also
holding up to criticism and ridicule some official policies of the
United States Government.</p>

<p>The most conspicuous example of some of these officers was Maj. Gen.
<ent type='PERSON'>Edwin</ent> A. <ent type='PERSON'>Walker</ent>, who was officially "admonished" for his activities
by the Secretary of the <ent type='ORG'>Army</ent> earlier this week.</p>

<p>General Walker's offense was in saying that a number of prominent
<ent type='NORP'>Americans</ent>, as well as elements of the newspaper and television industries,
were tainted with <ent type='NORP'>Communist</ent> ideology.</p>

<p>He did this in the course of a continuing effort that the general said
was "designed to develop an understanding of the <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n military and
civil heritage, responsibility toward that heritage and the facts and
objectives of those enemies who would destroy it."</p>

<p>General <ent type='PERSON'>Walker</ent> was the commander of the Twenty-Fourth Infantry Division
in <ent type='NORP'>German</ent>y at the time...</p>

<p>The problem for the <ent type='ORG'>Pentagon</ent> arises out of the fact that a number of its
higher ranking officers have participated in or publically lent their
support to a variety of so-called forums, schools, and seminars,
ostensibly focused on the issues of national security. However, many of
those groups -- at least incidentally -- are preoccupied with radically
right-wing political philosophies.</p>

<p> Stress on Anti-Communism</p>

<p>The chief ingredient of these philosophies is often a militant
anti-communism. The argument is that <ent type='NORP'>Communist</ent> subversion today is rife
among the schools, the churches, labor unions, Government offices, and
elsewhere.</p>

<p>In this argument, liberalism is equated with socialism and socialism with
communism. Thus it opposes most welfare legislation, many programs for
international cooperation such as foreign aid and disarmament
conferences...</p>

<p>The genesis of this program goes back to the so-called "cold war policy"
evolved by <ent type='ORG'>the National Security Council</ent> in the summer of 1958...</p>

<p> <ent type='EVENT'>Cold War</ent> Widened</p>

<p>President <ent type='PERSON'>Eisenhower</ent> and his top policy leaders decreed that the "cold
war" could not be fought as a series of separate and often unrelated
actions, as with foreign aid and propaganda. Rather, it must be fought
with a concentration of all the resources of the Government and with
the full understanding and support of the civilian population. It was
decided, in particular, that the military should be used to reinforce
the "cold war" effort.</p>

<p>This was the substance of the still-classified "cold-war policy" paper
of <ent type='ORG'>the National Security Council</ent>...</p>

<p>Of the hundreds of military bases here and abroad, only a score have
become involved in these programs to the point that they have caused
alarm among the new civilian team in the <ent type='ORG'>Pentagon</ent>. Officials suspect,
however, that the trend is somewhat more widespread than their reports
currently indicate. They are quietly trying to find out how widespread
it is.</p>

<p>A typical example about which they do know is a seminar labeled Project
Action.</p>

<p>This was held at the Naval <ent type='ORG'>Air</ent> Station, Wold-Chamberlain Field,
<ent type='GPE'>Minneapolis</ent>, on April 28 and 29 of this year. Capt. <ent type='PERSON'>Robert</ent> T. <ent type='PERSON'>Kieling</ent>
is the commanding officer of the station. He was a co-sponsor of the
program in collaboration with a committee of the <ent type='GPE'>Minneapolis</ent>-St. Paul
Chamber of Commerce.</p>

<p>The official announcement described the program as follows:</p>

<p>"The purpose of Project Action is to inspire the citizens of this area
to take an active part in the war against the danger that threatens our
freedom and <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n way of life."</p>

<p>"The program of talks and presentations by nationally-known leaders for
the cause of democracy will bring to light facts and figures concerning
the rising crime rate, juvenile delinquency, drug addiction, the general
degradation of morals, the complacent attitude toward patriotism, and
the tremendous gains the <ent type='NORP'>Communist</ent> conspiracy is making in this
country..."</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>The United</ent> States Naval <ent type='ORG'>Air</ent> Station is making facilities available for
the seminar at the request of the Twin Cities Council for <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>n
Ideals...</p>

<p>Among the scores of letters concerning Project Action that reached the
<ent type='ORG'>Pentagon</ent> in the following days was one from a newspaper editor. It said
in part:</p>

<p>"Perhaps someone can clear up for us our lack of understanding as to just
how co-sponsorship of such activities fits in with the <ent type='ORG'>Navy</ent> mission, or
the overall military mission, for that matter. It must be admitted that
the local Project Action is politically partisan in a very real sense,
although the partisanship is not that of the party label type." ...</p>

<p>Among numerous other incidents that have been brought to the attention
of <ent type='ORG'>the Defense Department</ent> is the "Fourth Dimensional Warfare Seminar"
held in <ent type='GPE'>Pittsburgh</ent> on April 15. Among those listed as giving "assistance
and support" to the program were Lieut. Gen. Ridgely Gaither, Commanding
General, Second <ent type='ORG'>Army</ent>, and Maj. Gen. Ralph C. Cooper, Commanding General
of the Twenty-First <ent type='ORG'>Army</ent> Corps, and their respective staffs...</p>

<p>"This sort of thing, if carried far enough among susceptible people,
can breed a wave of vigilantism and witch-hunting," one <ent type='ORG'>Pentagon</ent> official
said. "Even Mr. <ent type='PERSON'>Hoover</ent> of the F.B.I., whom nobody would call 'soft on
communism,' deplores these self-appointed counter-spies." ...</p>

<p>Reinforcing his point, he took from his desk a memorandum from Secretary
of <ent type='ORG'>Defense</ent> <ent type='PERSON'>Robert</ent> S. McNamara, which has been circulated as "guidance"
throughout the services. In part, it said:</p>

<p>"After the President has taken a position, has established a policy, or
after appropriate officials in <ent type='ORG'>the Defense Department</ent> have established a
policy, I expect that no member of the department, either civilian or
military, will discuss that policy other than in a way to support it
before the public." ...</p>

<p>=============================================================================
<ent type='ORG'>New York</ent> Times, September 8, 1961</p>

<p> McNamara Refuses to Identify Individual Censors in <ent type='ORG'>Pentagon</ent></p>

<p> But He Gives Senators a List of Security Staff --
<ent type='PERSON'>Thurmond</ent> Voices Criticism of Policy on Anti-Red Speeches</p>

<p>WASHINGTON, Sept. 7 -- <ent type='ORG'>Defense</ent> Secretary <ent type='PERSON'>Robert</ent> S. McNamara refused today
to give the name of the person in the <ent type='ORG'>Pentagon</ent> immediately responsible
for deleting anti-<ent type='NORP'>Communist</ent> statements from speeches by an <ent type='ORG'>Army</ent> general.</p>

<p>He did provide a roster of the twelve-man security and review staff,
which clears speeches. But he declined to identify particular individuals
in the section who had made specific deletions.</p>

<p>The demand for this information was made by Senator <ent type='PERSON'>Strom Thurmond</ent>,
<ent type='NORP'>Democrat</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>South Carolina</ent>, at the close of hearings before the Senate
Armed Services Committee on his resolution for a full investigation of
charges that military officers have been "muzzled." ...</p>

<p>It was also learned today that Gen. <ent type='PERSON'>Edwin</ent> A. <ent type='PERSON'>Walker</ent>, deposed last spring
from his command in Europe because of the nature of his troop
indoctrination program, had pleaded the military equivalent of the Fifth
Amendment's guarantee against self-incrimination during the investigation
of his case by the <ent type='ORG'>Army</ent> Inspector General...</p>

<p>The entire transcript of the proceedings involving General <ent type='PERSON'>Walker</ent>, which
runs to more than 900 pages, is in the process of being declassified by
<ent type='ORG'>the Department</ent> of <ent type='ORG'>Defense</ent>...</p>

<p>Senator Thurmond's inquiry today related to a speech prepared for delivery
last March by Gen. Arthur G. <ent type='PERSON'>Trudeau</ent>, Chief of <ent type='ORG'>Army</ent> Research. In
testimony today it was indicated that the excisions had the effect of
softening the general's blunt criticism of <ent type='NORP'>Soviet</ent> policies and tactics.</p>

<p>Mr. McNamara said that the justifications for the changes was that
negotiations were then going on with the <ent type='NORP'>Russians</ent> for release of the
downed RB-47. It was regarded as impolitic at the time, he explained,
to provoke the <ent type='NORP'>Russians</ent> unnecessarily...</p>

<p>=============================================================================
<ent type='ORG'>New York</ent> Times, November 19, 1961, page 1</p>

<p> <ent type='ORG'>KENNEDY ASSERTS</ent> FAR-RIGHT <ent type='ORG'>GROUPS</ent> PROVOKE DISUNITY</p>

<p> Attacks <ent type='ORG'>Birch Society</ent> and 'Minutemen' at a <ent type='ORG'>Party</ent> Dinner in <ent type='GPE'>Los</ent> Angeles</p>

<p> Spread of Fear Scored</p>

<p> President Says Real Threat Comes From Without, Not Within</p>

<p>by <ent type='PERSON'>Tom</ent> Wicker</p>

<p>LOS <ent type='GPE'>ANGELES</ent>, Nov. 18-- President <ent type='PERSON'>Kennedy</ent> spoke out tonight against the
right-wing John <ent type='ORG'>Birch Society</ent> and the so-called Minutemen in a speech
at a <ent type='NORP'>Democrat</ent>ic <ent type='ORG'>Party</ent> dinner here.</p>

<p>The President mentioned neither group by name but left no doubt whom he
meant.</p>

<p> [In <ent type='GPE'>Atlanta</ent>, Senator <ent type='PERSON'>Barry Goldwater</ent>, <ent type='GPE'>Arizona</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Republican</ent>, attacked
the "radicals in the <ent type='ORG'>White House</ent>." At a news conference, he called
President <ent type='PERSON'>Kennedy</ent> the "wagon master" who is "riding on the left
wheel all the time."]</p>

<p>The President, in his talk at the Hollywood Palladium, also made his
first public response to Edward M. <ent type='ORG'>Dealey</ent>, publisher of the <ent type='GPE'>Dallas</ent>
Morning News. Mr. <ent type='ORG'>Dealey</ent> attacked the President at a <ent type='ORG'>White House</ent>
luncheon for "riding Caroline's tricycle" instead of being "a man on
horseback."</p>

<p> Some '<ent type='ORG'>Escape Responsibility</ent>'</p>

<p>"There have always been those fringes of our society who have sought to
escape their own responsibility by finding a simple solution, an appealing
slogan or a convenient scapegoat," Mr. <ent type='PERSON'>Kennedy</ent> said.</p>

<p>Now, he continued, "men who are unwilling to face up to the danger from
without are convinced that the real danger comes from within."</p>

<p>"They look suspiciously at their neighbors and their leaders," he declared.
"They call for a 'man on horseback' because they do not trust the people.
They find treason in our finest churches, in our highest court, and even
in the treatment of our water."</p>

<p>"They equate the <ent type='NORP'>Democrat</ent>ic <ent type='ORG'>Party</ent> with the welfare state, the welfare
state with socialism, and socialism with communism. They object quite
rightly to politics' intruding on the military -- but they are anxious
for the military to engage in politics." ...</p>

<p>Mr. <ent type='PERSON'>Kennedy</ent> chose a region in which <ent type='ORG'>the John Birch Society</ent> has some of
its strongest support to make his third and sharpest attack on what he
called tonight "the discordant voices of extremism."</p>

<p>In the first two speeches, at <ent type='ORG'>Chapel Hill</ent>, N. C., and <ent type='GPE'>Seattle</ent>, he also
warned against left-wing and pacifist extremists. His remarks tonight
were directed to far-right groups and individuals.</p>

<p>The reference to "armed bands of civilian guerillas" appeared to be
directed at the Minutemen, individual groups of which are being
organized and armed in some parts of the country. The organization
is reputed to be particularly strong in <ent type='GPE'>California</ent>.</p>

<p><ent type='GPE'>Los</ent> Angeles is regarded as almost the heartland of the <ent type='ORG'>Birch Society</ent>.
Two <ent type='NORP'>Republican</ent> Representatives from its urban districts, John H.
Rousselot and Edgar W. Hiestland, are avowed members. ...</p>

<p>=============================================================================
<ent type='ORG'>New York</ent> Times, November 19, 1961, page 54</p>

<p> RIGHTISTS PICKET KENNEDY SPEECH</p>

<p> 3000 Parade in <ent type='GPE'>Los</ent> Angeles in Orderly Demonstration</p>

<p>LOS <ent type='GPE'>ANGELES</ent>, Nov. 18-- Raucous picketing took place outside the Hollywood
Palladium where President <ent type='PERSON'>Kennedy</ent> spoke.</p>

<p>For nearly an hour, 3000 persons paraded, carrying signs and chanting
and singing their protests over a variety of issues.</p>

<p>The demonstration, which started rather mildly five hours before the
President spoke, was suddenly stepped up by an apparent influx of
rightists.</p>

<p>Some of the signs carried by men and women wearing red, white, and blue
paper hats, read: "Unmuzzle the Military," "Clean Up the State
Department," "Veto <ent type='PERSON'>Tito</ent>," "Disarmament is Suicide," and "CommUNism is
Our Enemy."</p>

<p>The marchers sporadically chanted "Test the Bomb," and, "No Aid to <ent type='PERSON'>Tito</ent>."
They sang, among other things, "God Bless <ent type='GPE'>America</ent>" and "The Battle Hymn
of the Republic."</p>

<p>A much smaller contingent of pacifist marchers was elbowed out. Most of
these carried signs urging the end of all atomic testing...</p>

<p>=============================================================================
<ent type='ORG'>New York</ent> Times, November 19, 1961, page 54</p>

<p> <ent type='PERSON'>Eisenhower</ent> Travels Aloft With <ent type='PERSON'>Kennedy</ent></p>

<p>SHERMAN, Tex. Nov. 18 (AP) -- President <ent type='PERSON'>Kennedy</ent> and former President <ent type='PERSON'>Dwight</ent>
D. <ent type='PERSON'>Eisenhower</ent> rode together to <ent type='ORG'>Perrin Air Force Base</ent> near here by helicopter
today after attending the funeral of <ent type='PERSON'>Sam Rayburn</ent> at near-by <ent type='PERSON'>Bonham</ent>.</p>

<p>Senator <ent type='PERSON'>Carl Hayden</ent>, <ent type='NORP'>Democrat</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>Arizona</ent>, was also on the helicopter.</p>

<p>Mr. <ent type='PERSON'>Kennedy</ent> and General <ent type='PERSON'>Eisenhower</ent> stood together talking by the side of
the aircraft for about two minutes. Mr. <ent type='PERSON'>Kennedy</ent> gestured repeatedly with
his left hand and appearing to be explaining something to General
<ent type='PERSON'>Eisenhower</ent>. General <ent type='PERSON'>Eisenhower</ent> listened intently and shook his head
affirmatively several times.</p>

<p>They shook hands. Mr. <ent type='PERSON'>Kennedy</ent> then walked briskly to his plane and General
<ent type='PERSON'>Eisenhower</ent> got into an <ent type='ORG'>Air Force</ent> automobile.</p>

<p>=============================================================================
<ent type='ORG'>New York</ent> Times, November 24, 1961, page 1</p>

<p> <ent type='PERSON'>Eisenhower</ent> Says Officers Should Stay Out of Politics</p>

<p> Assails Extremists In TV Interview</p>

<p>Former President <ent type='PERSON'>Dwight</ent> D. <ent type='PERSON'>Eisenhower</ent> last night urged officers of the
armed services to shun partisan politics.</p>

<p>Speaking as a General of the <ent type='ORG'>Army</ent>, he declared it was "bad practice --
very bad" for an officer, even when testifying under oath before a
committee of <ent type='ORG'>Congress</ent>, to express opinions "on political matters or
economic matters that are contrary to the President's." ...</p>

<p>The former President was blunt in discussing the recent "rise of
extremists" in the country.</p>

<p>"I don't think <ent type='GPE'>the United</ent> States needs super-patriots," he declared.
"We need patriotism, honestly practiced by all of us, and we don't
need these people that are more patriotic than you or anybody else."</p>

<p>His definition of extremists embraced those who would "go back to
eliminating the income tax from our laws and the rights of people to
unionize... [and those] advocating some form of dictatorship." It
also included those who "make radical statements [and] attack people
of good repute who are proved patriots."</p>

<p>At that point, <ent type='PERSON'>Walter Cronkite</ent> of the C.B.S. news staff, who conducted
the interview, asked about the "military man's role in our modern
political life." He did not cite, but obviously referred to, the case
of Maj. Gen. <ent type='PERSON'>Edwin</ent> A. <ent type='PERSON'>Walker</ent>, who stirred up a controversy that led to
his "admonishment" for the political nature of the indoctrination of
his troops. General <ent type='PERSON'>Walker</ent> lated resigned from the <ent type='ORG'>Army</ent>.</p>

<p>"I believe the <ent type='ORG'>Army</ent> officer, <ent type='ORG'>Navy</ent> officer, <ent type='ORG'>Air</ent> officer," General
<ent type='PERSON'>Eisenhower</ent> said, "should not be talking about political matters,
particularly domestically, and never in the international field, unless
he is asked to do so because of some particular position he might
hold." ...</p>

<p>The general declared there was hope for disarmament and better
East-West relations. As the <ent type='NORP'>Russian</ent> standard of living improves, the
<ent type='NORP'>Russian</ent> people will begin to understand that there is another way of
life, he said...
=============================================================================
</p></xml>