<xml><p>From: wmcguire@world.std.com (Wayne McGuire)
To: talk.politics.<ent type='LOC'>mideast</ent>
Subject: The End of <ent type='NORP'>Zionism</ent> (Yet Another Failed <ent type='ORG'>Messianic Movement</ent>)
Organization: The World Public Access UNIX, <ent type='GPE'>Brookline</ent>, MA
Date: Tue, 17 Aug 1993 21:17:49 GMT
Lines: 239</p>

<p>With all due humility and modesty I want to announce that the
post below is probably one of the most important posts you'll
ever read in talk.politics.<ent type='LOC'>mideast</ent>. There, that should take care
of the levity for the day.</p>

<p>It is a message I posted to someone on another network, and sums
up a whole lot of reading and thinking I've been doing about the
<ent type='LOC'>Mideast</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent> for a few years now. Previous discussions here
in TPM, particularly interactions with ardent pro-<ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent>
partisans, helped clarify my thoughts.</p>

<p>For a number of years now I've been noticing with increasing
attention the remarkable resemblances between <ent type='NORP'>Zionism</ent> and earlier
episodes of messianic (and always disastrous) outbursts in <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent>
history, but wasn't quite prepared to make the leap that <ent type='NORP'>Zionism</ent>
as a whole fit the model. I thought that the dangerous messianic
elements were mostly on the religious right, and could be safely
isolated. But the more I read, the more I realized that
messianism permeated the <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent>i left as much as the <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent>i
right, and that the entire <ent type='NORP'>Zionist</ent> enterprise is fundamentally
messianic in its outlook and foundations.</p>

<p>The collapse of Communism (the 20th century's premier secular
messianic movement), the failure of the <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent>i kibbutz
movement, the rush to proclaim <ent type='PERSON'>Menachem Schneerson</ent> the Messiah,
the rise of Kahanism, and an unceasing succession of blunders by
the <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent>i government starting in the 1973 war and continuing
most recently in the Demjanjuk fiasco have all combined to lead
me to the conclusion that something is so seriously awry with the
<ent type='NORP'>Zionist</ent> experiment that it does in fact exhibit all the traits of
previous failed messianic movements in <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> history.</p>

<p>What really confirmed me in this conviction was reading five
books one after the other, and digesting all the information
interactively and seeing all the implications:</p>

<p><ent type='GPE'>Golan</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Matti</ent>. With Friends Like You: What <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent>is Really Think
About <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>. <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent>: <ent type='ORG'>The Free Press</ent>, 1992. Translated
from the Hebrew by Hillel Halkin.</p>

<p>Leibowitz, <ent type='PERSON'>Yeshayahu</ent>. Judaism, Human Values, and the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent>
State. <ent type='GPE'>Cambridge</ent>, MA: <ent type='ORG'>Harvard University Press</ent>, 1992.</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Roth</ent>, Philip. Operation Shylock: A Confession. <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent>: <ent type='PERSON'>Simon</ent> &amp;
Schuster, 1993.</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>Segev</ent>, Tom. The Seventh Million: The <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent>is and The Holocaust.
<ent type='GPE'>New York</ent>: Hill and <ent type='ORG'>Wang</ent>, 1993.</p>

<p>Sicker, Martin. Judaism, Nationalism, and <ent type='ORG'>the Land</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent>.
<ent type='GPE'>Boulder</ent>, CO. Westview Press, 1992.</p>

<p>Earlier here I tried to stimulate, without success, some serious
discussion about four of the books. If you want to get an idea of
how I reached my conclusions, try reading them and do some
creative thinking about what you've read. Attached below the post
is a longer list of books which collectively provide an
articulate explanation of why Zionism's future is bleak indeed.</p>

<p>If you want the really short course, just read the <ent type='PERSON'>Martin Sicker</ent>
book. Surveying thousands of years of failed messianism in a few
hundred pages is a real education, and puts mere decades of
<ent type='NORP'>Zionism</ent> into perspective.</p>

<p>I can imagine the howls of outrage or mirth the assertion that
<ent type='NORP'>Zionism</ent> is defunct will arouse, but that is entirely predictable
and not interesting. I am not particularly motivated to debate
the subject one way or the other, although I will read with
curiosity valuable insights, as opposed to polemics, anyone might
contribute to my, ahem, prophetic, shall we even say, messianic
pronouncement. For me, the essential debate is over. All the
angry back and forth that is going on here and elsewhere about
who is right and wrong concerning this and that incident between
<ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent> and its neighbors is just so much noise and is missing the
big picture. Trying to figure out what is going on in the <ent type='LOC'>Mideast</ent>
and the <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent>-<ent type='NORP'>Arab</ent> conflict was for me an exercise in solving a
knotty and fascinating intellectual problem. Once the problem is
figured out, it no longer excites one's attention.</p>

<div>----------------------------------------------------------------</div>

<p>[Post to Mary Weiss]</p>

<p>I've radically changed my views about <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent> and the <ent type='LOC'>Mideast</ent>
conflict since we last chatted. Back then I was advocating
positions, with my usual visionary foresight, that have been
adopted by the current <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent>i government. I was slightly ahead
of my time. Now I believe--make that KNOW--that <ent type='NORP'>Zionism</ent> may well
prove to be the greatest calamity for <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> in world history to
date, and will most certainly fail as a movement and a physical
state. <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent> may not even last out the decade. <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> will come to
regret the day that <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent> was ever founded. It doesn't matter
what policies <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent> adopts--left, right, center, whatever. <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>
will be weeping and gnashing their teeth over the fact that they
foolishly saddled themselves with the need to support and defend
a physical <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> state in the middle of a region which hates
that state. All the old anti-<ent type='NORP'>Zionist</ent> arguments that <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>
themselves hashed over before the founding of <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent> are going to
come to the surface again, and the original <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> anti-<ent type='NORP'>Zionist</ent>s
are going to look like prophets. <ent type='PERSON'>Theodore Herzl</ent> will come to be
seen as notorious a failed prophet as <ent type='PERSON'>Karl Marx</ent>.</p>

<p>The reason? <ent type='NORP'>Zionism</ent> is a false messianic movement, a well-known
phenomenon in <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> history. It is built on air, fantasies, and
intoxication, not solid ground. These messianic splurges always
end up in catastrophes for <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, and <ent type='NORP'>Zionism</ent> looks like it will
be the granddaddy of all these fiascos, for hundreds of reasons
which I could document for you at length. But you know the main
reason yourself if you examine your heart: ask yourself why you
don't live in <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent>. Then you'll know why so many <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> want to
leave <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent>.</p>

<p>Trust me, <ent type='PERSON'>Marty</ent>, it is over. Sometime during the last year or
two, deep in the secret soul of <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>, of history, of the world,
<ent type='NORP'>Zionism</ent> died, expired. <ent type='NORP'>Zionist</ent>s will continue to go through the
motions, engage in angry and self-destructive arguments with
fellow <ent type='NORP'>American</ent>s and others who criticize <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent>: you know the
whole drill. But at the core, the ball game is over. The more
that <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> get locked into the position of defending a state they
don't want to live in, and don't even believe in, the more pain
and difficulty they are going to cause themselves.</p>

<p>The best advice anyone could give to <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> who really cares about
them--not all of them, to be sure, but some of them--is to begin
to make preparations now for dissolving the state of <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent> that
are maximally advantageous for <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent>is and <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent> in general. Once
that is accomplished, then sit down and figure out why you keep
getting suckered in by self-destructive messianic movements, and
then fix the problem through some form of cultural self-analysis
and psychotherapy. Then get on with doing what you do best in a
modern pluralistic society like the U.S.--make art, make science,
make products, make friends, be happy, be self-fulfilled, etc.,
and just generally get on with making productive lives free of
the need to pursue a collective or ethnocentric messianic mission
of any kind, divine or secular.</p>

<p>If this doesn't happen, it seems certain that <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent> will be
heading for a mess that is beyond your wildest dreams. Those who
will be taking the deepest pleasure in Israel's continued
existence will be the world's most virulent anti-<ent type='NORP'>Semites</ent>.</p>

<p>I know you won't believe a word I am saying, and will react
defensively, but that's ok. I know what I know. And I only say
something like this with the utmost gravity and care, after a
tremendous amount of reading, thought, and conversation. I know
what I am talking about, and I came to these conclusions very
reluctantly, in fact resisted them with all my might, since they
are so disturbing. I mainly want to get this statement down on
the public record somewhere, in part for the ego gratification of
being recognized as one of the first people to figure this out.
Once you get a handle on the key features of false messianism, of
any messianism for that matter, and do a match against all the
developments that have been going on <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent> virtually since it's
founding, the truth becomes crystal clear. The coming collapse is
visible in Israel's every action and word.</p>

<p>One important point to keep in mind is that people who have been
bitten by the messianic bug NEVER know when the house is about to
cave in: that is one of the key traits of messianism: it destroys
your ability to read objective reality clearly. The mind of the
messianist--whether that of one of the leaders of the revolt
against <ent type='GPE'>Rome</ent>, or one of <ent type='PERSON'>Sabbatai Sevi</ent>'s followers, or one of Karl
Marx's disciples, or <ent type='PERSON'>Menachem Schneerson</ent>'s, or David Koresh's, is
clouded by a kind of drug which is able to ignore or distort
every fact relevant to his or her true situation. All messianists
are essentially mad, at least for the duration of their fever.
After every messianic binge comes the vicious headache: what the
hell were we up to?</p>

<p>What is the essence of messianism? Eventually your bullshit
catches up with you.</p>

<p>It wouldn't have made a damn bit of difference, by the way, if
the <ent type='NORP'>Arab</ent>s in the region had welcomed the state of <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent> with
open arms. In fact if that had been the case, <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent> would have
gone under much sooner. The <ent type='LOC'>Mideast</ent> wars, with their effect in
uniting <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent>is against a common external enemy, have served as
a distraction to keep <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent>is from dealing with their underlying
internal problems, all of which revolve around the
self-destructive tendencies inherent in all forms of messianism.</p>

<p>At some point the leaders of world <ent type='ORG'>Jewry</ent> are going to sit down
and ask--if they haven't already--on the whole is the state of
<ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent> a net positive or a net negative for the world's <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>? Is
it improving our health, wealth, reputation, peace of mind,
physical security, and good relations with our neighbors, or is
it damaging them? If <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent> has become a significant net
negative, and there is no realistic prospect of improving the
situation, is there any point in continuing to maintain it, or
like a business gone permanently bad, should we just put it to
rest and get on to more fruitful matters?</p>

<p><ent type='NORP'>Zionism</ent>, just like Communism, and for much the same reasons, is
intellectually, morally, spiritually, psychologically,
ideologically, and economically bankrupt.</p>

<p><ent type='NORP'>Zionism</ent>, like Communism, attempted to build a society in a
top-down fashion by imposing a rigid ideology and theory on an
unmalleable physical situation. Successful nations grow
organically from the bottom up, emerging naturally from and
cooperating with the facts on the ground.</p>

<p>All successful enterprises are fundamentally pragmatic and
bottom-up. All messianic movements in the world are doomed to
failure because they are top-down and over-ideological in their
essential nature. The curse of messianism is the curse of
ideology and theory on a megalomaniacal scale.</p>

<p>This ideology is no more. It has ceased to be. It's expired and
gone to meet its maker. This is a late ideology. It's a stiff.
<ent type='PERSON'>Bereft</ent> of life, its rests in peace. If you hadn't nailed it to
the perch, it would be pushing up the daisies. It's rung down the
curtain and joined the choir invisible. This is an ex-ideology.</p>

<p>In any case, enjoy the laugh--I can't guarantee I'll find the
time to participate in this conference at any length to provide
the long version of these insights. But after you laugh, give a
little serious thought to what I am saying. I just may be right.</p>

<p>Wayne</p>

<div>----------------------------------------------------------------</div>

<p>Reading List
************</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>Avineri</ent>, Shlomo. <ent type='PERSON'>Moses Hess</ent>: Prophet of Communism and <ent type='NORP'>Zionism</ent>.
<ent type='GPE'>New York</ent> and <ent type='GPE'>London</ent>: <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent> University Press, 1985.</p>

<p>Friedman, <ent type='PERSON'>Robert</ent> I. the False Prophet: Rabbi <ent type='PERSON'>Meir Kahane</ent>: From
<ent type='ORG'>FBI Informant</ent> to <ent type='ORG'>Knesset</ent> Member. <ent type='GPE'>Brooklyn</ent>: Lawrence Hill Books,
1990.</p>

<p><ent type='GPE'>Golan</ent>, <ent type='ORG'>Matti</ent>. With Friends Like You: What <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent>is Really Think
About <ent type='NORP'>American</ent> <ent type='NORP'>Jews</ent>. <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent>: <ent type='ORG'>The Free Press</ent>, 1992. Translated
from the Hebrew by Hillel Halkin.</p>

<p>Harkabi, <ent type='PERSON'>Yehoshafat</ent>. Israel's Fateful Hour. <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent>: Harper &amp;
Row, 1988.</p>

<p>Leibowitz, <ent type='PERSON'>Yeshayahu</ent>. Judaism, Human Values, and the <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent>
State. <ent type='GPE'>Cambridge</ent>, MA: <ent type='ORG'>Harvard University Press</ent>, 1992.</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>Leshem</ent>, Moshe. Balaam's Curse: How <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent> Lost Its Way, and How
It Can Find It Again. <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent>: <ent type='PERSON'>Simon</ent> and Schuster, 1989.</p>

<p>Lustick, Ian S. for <ent type='ORG'>the Land</ent> and the Lord: <ent type='NORP'>Jewish</ent> Fundamentalism
in <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent>. <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent>: Council on Foreign Relations, 1988.</p>

<p><ent type='PERSON'>Roth</ent>, Philip. Operation Shylock: A Confession. <ent type='GPE'>New York</ent>: <ent type='PERSON'>Simon</ent> &amp;
Schuster, 1993.</p>

<p>Scholem, Gershom. <ent type='PERSON'>Sabbatai Sevi</ent>: The Mystical Messiah. Princeton,
<ent type='GPE'>New Jersey</ent>: <ent type='ORG'>Princeton University Press</ent>, 1973. Translated by R. J.
Zwi Werblowsky.</p>

<p><ent type='ORG'>Segev</ent>, Tom. The Seventh Million: The <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent>is and The Holocaust.
<ent type='GPE'>New York</ent>: Hill and <ent type='ORG'>Wang</ent>, 1993.</p>

<p>Sicker, Martin. Judaism, Nationalism, and <ent type='ORG'>the Land</ent> of <ent type='GPE'>Israel</ent>.
<ent type='GPE'>Boulder</ent>, CO. Westview Press, 1992.
</p></xml>